He slaughtered our men,
our brothers,
our sons.
But they cry out to us for justice.
For their souls, I swear to you
the man who took our loved ones from us,
the man who brought us such pain and sorrow,
we will punish him.
We will bring him... here.
We'll not rest
until his blood flows into this very ground.
We will have our revenge.
- Sir? Excuse me.
- Yeah.
But the finish is included
in the cost of the wash.
That's okay, I'd rather do it myself,
I'm a little obsessive that way.
- Lenore.
- Bryan.
- Hi, how are you?
- Fine, you?
- Good, good.
- Somethin' up?
No. It's Saturday, 2 o'clock.
Kim's driving lesson?
Yeah, music lesson got switched.
- The Tuesday one or the Friday one?
- I have no idea.
You know how kids are.
Um-huh! Especially those who're desperate
to pass their driving test at their third try.
She's not desperate.
But she failed the test twice, Leny.
It's important.
So ... where is she? Really.
- I've never been a good liar, have I?
- No, it's not your forte.
She met her boyfriend.
She has a boyfriend?
Do you want to come in for a drink?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I think you should, okay.
Why didn’t she tell me, for God's sake?
She probably didn't want
you running a full security
check of everything thing
he's done since kindergarten.
But she's okay, right?
Yeah, she's okay.
Tell me it's none of my business, but ...
Are you okay?
No.
Not really, you know, we've separated.
Well, is there nothing I can do?
Well, I better... thanks for the wine.
- Bryan! Don't.
- I don't even know where the kid lives.
You found her in a city of
12 million people within 72 hours.
- Promise me.
- I just told you...
- Promise!
- I'm gonna give her her space.
Hi.
Can I help you?
Is Kim here?
- Yeah, and you are...?
- Her father.
Mr. Mills, what a pleasure, I'm Jamie.
Come in.
- Can I get you anything? A drink or...
- Just my daughter would be fine.
- Dad?
- Hi.
What are you doing here?
Well, I know how important it is
for you pass your tests.
Wait! Kim you don't have a license.?
Have you ever tried to parallel park an Escalade?
I told you to take the test with my car.
Dad.
Thank you.
It's a pleasure to meet you, Mr. Mills.
Could we slow down a little bit, please.
I can't believe you could do that.
You're leaving in fall, right, next week.
It's the only time I can get
to do this before I go to Istanbul.
We planned this.
When you make plans, you keep them...
No, Dad, you planned it.
- How did you even find me?
- Your mom and I were talking...
Why didn't you tell me you have a boyfriend?
Because I knew you'd over-react and I just
wanted to be normal, even if I'm just pretending.
- Remember to break before stop.
- Dad!
Mom doesn't know where Jamie lives.
GPS?
I had it installed on your phone, I'm sorry.
It's just... you hear so many scary stories
of goings-on of people your age.
Dad, I don't even know how to start feeling
normal again, but this definitely isn't it.
Kim, you can move.
Use your side mirror.
Perfect! Why couldn't you do that in the test?
I don't know.
Maybe I didn't really want a license.
Listen...
Of course I know where you're coming from.
But you gotta trust me to figure this out.
- Don't do this again, please.
- I won't.
And don't go running a background
check on him with your friend.
I won't.
Okay.
- See ya Wednesday.
- Au revoir.
- Love you.
- Hey, I love you.
One moment.
A package came for you.
- I'll meet you inside.
- As you wish, Sir.
Your mail.
Sebastian.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
Okay.
You want to play with me?
But then, you could play her tomorrow.
- Taken 2 (2012)
- IMDB #1397280
- Created by DonToribio (Subscene.Com moniker)
- October 18, 2012 posted first to Subscene.
- Version: Taken 2 2012 TS XviD AC3-ADTRG
- Look.
- No! No!
Again the rules are changing.
- What's happened? Are you okay?
- Yeah, no, I'm great.
I'll... come in, I'll get Kim.
Hey, hey,  hey, hey!
- Leny, talk to me.
- We...
We had this trip planned to
China for Kim's spring break...
the family, you know, to
try and work things out.
And when Stu and I... we thought
it'd be nice for Kim and I to...
you know, to be away... together,
away from all the tension.
- Sure.
- They cancelled everything, all the reservations.
I just can't believe he did that to us.
I'm tired of the fighting, the lawyers ...
- He's turned into such a bastard.
- I'm sorry, Leny, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, this is really not your problem.
It's my turn to have Kim for the fall,
I'll take care of that.
Look, why don't you and
Kim come with me?
But, we can't impose on you,
you're working.
You're not imposing,
I'm working for 3 days.
Then you could come over, it... could be fun.
That's so sweet.
I do not know, I... just...
I can't think of right now.
Sure, I understand, I understand, no pressure.
I leave in the morning,
I work three days. Call me.
If you're coming, I'll hang around,
if not I'll come back. That's it.
- I'll go get Kim.
- Okay.
Thank you, Bryan.
- She is definitely coming?
- I don't know.
- Come on.
- Come on, Sam, I don't know.
- You should have insisted.
- Come on, guys, cut me some slack.
She's going through a hard time,
I didn't want to make it harder on her.
- She was confiding in me.
- Oh!
Well, I didn't know you guys
were still so cozy, that
she shares her marriage issues with you.
Wait a minute, I mean, I mean,
I know you guys were close, obviously
but are you, like close again,
close like... you know?
- Lay money she still got something for him.
- Don't got there, friend.
- Whoa! Maybe he still has something for her.
- Well, that's...
Could we talk about basketball,
for God's sake! Come on!
Istanbul.
Thank you, Mr. Mills.
You made my stay feel very secure.
Thank you, have a safe trip home.
You also.
You reached Lenore,
leave a message after the beep.
Hey, it's me.
No message from you
so I guess probably found some place to go.
I hope things are a little easier.
If you ever need to talk
or anything, well, I'm here.
I mean, I'll be there.
I'll probably ship-out tomorrow.
No news from Kim, so I guess
she's busy with the boyfriend, and all.
Dad!
- Surprise!
- My God, Kim, baby!
- Hello, Leny.
- Hello, hi.
I was just leaving you a message...
when I didn't hear...
- We wanted to surprise you.
- Well, you succeeded.
You guys could've been surprised,
I coulda been outta here and headed home.
- Mom's been calling Sam.
- Oh yeah?
- Uh-huh, yes
- We've been tracking YOU.
Not exactly, you're not the only
one who's got moves, you know?
Apparently not!
Welcome to Istanbul.
- Not too shabby, huh?
- Wow!
Oh, my God!
Mom, Mom, look at this.
- Oh my God!
- Crazy, right?
- Thank you so much.
- My pleasure.
But, listen, I'll let you get settled and I'll come
and collect you, in what. half an hour?
Okay.
Later.
Pass.
The cause is still being investigated,
but a source... actually in the area at
the time of Thursday's crash.
on the island of Corsica.
After the... made an unauthorized entrance
the ship then keeled over on its side.
- Hey.
- You look great.
- You, too.
So, where are we heading?
Well, I am going nowhere, I'm beat,
so I'm just gonna take a
nice, long bath and get into bed.
- Leny, are you sure?
- Yeah.
I guess it's just you and me, Kiddo.
So, on this side is Europe
and the other side is Asia.
And every conquest since,
for the last 2 thousand 500 years
whether it was the West going east
or the East going west,
they all used this very same waterway.
- Do you want tea, Babe?
- Yeah.
Just one, please.
So, how do you know all this stuff.
How do I know? I read it in a book
on the flight over.
And you can borrow it if you wish.
Yeah, I would.
So... uh... this...
Jamie... is it... serious?
I wasn't really ready for this transition.
I don't know, it's only been a few months.
Are you in love with him?
I guess I'm not sure yet.
- Have you ever been in love before?
- Not...
Not the way that mom talks about it.
How does she describe it?
She said when you guys he met... that...
- It was Super Special.
- Super Special.
- She said that?
- I think the exact word she used was:
Magical.
Magical, huh?
It is good to see you again, my friend.
Is everything prepared?
As you requested.
Perfect.
- Yeah?
- They're in the lobby.
Wait until he's outside,
and remember... alive.
He's looking at me, I'm leaving.
- Hey.
- Hi.
I thought we were having lunch in the Bazaar.
Jet lag just hit me so I figured
I'd veg-out at the pool
and let you guys go and meet-up with you later.
- I guess, okay with you?
- Okay, fine.
Okay, bye.
- Hey, Kim.
- Yeah.
That book I was telling you about,
it's on my dresser.
- Definitely.
- No adventure.
- I’ll go call a car.
- Have fun.
- Hey, Kim. I know what you're doing.
- What?
Yeah?
The daughter is still here so what can we do?
I want all 3 of them.
Yes.
She thinks we just fell off the turnip truck.
- What do you mean?
- She's trying to play Cupid.
Oh, I see.
You know? When you first
came back and said you
wanted to make-up for all
the time you lost with Kim?
- Uh-huh.
- Is that right! Three weeks he's gone.
That was usually the full limit you stuck around.
Give or take a week.
We're too close.
You really proved me wrong,
I thought you'd never change.
- Why not?
- Ah... you're personality.
You know, when you commit to something, ya gotta
focus all your energy there,
like a dog with a bone.
Nice analogy.
You know what I mean.
When you give, it's 100 percent of 100 percent.
If I was on to something, it was just that thing,
even though I tell myself something should change,
I can never give it up.
- You gave us up.
- No, never.
Not in here.
Driver, turn left.
Leny, don't.
What?
- Will you tell me what's going on?
- It's okay.
Move!
See the gallery entrenched in
the middle of the block?
- Will you tell me what's going on?
- Do you see it?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I see it.
When we stop, I want you to get out of the car.
While you're a shopper I want you to get inside.
Okay, but will you tell me what's going on!
- Listen to me!
- Tell me what's happening!
Listen, Leny! There's no time for this!
- Please talk to me!
- Listen!
At the lights at the back of the
fabric store, turn right.
Take the first street on the right,
and then left on the very next street.
Go straight until you come to a set of steps.
There's a red corridor. It's a lane.
When you exit the lane,
there's a cab stand.
Go back to the hotel, get Kim,
get the head of hotel security
and demand they cordon-off your room.
Do not open the door for anyone.
No room service,
no police, no one!
- You wait for me.
- I can't believe this is happening.
I need you to focus.
- Are you ready?
- No.
Leny, I need you to be ready.
I need you to be ready!
Come on, focus.
Driver! Stop!
- Okay, go.
- Wait, what about you?
I'll be fine.
The guys following us are about to have a problem.
When the dog has a bone,
the last thing you want to
do is try to take it from him.
Be careful.
Out of the car.
Come on!
Move, move, move!
Sir! Please!
Please, Sir!
He knows.
Do it now.
Come on!
Shit!
Come on, Kim,
answer the God damn phone!
God, no!
Somebody help me!
The key! Open the door! Please!
Shit!
I'll blow his brains out.
Bryan!
- Please.
- Drop the gun.
- I really wish you were here.
- Me too.
You have no idea.
- What?
- My dad's calling,
he's on a date with my mom.
Don't go away.
I miss you.
- How's it going?
- Listen to me carefully, Kim.
Your mother...
and I... are going to be taken.
Daddy!
Oh, my God.
People are going to come for you, too.
Leave the place where you are, call me.
Go to where the book is I told you about.
There's the door. Go into the room
and hide in the closet. You got that?
- Yeah.
- Good, I'll call you.
Go... now!
No!
She is in room 4-22.
1, 2,
3, 4, 5, 6...
Right turn...
Men singing...
1, 2, 3...
4, boat...
The pool.
Security, 4th floor. Can you hear me?
Send someone now.
25, 26, 27...
28, 29, stop.
Hammer on metal.
Left, gear shift to second.
1, 2, 3...
Birds.
Take them to the shop... straight.
Right turn, 27.
Then stop.
Come on, Sam, pick up.
Hey, this is Sam, leave me a message.
Shit.
- Are you guys okay?
- No, no.
- Are you all right?
- Yes
- I'm just scared.
- Kim, listen to me very carefully.
I need you to calm down
and pull yourself together.
The men who came for you, did they leave?
Yes, what did they want?
- I'm going to find out.
- Is Mom okay?
- Dad?
- Mom's fine.
Good.
What are we gonna do?
I want you to go to the U.S. embassy.
- You'll be safe there.
- What about you and Mom?
I'll figure something out.
- Where are you now?
- I don't really know, Kim.
Dad, how can I tell them where to find you, then?
You can't. Now get going.
- No.
- Kimmy.
- No, tell me what to do.
- No, Kim.
Dad, if you tell me what to do, I can do it.
- Kim, this is not a game.
- I know that.
It’s my parents' lives.
Dad, please,
you're wasting time.
Please,
tell me what to do.
Can you get out of the closet safely?
Yes
If you can, take the case with you.
Okay.
- I'm aff!
- The combination is:
2-3, 2-8, 8-4.
It is open?
Yes!
- Okay, do you see a map?
- Yeah.
Take the map, you'll see a scale
on the top in kilometers.
Do you see it?
Yeah, I see it.
Take a shoelace from one
of my shoes in the closet.
Use it as a guide.
There's a pen in the case, take it.
Draw a circle
with the hotel in the center of it.
It's done!
Make the diameter
3 kilometers. You got that?
It's done!
Draw another circle with the market in the center.
Okay!
Do the circles
intersect at any point?
No.
Now take one of those little cans.
The ones with the pins on the top.
It's a grenade. I want you to
go to the balcony with the grenade.
Is there a safe place you can throw it?
- There’s a parking garage.
- Anyone on it?
- No.
- I want you to pull the pin out of the grenade,
count to 3 so that I can hear it,
and toss it as far as you can.
Then run back into the room,
keep the phone on so
I hear the explosion.
1, 2, 3.
1, 2, 3, 4.
- Dad?
- Now draw a circle on the map.
Put the hotel on the mid-line
and the circumference
at 4 point 5 kilometers.
Okay.
Do the circles intersect at any point?
Yes, two points.
I'm at one of the two intersecting points.
Now, go outside and
look at the flags on the rooftops.
Do you see the flags?
- Yes
- Are they in the wind?
- Going east, right?
I think so, yeah, how do you know?
Now look at the map.
I want you to go to the point
where the circles intersect at the east.
I want you to take one of the guns,
get to a rooftop, wait for my call,
And two of the grenades. You go to the
rooftop at the most easterly point.
Get up to the rooftop, wait for my call.
Be casual, Kim,
blend in.
Okay.
Dad?
What are you doing?
This is an employees' locker room!
Wait! Stop!
Do you know this man?
This one?
- This one?
- No.
This one?
- What do you want?
- You recognize none of them.
To you they were nothing, but to
other people they are... sons,
and grandsons,
fathers and husbands.
And you killed them all.
Like they were so many nothings.
And this one?
Do you recognize him?
You DO recognize him.
And you didn't just kill him,
you strapped him to a chair.
you touched electric cables to the chair
you turned the current on,
and you left it on until his heart burst.
He's the one who kidnapped dozens of girls
and ruined their lives.
He was my son, Marko
From Trepoja.
And I have come to take you to Trepoja
to face you to the people
whose lives you ruined.
- To give them justice.
- You mean to give them their revenge.
Because it gives us peace,
call it anything you wish.
I killed your son because
he kidnapped my daughter!
I don't care what he did!
I will know...
I will never see his face again.
I will never hear his voice.
And if you held him responsible
for your daughter,
I hold YOU responsible for him.
Your death will not be quick,
it will not be pleasant.
But before you die, this is what you'll see.
How long will it take for
the blood to rush to her head
and have no place to go?
- About 30 minutes.
- You are right.
You are next for this,
so you have 30 minutes to watch her die.
She had nothing to do with this.
Do what you want with me, let her go.
Don't play the hero with me.
Now we're going to get your daughter.
She will be sold to the
lowest brothel in this world.
She will be abused by so many men,
for she'll be nothing more than a piece of meat
that a dog would not have.
Don't listen to them, Leny.
Kim is safe, I talked to her.
She's safe.
You have to stay calm.
Breathe slowly, you have to.
I won't let anything happen to you,
or to her... I promise.
Quiet!
We lost the girl.
The girl has gone.
I'll be back as soon as we get her.
Then we move, let's go!
Hold on, Leny.
Hold on, Leny, hold on.
Sorry!
Leny!
I put your things down here, I'm here.
Come on, call!
Please.
Leny, I'm coming back.
- I'm here.
- Set-off another grenade.
- Dad
- You're close.
I want to keep moving east.
Count to 30
and then set-off another one.
1, 2, 3...
18, 19...
27, 28, 29, 30.
Go out and check what's going on.
Kim.
Yeah?
Look east!
Look for a white cloud of steam!
- I see it!
- Run for it,
tell me when you're there.
I'm going down.
- Dad
- Where are you?
I'm right by the steam.
Drop the gun down the vent.
- Those guys are here, they're coming.
- Drop the gun, Kim,
and run!
Go!
Dad, they're coming!
I'll be back.
Hey, what are you doing in the hall?
Drop it!
On your knees!
Don't do this.
Dad!
Dad! Dad!
Where's Mom? Is she okay?
She's safe, she's safe.
Slow down, slow down, slow down.
That man had the same
tattoo as the men in Paris.
It's not you they want
Kim, it's me.
I want you to wait here,
I'm going to get mom.
Wait five minutes and if I don't show up,
I want you to go straight here:
The American embassy.
- Tell them what happened.
- Dad.
No time, Kim, give me your phone.
You wait five minutes, not a moment longer.
No matter what happens, time runs out,
you go! You understand me?
Okay.
- Let me go.
Please.
Yes?
- Move!
- You killed him.
I had no choice, now move.
- Where's Mom?
- She's fine, she's not far.
- Where is she?
- Come on, Kim, move!
- I don't wanna do this.
- Go on, Kim.
- Where are we going?
- Go straight!
We have to go to the embassy.
- I'm not sure I can.
- You know how to shoot?
- No.
- Then drive.
They escaped.
Shit! The Cops!
- Dad, I have to stop.
- No, I just shot one of them, now go!
Come on, go!
Go right!
Back, back, back!
Come on, move!
Come on, Kim.
Go! Go!
Come on, keep going!
Left!
Yes.
Keep going!
- Oh, no, they're shooting.
- Stay low, keep going.
- Come on, faster.
- I can't!
- Do it!
Come on, move! Move!
- Dad!
- Keep going! Watch the road!
Right!
Oh, shit!
Come on, Kim, move!
- Go! - Okay! - Go!
C'mon! Keep going!
Come on!
Shit!
- Dad!
- Keep going, stay low!
- Faster, Kim.
- I can't!
- Come on, faster!
- Dad!
Keep going!
You can make it!
Do it.
- Here, Don't stop!
- But there's soldiers.
They'll move!
Down, Kim!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Keep your head down, Kimmy.
Hey, Bry.
Sam, we're in the courtyard of
the U.S. embassy in Istanbul
with a smashed-up car.
Don't ask. Can you
call someone to make
sure we don't get shot?
Yeah, of course.
Thanks.
It's Bry, he's in trouble in Istanbul.
Mom didn't get away, did she?
- No.
- Oh, God, Dad.
- Tell me the truth, is she...?
- No, no, no, no, Kim.
No, no she's not.
But they have her.
And they will use her until
they get what they want.
Me!
You'll be safe here in the
embassy until I come back.
- Kimmy, it's gonna be okay.
- Dad, it's okay.
Kim, Kim listen.
I have to find them,
and bring your mom back.
And then I have to make sure these
people never bother us again in our lives.
What are you gonna do?
What I do best.
Mrs. Mills.
What should I do with you, Mrs. Mills?
I have nothing against you.
You didn't kill my son.
But your husband did.
Now he betrayed you,
by choosing to save your daughter,
instead of you.
He left you here like a dog.
At least my daughter is still alive.
Mrs. Mills,
you are a good mother,
and a brave woman.
For that, I'm going to send you back home...
piece by piece.
Boris, shut the dog up!
Go and see what happened.
Let's go! Move her here to the Hammond.
Quick, quick!
You stay here.
Go!
Come on!
Get lost!
Honey?
I'm here, Baby, I'm here.
I'm coming back, Leny, I'm coming back.
Okay.
What are you waiting for?
- You have other sons?
- Two.
And if I killed you, they will
come and seek revenge.
They will for sure.
And I will kill them, too.
You can change that.
You can go home, live your life,
enjoy your sons, your grandsons.
But my other son, Marko,
the son you killed...
am I supposed just to forget it?
No, you'll just have to live with it,
like the parents of all those kidnapped girls,
or you can die... here.
- What are you telling me?
- What I'm saying is...
if you give me your word,
I will throw-down this gun,
and simply walk away.
Why?
Because I'm tired of it all.
Leny, I'm here.
I'm here, baby. I'm here.
Come on.
It's all right, Leny.
It's okay.
We're safe.
Bryan?
- Kim? Kim?
- She's safe.
She's safe.
We're all safe.
Three weeks after
Line it up!
That's it!
Now, begin to cut! Not too fast. Not so fast.
Straighten it out! Straighten! Straighten!
Stop, stop stop!
Perfect.
- Well... perfect score.
- Great!
- Congratulations.
- Thank you. Thank you.
I was perfect.
I've been saying that since the day you were born.
Congratulations!
So... what would you like to do to celebrate?
- I think I have an idea.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, I'll drive.
- Of course!
Here you go! 3 double chocolate fudge.
- Thank you.
- And who's having the strawberry?
I'm sorry, but I just ordered 3.
Well, actually the order said 4.
- I ordered a 4th one.
- Yeah? For who?
- Oh, Jamie. Hey.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Hi! Pretty good timing.
Jamie.
- It's cool if he joins us, right?
- Of course he can, Kim.
Dad?
- Right?
- Of course it is, Honey.
Behave!
It's nice to see you again, Sir.
Nice to see you, too. Sit down.
Hi.
- We got you a strawberry.
- Oh, please.
Thanks, Dad.
Do not shoot this one, I really like him.