I hereby decree that Prime Minister Cao Cao
lead the Imperial Army
to pacify the rebels Liu Bei
and Sun Quan.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
These people are loyal
to the Han Empire.
They followed us
to escape Cao Cao's regime.
If we do not protect civilians,
then what is the meaning
of this war?
An alliance will strengthen us both.
When a loser joins forces with a coward
what can they accomplish?
What the Southlands need is unity!
My decision to fight is final.
Anyone who dares
mention surrender
will end up like this table!
You need to fight this war.
I am not afraid of him.
I have been waiting for this day!
We shall fight,
not waste time with words.
Make camp there!
On the bank facing Red Cliff.
Tomorrow, we may be enemies.
If that day ever comes,
it will be each man for himself.
Cao Cao has no experience
in naval warfare.
He must rely on Admirals Cai Mao
and Zhang Yun.
If I can eliminate them,
his navy will be powerless.
Nice play!
Goal!
These little monkeys
are getting quicker!
The Prime Minister's
order to practice Cuju
has toughened these kids up.
Follow closely.
- Carry him inside quickly.
- Follow me.
Just my stomach growling.
- Yes!
- Goal!
What do you think?
Not bad, right?
Block him!
Yeah!
That pot isn't wide enough.
You would miss no matter
how wide it was.
Pitch pot is a game for aristocrats...
not for soldiers in wartime.
Your Honor, how'd you
throw that bull's eye?
Concentration.
When the enemy is over-confident,
we must double
our concentration.
With concentration,
you can kill a giant with a pebble.
Your Highness,
Zhou Yu's army is small.
He'll have to resort to guerrilla warfare.
That last puny victory
has made Zhou Yu cocky.
He's no guerrilla warrior.
He will confront us face to face.
They are readying for battle.
We need a strategy
to counter them.
Cao Cao wants to surround us
without breaking
the basic rules of strategy.
The first army to the field
will be rested.
The second army
will arrive exhausted.
Attack where the enemy
is least prepared.
Strike where they least expect it.
We must concentrate all forces
on their strongest position.
Naval victory depends on
Admirals Cai Mao and Zhang Yun.
We are loyal to
Your Highness until death.
Cao Cao underestimates us.
He will never expect us
to hit their navy.
What is your name?
Private Sun Shucai.
You are an outstanding player
and a good soldier.
From this day forward,
you are promoted
to battalion commander.
Thank you, Your Highness!
Everyone must
practice hard at Cuju.
Only with tough bodies
can we win this war.
Once the Southlands
are subdued,
your families will be exempt
from taxes for three years.
Thank you, Your Highness!
What are you doing?
I'm... setting these
birds free.
That's very kind of you.
You're leaving?
Judging by your accent,
I'll bet you're a Southerner.
- That's right.
- Southerners are warm-hearted people.
Northerners are free-spirited.
I'm kind of dumb.
My whole life,
people have said...
You're not dumb,
just too honest.
You're good at Cuju.
Thanks for heading the ball.
What's your name?
My name is...
Look at the size of me.
My mother calls me "Piggy."
Piggy?
So you can play Cuju right?
You kidding?
I only know hacky-sack.
Congratulations on your promotion.
So does a commander get bigger meals?
You're a big officer now.
You can eat as much as you want.
Are you fighting just to fill your stomach?
Mother says my stomach
is a bottomless pit.
My family's too poor to feed me.
We're Pit and Piggy!
What a pair!
The new environment
has made our men ill.
They are weak from a long war
and have lost all immunity.
So typhoid quickly...
Can it be cured?
Yes,
but not overnight.
How many have died?
Over a hundred.
In a few days, it will be out of control.
We must bury them right away.
No burials! We must cremate.
Cremation is the only
way to stop its spread.
Ready the funeral pyres.
Hold on.
"Epidemic outbreak"
The climate has weakened
Cao Cao's army.
- Disease is rampant.
- Great.
Your Honor,
let's seize this chance and attack.
The navy is still healthy.
We must not act recklessly.
Your Honor, this is the time to attack!
Yes!
This is a battle of honor.
Even war must be fair.
Your Highness,
isn't this a bit inhumane?
Cast off the soldiers of the dead!
What's the matter?
Pull the boats here.
Look, what is that?
Pull it here.
Pull the boats here.
- They're all dead.
- They were enemy soldiers.
- Go report this to the general.
- Yes, sir.
Pile weapons and armor here.
Put the corpses there.
Get away from here!
Don't touch them!
They died from typhoid!
Move! It's contagious!
Move! Don't touch anything!
Get out of here!
Everyone must leave!
Escort these people away.
This is for your own good.
This place is infected.
Leave here immediately!
Cao Cao truly is ruthless.
Those soldiers have touched corpses.
I've quarantined them
so they do not infect others.
And the villagers?
I fear many have already been infected.
Cao Cao has stooped to evil tricks.
This is psychological warfare.
He's attacking our morale.
How do we dispose of the bodies?
These are the bodies of our enemies.
Feed them to the fishes.
No, we must lay them to rest.
No burials.
We must cremate them.
I lift my drink and sing a song
For who knows if life be short or long
Man's life is but the morning dew
Past days many, future ones few
The melancholy my heart begets
Comes from cares I cannot forget
Who can unravel these woes of mine?
I know but one man... the God of Wine!
Disciples dressed in blue
My heart worries for you
You are the cause
Of this song without pause
Across the bank, a deer bleats
In the wilds where it eats
Honored guests I salute
Strike the harp! Play the flute!
Bright is the moon's spark
Never ceasing, never dark
Thoughts of you from deep inside
Cannot settle, cannot subside
Stars around the moon are few
Southward the crows flew
Flying with no rest
Where shall they nest?
No mountain too steep
No ocean too deep
Sages rush when guests call
So at their feet...
The empire does fall!
Take your time. Careful, it's hot.
More fall sick every day.
You have enough medicine?
Cassia trees are scarce here.
Our men will keep searching.
Can cassia cure typhoid?
It will ease current symptoms.
But a true cure
requires other ingredients.
Let me take a look.
Hurry! Carry our men out!
Move it!
Stand up, let's go.
Stop! What do you think
you're doing?
General, what are you doing?
These patients cannot be moved.
Hurry! Put our men on the horses.
Please, these men must not leave.
They are still ill.
You're leaving?
Viceroy, this epidemic
is beyond our control.
I have barely 20,000 men.
If this continues,
I might lose everything.
I must retreat
and reformulate my strategy.
You withdraw at a moment like this?
You proposed this alliance.
Now, with our lives at stake, you flee?
This is betrayal.
You can't say that.
We are men of our word.
But look what has happened to our men!
So our men count for nothing?
- Selfishness.
- Who is selfish?
- Zhang Fei!
- General!
My Lord, the battle is set.
How can you...
Zhu-ge Liang.
I have seen over a decade of defeat.
I cannot endure another setback.
Even soldiers must obey
the law of survival.
We must not lose our allies' trust.
I know you feel strongly.
But in chaotic times,
you cannot live on justice alone.
It's time I let others fight
the tough battles.
One day,
you will understand this.
Liu Bei.
It was an honor
to fight alongside your men.
We believed in the same goal.
Achieving it will not be
so easy after all.
Take care.
We shall meet again.
Aren't you leaving?
A man must honor his promises.
If I start something, I see it to the end.
Anyone who talks like that is insane.
Then we are all insane.
Your Highness, tea is ready.
Brother, scouts report
that the typhoid was successful.
- The Southlands are in chaos.
- Good.
One more thing.
Liu Bei has left with all his men.
- Good.
- Their alliance is broken.
Excellent
"Swift as the wind.
Gentle as a forest.
Fierce as fire.
Firm as a mountain."
If you hate war,
why can you quote "The Art of War"?
To understand you,
I must sneak glances at your books.
A thousand books
cannot equal a cup of your tea.
I'm happy so long
as YOU enjoy it.
I wish we could
invite Cao Cao for tea,
forget the war
and just enjoy the scenery.
Wouldn't that be great?
I doubt he appreciates the art of tea.
You wield your sword
like you know a way to beat Cao Cao.
A way as mysterious as darkness.
And as powerful as thunder.
It is time for us to act.
Greetings, Your Highness.
How goes the naval training, Admirals?
Very well, Your Highness.
We're using iron beams
to join the fleet.
Our men are Northerners
and new to naval battle.
Now our ships shall be stable
as solid ground.
Not even a storm
will make our men seasick.
- Can they be separated?
- Of course.
Men, separate the ships!
Unlocking the iron beams
separates the ships.
The fleet will move into the pincer
formation, ready for battle.
You truly are naval experts
- to invent this tactic.
- Thank you, Your Highness.
- Jiang Gan.
- At your service, Your Highness.
You grew up with Zhou Yu, right?
Yes, we were childhood friends.
Cross the river.
Urge him to surrender.
Surrender?
Zhou Yu's loyalty
to Sun Quan runs deep.
- I'm afraid he won't...
- The Southlands are falling apart.
Liu Bei has fled.
Now is the time
to ask Zhou Yu to surrender.
Yes, Your Highness.
Piggy?
Scared you, didn't I?
These guys keep tailing me.
How can I have any fun like this?
You're battalion commander.
They have to follow you.
Listen up!
Everyone go practice Cuju.
Yes, sir!
It worked!
- Let's have some fun!
- Great.
What should we play?
Let's play
- Let's play Ride High.
- Okay.
Come on.
You really are heavy.
Your mother gave you
the right nickname.
This isn't high enough.
Let's go up there.
Watch your balance.
Be careful.
This high enough for you?
Yeah.
Stay still.
- That itches.
- Itches?
Here, let me scratch it.
Much better.
Turn left.
What's so interesting there?
It's just the fleet.
Don't move.
My Lord.
Cao Cao has several
hundred thousand soldiers.
We have only 30,000.
We are totally outnumbered.
How can we fight like this?
This will decide the fate
of the Southlands.
We must fight,
even if we cannot win.
How many arrows do we have?
Not even 50,000.
Liu Bei took 40,000 when he fled.
Without those arrows,
we cannot fight.
The arrows are my responsibility.
As well they should be.
Your Lord took them.
We need 100,000 arrows.
You still think you can handle it?
Fine. If I cannot come up
with 100,000 arrows,
you may take my head.
We only have food for 10 days.
I give you 10 days' time.
I don't need 10, just three.
We soldiers do not joke.
You said you'd eliminate
Admirals Cai Mao and Zhang Yun.
If not, then what?
You may have my head.
By night, the Milky Way.
By day, snaking clouds.
You were here all night.
What are you up to?
See for yourself.
Wind and water converge here.
The feng shui is excellent.
I'm glad you're relaxed.
You are worrying me to death.
The 20 ships with crew you requested
are ready.
There's only one day left.
Where are the arrows?
You haven't made even one!
You should be in a nervous sweat.
My sweat is of no concern.
But see if the tortoise is sweating.
It is.
As I predicted, fog is coming.
What fog?
The only fog here is around my head.
What is this plan of yours?
Nature's secrets cannot be revealed.
Old cow plows the paddy's rows
Young calf munches on what grows
You really are something.
Back then, you were just a kid
who loved to sing.
Who'd have guessed that kid
would be a Viceroy?
Planting rice
is the old man's chore
We were 10 when you clubbed
that bandit from behind.
He spun around and somehow
the club was in my hands.
He gave me the beating of my life.
In the sedan chair,
the young boy snores
To this day I still don't understand
how that club got into my hand.
You're too slow.
You remember that time...
I wrote on the tutor's exam book
in your handwriting,
"senile bastard"!
That's right!
He gave me 20 swats
across my backside.
Back in those days,
there was no prank we didn't pull.
I can trick any man I meet.
But with you,
I always play the fool.
Bring my sword!
Marvelous!
You are a fine sword dancer.
Are you here as Cao Cao's emissary?
Me?
I can barely speak for myself.
How could I speak for Cao Cao?
I'm not as clever as you,
but I know what song you're singing.
You do not give me enough credit.
I'd never disrespect a talented Southerner,
but to serve Cao Cao is wrong.
You have your Lord
and I have mine, but...
No matter.
A few days from now
someone will lay Cao Cao's head
at my feet.
You believe me?
Yes, I do.
Your Honor, urgent news!
Can't you see I have a guest?
I know we've no arrows.
If Zhu-ge Liang fails to get more,
I'll have his head.
Maybe our friends
across the river can help.
They have a more
important mission.
Admirals Cai Mao
and Zhang Yun report that
Cao Cao's head
cannot be taken just yet.
I fear...
Do not underestimate them.
Here is their message.
Excellent!
Mr. Jiang.
What are you doing here alone?
Mrs. Zhou?
Come sit inside.
Xiao Qiao, bring more wine.
Any more and you'll be drunk.
Come on, we'll drink more upstairs.
- Drink more?
- Why end a good time?
I hear Cao Cao invaded
the Southlands all for your wife.
Is that so?
Cao Cao has a reputation
for stealing men's wives.
You're drunk.
- More wine.
- More? Where?
"We surrendered to Cao Cao
not for profit
but out of desperation.
We now have the Northerners
entrapped in camp.
Soon we will deliver his decap...
...his decapitated head.
Further reports to come.
Admiral Cai Mao"
What are you looking at?
Just one of my tricks.
You do love to play tricks on me.
I'll trick you again...
and again...
Not this time you won't.
Scarecrow, you're more
of a man than that fellow.
That fellow
doesn't tell me a thing.
You're a better drinking buddy.
Cheers!
Scarecrow...
why are we heading
for the enemy camp?
You're not surrendering are you?
The enemy!
The enemy is approaching!
Separate ships.
Send the left flank
to intercept the enemy.
Faster!
Scarecrow, stop drumming.
What if Cao Cao's men come for us?
They wouldn't dare.
A heavy fog might hide an ambush.
Oh, so you've decided to talk to me?
Ready all archers.
Shoot at first sight.
Ready!
All ships line up!
This is a plot to turn us
against each other.
We're not fools.
Would Zhou Yu use
such an obvious trick?
Sometimes the simplest trick
is the best way to lead
someone to their death.
Shoot
Shoot!
Your Highness,
whether this is a trick or not,
we should proceed with caution.
What if their navy mutinies?
That would be a disaster.
Shoot!
Besides the letter,
I heard them mention
that friends here
would get them arrows.
Don't worry.
Scarecrow will protect you.
Cease drumming!
Call Admirals Cai Mao
and Zhang Yun in for questioning.
They are out training the fleet.
If they are not here,
then their handwriting is.
Bring their letter of surrender.
Ready, all ships about-face!
What?
Drum in unison.
Give them a target to shoot.
Aim for the drums.
Shoot
Drink up.
Watch your seat.
Fire at will!
The handwriting is a perfect match
and full of the same mistakes.
This must be the work of Cai Mao.
Shoot!
We return home victorious!
Cheers!
Nothing but scared mice.
Return to your positions!
Thank you, Prime Minister, for your gift.
Thank you! Thank you!
Marvelous!
Mr. Zhu-gel
Look!
How did you know the fog was coming?
A clear Milky Way and snaking clouds
signal fog is near.
If you know how earth, sky,
yin and yang change,
then the sun, moon and stars,
the wind, forest,
mountains and fire,
all become soldiers
at your command.
So you can read
Mother Nature's moods, huh?
We lost one!
- What a shame.
- Hey, come back!
A small victory hardly deserves
such a reception Your Highness.
A small victory?
How many men did the enemy send?
Fog covered the river.
Impossible to see.
If you could not see,
how did you repel them?
Firing at will forced retreat.
Firing at will?
- How many arrows is that?
- About 100,000.
About 100,000.
And why didn't you pursue them?
Fog meant possible ambush,
Your Highness.
So...
Again with the fog.
Seems like you are hiding
something in that fog.
Look, a boat is floating this way.
Pull it in!
Your Highness.
Can't you tell a soldier
from a scarecrow?
100,000 arrows?
You're mighty generous.
- Please forgive me, Your Highness.
- I deserve death, Your Highness.
Today it's arrows.
Tomorrow it's my head,
am I right?
Zhou Yu is turning us
against each other.
No spy is stupid enough to...
Silence!
I trust and honor talented men,
but I abhor deceivers and traitors.
Guards!
Your Highness, we have
trained day and night.
Take them away and behead them.
We swear our loyalty to Your Highness.
Didn't I surrender to a benevolent ruler?
We have trained night and day.
Wait, Your Highness.
If you kill them, who will lead the navy?
Halt!
Ninety-three thousand,
eight hundred...
Ninety-four thousand...
Ninety-four thousand, two hundred...
Ninety-four thousand, six hundred...
We'll shoot Cao Cao with his own arrows.
This battle will be interesting.
Concentrate! No mistakes.
Wait.
Don't interrupt.
Two hundred per person.
There'll be no mistakes.
Mr. Zhu-ge, what is this new invention?
A rapid-fire crossbow.
It shoots 10 arrows without reloading.
Here, watch.
Great.
Ninety-nine thousand, four hundred...
Ninety-nine thousand, six hundred...
Impressive!
You know a trifle
about weapons design too.
Knowing a trifle about everything
gives life more color.
Your Honor.
Did he reach 100,000?
The total is 99,600.
Now what?
Well...
Your Honor, it's only 400.
Short one is still short.
The law is firm as a mountain.
That's right.
So what does the law say?
The law prescribes beheading.
Bastards!
What took you so long?
Hurry and bring them over.
Thank God!
The total is 100,200.
Mr. Zhu-ge has completed his mission.
Seems like my head is safe where it is.
How about yours?
You want my head?
Mr. Zhu-ge.
We're just joking.
When I lost, was he joking?
Of course not.
Looks like you haven't lost after all.
Cao Cao has executed
Admirals Cai Mao and Zhang Yun.
I think we've been duped.
Steal the enemy's weapons,
then destroy their morale.
Your strategies
worked together brilliantly.
Cao Cao must be going crazy
right about now.
In two or three days,
he will try something desperate.
But this will not be good for Jiang Gan.
I've lost an old friend.
Honored guests.
Zhou Yu is just showing
off his cleverness.
He undoubtedly thinks
I have gone crazy.
Tell me, do I look crazy?
Not at all.
Come, let us root out the traitor.
Then we can sleep easy. Cheers!
- Jiang Gan.
- Yes.
Today, you were of great service.
Please drink.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Sir!
Sir! Are you...
Your stupidity was trivial.
But you brought
your stupidity upon me.
Hear this!
In two days, our army shall cross the river
and take Red Cliff!
Yes, Your Highness!
All hear this! In two days,
the army will cross the river.
What's going on here?
There's a spy! Catch the spy!
Halt!
Don't let him escape!
Grab him!
Piggy, why do they want to hurt you?
It's a misunderstanding.
A misunderstanding?
What's going on?
He's a SPY-
Nonsense, he is my friend.
Friend? Are you stupid?
Come on, they're beating up
the commander.
A fight!
- What is the fight all about?
- Nothing, just some roughhousing.
Pit!
Piggy, are you all right?
I have to go.
Piggy-
Where are you going?
My mother is sick.
I must go home.
That's very kind of you to visit her.
You should go home too.
No, I'll return after the war.
Fighting means no taxes.
That means more food on the table.
Hurry, go visit your mother!
I will come back to see you.
Ride high.
Don't let him escape!
He's just going to see his mother.
Hit him! Pummel him!
In 18 years of battle
I have never lost.
If I fail to capture this tiny cliff,
I shudder to think what
historians will say.
Yes.
Your Highness.
How are things?
Worse than expected.
The disease's spread has not slowed.
At this rate,
it will take a month to control.
I respectfully request
you delay the assault.
Stop! Lie still.
- Your Highness
- Sit up.
You are ill and must recuperate.
Man Tun, how can you be ill?
You were always in perfect health.
What is on your mind?
Go ahead.
I want to go home.
I too have not been home
for a long time.
I want to see my youngest son.
He is only 13 years old...
Younger than you even.
He is kind-hearted and bright.
He has been frail since birth
and is often sick.
Yet, in front of me,
he pretends everything is fine.
Whatever the illness, he endures.
He never complains to me.
I swore at the start of this war
to cleanse the world of warlords.
We must seize Red Cliff
and storm the capital,
then bring the mud
of this land back home
and tell our families
we were victorious.
We were victorious!
So you all must be strong,
as must I.
Because I must
bring you back home.
Victory!
Greetings, everyone.
- Sorry for the wait.
- We're glad you're back safely.
- Did you have any problems?
- No.
I just fell into the mud
jumping the stockade.
Shang Xiang.
You're always causing trouble.
Where have you been?
They are ready to attack.
Shang Xiang.
You're back.
Xiao Qiao.
Shang Xiang?
Please help me pull this.
Go ahead, pull it.
This is a map of Cao Cao's camp.
This tower here
is Cao Cao's headquarters.
Their best troops guard it.
The barracks are here.
East and west are well-defended.
The rear hill is weakest.
It's like a tiger that stares ahead,
but forgets its tail.
- The navy is here?
- Put this on.
- You'll catch a chill.
- I'm not cold.
A third of their forces
are on board ready for assault.
Warships lead the smaller boats.
Transport ships are in the middle.
This is an interlocked naval formation.
I'm fine.
Every ship is ready for attack or defense.
I was wrong to scold you.
If you were Zhou Yu,
how would you attack?
He only has enough men for one assault-
an all-out attack on our fleet.
They will want to attack with fire.
Fire? I doubt it.
Without manpower, they need strength.
Where can they get it? Fire, of course.
This is a standard rule of war.
Too bad it won't work.
A northwest wind is blowing.
If they attack our fleet with fire,
they will be fighting the wind
and burn themselves.
We are the ones who should use fire.
Yes, load the ships with brimstone.
Tomorrow, we shall burn Red Cliff
to the ground!
The map shows
that Cao Cao's army
has finished deployment.
Tonight may be the decisive battle.
This is a fight to the death.
Win or lose, we must fight
with everything we have.
Shang Xiang.
What are these lines between the ships?
It sounds funny.
They've locked their boats together
to stabilize the fleet,
so the Northerners won't get seasick.
Enough talk.
What is your strategy?
Cao Cao made camp
in a bad location.
It is hook-shaped.
This makes return difficult.
If their assault fails,
they cannot fall back.
We should use fire.
The terrain is in our favor.
If we can burn the fleet's vanguard,
they will be trapped and vulnerable.
Yes, a fire attack!
Just give me 10 fire ships.
Two will hit their left and right flanks.
The remaining eight will ram the center.
We'll burn an opening here!
Next, you follow closely and rush in.
No matter how great their numbers,
we will crush them.
If only we still had Liu Bei's cavalry,
we could attack their camp at the rear.
Then victory would be assured.
This wind is to Cao Cao's advantage.
A northwest wind is blowing.
Sailing into the wind
will burn our own fleet.
Cao Cao knows the wind is on his side.
He will also think of using fire.
Why are you so quiet?
What are you looking at?
Look, those dark clouds in the east
are enshrouding the sun.
Isn't that rather unusual?
Zhu-ge Liang, what does that mean?
The winds will change.
I know from farming,
if, during a warm winter,
clouds enshroud the sun
then along the Yangtze River
an unseasonal wind will blow.
What do you mean unseasonal?
A warm southeast wind.
It blows from southeast to northwest.
What if Cao Cao knows this too?
Only Admiral Cai Mao
would know and he is dead.
Zhu-ge Liang.
Can you predict when it will change?
Tonight or tomorrow morning.
History shows the timing of weather is key.
He who can predict it will win.
We must delay his attack.
Only then will we have a chance at victory.
Greetings, General.
Terrific, just terrific!
This fish oil is perfect!
- Bigger.
- Yes, General!
No good. Bigger!
Yes, General.
Just how big do you want it?
Go!
That's about right.
Yes! This is it!
See how strong this west wind is?
It will never shift.
We'll never get near their navy.
Your Honor, I can fake a defection.
Invent some excuse
to punish me with 50 lashes.
I'll fake a surrender in anger.
That way Cao Cao is sure to believe me.
Then I can sail my fire ships in range.
How could you fight after such a beating?
I could never treat a general that way.
Do not lose heart.
The east wind will come.
Your Honor.
Terrible news!
Our Lady has disappeared!
My dear husband,
by the time you read this
I will be on the way to Cao Cao's camp.
I will be cautious,
and only act when the moment is right.
Yet, I hope the east wind will come early.
Where there is faith, there is hope.
The clear waters of the Yangtze,
the emerald leaves of the mountains,
the birds returning to nest,
the fisherman singing his evening song.
This is our home,
our beautiful native land.
Our people gladly
give their lives for her sake.
I cannot stand idly by.
I have been carrying our child Ping An
for three months.
I did not tell you,
fearing it might distract you.
We cannot, in caring for our child,
forget the children of the Southlands.
I want to see them grow up together,
to have a future where they can play,
swim, pick flowers
and plant rice in peace.
"Your child Ping An"
"Pregnant"
Do not fear.
I shall bring Ping An home.
Some traditions
still carry great meaning.
For example,
rice flour and sugar
stick together
like a family at reunion.
Over here!
Bring the cart here!
There are sweet
rice dumplings for everyone.
Today is winter solstice,
a time for reunion.
Everyone have some rice dumplings.
Two or three per person! Eat up!
Officers and soldiers alike, come on.
Come on.
Give me a bowl.
Zhang Fei,
you're making them too big.
Do you want us to choke?
Fine with me.
I couldn't be happier.
Zhao Yun.
Has your wound healed
from combat practice?
So long as I can fight,
a wound means nothing.
Guan Yu, how many times
have you read the classics?
If a man of learning
does not understand brotherhood,
isn't his learning worthless?
My Lord, what are we doing here?
Waiting.
Waiting for what?
Waiting for Zhu-ge Liang.
Waiting for his return,
so we can go home.
Do we still have a home?
Sons of the Southlands, listen.
Today is the winter solstice,
a day for family reunion.
Yet thieves encircle our home.
How can we celebrate like this?
I say, let us drive them
from this land.
Then we shall have
our celebratory family meal.
Here here!
My Lord.
Though I sometimes disagree with you,
I have never said a word against you.
But this is a choice between
right and wrong.
I acted for the good of us all,
yet you lecture me
for being unrighteous.
You have followed me
so long and for what?
I just want to ensure we live on.
There are some things I value
more than my life.
Zhou Yu, may your plans
come to fruition.
We will fight the good fight.
Zhou Yu's wife is here.
She came alone.
Zhou Yu.
We must alter our plan of attack.
Consider your wife's safety.
I will send our best men
around back to rescue her.
No changes.
All our forces must be focused
on frontal assault.
We cannot divide
our strength.
Your Honor, we stand alone
on the battlefield.
Without allied support,
the chance for victory seems slight.
I have never given up on my dream.
Victory cannot rest on dreams alone.
When will the east wind come?
Based on new observations
at around one o'clock.
If at that time you still
trust your friends,
light a lantern for a signal.
If misfortune befalls Xiao Qiao,
will you still fight a war of honor?
I saw you once in the back
of your family's estate.
Though young, you were
already a great beauty.
You were studying
the tea ceremony
and liked catching butterflies.
Did you launch this war for me?
You believe that?
My father was very fond of you.
At that time, Cao Cao
believed in justice, ideals
and loyalty to the Han throne.
He was a young hero.
How else could he have become
Prime Minister?
By killing many people.
I hear many Southlands
soldiers have fallen ill.
Yes.
I hear Liu Bei has fled
and the alliance is broken.
Yes.
Then Zhou Yu must be a lonely man.
Did he send you?
This was my idea.
Why are you here?
Please withdraw your troops.
Victory is yours.
What need is there to fight on?
No.
Zhou Yu shall kneel
before me in surrender.
What is this?
I am not here for my husband,
but for the people of this kingdom.
Please end this war.
And if I refuse?
Stop playing.
You must witness
how I defeat Zhou Yu.
What's on your mind?
Just thinking of a silly friend.
The times make the hero.
After this battle,
I will have time to savor your tea.
Just one cup?
It'll help you relax.
Fine.
No one's ever given us respect.
So what?
Who cares so long
as we respect ourselves?
Listen up!
Our boats will soon charge
Cao Cao's fleet.
No man jumps ship
until their ships burn.
Yes, sir!
Any problem with that?
No, sir!
That's what I thought.
Have you all written
to your families?
Yes.
Don't rush!
Appreciate the tea's color
and bouquet.
Oh.
Why is the Prime Minister
waiting to attack?
The wind is behaving strangely.
I know.
He is drinking tea
with that woman.
Tea?
What makes brewing tea
so difficult?
Leaves, heat, water, and utensils
all demand study.
Yet boiling water
is the most difficult.
Boiling water?
Look!
The wind has stopped.
At first boil, the bubbles hiss
and resemble tiny fish eyes.
At second boil,
the edge simmers like a fountain.
This is when tea is finest.
At third boil,
the water seethes and spurts.
Any further and the water
is past its prime.
Your Honor, the wind
seems about to shift.
It's time to attack.
What are we waiting for?
Our allies.
What allies?
Liu Bei fled days ago.
This is all part of Zhou Yu's plan.
Some plans are best kept quiet.
Enough! It is full!
Your Highness.
Don't you see your true self
reflected in this tea?
Your heart is overflowing with ambition.
It's too full to let other people in.
You've carried this full heart
to Red Cliff.
Someone here will pour
that heart onto the floor.
Your Highness.
You do not understand
the art of tea.
Your Honor, tell us what we must do.
At two o'clock,
the 10 fire ships will ram Cao Cao's fleet,
burning through their vanguard.
With the fleet broken,
Zhao Yun will hit the east gate
to divert their attention.
Liu Bei, Guan Yu, and Zhang Fei
will overwhelm Cao Cao's camp
from the west gate.
Doctor!
Your Highness.
Call Doctor Hua Tuo.
My head aches.
Your Highness,
Hua Tuo has left.
What did you say?
Hua Tuo is gone.
Cast off!
What is this wind?
It's an easterly wind, Your Highness.
It shifted? Impossible!
Enemy ships approaching!
General, enemy ships approaching!
Hurry, separate the ships!
Separate ships!
What is that?
Those are their lanterns,
Your Highness.
Forward.
Zhou Yu.
I have done all I can.
Tonight will decide the fate of the empire.
There must be no mistakes.
Zhu-ge Liang!
You weren't lying after all!
Report!
Boats are approaching fast.
- Separate ships immediately.
- Separation has already begun.
Light the fires!
Forward.
Hurry over here!
Full speed ahead!
Hurry, separate the ships.
Faster.
Retreat!
Protect the main gate!
Faster, toward Cao Cao's flagship!
Strike as powerful as thunder!
Charge!
- Go ahead.
- Charge!
Follow me.
Shoot!
Launch catapults!
Hurry, the enemy is approaching.
Look, over there!
Your Highness! Terrible news!
They have broken through the stockade!
Why are you panicking?
Do not forget you are a general.
I...
Try to endure the pain.
Reinforce Zhang Fei! Move!
Your Highness.
The rear gate is under surprise attack.
It is Liu Bei's allied forces.
Liu Bei?
Free the horses!
Pull!
General Gan.
We must save energy for inside.
You must break down this gate
so we can join our allies.
Otherwise, all is lost.
- No problem.
- Good luck.
Halt.
Tear down the barricade!
Shoot!
Forward.
Attack the main gate.
Come on, soldier.
Hang in there.
General Gan!
Individual bombs
aren't strong enough.
Run! The fire is coming!
Give me all your fire bombs.
There are only three left!
No retreat! No surrender!
This is it!
All forces attack!
Shoot!
Your Highness.
The navy is lost.
East, south, and west...
all three sides have been sunk.
It seems like
they went up in flames too.
Yes, Your Highness.
All is quiet below.
The fire is too fierce!
Stay together at all costs!
Don't get separated!
Your Highness.
Perhaps retreat is best.
Retreat?
With our best soldiers still remaining?
They would give their lives for me.
Even if all will die, they must fight.
This is military power.
All together! Charge!
Fight me if you dare.
Come back here!
Come on, you traitor!
General!
Don't give up, my brother.
Guan Yu!
Where is Liu Bei?
Full speed ahead!
Break formation!
Launch spears!
Forward!
Crush them or die trying!
Hang in there.
I oversaw the end of every warlord.
I saw the end of one here and one there...
The end of all but here.
Just in time.
I knew you wouldn't let me down.
I said we would meet again.
Gan Xing sacrificed himself.
But not in vain.
The fire is approaching.
We must save Xiao Qiao now!
First find Cao Cao.
We have lost
all because
of that accursed woman.
She ruined our chance to attack.
- I'll kill her!
- Kill her!
Come no further.
Don't let the enemy through.
That way, quickly!
Protect the Prime Minister! Get them!
Pit?
Pit.
It's me, Piggy-
Piggy?
Piggy-
You came to see me.
I said I would.
Piggy-
Still want to play Ride High?
I'll kill that witch.
Don't move.
Zhou Yu.
Viceroy Zhou.
- The traitor Cao Cao.
- Silence!
You shall call me
Prime Minister.
I never guessed I'd lose
to a gust of wind.
Because you don't understand
the Will of Heaven.
I never dreamed I'd be defeated
by a cup of tea.
For you, war was just
a tea ceremony.
Such a pity.
You never knew
what you were fighting for.
I come by order of the Emperor
to subdue rebels like you.
We are not rebelling against the Emperor,
but against you.
You scum.
Little boy.
This has been quite
an enjoyable hunt.
What do you want to hunt?
Tigers.
By the looks of you,
you are a far cry
from your father.
Shoot!
I am Prime Minister
of the Emperor's court.
Death is too good
for rebels like you.
If you declare allegiance to me,
I can pardon you.
Kneel down, all of you.
Your time is over.
Lay down your sword.
Your Highness, kill them.
Kill them all!
Xiao Qiao!
Are you both safe?
We are both fine.
We lost
all because of you!
Kneel down before me.
Kneel to me and
I will spare Xiao Qiao.
We won't let you harm her.
We?
You mean them?
That motley troop?
They are my friends.
War knows no friends.
Tomorrow, they will be your enemies.
General!
Push her off!
Die!
Your Honor!
Are you both all right?
Let's go.
I promise I will take you home.
Go.
Go back to where ever you came from.
There is no victor here.
Meng Mel19-
Go on now, go.
From division comes unity,
and from unity, division.
Liu Bei won't stand
being second best.
One day, we will face each other
on the battlefield.
No man can tell the future.
The world is full of heroes,
but you're the one
I most fear offending.
You would be
an opponent I'd truly fear.
Me?
I'd best return home
and get some sleep.
Are you a good farmer?
I planted lotus flowers once
but none lived long.
Do not be humble.
You have brought peace to the land.
In this alliance, I found true friends.
No matter what
may happen,
this experience
is engraved in my heart.
I too will not forget.
Zhu-ge Liang!
When Meng Meng has grown,
do not make her a war horse.
Don't worry.
These hands helped birth her.
I shall always cherish her.