AUTUMN
It began with the chair.
I have been waiting for
This long.
I know.
Loser.
Heaven, Banana, dance
Damned snout, would you like?
This is the game room
Most magnificent I have ever seen.
Well, well as you
Feel after the crime.
Do Regresas for another test?
I think that the first was not very effective,
Symbol appeared positive for
Percent, so I am not convinced.
Third test today, Mom
Bear, you are pregnant, there is no question about that.
It is very easy to know, does your
Nipples are Carmelites?
Yes, perhaps your boyfriend spread
His sperm throughout your body.
Silence, man. Watch just take 2
Litres of juice and I have to urinate soon.
You know where is the laboratory.
I pay for it when finish.
Do not think that is yours alone
Because what marques with your urine.
You should not be surprised
With that, already know.
I do not know, it is not time yet.
I bring one of these.
Therein lies.
A small symbol of positive
Pink, is so uncomfortable.
I do not know why you do, this is
One thing that can not be undone.
Hello, hello, hello.
I almost committed suicide.
Is Juno?
No, it's Morgan Freeman, is there
Some collector bones?
I have one in my belly, what happens?
I am pregnant.
What? Are you sure?
Yes is Bleeker.
Probably you
Feel weak, do almorzaste well?
This is not a problem of hunger, I did
3 pregnancy test and I am more than sure.
How did produjiste urinates
3 to test? It is amazing.
I do not know, I took like 10 tons
Juice, anyway
I am telling you that I am pregnant
And you are acting as if you do not import it.
Is it really true?
Unfortunately yes.
Oh, my God.
Oh shit, that stinks.
That was the emotion that
Expected at first.
Will you go to the hospital or not? Why not
I think you want to make your parents know.
I will not go to Women Now
Just going to do that.
Would you like to call on you? What
Becky did it for the past year.
No, I call myself, but I want
Help me out of something that is very important.
You know, if I had known
You would have helped.
Seriously.
Were it so boring
Wanted to have a child?
He asked me, I mean
Sex, not to get pregnant.
When I decided that
Ibas to stay with Bleeker?
I do not know.
A year ago in the Spanish class.
You love it.
It is not, it is very
Complicated, does agree?
And I do not feel good talking about that.
So how was it?
How does it feel?
Is Magnificent?
Hello, Bleek.
Lindo tiger.
You should be proud.
Sudé much to do.
Why your shorts
Are so yellow today?
My mom said that the colour speaks volumes.
Say hello to Carol.
I will tell.
When I see men running well,
Things with their swinging by the short,
I always imagine things but not
Want, all I saw were swords.
It should be running.
So guess what.
What? I do not know.
I am pregnant.
What should we do?
Oh, you know, I think that just as in botaré
Trash, before they make worse.
In class we talked
How is she is pregnant,
And tends to make an infant.
Typical, yes, yes.
That's what happens when
Our mothers leave pregnant.
So, are you okay with this?
Yes, yes of course,
I mean, you know,
I think you should do what
You create better, you know?
Oh, I am sorry to have had sex with you,
It was not your idea.
What do you say? Who was?
I went where I wanted, did agree?
What did we do then?
The book is breaking.
Why?
Just look at their pages.
The funny thing is that Steve
I wish secret.
As always desired
Girls strangers.
Girls who wear glasses,
Trousers and a grotesque makeup.
Best if it touches the zeal and read scores and
It is behind a desk when I grow up.
Oh, yes, he loves all that shit.
He does not want to admit it because he wants
Be a perfect cheerleader,
As Leah, who incidentally
Is attracted by teachers.
I, too, I love Woody Allen.
Okay people.
We will practice today chromatography,
So you feel fortunate if grab a 4.
Well, there's nothing like an experiment.
I made the questions last night,
So that you can copy.
Not copiaré your work.
You do every week.
True, I do not
Feel indebted, can agree?
No, no, definitely
I want to bring something to the table.
A strange way.
Who is ready for a wonderful thing?
It hurts me to the brain so it's not
I look bright lights today.
I have tried to explicártelo
By 9 pm, never hear.
No, Josh, because no receipt
Orders, neither you nor anyone.
Not if indeed the shots
Of a type known as Kato.
As I told you, nothing happened.
I will prepare things,
Juno, would you like to put some in the box?
It is a pleasure.
I go to the infirmary.
Well, how do you do?
Well, call me when you learn
To love, as did your brother,
Should have their biceps to
You can endure when the urines.
Sure, Amanda, I will make sure
To do so, and you know what I will do.
In fact to do so, flavored
Are the best to do so.
Did you?
Pregnant? WOMEN NOW
Press the number of your question.
Hello, just call for
Manage an abortion.
What?
You can wait a moment,
I am a little busy.
Okay, tell me.
Yes, it is already decided.
Yes, yes, I need an abortion.
16.
Let's say you have spent 2
Months and 4 days after I did.
More or less, it's just an estimate.
Sorry, what I am doing everything?
Oh, say the hatred cundo
"Sexually active".
What does it mean?
To me, or is activated someday
A kind of permanent status.
I believe that when you do the
Real life is not what you think of ways.
You should have seen, when I
Took off his hat and seemed quite the opposite.
My dad was in the Army, but
Now is a specialist at H-Vac.
He and my mother divorced
When I was 5 y. ..
... Lives in a reservation in Arizona with
Her husband and 3 children new replacement.
Strangely she commanded by cactus
Mail every day Valentine
I think they are things that she believes,
As cacti that last longer than oneself.
That is my stepmother Bren, it is
Completely obsessed with the dogs.
Have a beauty salon
And always smells like acetone.
So how was
Your delivery last night?
Which of them, sir, I was moving
A game room of a house to another.
After that I went to
Eat sushi in a place.
Juno, how did you do something on my urn?
Mac, you know? I ordered the box.
There was a blue shit.
I mean, shit,
In it this morning.
Never would you anything to your box, Brenda.
I mean, maybe I have encountered.
Mary Beth, if you cast over it in the
Potatoes, I will hit your tiny ass.
All babies want to get on board.
All babies want
Board. All ...
Hello Su-Chin.
Hello, Juno.
How are you?
You know, quite well.
So what did the
Task for the class?
No, not yet.
I want to do that at this point,
If not, I can not concentrate.
I can help you if you want.
No thanks, not necessary.
That is a wise decision, know
This girl who became crazy ...
... And took many beers at once, and will only be removed
Clothes and threw in bed with another, and it was like ...
Demons, I am a big disease.
That you were you.
It was good to see, Su-Chin.
Your baby does not have to
Be hurt, you know?
They can feel the pain,
And have nails.
Do Nails? Really?
Welcome to Women Now,
Friendly place for needy
Please put your hands where
Could see them and put them into the box.
Hey, I am here for the big show.
Your name, please.
Juno McGuff.
She believes it is a false name,
Jean Stewards or Mother Teresa.
I need to fill this for both sides. We need
All the details of every time he did.
Want some condoms?
They are free.
No, I am out of sex.
My boyfriend said that those you love.
He says that smell like a cake.
All babies want to get on board.
God will appreciate this miracle.
Hey, what are you doing here?
It was assumed that you seek to 4.
Not what I could do.
Olía very bad there,
And had horrible magazines
To save money.
And the strange receptionist was trying to
Give me some condoms that looked like grape gum.
And he would tell me about the flavor cake
Having the balls of your boyfriend.
Oh, great.
And Su-Chin was there, and I said:
Oh, hello, babies have claws.
Nails.
That's grotesque.
Do you think that babies can
Squeeze your bag to leave?
I still fraught, Leah.
Girl, you have to lower our voices, my mother is
Indoors and do not know that we are sexually active.
What does that mean?
I have been thinking,
I have this baby ...
... And feed it to a
Women in need,
Some women infertile,
A lesbian couple.
But then you play too fat and your
Breasts grow and you have to say.
Maybe not want to be so selfish.
Or maybe everything can be going to shit and get very
Wrong and you can not graduate or not enjoy your holiday.
I was going to say to
Bleeker of toas forms.
You see ads for adoption,
See them all the time magazines.
Do advertisements for parents?
Yes, desperate because they respond,
Say their preferences and their customs,
Is absolutely legitimate.
Magnificent, partner united spiritually
Found true love.
Do not miss this.
I do not want these.
Juno, it would be good to hear me.
No, I hear you, it's just that I do not want to give the baby
A family which describes itself as magnificent.
-- Why?
-- It's just that I think is a great exaggeration.
-- Okay, what you have in mind exactly?
-- I was thinking of graphic designers,
They have 30 years, you know, an Asian girlfriend,
Impressive dresses, plays guitar base,
But I do not want to be
Too.
Okay, what about this?
Young educated and looking for a successful
And a baby to a family of 5.
It will be rewarded if we aid
To complete the circle of love.
That sounds great.
Sounds like a call, and they have
3 children must be 3 small devils.
Oh, what about this?
Those are Mark and Vanessa Loring,
And are a beautiful couple.
Hello boy, are you ready to eat?
No, I do not think so.
Corriste 8 miles today.
I have no famine yet.
But there is soup, your favorite dish.
Yes.
Did you know that McGuff called
Today while you run?
You know that I think of it.
Yes, yes, you have mentioned
A couple of times.
She is just ...
... Different.
Yes.
I am not quite sure of this, but ...
How deletearías what?
No school has been more of a contact
That led you to be exposed.
Well, it was only
Wondering as a possibility.
I am asking you money,
Do for a legal consultation?
I am not asking for anything.
Except, perhaps pity, try
To be fresh and not beating me.
What did you do, golpeaste someone?
Not.
I think it is better than
Finish what to say.
I am pregnant.
Oh, God.
The handing in adoption, and
Find the perfect match ...
... And are going to pay for
Medical expenses and everything y. ..
... Within 38 weeks we can
Pretend that this never happened.
Are you pregnant?
Sorry.
Sorry, and what it is
Consolation, was drunk y. ..
... I did not know what he was doing y. ..
... I have not taken a
Drink since Wednesday ...
... In the morning.
I did not even know that
Were sexually active.
Who's the Man?
I do not know the exact name,
I mean, you have nails.
Nails, did indeed?
Yes.
I mean, who is the father, Juno?
It Paulie Bleeker.
Does Paulie Bleeker?
What?
I do not think that is the most appropriate.
That's right, no?
There is what laugh.
No, it's not.
Paulie is indeed brilliant in ...
Okay.
... Whole.
Have you thought about adoption?
Yes, yes, and there are a couple
Who have been unable ...
... You know, have tried for 5 years.
-- Are in a magazine that those bored.
And they have a lawyer who is really
Meet with me next weekend.
Juno is something very difficult to do, is
Probably harder to understand what you can now.
I know ...
... And it is just that I am not
Ready to be a mother.
Of course you are not.
Even you agreed
The medicine for asthma.
That was once, and she
Did not die if you remember.
Honey, have you considered,
You know, the alternative?
Not.
Well, you are a small Viking.
First things first.
Okay, we
To keep healthy
Need prenatal vitamins ...
... Incidentally do incredible things
For us, so that is something positive.
We need to schedule an appointment with the
Doctor, to tell us when you are going to give birth.
I will go to
Know this couple.
You are just a little girl, I do not want to leave
Alone with a couple of desperate.
Thanks, Dad.
When are you going to be the girl on the
That we must not say when?
I do not know really what kind of girl I am.
I have to accept that
This is all my fault.
I think that was
Bored and wanted to do it.
I would like to think that Juno
Was naive with that, Mac.
I am not ready to become a grandfather.
You will not be a grandfather.
Somebody's going to find a tremendous blessing
Jesus to take charge of this situation.
Do you think he did without
Be mad?
Yes, but expected to be
Rope in spite of the drugs.
Yes, that's what I thought, which took
Something, anything less this.
I am going to beat this guy in the
Eggs the next time you see it.
Mac, we, you know that idea was not him.
Hello, I am Vanessa, you should be
Juno and Mr. McGuff. Hello.
Vanessa Loring.
Vanessa you, right?
Thanks for welcome me and
Irresponsible my daughter in her house.
Oh no, thank you.
Thanks.
Forward.
Do I want to give their coats or your shirt?
Oh, yes, sure, thanks.
I read in a magazine that said they were superelegantes,
As these people have artificial wood at home,
Honestly, who
Believe that deceiving these people?
Do we have found in a magazine?
Hello, Mark Loring, I am her husband.
-- How are you? I'ma Mac McGuff.
-- Pleased to meet you.
Hello.
She is Gerta Rauss, our lawyer.
Gerta Rauss.
Hello, pleased to meet you.
And, of course, she is Juno.
As the city in Alaska.
Not.
No?
Okay.
Honey, do you have
The honour to sit?
I thought in search of something to drink.
What they would like? A coca or
Vitaminized water or orange juice.
I want a beer, please.
She has ...
... A wonderful sense of
Humor, a thing inherited from me.
I sit.
Then, Juno, the first thing,
How advanced are you?
I am in the Pre.
No, I mean in your pregnancy.
In fact, my stepmother took me yesterday
And the doctor said that she was 12 weeks.
That's great.
You are in your second trimester.
Yes, apparently.
I am doing my fourth month.
Great.
My friend told me that
The first 2 months are tough.
I have not noticed at all.
I am more concerned about when you have to put
These elastic pants, instead of jeans.
I think that being pregnant is beautiful.
You do not know how fortunate you are.
Let's talk about
How will we do this thing.
What talk? What
When you have the thing?
The arroparé and are shipped.
Mark and Vanessa are ready
To make an open adoption.
What does that mean?
That means they will be sending recent photo
The baby so that they can know how your child grows.
No, no, no, I do not want any photos
Nor any notification.
I mean, let us do it as old school, and
Know, I leave the baby in a basket, and then I leave.
I think that patearía
The Old Testament.
Exactly, is not it?
You know what I mean?
As in the old days,
When it was quick and dirty.
Well, we agree, a traditional
Abortion is what will be involved.
Shit, yeah, just close the deal.
Obviously, you will be compensated
With all the medical expenses.
Looking for some
Other compensation?
Do we apologize?
Not.
No, I do not want to sell it, just ...
... I ...
... I just want the baby
Be with people who love,
And become good parents, do you know?
I mean, I am in the Pre.
It is too early.
You are doing a beautiful and
Kind event for us.
Vanessa wanted the baby
Since we were married.
I would be much Mom.
I know what we mean.
Never has meaning
Born to do something?
Yes.
Heating and Air Conditioning.
There you have it.
I was born to be a parent.
That is what I believe.
What about you, Mark? Feeling
Well with the idea of being a parent?
Yes.
Every man wants to be a father, wants
Train your football team, y. ..
... Attend the Science Fair
And see how its done volcano.
Yes, all that.
Perhaps Gerta wants to give documents
Preliminary to sign.
Will could use the bathroom first because
Pregnancy makes me urinate much?
The bath is broken down but if you upload, doubles
To the right and then left you go a. ..
Oh, yes, a room with bath.
Is she okay?
Sorry.
Sorry, did not expect to see.
Subí to find one thing.
Were you trying espiarme?
Not.
Do you have any kind of paranoia?
I caught a little perfume on your wife.
Really?
Yes, smells like happiness.
Smell, so you see what it feels like.
Does that make me happy?
Of course.
I am giving the best gift of his life, without asking
Anything in return, just have to be there when ...
Everything is covered with ...
Placenta.
Yes that.
Is that an LS Paul?
Yes it is.
Vanessa gave me a
Room for my stuff.
Have you had a room in
The whole house for your stuff?
Well, you are very fortunate, Mark.
Oh, it was beautiful.
You know? I always thought that
No sounds better than a Fender.
What play?
Oh, harmonic rock.
Is repaired?
Yes.
This arm is very expensive, you should
Being an investment.
You tell me, solí playing in a band in Chicago and I
Broke, I had to pay 800 dollars to settle that.
When was that?
In'93. The best
Moment of Rock & Roll.
'77 Is the first of every year.
You are mad.
Was there?
You can not understand what I say.
Even were alive.
What is that?
It is a machine.
What are you doing with it?
Nothing to
It is exercised.
My wife was once one of those ...
... Tony "small"
Gonzalez, on TV.
The kind of history that.
That kind I looked good.
Return immediately.
Sorry.
Hello.
You are playing music.
She wanted hot
Look closely Kimber.
Does your guitar called Kimber?
Yes.
Mine is called Rosabel, but
Is a Franklin, did know?
Dear back down
We have a kind of ...
... Case to be solved.
The I, I have.
The gym is there.
Léanlos with care and whether they have any
Question, I called to the office.
Please lot to us
Mantuvieras aware of anything.
Ultrasounds, or any
Something of that nature.
Yes, yes, I understand they want to know how
Is cooking her son, I understand.
Are you sure do this?
Yes, yes, I fall well, yes.
How secure are you?
Do Dirías 80% or 90% secure?
I say that I am 104% sure.
Really?
You know, if I could be
Thing and give it now, I would,
But I think that asustarían
Because it must seem like a monkey,
You know wait for
Is a little more beautiful.
-- Yes.
-- Great.
You are right.
That is a great idea.
Pleased to meet you.
Please handle with
Care, I hope to see them soon.
-- Goodbye.
-- Beware.
-- Agreed.
WINTER
Hello.
Hello, Vijay. How spirit that?
Do Oíste? There is a girl pregnant.
Yes.
-- It was only a teenager.
-- Yes.
Have you heard anything?
Yes.
What thing, huh?
I do not want to speak much of it.
You should use mustache.
I can not.
Me neither.
Even I
Under his trousers.
I will see what I do, we are.
Juno, hello.
Hello, Bleek.
Me and some guys are going to go to the movies after
School to eat all these threads ...
... In honor of those who serve 18.
Do you want to come?
Sounds great, but I have an ultrasound.
Oh, do you really?
Can I ...
... Should go?
Oh, you can not miss this,
But perhaps I can go after.
Okay, great.
-- We feel, Bleek.
-- We feel.
We keep a seat.
Therein lies your baby.
Oh, my God.
Therein lies its power.
And the arm.
And there are the feet.
Do you see that?
That baby has tremendous
Head, it frightened.
I have seen bigger.
It seems someone from Taco Bell.
It's incredible how excited you this.
What? I am not made of stone.
Well, there is.
Do they want to know the sex?
-- Yes.
-- No.
-- Please.
-- No, not sex.
You will be surprised when des birth.
Well, I want to be surprised Mark and Vanessa
And if you tell me not know hide.
Did Mark and Vanessa are
College buddies?
No, no, they are the adoptive parents.
Oh, well, thank God for that.
What does that mean?
It's just that I have seen many
Teenage mothers y. ..
... Obviously are not the best
Environment to raise a baby.
How can you say that?
What if these parents
Adoptive are evil?
As parents evil.
They can be negligent, it is perhaps safer
She raise it better, has seen that?
No, I suppose not.
What exactly is your job?
I am an ultrasound technician, ma'am.
Well, I am a nail technician and I think
We both must restrict what we know.
Excuse me.
He believes that is so special because it draws pictures
Babies there, my daughter 5 years what can be done,
Let me tell you that is
The brain of a nené.
So why not return to ninth grade
And tries to make a career of truth.
Bren speaking well.
The adore.
Juno, not expecting to see you here.
I have something very special that
Teach, how Vanessa is here?
There, she will work until evening.
She is taking advantage throughout the
Free time you have before ...
Oh, yes, wait stinks.
Do you want to move, I was taking a drink?
Want one?
What is going on the rich
With their urban habits?
I have nothing better
What to do with these 44.
There are so badly at the end.
What you work?
Working at home, I am a composer.
I jodas.
As Johan Brams O. ..
No, things commercial.
How?
Commercial.
Yes, Ali wears the commercial
Children Paramount?
Yes, I paid for that.
Good sales.
I wonder what would your group.
You said you had something to show me.
Cálmese, good man, his future child.
Hey, check it out.
I think it looks like my friend Paulie.
She also is like you.
More polite.
Know if a boy or girl.
I can not, the doctor can,
Meant to be a surprise.
That is something we would like to know.
When you take tons of alcohol, you are not aware
You can get pregnant, not an imbecile.
Imbecile, huh?
Yes, you know.
I know what it is.
All right?
Definitely we
Chocolate, please.
Do not worry about that.
I have a rest, I
Make eating healthy
I can not stop
In front of my computer.
Anyway, I hope you are ready.
Do You Hear that?
What?
This is my favorite song. It'sa
Song made for a few superstars.
The Carpenters.
Oh, yes, yes, I know the Carpenters.
A woman drummer, a format
Like The White Stripes.
Yes, the Carpenters are so fascinating.
Yes, yes I enjoy.
What you said that it was your group?
Not what you said, is a mixture of
Stungeons, Pathy Smith and the Runaway.
Definitely this is serious,
Is enough for my son.
The magician of the grotesque?
That is the magician Lewis is the best magician.
Please Derryl
Argento is the best magician.
Is Argento?
He is okay, but Lewis
Is completely insane.
You have spoken of buckets full of blood, you
Corners are red brains out of the picture.
Frankly it looks
Stupidly old.
Give me the tape.
This is better than I thought.
What you said?
Cursed you got a taste
Decent in this type of film.
Very interesting.
Do you already have a name for the baby?
Yes, something like that, you Vanessa
Like if Madison girl.
Does Madison? Wait, endures.
There is a little gay.
What pretentious dare you
Say that with a name like Juno.
Look, my father had tremendous obsession
With Rome and Greek mythology
Then decided to appoint well
As one of the wives of Caesar,
Is a bit strange, but I am quite sure
That was his only wife Juno because ...
... It is assumed that it was very
Beautiful, as Diana Ross.
That is interesting.
Thank you?
There is something else.
Therein lies Vanessa, the better you go.
She fights me when I see
Films that "do not contribute."
I handling this, I am very
Sound convincing to people.
No, Juno, no.
Juno, what happens?
-- Nothing.
-- What are you doing here? What's going on?
Nothing, I went to the doctor today.
Is there something wrong with the baby?
The baby is great, this is the hand
Right until you can see phalanges.
Watch it here.
It is the baby.
It's your baby.
Do not think that is sleeping?
Hey, I am crazy about seeing my mom.
Which is nice.
Juno was very gracious in
Bring to that we saw.
Yes, I came as soon as I could.
The ultrasound technician
Said something stupid y. ..
Technically my stepmother ...
Abuse of her by saying that.
What kind of suite have done.
Madness mother.
There are just some things
I bought for the baby.
It is not supposed to you the
Gifting in a Baby Shower.
My stepmother when I was pregnant with my
Hermanastra, received one million gifts.
But he was not jealous
Because it is super to me.
I do not think we do one.
Why they would not?
I do not think people know how I
Feel about this situation because ...
... Do not understand.
What is the point?
No, no, no, do not believe
That I will leave.
No, I do not think so.
We went through a situation
And above.
This did not work.
Yes, Call it fear.
They should not be suspicious.
I do not like children
Ipods were free.
Those who put on those
Pulóveres weapon,
They shot in 40 minutes.
Your parents should be
Worried without knowing where you are.
No, I mean, I am pregnant.
What else could I put?
It should probably be back.
Hey, do not forget your bag.
Oh, thanks.
Okay, beware.
Where the hell were Juno?
I was at the home of Mark and Vanessa, I went to teach
Ultrasound and I stayed for a couple of hours.
A couple of hours to Do
What were you in the first place?
They wanted to know about everything and told them
To keep abreast and it did.
Are you a kind of messenger?
Viajaste one hour to the east.
Only I did, you know, while
Mark and I were ...
Vanessa waiting ...
Look to the Wizard of the grotesque,
He put me some discs
Of his music, so ...
... Was good, very good.
Juno, you can not do that well.
No, that was not the case, they were
Agree completely with that.
I do not understand.
Mark is a married man, there are limits.
Oh, come on.
Listen.
Brenda.
You are acting as if you are pregnant,
As if you were the one he was going to deliver her baby.
What does it matter who is married?
I have friends who are married.
It does not work well, girl. No.
Know the dynamics of marriage.
You do not know anything about me.
I know enough.
We do not even have a dog.
Yes, we do not have a dog because
You are allergic to their saliva.
I have sacrificed for you Juno
And in a few years when you move,
Going to get one of these.
Ojala is big.
Oh, go fly high.
Hello, Juno.
What can I do for you?
Is Bleeker?
The mother Bleeker
Possibly was attractive,
But the nature ended.
You know, one of those fat.
Hello, man.
You are so concentrated
That seems not to hear anything.
Hello, what happens?
Just came to greet,
Surprised to see at night.
The Tic Tacs orange is
The only flaw of Bleeker.
The day that I was pregnant, he smelled
You are a small but delicious.
It seems that you are
Becoming a ...
... Pregnant these days.
We told you about the adoption ...
... And there are a couple who are
Desperate and I met so it is ...
... Yes.
How are they?
Well, the guy is great.
His name is Mark y. ..
... Likes film
Grotesque and plays guitar ...
... Actually went to see this afternoon.
Is that normal?
Probably not, but ...
Listen, I spoke to Dad and Bren
And say they do not due.
You rightly so,
I think it should be great.
That is a relief.
These types seem about ...
... Bobos.
You think I am beautiful now.
Whenever you see infancy.
I think you are beautiful.
Heavens, Bleek.
Really.
The boys and I were thinking
Gather in the band again.
Yes, that could be.
It would be great.
I mean, once
Enters into this is not going to be able to ...
... Touching.
We can go back to being together as well.
It is an option.
Are We were together?
Yes, we were, you know?
Over time.
Why not you like Devoy Katrina?
They love it.
I do not like, smells like soup.
Did not you have smelled?
And the whole house smells like soup.
Okay.
So we have ivory and cheese cake.
It is yellow.
I wanted to paint a color
Neutral until we have the baby.
Why do you think that
Yellow is a color neutral?
I know of no one
With a fourth yellow.
I was thinking of
Ivory for this side.
I do not know, maybe I should put
A large poster for this part.
Why not wait a few months?
I do not believe that the baby wants
Have a wall full of clouds.
What are you waiting if you say that this
Is a process for women.
Especially if it adopts,
Called anxiety.
Anxiety.
More than you
Had all these days.
Should we read a book, there
Chapters devoted to this.
I think it is too early to paint.
This is my opinion.
I disagree.
This wall can mean something.
A photo there in the middle.
What do you think?
See?
Come on, you do not put
And for a doughnut.
I am hungry, please.
You do not have.
Suéltame.
I am going to stun.
Oh, my God.
That's it, that's Vanessa Loring.
Does the magazine?
She is very pretty.
It looks like a model or something.
It appears that you love children.
Yes, seriously.
I do not get.
I imagine a large biscuit,
With strawberry jelly or something.
Oh, God, you are sick,
Just think in eating.
You have no substance.
Juno.
Hello.
What are you doing here?
I was shopping with my friends.
Are you gay?
Not.
-- Please ignórala.
-- Agreed.
How do you feel?
Great, everything is wonderful.
This seems a button.
It's incredible.
Oh, God.
What?
Patadas, come and go.
What would you feel?
Are you kidding?
It's great, everyone wants tocarme
All the time, it's crazy.
You know, I am allergic, I
Could sneeze.
Would whatever.
There is moving to me.
You should try to talk, because it supposedly
You can hear, as if it were at sea.
Hello baby.
It's me, it is Vanessa ...
I can not wait to meet you.
Do I hear you, baby?
Sweet Angel.
Oh, God.
It is magical.
Thanks.
SPRING
Hello.
I saw this rare CD that you gave me.
Yes, why did you do it?
Because it's funny.
Is it funny?
Where does the power of rock,
Everything looks beautiful and embarrassing.
Maybe you want an entire
Collection so that you can prove.
Well ...
... Considering your musical education ...
I can not wait to see how I teach.
You will not win, returns to work.
Just called to say hello.
Well, thanks for calling.
Or that seems to eat Mexican,
And Chinese food, apparently.
How many more things pick?
You are putting enormous.
I need to eat, you should see me naked.
I do not think you have desires.
Believe me, you do not want to, in fact use a
Gaza rare that I have any tight.
I do not know, resemble a whale.
Heat.
Why the whole world looks at me?
Probably want to fight.
He gave a kiss to
Geometry teacher.
I had no choice, kissing me
Work a lot lately.
Do not do with Mr. Keith.
Because it is not well
Do that these days.
Keith is burning.
That is all purity.
Is that Bleek has Escuchaste
Katrina Devoy something?
Is Katrina?
No way,
He does not like Katrina.
He says he is a pig or something.
We listened to ask her, and will go to Benny
Hana, and then take and then go to his cabin.
He told me that she smelled of soup.
I can not believe that you have believed him.
I went to his house for the last 4 years
His birthday, and I know that smelled strange.
But you know what they do
Boys when they want a powder.
Oh, please.
There is no way to have sex.
Even I have seen
Cogiéndose hands.
It would not be so sure, did you.
Yes, it was because I wanted to, you know?
We were friends.
Are you jealous?
I thought you had said no
You mattered what he did.
I am not jealous, is a joke.
It's just that I know he does not like to Bleek Katrina, not
Like emotions such, it is quite good.
I am now convinced.
You know, actually I do not care.
As can do
He is going to eat my hand.
Are you going to honestly
Devoy provide you with Katrina?
Hello.
Leah said that ibas to go with it.
Yes, I asked him if he wanted to go.
I was going to say that Benny Hana, the palmar
And then go to my parents' cottage on the beach.
Let's go in a limo.
Your mother must be very happy
I am not that you chose me.
You are brave, why?
I am not brave.
I am brilliant, it just
Fact that I can not leave,
Also that everyone look at me all day on my
Bag and also that your noviecita told me that reeks.
Katrina is not my girlfriend, I doubt
She accepts, it's just that ...
... The shape of his face,
It is only because his face.
Yes, just go to have a good time, I think there are
Many good things to do that night.
I will promise to my feet that perhaps walk up
The church, perhaps hit by a garbage truck,
Because everything would be more
Good to go too.
You are being immature.
You have no reason to be
Angry with me, I mean,
Broke my heart, I should be the one who is,
Should be very angry, it should not ever talk.
Why was boring and I
Sex with you, and I did not want to get married?
As you did it, you
The most poor, can agree?
And I know that you were not boring that day.
Because there were so many things on TV And
Draft of the Witches Blair was about to begin.
What you saw from the beginning, you could
Have seen but only wanted to do it and now.
I know that sometimes I am not very decent,
That sometimes I am a real bitch.
I still have your underwear.
This is your virginity.
Would you can silence?
Avergüenzas Would you have done?
-- No.
-- Because at least
Not have to bear the
Evidence under your sweater.
I'ma planet.
Wait, let me help you.
There are only 10 other pounds.
Hello.
It seems that weighs.
Is Vanessa is?
No, it has not arrived yet.
Why are you here? I have something for you.
Watch this.
Is this is the room
Baby? It is beautiful.
Oh, you are funny.
This is where I save all my comics.
Let me show you one.
One of those types.
Take a look.
Yuki, the most fertile.
Is it a superheroína pregnant?
Is not it great?
The found when he was
Organizing and reminded me of you.
Devils, yes.
This actually makes me
Feel much better.
Yuki is a sore back, you must be
Proud to have the same status.
Thanks.
What do you think of Toonish?
Okay, do not look, no matter what.
This is a little slower, but it sounds
Well, totally crazy, and hardcore.
I heard this song.
-- Really?
-- Yes, this song is older than me.
I single out there.
Who bailabas?
Sandy Aborgo,
Dance company great.
-- Burning.
-- Much.
I can imagine how bailabas.
As a total imbecile.
In fact, your hands go here,
Mine here.
That is what we did in'88.
In this way.
Yes, well.
Are you sure that no
Fuiste dancer before?
The dance is for morons.
How you?
I do not know.
Did not feel something between us?
I am separating Vanessa.
What?
I have a place in the city, everything is planned,
It is something I want to do long ago.
Not.
No?
No, definitely can not be there.
When I released it ...
... Not ...
What is the problem?
I mean, you
Going to deal with this, you know?
I thought I would agree with that.
I thought it would be perfect, I did not want to grow in the
Shit with separated parents, as almost every family.
Look, I will have the baby and
Vanessa will be very happy.
You just ...
The baby be remedied, however,
I think it is ready to be a father.
But you are old.
What do you think about me?
Why are you here?
Yo ...
... I just like to be a part
A rare piece of furniture in their lives.
This, this is what is becoming my life, draw
Boxes of things, I am the floor, how that's what you like?
-- This is my fault.
-- No.
Is Vanessa has infuriated
To see me here or something like that?
You do not have anything to do,
Vanessa and I no longer love us.
You were in love when
You married her.
And if you were in love you can do it again as my
Leah friend who has returned with the same type as 4 times.
Not what you are trying enough.
You can not blame anyone for this.
No, you know what, Mark.
No divorcies your wife.
Does Please, I can do the
Please stay with Vanessa?
Sorry, I ...
I am not so young, I am 16, old enough
To know that you are acting like a stupid.
Oh, and you know what?
I bought another CD that I
Hit and stinks, it's just noise.
Juno, what happens?
Nothing.
Why cry?
Do not cry, is that I am allergic to dust.
What is the problem?
It is a bit sensitive, does not
It? Esparte process.
What did you do?
There did nothing.
Only ...
... I have been thinking ...
-- What?
-- Just when I thought we were doing the right thing.
What talk?
Only I wonder if ...
... I am ready.
I list.
We are ready, we are, we have to all
Classes, the nurse said we had finished.
Listen, I am not prepared and
She wondered whether I am.
Wait a minute.
You know what happens,
He has called fear.
It is a type.
Both thought the same thing, a woman
Becomes mother becomes pregnant when,
Perhaps he becomes a
Father when he sees her baby.
It's going to be there, going to be there.
Everything happened so fast and we went to
Newspaper, I thought it would take a few months y. ..
Within 2 weeks she was in that couch.
But she does not know that.
Since then it has been like a clock.
What do you say?
It seems that bad times will come.
What would be good
Time for you, Mark?
Unless there are things I want to do.
How? Being a rock star.
Do not laugh.
Just say that this is ...
... This is something that will never happen.
That pullover is stupid.
It grows.
If I have to wait for you to become
In Kurt Cobain, I will be ever mother.
Never said I would be a good father.
Call Gerta Rauss, and she said that we can
Represent the two, is called divorce evenly.
So from now on, it is possible ...
... Which is easier,
Since there are no children.
Thank you for making the call, I think.
Have you found a place to stay?
Yes, in the middle.
No, it's not a hotel, is a floor.
Did not the type eras good?
I wanted both the baby.
I know.
-- It seems a ticket ...
-- Let me see.
I never realized how much I liked being in
Home, I have been very different for some time.
Hello, Dad.
Hello, large piece of Jumbo.
Where were you?
Just watching the way
Fastest to reach here.
Where are you all?
Bren was to carry Tod
His kind of skating.
When will learn that there can skate?
You seem a little angry, sweetheart.
What happens?
I do not know.
It is just that I am losing
My faith in humanity.
Can you tell me why?
I just ...
... I wonder if ...
Two people can ...
Be together for good.
How couples?
You know.
People in love.
Got problems loves? Because I have to be
Honest, I do not approve that you are out on your condition.
That is a disaster.
No, Dad, it is not ...
This is very shocking.
You know what I mean, salidita.
Please, stop.
Round the world.
This is not that.
I only need to know that it is possible that two people
That love can be happy together forever.
That is not easy, of course.
I am not the best example
Of the world, but ...
... I have been your mother 10 years and I do not know ...
... We can say that we are very happy.
Watch ...
... In my opinion ...
... The best thing you can do is to look
To the person who loves you for what you are.
Good things, bad things. Fea, beautiful.
I bet, which you are.
The person named will always believe
That the sun goes behind your ass.
That is the kind of
Person we all want.
Yes.
Yes, I believe that I am that person.
Yes, of course, we can all be.
Yes, there will always be someone who loves you and you
Support no matter how annoying you are.
Obviously.
Dad, I think I am going a. ..
Leave a moment, but ...
... I come back early.
Okay.
You are talking about me, this is not the case.
Oh, yes.
Bleeker, check your mail.
Hello.
Do you Fuiste which put 100
Tic Tac boxes, in my mailbox?
Oh, yeah, that was me.
Why?
Well, you know, are your favorites y. ..
You can never take ...
When you want so ...
Regalártelos wanted ....
Yeah, well thanks, I ...
... I think I am too
Coupled with those tic tacs.
You know, Bleek, I was thinking ...
... And so sorry for
Before, you do not deserve it.
Okay, you know, okay.
Besides ...
... I think I love you.
Are you teasing me?
Not.
I mean, really.
You are the best person
I have known good ...
... And even
Have to try ...
... Know.
The attempt lot, in fact.
You are intelligent in nature.
You are not like others.
Although you always see,
Every time I order ...
... You see y. ..
Beams my heart ...
Tin super.
Really?
That's how my late
Heart every time you see it.
Mine too.
Well, it's everything you can ask.
The golden boy.
Can we make love now?
Yes.
Hey, you know, going to give birth soon
Time if you continue doing that.
Dad.
What?
Dad, you run, I think
Broke the source o. ..
Or?
We must leave.
We run away.
Okay.
Did you have everything ready?
Yes.
That is not left anything.
Oh, please, please.
There we go.
Hurry, it starts the car.
Dad.
-- Wait, wait.
-- Get out of the medium.
-- Do not do that.
-- What?
-- What are you doing.
-- But it is fun.
I was pressing the spine.
It's called spinal what to do, you can not have it
Still, the doctor says that you are not extensive enough.
Oh, come on, I do not think it has anything
Worse, I can not think of anything more.
Doctors say that.
Too late to make
God, let the people shout.
Oh, shit.
Excuse me, may end up
To meet my daughter.
Bid, bid, bid.
And then ...
... I do not know where ...
... There was ...
... Why was it.
I said that we were not to tell
Bleek who was having the baby,
She had great competition and not
I wanted to be worried about me.
But what he discovered anyway.
Someday back here, sweetheart.
When you tap.
Hello.
We apologize.
Bleeker decided that
I did not want to see the baby.
Me neither, it will not
I felt it was ours.
I think it was always there.
You can see his son.
I have a son.
This is.
How luzco?
As a new mother.
Asustada up bones.
And then there was the chair.
Vanessa, if you stay
I maintain, Juno.
SUMMER
As a boyfriend, Paulie Bleeker is lost,
It is my cheese macaroni.
I know that people tend to romanticize
Before playing, but ...
... I believe that in my usual style ...
Hello.
Ready?
Yes.