One! One!
One, two, one!
Dear Mother:
I hope you are keeping well
and not worrying too much about me.
You mustn't think that any of us
are going to be killed...
...for they are collecting such a force
here that an attack would be insane.
The Massachusetts men
passed through here this morning.
How grand it is to meet the men
from all the states, east and west...
...down here ready
to fight for their country...
...as the old fellows did
in the Revolution.
But this time we must make it
a whole country...
...for all who live here,
so that all can speak.
Before this war began...
...many of my regiment
had never seen a Negro.
Now the roads are choked
with the dispossessed.
We fight for men and women
whose poetry is not yet written...
...but which will presently be
as enviable and as renowned as any.
Last night we heard
of yet another defeat.
But we are not disheartened.
I am honored to be part
of such a splendid company.
They have made me captain,
of which I am enormously proud.
You would think it strange to see me
giving orders to a hundred men...
...most of whom are older
than I am.
Thank you for sending
my volume of Emerson.
His words come home to me
like truth.
'A deep man,' he says, 'believes
that the evil eye can wither...
...that the heart's blessing
can heal...
...and that love
can overcome all odds. '
My dearest love to Father.
Your son, Robert.
Company, forward!
- Charge!
- Fire!
Fire!
Ready, men?
- Aim!
- Fire!
Stand. Fire!
Steady, boys!
- Forward!
- Fire!
Fire!
Forward, men! Forward!
For God's sake, come on!
Fire!
Robert, come on!
We must fall back!
No! Forbes!
Forbes!
Charge!
You all right there, captain?
Please! Not my leg!
- Where's the chloroform?
- Stop!
Stop!
No! Wait!
- No!
- Hold on!
So it's the neck, right, captain?
Well, the surgeons are all busy,
but I'll fix you up.
All right, I'll just-
- Let me know if I hurt you.
- Stop!
Oh, this is nothing.
- Heard the latest?
- What's that?
Well, I heard it from a friend
who's a dispatch rider...
...who got it from a friend who's one
of Stanton's clerks in the War Office.
He says Lincoln is gonna issue
an emancipation proclamation.
Gonna free the slaves.
What?
Maybe not in the border states
or something...
...but he's gonna free
some of them, anyway.
- My God.
- Yeah.
Would've done it sooner,
only he was waiting on a big victory...
...which is, I guess, what this is.
Oh, my God!
Please don't cut anymore, please!
Please!
This might hurt you, captain.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Dashing.
- Robert.
- Thomas.
Captain Shaw.
I was so proud when I heard.
Well, they had no choice.
All the other officers are dead.
- And Forbes?
- Impossible, as always.
He's around here somewhere.
How about you?
Working for your father,
helping him with the resettlement...
...for the Freedmen's
Relief Association.
There's a shortage of housing.
Robert! Are you all right?
Yes. I'm sorry.
Robert! Darling, there's someone
who wishes to meet you.
General Hunter rounded up
a bunch of slaves from the fields...
...called them "contraband"
and put them in camps like cattle.
Then the War Department decided
to issue them pikes rather than guns.
Of course they deserted.
So would I.
Robert.
Governor, you know my son Robert.
- Yes, good to see you again, Robert.
- Governor Andrew.
Robert, have you met
Frederick Douglass?
Mr. Douglass.
I understand you were at Antietam.
Yes.
A great and a terrible day.
Well, I could use your help, Robert.
The governor is proposing to raise
a regiment of Negro soldiers.
No, no. It was not just my idea.
Mr. Douglass and some of us-
We will offer pride and dignity...
...to those who have known
only degradation.
Colored soldiers, Robert.
Just think of it.
Wonderful.
I've submitted your name
to be commissioned colonel...
...of the 54th Massachusetts Infantry.
Thank you, governor. That's-
It's a wonderful idea.
Excuse me.
- Well done, Shaw.
- Well done, captain.
- Splendid job, young man.
- Bravo, Robert.
What's the matter, chester?
Too much punch?
I mean, I know how much
you'd like to make colonel...
...but a colored regiment?
You know how popular
that would be?
Handing out guns
to a thousand coloreds?
Hey, Robert.
What's wrong?
I'm gonna do it.
You're not serious.
Yeah.
- I want you to come with me.
- Me?
And you?
Can you picture me
in charge of a regiment?
Picture me in charge of anything?
I would be honored to have you.
Well, then you're an idiot.
Rob, is it true?
There's to be a colored regiment?
So it seems.
Then I am your first volunteer.
Present arms!
How do we look, colonel?
We gonna whup the Secesh?
Boss, when do we get the blue suit?
- Yeah, the blue suit.
- Yeah.
- Ready to whip them Rebs.
- Ready, colonel!
- When are we gonna get to fight?
- Yeah!
Are we really gonna get to fight
this time?
Attention!
- Morning.
Good morning, gentlemen.
I am Colonel Robert Gould Shaw.
I am your commanding officer.
It is a great pleasure
to see you all here today.
It is my hope
that the same courage...
...spirit and honor,
which has brought us together...
...will one day restore this Union.
May God bless us all!
Yeah!
Form companies?
We will commence
with forming companies.
Company officers, take charge.
You recruits will report
to your respective officers...
...by the letter of your company
in alphabetical order...
...which is in the top left-hand corner
of your muster sheet.
- Good book, brother?
- Yes, it is, actually.
Name's Searles. Thomas Searles.
Jupiter Sharts, sir.
What it about, that book?
It's a collection of essays actually.
Fourier, Emerson,
all the transcendentalists.
- It got pictures?
- No.
- Teach me?
- Yes, I'd be happy to.
- Yes, I'd be happy to...
- Teach me?
- Yes, I'd be happy to.
Will you look at what's
walking in here! Look at them.
I'd rather have a hog than a nigger.
At least you could eat the hog!
Getting dark mighty early
around here.
Come on! Show us a little dance,
will you, boys?
Sergeant of the guard,
post your sentry.
Yes, sir!
Right there!
Shoulder!
Right file, right. March!
Wait, no.
See, that's my space, nigger.
I sleep better close-up on that door.
If you don't mind, I'd prefer a space
with more sufficient reading light.
Oh, I like it when niggers
talk good as white folk.
I'd be happy to teach you.
It would be my pleasure.
Hey, look here, snowflake, I ain't got
nothing to learn from no house nigger.
I am a free man,
as was my father before me.
- Oh, you free, nigger?
- Yes.
Good. Why don't you move
your free black ass before I bust it up?
- Hey, hold up, buck.
- Nobody said nothing to you, pap.
It's all right.
I'll be fine over here.
Excuse me.
Wonder when they gonna
give us the blue suit.
Ain't give no blue suit to no black
soldiers. Blue suits for the whites.
Well, we soldiers now.
- Where you from, field hand?
- South Carolina.
South Carolina? Well, you ought
to know better than that, boy.
Hey, would you quit that?
Say, boy, quit that drumming.
Hey, hey, hey.
What's your name, boy?
I said what's your name, boy?
- Can't you see that he's mute?
- He what?
He's mute.
You mean this child can't talk?
Hey, come over here, hon.
Dummies and field hands.
Ain't that a bitch?
What about you there, buck?
Whereabouts are you from?
I'm from around Tennessee.
Ran away when I 12 years old,
I ain't never looked back.
Wh-? What you doing since then?
I've run for president.
I didn't win though.
Boy.
Come on, give us some food, man.
Major? Forbes?
That's you.
- Thomas.
- Hello.
- How are you?
- You know Charlie Morse.
- Charlie.
- Thomas Searles.
- Hello.
- Cabot.
So how was your meal?
The rémoulade was a trifle tart...
...but the soufflé for dessert
more than made up for it.
And your comrades?
Charming. Extraordinary
conversationalists, every one.
Major Forbes.
A word, please.
Oh, excuse me, Thomas.
Yes, Robert?
I won't permit
that kind of fraternization.
- It's only Thomas.
- He's an enlisted man.
You're right, of course.
I've sent for help.
These men need a proper teacher.
For God's sakes, men, you march
like a bunch of crippled old goats!
Jesus Christ, we're gonna be here
day and night until we get this right.
One, one!
Company, halt!
About-face!
You are ugly Mexican,
African fucking whores!
We're gonna work on this
day and night, gentlemen.
Forward at the half step. March!
One. You half-wit black bastard.
Is it true they cut your balls off
at birth?
I'm gonna work on you, you bastard,
until I get you broken.
Company, halt!
For God's sake, do you not know
your right from your left?
No, no, no, sir.
How many here do not know
right from left?
Jesus, have pity.
This is your front!
This is your rear!
This is your right! And this-
Now you're learning, boyo.
Company, forward, march!
One, one, one.
- Two!
- One!
- One.!
- Two!
- One!
You bloody Hindus, get it right!
Stop. Start it again.
In each rank. Count!
Left. Left, right, left.
Right, on my word, march.
Left- Get your goddamn hand
out of your pocket, soldier!
Left. Left, right, left.
Oh, look at this.
Bonnie Prince Charlie.
Are you a gentleman? Are you
a member of congress, or something?
Or are you the bloody
prince of Africa?
Don't look at me! Look straight
ahead! Look straight ahead!
I'll eat your ass up, boyo.
You know, the Irish are not noted
for their fondness for the coloreds.
What about the uniforms?
Still no word.
The rifles?
- Left. Left, right left.
- See to it.
You're a big buck.
You're tough, aren't you?
You've got a lot to learn.
You haven't had a master like me.
Dear, Mother.
The men learn very quickly.
Faster than white troops,
it seems to me.
They are almost grave
and sedate under instruction...
...and they restrain themselves.
But the moment
they are dismissed from drill...
...every tongue is relaxed
and every ivory tooth is visible.
And you would not know from the
sound of it that this is an Army camp.
They must have had to learn this
from long hours of meaningless...
...and inhuman work.
To set their minds free so quickly...
...it gives them great energy.
And there is no doubt
that we will leave this state...
...as fine a regiment as any
that has marched.
As ever, your son, Robert.
They've done it.
Assemble the men.
Attention!
Battalion!
In accordance with
President Lincoln's wishes...
...you men are advised...
...that the Confederate Congress
has issued a proclamation.
It reads:
"Any Negro taken in arms...
...against the Confederacy...
...will immediately be returned
to a state of slavery.
Any Negro
taken in Federal uniform...
...will be summarily put to death.
Any white officer
taken in command of Negro troops...
...shall be deemed as inciting
servile insurrection...
...and shall likewise
be put to death. "
Full discharges
will be granted in the morning...
...to all those who apply.
- Dismissed.
If you're not here in the morning...
...I understand.
Still want that blue suit, nigger?
- Good morning, major.
- Sir. Formed and ready, sir.
How many are left?
Attention!
Battalion!
Glory hallelujah.
One. One, two, one.
One, one. One, two, one.
Company, halt!
You're not dismissed, boyo!
Get up!
You'll fall out when I say
and not before. Do you understand?
I said, get up!
Sergeant major.
- Sir.
- At ease, sergeant.
I have no doubt
that you are a fair man, Mulcahy.
I wonder if you are
treating these men too hard.
You disagree?
- You may speak freely.
- The boy's your friend, is he?
We grew up together, yes.
Let him grow up some more.
- I see.
- Will that be all, sir?
Yes.
Dismissed.
- Order.
Fifty-seven caliber Enfield rifle musket.
Best in the world here, boy.
Sharts.
"11911."
Think you can handle that, boy?
Shit, I can knock something down
with this.
Trip.
"12192."
- Beautiful.
- Hawkins.
"12186."
- Jefferson.
- Yes, sir.
Robert.
Finally.
There's a rumor going around...
...that we're to be used
only for manual labor.
I can't believe
the kind of things we hear.
It's not true, is it? I mean,
about not being allowed to fight.
The men are all living for that day.
I know I am.
- Fletch.
- Don't bother about him.
- He's just ignorant.
- Excuse me.
For God's sake, come on!
Good shot, man.
Do that again. Here, give him
your weapon. Give him that.
Do that again.
- One dime, he can't do it.
- Dime? Dime on each of you.
- I want money.
- That's a bet.
- Go on, boy.
- Go ahead. Go ahead, Sharts.
- That's a dime on each of you!
- Double or nothing!
Attention, company!
As you were.
Front and center.
You're a good shot, private.
Thank you, sir. Squirrel hunting.
- You ever killed a man?
- No, sir.
- But you're handy with a gun.
- Yes, sir.
Reload.
Faster.
Faster!
Discharge your weapon.
Do it!
Now do it again.
Only this time, I want it done quickly.
A good man can fire three aimed shots
in a minute.
Major Forbes,
give me your Colt revolver.
- What?
- Your gun.
Give it to me.
Faster.
Reload.
Quickly. Faster!
Faster! Load.
Faster!
Do it! Do it!
Do it!
Teach them properly, major.
Yes, sir.
Attention, company!
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Good morning, major.
You're up early.
I wanna talk to you.
Certainly.
If you wouldn't mind
getting down from your horse.
Better?
Why do you treat the men this way,
Robert?
How should I treat them?
Like men?
And what about Thomas?
Why are you so hard on him?
He's not a very good soldier.
I'm getting these men ready for battle.
Robert, they're already as good
as the Seventh ever was.
- They march well. They're disciplined.
- No thanks to you.
- I beg your pardon?
- You heard me.
Who do you think you are,
acting the high-up colonel?
You seem to forget, I know you...
...and so does Thomas.
Forbes.
If you don't believe in
what we're doing here...
- ... maybe you shouldn't be part of it.
- Part of what?
Left, right, left, right, little finger
along the seams of your trousers?
Marching is probably all
they'll ever get to do, Robert.
It is my job...
...to get these men ready.
And I will.
They have risked their lives
to be here.
They have given up their freedom.
I owe them as much
as they've given.
I owe them my freedom...
...my life, if necessary.
Maybe so do you, Cabot.
I think you do.
Develop! Guard!
Thrust! Develop!
Guard! Thrust!
Develop! Guard!
You're not at dancing school, son.
Take his head off.
Thrust! Develop!
Guard!
Jesus, Mary and Joseph,
what have we here?
Bonnie Prince Charlie
and his little toy bayonet.
You're not reading your books now.
Go on, go on, get over there.
- Now stab me.
- What?
Stab me.
Come on, stab, not tickle. Hit me.
Come on!
You prissy little schoolgirl.
You're the worst soldier
in this whole company. Now hit me!
No shame, son. Get up.
I said, get up.
Nigger forgot to duck. That's all.
Sergeant, deal with that man.
Let me tell you a wee secret, son.
The only thing you're to learn
to do is to keep your mouth shut.
Save it, son. Save it.
Carry on, Sergeant Mulcahy.
- First rank to the rear. Back to work.
- Robert. Robert.
I'd like to speak to you
for a moment in private, if I may.
Enlisted men wishing to speak
to their commanding officer...
...must first get permission.
You understand, private?
Yes, sir.
Guard! Thrust!
Develop! Recover!
Thrust! Develop! Recover!
En garde!
You better put some oomph
into that, boyo!
Oh, my, my, my.
Some things never change.
I guess the whole world
hate the nigger.
Boy, if you don't quit
that drumming in here...
Honey, why don't you take your drum
on outside and practice?
That Colonel Shaw, he a hard man.
Yeah, swell.
Just a nigger-beating swell.
But he in the same boat with us.
Secesh come, take him, kill him too.
Not him.
He a swell.
He just a boy.
Yeah. He a weak white boy.
Beating on a nigger
make him feel strong.
Ain't that right, snowflake?
You know, he ain't never been
to no West Point...
...and the only reason
he in charge...
...is because
his mommy and daddy fixed it.
Ain't that so?
You thought he was different,
didn't you?
What you think now?
You just thought you was so smart,
didn't you, nigger?
Yeah, you in real school now
though, ain't you?
What you gonna do? Cry?
Yeah, he sure enough
learning now, ain't he?
- Sergeant, post your sentries.
- Yes, sir.
Attention, company.
Forward, march.
Right face.
Oh, shit.
Young man say there's a farm
ain't but two or three miles from here.
Said the lady over there
give him biscuits and gravy.
She said, if he bring his friends,
she feed them too.
- Don't even think about it.
- What you say, buck?
Biscuits and gravy sound good to me.
Maybe get myself some real shoes.
I'm telling you, boy.
They find out, they liable to shoot you.
Nigger, is you an old man
or is you an old woman? I forget.
All right.
Collard greens.
Corn bread.
Come on, dream.
I'm waiting on you.
Throw it over here.
Dear, Mother.
News today of the defeat
at Fredericksburg.
If things continue to go badly,
I wonder if I might not end my days...
...as an outlaw leader
of a band of fugitive slaves.
Try as I may,
I don't know these men.
Their music, their camaraderie...
...which is different from ours.
I am placed in a position where,
if I were a man of real strength...
...I might do a great deal.
But I am afraid I shall show
that I am not of much account.
I don't want to stand in their way
because of my own weakness.
I miss Christmas
on the Shaw Island...
...and the smell of the sea.
Robert.
It's Thomas.
I just wanted to say...
I wanted to say...
Merry Christmas, Robert.
Merry Christmas, Thomas.
You're Shaw, aren't you?
Merry Christmas.
Kendric, division quartermaster.
This sorry piece of work is Haggis.
He writes vouchers.
- Pleasure.
- How's it going down there?
- Oh, very well. Thank you.
That's all right. Brass are all up
to division, planning the next disaster.
You're among friends.
How much longer do you figure
they last?
I hear they're deserting,
10 at a time.
Oh, you're misinformed.
- We haven't had a single incident.
- See?
I figure the nigs
never had it so good.
Three square a day,
a roof over their heads.
And they gotta know that nobody's
gonna let them fight. Am I right?
Yes, of course.
Listen, if there's anything you need.
- A bottle for the cold nights?
- Yes, actually, I put in a requisition...
...for some shoes two weeks ago...
...and I haven't heard anything.
Well, provisionally speaking...
...we're extremely limited
as to footwear.
I'm afraid that kind of item
has to be reserved...
...for those units
whose fighting readiness...
...supersede yours.
You understand, I'm sure.
Yes, I understand.
- Excuse me.
- Oh, stop by tomorrow.
I have got my hands on
the most delicious local jam.
- Myrtle berry, isn't it?
- Blueberry.
Oh, right, right.
Nice meeting you, Shaw.
Twit.
- Excuse me, sir.
- What is it?
We've caught a deserter.
Oh, lordy, this is bad.
They ain't gonna shoot him, is they?
No.
It'll be all right.
Won't it?
Re-form your ranks!
- Re-form your ranks!
Fall in. Quiet in the ranks.
Quiet in the ranks!
Right. Untie his hands
and take off his coat.
The prisoner is in position, sir.
What is this?
The prisoner is to be flogged
before the entire regiment.
Robert, not with a whip.
Not on them.
- Excuse us, Sergeant Mulcahy.
- At your pleasure, colonel.
Never question my authority
in front of others.
Well, I is sorry, massa. You be
the boss man now and all us chilluns...
- ... must learn to obey.
- Major Forbes, stand at attention.
Sergeant Mulcahy.
You may commence.
Proceed.
Attention.
Mr. Rawlins.
This morning I-
It would be a great help
if I could talk to you...
...about the men from time to time.
That's all.
Shoes, sir.
The men need shoes, colonel.
Yes, I know. I've been after
the quartermaster for some time now.
No, sir. Now.
The boy was off trying to find hisself
some shoes, colonel.
He wants to fight...
...same as the rest of us.
More, even.
All of the men, like this?
Yes. Most of them.
Good afternoon, colonel.
You change your mind about
that bottle I was talking about?
I want 600 pair of shoes
and 1200 pair of socks...
...and anything else
you've been holding out on us.
Piece of rat filth.
I'd love to help you, colonel,
but we just don't have any.
Not for niggers, you don't.
- Not for anybody.
- I see. Pity.
I'll just have a look around,
see that you haven't misplaced them.
Hey.
Hey!
Son of a bitch!
- Damn it, you can't-
- Can't I?
I'm a colonel, nasty little cuss.
You really think you can keep
700 Union soldiers...
...without proper shoes
because you think it's funny?
- Where would that power come from?
- All right, all right. Calm down.
Look, have a drink.
Hey, you barefoot men,
come on out here!
Got something for you.
Shoes! Shoes!
Have a pair.
Here's a pair there.
One pair of shoes here.
Here's another pair.
One pair per customer.
Steward, is there
anything you need?
- No, sir.
- Keep me informed.
Yes, sir. I will.
Shoulder arms!
Sir.
From the War Department.
Can anything be done?
- They've got families.
- I know.
We'll protest this
through channels later on.
- Attention, battalion.
- Yes, sir.
Attention, battalion!
You men enlisted in this regiment...
...on the understanding...
...that you would be paid
the regular Army wage...
...of $13 a month.
This morning I have been notified...
...that since you are
a colored regiment...
...you will be paid $10 a month.
That ain't fair. They said 13.
Regiment, fall out by company
to receive pay.
- Where you going, boy?
- To get paid.
Ten dollar, a lot of money.
Hey, pop, you fitting to lay down
for this too?
- Fall in!
Hey. Hey, come on.
Where's your pride, now?
Make your mark right here.
- I can write my name.
- Then do it.
They give them $13, only gonna give
us but ten? You gonna go for that?
I mean, a colored soldier stop a bullet
just as good as a white one!
And for less money too!
Yeah. Yeah, Uncle Abe got hisself
a real bargain here!
- Hey, what you say, boy?
- That's right, slaves!
Step right up, make your mark.
Get your slave wages.
All you good colored boys,
go ahead and sign up.
That's right. Tear it up, tear it up.
Tear it up! Tear it up!
- Get back in line!
- Tear it up, tear it up!
Tear it up, tear it up!
Tear it up! Tear it up!
Tear it up, tear it up, tear it up!
Tear it up, tear it up,
tear it up, tear-
If you men will take no pay...
...then none of us will.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Let's hear it for the colonel!
Yeah!
Attention, battalion!
Attention.
Eyes right!
Eyes front!
Eyes...
...right.
Mainly, I forgot how hot
it was down here.
Welcome home, boy.
Don't worry about it, buck.
Take a good look.
It's all a memory
now that the North man come.
Now that we come.
Colonel Shaw?
Edward Pierce, special assignment
from Harper's Weekly.
- Harper's Weekly?
- Serving an entire nation.
Million readers want to know
what happens...
...when the men
of the 54th see action.
A million and one.
Well, you'll want to see this.
Attention, company!
- Rawlins, front and center.
- Sir!
Mr. Rawlins, this regiment
was formed with the promise...
...that only white officers
would be commissioned to lead it.
Nothing was mentioned, however,
about noncommissioned officers.
Therefore, in recognition of initiative
taken not only for yourself...
...but on behalf
of the entire regiment...
...you are hereby awarded the rank
of sergeant major.
Congratulations.
- Thank you, sir.
- Hip, hip, hooray!
Hip, hip, hooray! Hip, hip, hooray!
Congratulations.
I ain't sure I'm wanting this, colonel.
I know exactly how you feel.
Mama, they're coming home!
They're coming home!
That's right, hons. Ain't no dream.
We runaway slaves,
but we come back fighting men.
Go tell your folks how kingdom come
in the year of jubilee!
Left. Up tight up there.
Left.
- Who are these ragamuffin?
- Contrabands, right out of the fields.
- Hey. Hey, old man, where from?
- Massachusetts.
Oona march better than we.
Oona march like the buckra soldier.
- I beg your pardon?
- He says we march like white soldiers.
Even talk like the buckra soldier.
- Where you from?
- Oh, round about here.
We were slaves in the field when the
Yankee man come. Say we soldiers.
How you like the Army, contraband?
Oh, we love it. We thank the Lord
every day for the good vittles...
...and these beautiful clothes.
Tell true.
This year, every day like Christmas.
- Like what?
- Like Christmas.
Splendid.
They've been working for weeks
in anticipation of your arrival.
We're all very excited
to have you here, Shaw.
- Thank you, sir.
- Lincoln's idea.
Hired a group of New Englanders...
...to teach our colored
how to read and write.
Just your sort of people,
I should think.
The regiment should enjoy
their stay here.
Yes, I'm sure we'll have a fine time,
but that's not why we're here.
Well, can't promise you much action.
Just having the coloreds around...
...seems to have scared the bejesus
out of the Rebs.
- Colonel Shaw?
- Excuse me.
I'd like you to meet
some of our instructors.
Dr. Thorpe of Salem.
- It's my pleasure, Colonel Shaw.
- Pleasure.
Dr. Rogers of Philadelphia.
- I know and admire your parents.
- You do, sir? Why, thank you, sir.
Shaw, meet Colonel Montgomery.
He's your brigade commander.
- Colonel.
- Honored, sir.
Colonel Montgomery's
a real jayhawker from Kansas.
Contraband regiment
is his brainchild.
You didn't think yours were the only
coloreds around, did you, colonel?
- I did, actually.
- Well, I'm sure they'll do just fine.
Have they seen any mischief?
No, sir.
I'm hiking a company over
to the Georgia coast in the morning.
We'll be foraging for supplies.
I could use a hand.
That is, if you think
your men are up to it.
They are indeed, sir.
Good. Very good.
- A pleasure.
- Good night.
Beg to report, colonel, sir.
The troop is fed
and bedded down for the night, sir.
Very good, corporal.
Pass the word along to A company...
...we'll be going into action
in the morning.
Very good, sir.
Your men march handsomely, colonel.
My compliments.
Thank you, sir.
I am surprised at how well
you handle them.
See, I am from Kentucky originally
and we owned a few ourselves...
...so it comes naturally to me.
- You are from Boston, are you not?
- Yes.
It is impossible to imagine
Boston with slaves.
Company, halt!
- Halt.
- Shoulder arms!
Town's clean, sir.
Ain't no Rebs here, just some women.
Well, all right. You hear that, boys?
Let's clear her out!
- What are you doing?
- Liberating this town...
- ... in the name of the Republic.
- The musket, colonel?
Never shoot it. Shoot now?
Yeah, I don't see why not.
Go ahead.
Shoot the lady, boys!
- Don't shoot! We ain't Secesh here.
- That man is a civilian.
That man is Secesh,
and Secesh is all the same, son.
Look around you. You really think
anybody's gonna put these boys...
...into some real combat?
Do you?
They're little children.
Little monkey children.
You just gotta know
how to control them.
Please, let go! Oh, God!
You see what I mean? Children.
- Animal! Leave her alone!
- Hey, boy.
Take your hands off the white lady.
That would not have been necessary
if that Secesh woman hadn't started it.
They'll never learn.
You see, Secesh has got to be
swept away by the hand of God...
...like the Jews of old.
And now I'll have to burn this town.
Nigger soldiers! Nigger soldiers!
Tell your men to set torches
and prepare to fire the buildings.
I will not.
That is an order.
You will do it or you will be
brought up on charges for disobeying.
It is an immoral order, and by articles
of war I am not bound to obey it.
Well, you can just explain that
at your court-marital...
...after your men are placed
under my command.
First squad, second platoon.
Fall out to set torches.
Prepare to fire the town.
First squad, second platoon!
Fall out!
Right face!
Forward march!
Change the colors, sergeant major.
Change the colors.
What you looking at,
biscuit eaters?
You think you better than me?
You think you my judge?
You ain't nothing.
Dear Father, I need your help.
Despite my many requests,
it has become clear...
...that we are to be
used only for manual labor.
Morale is low.
The men's good humor
darkened by idleness and despair.
Why keep drilling if they are
never given the opportunity...
...to prove themselves?
Attention!
I have written to Governor Andrew
as well as to...
...the general staff in Washington.
But I feel that only a letter
directly from you to Lincoln himself...
...can have the desired effect.
I can think of no other course.
I am sure you both pray,
as I do...
...that all this has not been in vain.
Look like we going the wrong way.
Hey. Hey, come on, now.
Buck up, boys.
Hey, buck up, now. Come on.
See, someday they're gonna
let the 54th get into it, see?
And all your troubles
would be over, huh?
Come on now, cheer up. Hey.
What did you say, boy?
"Boy"? Let me tell you-
- Shut up, Trip-
- Would you get up off me, snowflake?
See, let me explain
something to you.
See, the way I figure, I figure this war
would be over a whole lot sooner...
...if you boys just turn right on around
and head on back down that way...
...and let us head
where the real fighting is.
Them men dying up that road.
And it wouldn't be nothing but
Rebs dying, if they let the 54th in it.
- Listen-
- Hold it!
As you were, Trip. As you were!
You men move on.
Stripes on a nigger.
That's like tits on a bull.
You're looking at
a higher rank, corporal.
Now, you'll obey and you'll like it.
- Make me.
- I'll make you.
- What the hell is going on here?
- Attention!
Attention!
You! Yes, you. What's your name?
I'm putting you up on charges.
- Oh, there ain't no cause for that, sir.
- What's that, sergeant?
Well, I mean, it's just
a soldiers' fight, sir.
- All right, you men move along.
- Front step! Forward! March!
Move it!
You men get back to work.
Back to work! Let's go!
- We'll see you again.
- Go dig a latrine.
Go strum a banjo, boy.
Come on.
I've got the guard.
Let me use your looking glass.
Thank you.
Yeah, button up that collar.
Suck in that gut.
Tuck in them big, black lips.
Lighten your skin.
Shrink up that nose.
I don't have to listen to this.
Where you going, boy?
- Let me by.
- Let you by?
Let you by?
Let me tell you something, boy.
You can march like the white man.
You can talk like him.
You can learn his songs.
You can even wear his suits.
But you ain't never
gonna be nothing to him...
...but an ugly-ass chimp
in a blue suit.
- Oh, you don't like that, do you?
- No.
Well, what we gonna do about it?
Want to fight me, boy?
What you gonna do about it?
You want to fight me, don't you?
Don't you?
- Come on, nig.
- All right! All right!
Hey, get your hands off me,
gravedigger.
Does the whole world
gotta stomp in your face?
- Nigger, get your hands off me.
- Ain't no niggers around here.
So the white man give you
a couple of stripes...
...next thing you know, you ordering
everybody around like you the massa.
Nigger, you ain't nothing
but the white man's dog.
And what are you?
So full of hate you just wanna go
and fight everybody...
...because you've been whipped
and chased by hounds.
That might not be living,
but it sure ain't dying.
And dying's what these white boys
been doing for going on three years.
Dying by the thousands.
Dying for you, fool.
I know, because I dug the graves.
And all the time I'm digging,
I'm asking myself:
"When? When, O Lord,
is it gonna be our time?"
Well, time's coming when
we're gonna have to ante up.
Ante up and kick in like men.
Like men!
You watch who you call a nigger.
If there are any niggers
around here, it's you.
Smart-mouth, stupid-ass,
swamp-running nigger.
If you ain't careful,
that's all you ever gonna be.
You men go on back to business.
Shaw.
Sit down.
Well, colonel,
what can I do for you?
You can give me and my regiment
a transfer to combat command.
Couldn't do it, colonel.
You're much too valuable
to my operations here.
May I sit?
Thank you. Major.
I've written a letter to my father...
...asking him
to press Governor Andrew...
...and President Lincoln.
But I don't have to wait for all that,
do I?
Colonel Montgomery, would you
bring that ashtray over here?
But valuable to your operations here,
do you say?
Your foraging, your depredations?
Yes, I've become quite a student
of your operations in this region.
Thirty-four mansions,
I think it was, pillaged and burned...
...under Colonel Montgomery's
expedition of the Combahee.
Four thousand bales of cotton
smuggled through the lines...
...with payment
to parties unknown...
...except by you.
False quartermaster requisitions.
Major Forbes here
has seen the copies.
Yes, indeed.
Along with confiscated valuables
shipped north as personal baggage.
Shall I go on?
Can you?
I can report you
to the War Department.
Oh, yes. I can do that.
Let you take your regiment
out to fight.
That's what you want, isn't it?
Show what they can do.
- When?
- You are bright-eyed, aren't you?
When?
Just as soon
as I can write the orders.
Major.
Double-quick!
All right, company, in a line.
All right, men, form a firing line.
Over here.
Form a firing line right here.
Front rank, kneel!
Steady, boys!
Firing by battalion!
- Aim!
Charge!
Fire!
Cease-fire! Recover!
Here they come!
- Reload!
- Reload! Load!
- Load it! Load it!
- Quickly, men!
- Ready!
- Aim!
Get ready. Get ready.
Fire!
- Reload!
Quickly.
- Fire at will!
Pour it in!
Charge!
Look out, boy! Look out!
Fire!
They're turning tail!
Run, you Rebs!
Another victory!
Deploy skirmishers, captain.
- Re-form your ranks!
Fall in, on the double.
Form up! Form up!
- Let's do it.
- Skirmish lines.
Fall in! On the double!
- Form company!
- Thomas.
How do, colonel?
Hurts, doesn't it?
Well, I'm extremely jealous.
You'll be back in Boston
before me...
...sitting by the fire,
reading Hawthorne...
...cup of decent coffee.
I'm not going back.
Thomas, listen to me.
You're shot. You have to go back.
Robert, promise me...
...that you won't send me back.
Promise me.
All right.
Colonel Shaw!
- What is all this?
- You haven't heard?
Lee was turned back
in Pennsylvania at Gettysburg.
Now Grant's taken Vicksburg
and all on the Fourth of July.
- My God.
- Yeah.
I know. It looks like it'll all be over
by Christmas.
- So how did they do?
- Splendid. Just splendid.
- Any casualties?
- Forty-two.
Oh, give me the details. I'll wire it in.
I don't think we got
a prayer of making the paper.
I'll talk to you later in your tent.
As you were.
- Trip, isn't it?
- Yes, sir.
You fought very well yesterday,
Trip.
Sergeant Rawlins has recommended
that you receive a commendation.
Yes, sir.
Yes, and I think you should bear
the regimental colors.
Well-
It's considered quite an honor.
Why not?
Well, I'm...
Wanting to say something, sir,
but I...
Go ahead.
All right. See...
...I ain't fighting this war...
...for you, sir.
I see.
I mean, what's the point?
Ain't nobody gonna win.
It's gonna go on and on.
- It can't go on forever.
- But ain't nobody gonna win.
Somebody's gonna win.
Who?
I mean, you, you get to go on back
to Boston, big house and all that.
What about us?
What do we get?
Well, you won't get anything
if we lose.
What do you wanna do?
I don't know, sir.
It stinks, I suppose.
Yeah.
It stinks bad.
And we all covered up in it too.
I mean, ain't nobody clean.
Be nice to get clean though.
How do we do that?
We ante up and kick in, sir.
But I still don't wanna
carry your flag.
No one will ever take Charleston...
...without first silencing the forts
which protect its harbor.
And the first one that must
be taken is that: Fort Wagner.
Wagner mounts
a 10-inch Columbiad...
...three smoothbore 32-pounders...
...a 42-pound carronade...
...a 10-inch coast mortar...
...and four 12-pound howitzers...
...plus a garrison
of about a thousand men.
As many of you gentlemen
may be aware...
...for the last four days,
our Navy has weakened Wagner...
...with a constant barrage.
Headquarters has determined
a time for our attack.
We will proceed
with a direct frontal assault...
...tomorrow at dusk.
The problem, gentlemen,
is the approach.
The ocean and the marsh
leave only a narrow strip of sand.
A natural defile through which we can
only send one regiment at a time.
Our best hope is that that leading
regiment can keep the Rebs occupied...
...long enough for reinforcements
to exploit the breach.
Needless to say...
...casualties in the leading regiment
may be extreme.
General Strong.
The 54th Massachusetts...
...requests the honor of leading
the attack on Fort Wagner.
It's Colonel Shaw, isn't it?
Yes, sir.
You and your men
haven't slept for two days.
That's right, sir.
You think they have the strength
to lead this charge?
There's more to fighting
than rest, sir.
There's character.
There's strength of heart.
You should have seen us
in action two days ago.
We were a sight to see.
We'll be ready, sir.
When do you want us?
- Tomorrow, we go into battle.
- All right.
So, Lordy, let me fight
with the rifle in one hand...
...and the Good Book in the other.
- Amen, brother.
- Amen.
That if I should die
at the muzzle of the rifle...
...die on water or on land...
...I may know that you,
blessed Jesus Almighty, are with me.
- With Jesus. With us.
- That's right.
And I have no fear. Amen.
- Amen.
Lord...
...we stand before you
this evening...
- ... to say thank you.
- Thank the Lord.
We thank you, Father...
...for your grace
and your many blessings.
Yes, sir.
Now, I run off...
...and left all my young'uns
and my kinfolk in bondage.
So I'm standing here this evening,
Heavenly Father...
...to ask your blessings on all of us.
So that if tomorrow
is our great getting-up morning...
...if tomorrow we have to meet
the Judgment Day...
...oh, Heavenly Father,
we want you to let our folks know...
...that we died facing the enemy.
We want them to know
that we went down standing up-
Yes, Lord!
- among those that are fighting
against our oppression.
We want them to know,
Heavenly Father...
...that we died for freedom.
We ask these blessings
in Jesus' name. Amen.
- Amen.
Trip. Come on.
- No, I-
- You better get your butt up there, boy.
Just say what you think.
Just say what you feel. Go on now.
- Come on.
- Preach it, brother.
Go on, let it out.
I ain't much about
no praying now.
Well, you always say your piece.
I ain't never had no family and...
- Killed off my mama.
- Well...
This feels funny.
- Come on.
- It's all right.
Come on now. You're doing fine.
Well, I just-
You know, y'all's- Y'all's-
Y'all's the onliest family I got.
Well, that's all right.
And...
...I love the 54th.
All right.
Ain't much matter
what happens tomorrow...
...because we men, ain't we?
- Yes, sir.
- Amen.
- We men, ain't we?
- Yes, sir.
- Shit.
- All right, man.
- Attention, company!
Attention, company!
Battalion, halt!
We ready, colonel.
Left. Left. Left, right.
- Give them hell, 54th!
- Ready, fire!
- Ought to be quite a show, Pierce.
- Best seat in the house.
I wonder if you might
do something for me.
I have some letters here.
Personal things.
Certainly, colonel.
Also, if I should fall...
...remember what you see here.
- Ready!
- Fire!
- Reload!
You men are relieved.
Report to the rear
as stretcher bearers.
- Do it now!
- Right face!
Forward, march!
You go on, honey.
We be by directly.
Shaw!
If this man should fall...
...who will lift the flag and carry on?
I will.
Huzzah! Huzzah! Huzzah!
I'll see you in the fort, Thomas.
- Fix!
Bayonets!
- Shoulder!
Arms!
- Charge!
Bayonets!
- At the quickstep!
Forward!
March!
Double-quick time!
Steady, boys!
Charge!
Come on!
Forward!
Keep your ranks!
Take cover in the dunes!
Take cover!
Company commanders, we'll wait here
and advance under cover of darkness.
Men, get down over there!
Get down!
Company commanders,
order your men to wait here!
Get down!
- Sergeant Rawlins!
- Sir!
Pass the word along!
Forward on my command!
Ready on the colors, men!
Ready!
- Charge!
Forward, men! Forward!
Forward!
I've been hit!
Forward! Forward, men!
Come on, men, forward!
Come on, you men! Come on!
Don't stop! Get up there!
No!
Come on!
Come on, 54th!
Robert!
Come on!
Charge!
My eye!
Rally!
- Form a firing line right here!
- No!
Get out of here!
Fire!
Let's go! Move! Move!
Come on! Come on!