So what's in the video?
Come on, Yukiko!
You saw it, didn't you?
You can tell me!
What? No way!
I'm not watching it!
A well?
No, nothing.
Last night I had a strange dream.
There was a well in it.
A really old one...
The edge had crumbled away.
I looked inside, but...
..it was pitch black,
I couldn't see anything.
The house looked empty.
I went inside.
The place was a ruin.
There was a flight of stairs.
But something told me
I absolutely shouldn't go up.
I just stood there. I couldn't move.
30 Years Before
Ms Sudo...
There's a reporter to see you...
in there.
Thank you.
I'm Miyaji, from 'Chuo Nippo'.
You taught a Yamamura Sadako
1 1 years ago...
I'm afraid there's no picture of her.
Would you like to look?
She came into the school
after the year had started.
Then her mother died
and her father came for her.
They left the island.
- Dr lkuma Heihachiro?
- Yes.
Sadako was only here
until the middle of the second term.
What was she like?
A very intelligent girl.
Very pretty.
I went to see her relatives.
They wouldn't talk to me.
There was all that trouble
over her mother, Shizuko...
Her suicide and all...
Did Sadako have powers...
..Iike her mother did?
That I wouldn't know.
Only...
Sadako was...
..terribly afraid of the sea.
The sea?
All those children
in the picture drowned.
14 of them.
One swimming class,
they went to the beach.
Sadako was simply terrified.
"lf you go in the sea,
you'll all die!" she said.
No luck! No one knows
where Dr lkuma went!
Miyaji!
Sadako was the only one
who didn't swim.
She just sat all hunched up
on the beach, staring at the sea.
Then, from out in the bay,
the kids all staed screaming...
RING O 'BIRTHDAY'
"lf I could be reborn...
..even though it violate
the will of God himself...
..I would want to be at your side...
..with you."
If it were all a dream...
..when I awoke...
If only you were there...
But...
the morning light
shows me as I really am.
Stop!
Enough.
Take a break.
We'll break for lunch.
Everyone back in an hour.
Aiko's not herself lately.
Maybe if Mr Shigemori
wasn't so irritable...
- Where should we have lunch?
- I don't care.
You're no fun!
What?
What are you staring at?
Creep!
You know, before that girl came,
Aiko and Shigemori got along fine.
What do you mean?
Nothing...just the feeling I get.
Sadako, huh?
She works really hard
and she's so pretty...
..but she is a little strange.
So... are you getting used
to life in Tokyo?
Yes.
Last time I gave you
a fairly strong tranquilliser.
Are you still seeing strange things?
No.
I'm sure it's just nerves.
It's a psychogenic disorder.
I feel more relaxed
now I've joined the drama troupe.
You do?
Certainly performing
has therapeutic value.
Do you like the troupe?
Yes.
Amazing!
So drama is the best medicine...
Sadako...
Don't be too enthusiastic.
People won't like it.
OK.
Come in!
Excuse me!
- Your costume is done.
- Hang it up!
Aiko, you're looking
a little pale. Are you all right?
- Since that girl came...
- Who?
Oh, Sadako...
I keep seeing something behind her.
Here we go again!
And a well, too.
A well?
I keep having these bad dreams.
I go into a house by the well
and there are stairs leading up...
..but I'm too terrified to go up
them.
What?
I've had the same dream.
She was found in the river
this morning.
She fits the description
of the missing girl...
A scar on her face?
Doctor!
Is it her?
- Anna!
- Don't look!
She would hate you...
..to see that ugly scar.
I don't care how she looks!
If only I'd gone to see her...
..in the hospital!
Don't blame yourself.
There's no mistake.
That is my daughter.
I'm sorty.
It may all be for the best.
She might just as well
have been dead,
before this unfortunate accident.
Doctor!
Have you seen my daughter?
She left your hospital four days ago!
Once a patient sets foot
outside my hospital...
..she is my patient no longer.
Where your daughter may be
...I have no idea.
But that corpse in the river!
- Was it her?
- Unfortunately...
..it's my daughter who's dead.
What?
I am the one in need of sympathy.
I must prepare for her funeral.
If you would excuse me...
I would like to spend today
alone with my daughter.
Right! OK.
On to scene 2.
We'll take a short break.
Aiko?
I understand you studied
under Dr lkuma Heihachiro.
That's correct.
But his ESP research
was too much, even for me.
In the end he retracted
his own theories.
- And you agree with that?
- Of course.
I'd like you to listen to something.
There was the experiment
that drove him out of the profession.
Do you remember?
Yes.
And that a man died?
There was no connection.
This is a tape of that day.
Correct!
Fraud!
It's nothing but a vulgar magic show!
I won't be fooled!
Dr Ikuma! You're being deceived!
Yes, that's right!
What's wrong?
She's a freak!
That noise appeared
only on this tape.
Can you explain that?
No.
More than one man has died.
In the last 1 2 years...
..everyone who was there has died.
The reporters
at that demonstration...
not one is alive today.
Do you have any idea
where Dr lkuma might be?
No.
Or his daughter Sadako?
I don't know.
So we don't even know yet
when the funeral will be.
Do we open or not?!
Wait! Wait a minute! Listen!
Losing Aiko is a heavy blow.
But we must carty on with the play.
She would have wanted that.
Now, I want you all to listen
carefully.
I've decided on an actress
who will take the part.
Yamamura Sadako, our student.
That's all.
Mr Shigemori!
Why Sadako?
Ignore them.
OK!
Places!
Hello?
Who is this?
Why do you never speak?
- Andrei...
- Anna? Is that you?
Anna!
Do you know what will happen?!
Was that Andrei?
You died in that accident.
And soon you will be reborn!
Reborn?
Yes!
If...
..I could be reborn...
..even though it violate
the will of God himself...
..I would want to be at your side...
..with you.
If it were all a dream...
..when I awoke...
If only you were there...
But...
But the morning light
shows me...
..as I really am.
Still I want to say it...
I love you.
Goodnight.
Sadako!
It'll be great.
Thanks.
Mr Toyama...
Don't look!
No!
It wasn't me!
Sadako!
- What did you see?
- Toyama...
- Yes?
- We don't have much time.
- Are you all ready?
- No.
So you're going to be working
all night...
About your cue here...
When the light comes on,
wait two beats.
Raise the tempo,
but don't lose the tension.
Here.
- Listen to this.
- What?
- Hear that?
- What is it?
This tape was running when Aiko died.
That noise wasn't there before.
So it was added later?
Was that someone saying
"I'm being killed"?
Rain, huh?
Your mother?
She's dead?
Go away.
I'll make you a star.
I can do that, you know.
- It's late. Why not stay the night?
- Yes, that would be best.
I can't. Tonight I'm meeting
a friend...
- Still here?
- Waiting for Toyama?
I've got to alter Sadako's dress.
Let her do that.
She's just a student!
That's not an actor's job.
By the way, Sadako and
Toyama have been acting funny.
I'd watch out.
- See you.
- Goodnight.
- Did you see Sadako here?
- No.
Something's strange...
Sadako?
So, you took the dress!
What for?
Me?
- Don't play the innocent!
- Hey!
It's like Kaoru said!
Since she came...
Stop it!
I'm sorty.
Sometimes I do things,
and I don't remember them.
Last night Mr Shigemori came
to my apartment...
..and I don't remember.
Sadako, won't you tell me
what it is that scares you?
There's someone here with me.
Even now?
It's not someone...
..that I don't know.
It's like a long, long time ago...
But I only remember fragments...
..from when I was a child...
..and there's something there
that terrifies me.
Mother...Mother...
Who is my father?
You were dreaming.
You fainted. Do you remember?
There's only coffee.
Sadako...
..there's no one here, is there?
What?
Sadako!
CV - Sadako Yamamura
Dr Kuno, please.
Dr Kuno, someone to see you.
I'm Tachihara Etsuko.
I'm in Yamamura Sadako's troupe.
She gave your name for a reference.
I'm sorty, I'm very busy.
Doctor!
Someone in our troupe is dead.
Right out of the blue.
Strange things have been happening
since she came.
Is there something unusual
about Sadako?
I'm afraid
I'm not in a position to say.
The Mask by Isamu Shigemori
Starring Sadako Yamamura
Toyama...
..keep away from Sadako. Please!
I met a doctor who knows her.
She's hiding something!
Not from me.
Oh?
Mr Shigemori's gone all strange.
You've noticed it, haven't you?
Everyone says
it's because of Sadako.
And it's not just him!
They say Aiko's death...
was her fault, too!
Everyone says so.
She's not normal!
Places, everyone.
Get out, will you?
That's Mr Shigemori.
- Please...
- Thank you.
I'm from 'Chuo Nippo'.
My name is Miyaji.
I realise you open tomorrow.
Thank you for giving us your time.
Not at all.
I understand you've chosen
a new actress...
..for the lead role.
Yes.
That's her.
"lf I could be reborn even though it
violate the will of God himself..."
May I talk to her?
Certainly.
Sadako!
Miss Sadako Yamamura?
May we have a word?
Miyaji...
That's her.
Find out where we can reach her.
Miyaji! There's someone here
from Oshima lsland. Over there.
What brings you all this way?
There was something
I just couldn't bring myself to say
when we last met.
I've never told this to anyone.
It's about the Yamamuras.
I called on them once
after Sadako started at our school.
By then, her mother,
Shizuko, had gone strange...
Suddenly there was
no-one else around.
I heard...
..a crawling sound
coming from upstairs...
After that...
I was always
afraid of the child, too.
I'd think crazy things...
..Iike which of the Sadakos...
..was at school today...
Well?
See for yourself.
The whole troupe is cursed.
And the photo of me?
There are other people
in the picture.
Those who died at the
demonstration...
Your fiancee.
Dr lkuma claimed that intentions
could become living things...
..that human thought
could change to energy.
But is that all it is?
Maybe it's another force
that summons Sadako.
Another one...
Anyway, this is one article
you won't be able to write.
This was never for an article.
Thanks for everything.
Don't you like
having your picture taken?
I've finally remembered...
who your mother was.
I remember the stoty.
She killed a man,
during a kind of experiment.
She didn't!
Aiko's death was no accident.
You'll do anything to be a star,
won't you.
Wait a minute!
Was it you who killed that reporter?
Just the woman I've been looking for!
You're perfect for an actress!
Sadako, do you intend to kill me?
You like Toyama that much?
If I die, I'll take you with me.
I'll tell everyone about you.
They won't let you live.
You're mine.
Is that you?
No!
It's not me!
Mr Shigemori!
You bastard!
Toyama!
- You won't kill me!
- Mr Shigemori!
Toyama, don't!
Please! Keep away from me!
You're hurt!
Hold on, Toyama!
Let me see it!
The wound's closed up!
A deep cut like that!
The things left behind
Is that Etsuko?
This is Miyaji,
the reporter from earlier today.
I need your help.
They'll find Mr Shigemori
in the morning...
I'll confess.
No!
I won't let them torment you.
Stop it!
It's the only way.
Your hand's hot.
It has been for a while.
Here we go.
It's time for TV.
Aren't you cold?
I'll get you a glass of water.
You wait here.
We're not finished yet.
Go backstage.
Sadako! Go to the dressing room!
Quick!
- Where's Shigemori?
- He's not at home either.
- What do we do?
- We can't cancel. We'll go on.
Toyama...
When this is over,
let's go away somewhere.
Don't worty.
You'll be great.
You're beautiful.
We're about to open the doors!
Please get ready!
It's all right.
The girl touched him,
and suddenly he stood up!
- Watch him.
- Doctor!
- How much?
- 800 yen.
Your change.
Doctor!
Is it her?
- Anna!
- Don't look!
She would hate you...
to see that ugly scar.
I don't care how she looks!
If only I'd gone to see her
in the hospital!
Don't blame yourself.
There's no mistake.
That is my daughter.
I'm sorty.
It may all be for the best.
She might just as well have been dead
before this unfortunate accident.
Doctor!
Could you come here a minute?
Mr Shigemori's dead!
Sadako! She did this!
Don't let her get away!
Toyama... Yuki wants you.
There's a problem.
I know the cues. I'll take over.
OK.
Correct!
Toyama! What are you doing?!
Hey, Toyama!
Correct!
- What's wrong?
- I don't know!
Correct!
Etsuko, what did you do?
Don't you want to know
Everything about Sadako?
Who's that in the kimono?
Fraud!
It's nothing but...
a vulgar magic show!
- You can't fool me!
- Dr Ikuma!
You're being deceived!
Mother!
What's wrong?
She's a freak!
That sound...
It's the same as when Aiko died!
Sadako... Stop.
You have to stop.
You have a wonderful gift!
Settle down...
You must be calm.
Sadako!
Calm down!
Another one...
- Stop her!
- Don't let that monster get away!
Don't let her go!
Stop!
- Toyama!
- Sadako!
No!
- No!
- Sadako!
We won't do anything.
- We won't hurt you.
- Please! Stop it!
No! It's not me!
Sadako!
Stop it! Stop!
I was here to kill her!
But it's not over.
You've all had the dream
about the well, haven't you?
There's another Sadako.
If we don't kill her,
we'll all die under the curse.
Ikuma Heihachiro
Dr lkuma raised Sadako.
He must be hiding her alter ego
somewhere else.
But where?
Probably not far from him.
Kaoru, watch Etsuko and Toyama.
Are you here to kill Sadako?
There was only one at first.
But at some point she split...
..into two.
One took after her mother.
The other one was probably
like her real father.
It drove her mother mad.
All I could do was use drugs
to stop the other one from growing.
Sadako!
Don't tell me
you brought Sadako here!
Please! Let them go!
Sadako's getting away!
She got away!
We have to get out of here!
Let me go!
Over there! That way!
No! Please! Stop!
Come on!
Are the people chasing us?
You go, Toyama.
No. We'll go together!
Quickly! Get away from me.
What are you saying?
Over here! This way!
I...
..want you to...
Get away!
Run!
Sadako! Not that way!
What are you going to do?
Stay back!
I can't...
..do any more.
Sadako, I love you.
Run! Kaoru!
Etsuko!
Miss Miyaji!
What are you doing? Run!
Sadako! Stop this! Sadako!
Get up!
Calm down!
Sadako!
Sadako...
Come on.
Let's go home. OK?
This will calm you.
- Father...
- What?
Who's my real father?
What a silly thing to ask!
I am, of course.
Of course.
Father!
Sadako...
..Iet's end this now.
I'll follow after you.
Father!
I can't breathe!
Help me!
Sadako!
No... No!
Forgive me, Sadako!
Forgive me!
Father, no! Don't!
Sadako!
Forgive me, Sadako!
Forgive me!
Sadako...
You were dreaming.
Toyama...
Toyama?
Toyama!
Directed by Norio Tsuruta
RING 0 'BIRTHDAY'
Based on the novel by
Koji Suzuki
Screenplay by
Hiroshi Takahashi
Starring
Yukie Nakama
Seiichi Tanabe
Kumiko Aso
Yoshiko Tanaka
Directed by
Norio Tsuruta