60 knots? No way, Barnes.
The Reds don't have anything that fast.
Checked it twice. I mean,
it's a real unique signature.
No cavitation. No reactor noise.
It doesn't even sound like screws.
What the hell is it?
I'll tell you what it's not.
It's not one of ours.
Sir, contact changing to heading
214.
Speed,
80 knots.
Still diving. Depth 900 feet.
Port clearance 150 feet from the cliff wall, sir.
It's getting tight in here.
We can still give him a haircut.
Helm, come right to... 069.
Down five degrees.
Coming right 069. Down five degrees. Aye.
Port side clearance 120 feet. Narrowing 75.
Sir, we have a proximity warning light.
It's too damn close! We gotta back off.
Sir, range to contact 200.
Contact justjinked to bearing 260
and accelerated to...
to 130 knots, sir.
Nothin' goes 130.
Sir, range to contact 100 yards.
80 yards, sir!
60!
It's turbulence! We're in its wake!
Helm, all stop! Full right rudder.
Hydraulic failure. Planes not responding, sir.
Auxiliary power. Monitors back.
Hydraulics restored, sir.
Oh, my God!
Fire in sonar!
Collision alarm!
Fire control to sonar!
Let's get outta here!
- Lighten her up, Charlie!
- Port torpedo room is flooded, sir!
Blow all tanks!
Blow all the tanks! Blow everything!
All back full!
Answering, all back full!
Give me a damage report! What's our depth?
Passing 1400, sir.
Main forward tanks are ruptured!
Still descending, sir!
1450.
Passing 1500, sir.
Still descending.
- We're too deep to pump auxiliaries.
- Passing 1550. Still descending.
- We're losin' her!
- Passing 1600, sir,
- and still descending!
- Launch the buoy.
Passing 1650.
- Passing 1700, sir.
- Launching!
Come on! Give me your hand!
Get the door closed!
Benthic Explorer, Salvor One on final. Over.
Copy you, Salvor One.
This is Benthic Explorer.
You're cleared to land.
Hey! They're coming.
This... could get pretty ugly.
Yeah.
Does not look good at all.
Oh, no. Look who's with them.
The queen bitch of the universe.
Sonny, how you doin'?
I've got two more welds on this bypass valve.
No light from the surface.
- How deep are they?
- McBride?
1700 feet.
- I need them to go below 2,000.
- No problem. They can do that.
So that's it? You just cheerfully turn
the whole thing over to the goon squad?
Look, I was told to cooperate.
I'm cooperating.
Kirkhill, you're pathetic.
Get Brigman on the line.
Deepcore, this is Benthic.
Man, if Bud goes along with this,
they're gonna have to shoot her
with a tranquilliser gun.
- Roger.
- Hippy, get me Bud.
Catfish, get them old bones up here
and give me a hand.
Hang on. I'll be up there in a second.
Hey, you guys are milkin' that job.
Yeah, it's just because we love freezing
our butts off out here for you so much.
Bring me another hammer!
- Hey, Bud!
- Yeah!
Hippy's on the bitch box!
It's a call from topside.
That new company man.
- Kirkhill?
- Yeah.
That guy don't know his butt from a rathole.
Perry, square away this mud hose
and get rid of some of these empty sacks.
- It's starting to look like my apartment.
- You got it, boss!
- Bud, pick up the topside line. Urgent.
- I'm coming!
I'm coming! Jesus! Keep your pantyhose on!
Brigman here.
Yeah, Kirkhill. What's goin' on?
Yeah, I'm calm.
I'm a calm person. Is there some reason
why I shouldn't be calm?
What?
I am on last feed now.
Can you get that goddamn hippy shit music
off the comm line, please?
I'm almost done with the shut-off valve.
Sonny, I'm right behind you
with the next fitting.
Hang on a second.
- OK, give it to me.
- Here you go.
Thanks, sweetie.
All divers, drop what you're doin'.
Everybody out of the pool.
I mean everybody right now.
Sonny, One Night, let's go.
Damn it. We just got out here.
There was a time when I woulda asked why.
- Get a move on!
- Shit, woman!
Deepcore, Deepcore.
This is Flatbed preparing to surface.
Roger, Flatbed. Come on up.
All rig personnel assemble at the moon pool.
Everybody get to sub-bay. ASAP.
Come on. Let's get his hat off.
- Take it off.
- What the hell's goin' on?
- How come we got recalled?
- The hell if I know.
I got it.
- What's the drift, pardner? Why are we up?
- Just follow standard procedure.
Flog your dog till somebody
tells you what's happenin'.
- What's the story, boss?
- Folks, listen up!
We just been told to shut down the hole
and prepare to move the rig.
- Oh, shit!
- What?
We've received an invitation to, um,
cooperate in a matter of national security.
Now you know as much as I do.
Get your gear off and get to control.
We've got a briefing in ten minutes.
Come on! Let's move it!
At 0922 local time today
an American nuclear submarine,
the USS Montana,
with 156 men aboard, went down
- about 22 miles from here.
- Damn!
There's been no contact with the sub since
then. The cause of the incident is not known.
Your company has authorised
the navy's use of this facility
for a rescue operation
code-named Operation Salvor.
- You want us to search for the sub?
- No. We know where it is.
But she's in 2,000 feet of water
and we can't reach her.
We need divers to enter the sub
and search for survivors... if any.
Don't you have your own stuff for this?
By the time we get our submersibles here,
the storm'll be on us.
You can get your rig in and be on site
in 15 hours. That makes you our best option.
Why should we risk our butts
for something like this?
I have been authorised
to offer you all special bonuses
equivalent to three times normal dive pay.
Yes, sir, buddy!
For triple time, I'd eat Beany!
Set me on fire
and put me out with horse piss.
I don't know what kind of deal
you made with the company,
but my people are not qualified for this.
We're oil workers.
Shut up! Hold it down.
This is Lieutenant Coffey.
He will transfer down to you with
a SEAL team and supervise the operation.
Send down whoever you like,
but I'm the tool pusher on this rig.
When it comes to the safety of these people,
there's me and then God.
Understand? If things get dicey,
I'm pulling the plug.
I think we're all
on the same wavelength, Brigman.
Now, let's get the wellhead uncoupled,
shall we?
Let's take it about five degrees left, all right?
Roger. Five degrees left, Bud.
Plot these numbers to our position.
I need to know when the leading edge will hit.
Well, it's official.
They're calling it Hurricane Frederick.
And it's gonna be making our lives
- real interesting in a few hours.
- Fred?
I don't know, man. I think hurricanes
should be named after women, don't you?
- I can't believe you're letting them do this.
- Hi, Lins!
I thought you were in Houston.
I was. Now I'm here.
- Only here isn't where I left it, is it, Bud?
- Wasn't up to me.
We were that close to proving
a submersible drilling platform could work.
- I can't believe you let them grab my rig!
- Your rig?
- I designed the damn thing.
- Benthic Petroleum paid for it.
So as long as they're holding the pink slip,
I go where they tell me.
I had a lot riding on this. They bought you,
didn't they? More like rented you cheap!
I'm switchin' off now.
Bye-bye.
Oh, OK. Virgil, you wiener!
You never could stand up to a fight!
Bye-bye.
Virgil?
God, I hate that bitch!
Probably shouldn't have married her,
then, huh?
Get it stable!
Cab 3. You're clear to launch.
Hang on, gentlemen.
Touchdown! Crowd goes wild!
Explorer, this is Cab 3. We are styling.
- How you boys doin' back there?
- Great.
Explorer, this is Cab 3.
Starting our descent along the umbilical.
- Roger that, Cab 3. Good luck.
- Luck is not a factor.
- Hey, One Night. How you doin'?
- I got a white line fever, baby.
Yeah, I heard that.
Deepcore, Deepcore.
- This is Cab 3 on final approach.
- Roger, Cab 3. Is that you, Lindsey?
None other.
Oh, no!
Howdy, boys!
Hey, Lindsey!
I'll be damned!
Y'all shouldn't be down here, sweet thing.
You might ruin your stockings.
The bad news is we got eight hours
in this can blowin' down.
And the worse news is
it's gonna take us three weeks
- to decompress later.
- We've all been fully briefed, Mrs Brigman.
Just don't call me that, OK? I hate that.
All right. What would you like us to call you?
Sir?
There we go!
Y'all start equalisin'... now!
Let's watch each other closely
for signs of HPNS.
High pressure nervous syndrome.
Muscle tremors, usually in the hands first.
- Nausea, excitability...
- Disorientation.
And a partridge in a pear tree.
About one person in 20 can't handle it.
They just go buggo.
Look, they've all made runs to this depth.
- They checked out.
- I understand that.
What I'm saying is it's impossible to predict
- just who's susceptible.
- They checked out.
- These guys the SEALs?
- Yeah.
Those guys ain't so tough.
I've fought guys plenty tougher than them.
Now we get to hear
how you could have been a contender?
Hey!
- You see this?
- Yeah.
They used to call this the hammer.
Y'all done to a turn and ready to serve.
Everybody OK?
- They're really very sweet.
- Yeah.
Hey! I don't remember putting a wall here.
How you doin', Jammer?
- Pretty good. How are you, little lady?
- I'm OK.
I want a full check on their gear.
These guys are about as much fun
as a tax audit.
Hippy, you're gonna give that rat a disease.
Hi, Lins!
Well, well. Mrs Brigman.
Not for long.
You never did like being called that, did you?
Not even when it meant something.
- Is that One Night in Flatbed?
- Yeah. Who else? Here. Say hi.
- Hey, One Night. It's Lindsey.
- Oh, hi, Lindsey.
Obstacle-avoidance is showin'a rise
out about 100m. What do you wanna do?
I can't believe
you were dumb enough to come down here.
Now you're stuck here for the storm.
- That was dumb, hot rod. Real dumb.
- I didn't come down here to fight with you.
Yeah, well...
Then why did you come down?
You need me. Nobody knows
the systems on this rig better than I do.
Once you're disconnected, you guys are on
your own for however long this storm lasts.
What if something was to happen
after the surface support clears off?
Wow, you're right. Us poor dumb old boys
might've had to think for ourselves.
It could've been a disaster.
- You wanna know what I think?
- Jesus! Look where this thing is set.
- Not particularly.
- I think you were worried about me.
- Then that must be it.
No, seriously. I think you were.
Come on. It's OK.
It's OK. You can admit it.
I was worried... about the rig.
I've got over four years
invested in this project.
Yeah. You only had three years
invested in me.
Well, you have to have priorities.
It's kinda messy, but I guarantee you
it's the only bunk that won't be occupied.
You can get a couple of hours' rest
before we get there.
What are you still wearing that for?
I don't know.
Divorce ain't final.
Forgot to take it off.
I haven't worn mine in months.
Yeah.
Well, whatshisname wouldn't like it.
The suit.
Do you always have to call him that?
The suit. Makes you sound like such a hick.
His name is Michael.
How is Michael, then? Mr Brooks Brothers.
Mr BMW.
You still seeing him?
No.
No, I haven't seen him in a few weeks.
Terribly sorry. What happened?
Why are you doing this?
This is none of your business!
It's not a part of your life any more.
I'll tell you what happened.
You woke up one morning
in those satin sheets,
rolled over,
and there was this good-looking guy.
Well-groomed, expensive watch on.
And you realised
"This guy never makes me laugh."
That's it, Bud. That's it!
Aren't you clever? Jesus! You're clever!
You should start your own talk show!
Ask Dr Bud.
Advice to the lovelorn from 300 fathoms.
Thank you. Thank you.
Oh, shit!
- Cuttin'you loose, Bud.
- OK, One Night. Stay clear.
We're setting her down.
Touchdown!
This is us, sitting right on the edge
of the Cayman Trough.
This is the Montana.
300m away, 70m below us.
We think she slid down the wall
and now sits here on this outcropping.
So we're gonna have to drop
straight down... here and...
This tell us how much radiation we're gettin'?
Whoa! I'm not going near
no radiation! No way!
- Hippy, you pussy.
- What good is the money,
six months later your dick drops off?
We'll take readings as we go.
If the reactor's breached,
the warheads have released
any radioactive debris, we'll just back off.
- It's that simple.
- OK.
OK. Hippy's not going,
so, McWhirter, you can run Little Geek.
Goddamn it! You know
McWhirter can't run an ROV worth shit!
Then you'd better go.
I'll go.
What is your problem? On this dive
you'll do absolutely nothing
without direct orders from me.
And you'll follow those orders
without discussion. Is that clear?
I want everyone
ready to get wet in 15 minutes.
- Gimme a hand loading Little Geek.
- Let's get suited up.
Hey, guys! Hold it a second.
Hold it!
Whoa!
Look...
...it's 3am. These guys are running on
bad coffee and about four hours of sleep.
Maybe you could cut them some slack.
- I can't afford slack.
- You come on my rig, you don't talk to me,
and you start ordering my people around.
It's not gonna work.
You gotta know how to handle these people.
We got a certain way of doing things here.
I'm not interested in your way of doing
things. Just get your team ready to dive.
These guys have got no sense of humour.
Bud, do you know your hand is blue?
Finler, why don't you just shut up
and put your gear on?
Keep it coming.
Hippy, throw me
one of them cyalumes, please.
- Good.
- Excuse me.
- What is all this stuff?
- Fluid breathing system. We just got them.
- You use it when you go really deep.
- How deep?
- Deep.
It's classified.
You breathe liquid
so you can't get compressed.
- The pressure doesn't get you.
- You mean you got liquid in your lungs?
Oxygenated, fluorocarbon
- emulsion.
- Bullshit!
Check this out.
- Can I borrow your rat?
- What are you doin'?
- It's gonna be fine.
- No, man. She's gonna drown!
He's gonna be fine.
I've breathed this myself.
Getting plenty of oxygen.
Damn rat's breathing that shit.
He's taking the fluid into his lungs.
She's doin' it. She ain't diggin' it.
All right, let her out now!
OK. Now we let the fluid drain from his lungs.
All right. Give her here. Give her here.
Here's your rat.
- See? He's fine!
- It's a she.
Going over the wall.
Coming to bearing 065.
Flatbed, you on line?
Ten-four, Lindsey.
We read you loud and clear.
Starting our descent. Divers, how you doin'?
Everybody's OK so far.
Hang on, boys. It's all downhill from here.
- Hey, how deep's the drop-off here?
- This here's the bottomless pit, baby.
Two and a half miles straight down.
Cab 3, it's Bud. You on line?
Cab 3 check.
I'm right behind you.
Cab 1, do you see it yet?
Magnetometer's twitching,
but I don't see anything yet.
Hang on. I'm gonna test my strobes.
Cab 1, do you have a visual?
- Cab 1, do you copy?
- Yeah.
Roger that. Found it.
Cab 1, radiation readings?
Neutron counter's not showing much.
All right.
Just continue forward along the hull.
Copy that. Continuing forward.
You want me to get shots of everything, yes?
Roger that. Document as much as you can.
But, please, keep moving.
Remember, we're on a tight time line.
Copy that.
Coming up to the midships hatch.
Do you see it, Cab 3?
Yeah, roger. I got it.
- How do you want me?
- Just hold above it.
- Roger. Holding.
- OK. It's all yours, Lieutenant.
- All right, A Team.
- Let's do it.
OK. Perry, Hippy.
- Let's get that ROVlaunched.
- OK. We're on it, boss.
Go!
Little Geek is on the case.
Monk here, sir.
We got the midships outer hatch open.
Entering escape trunk.
Inner hatch looks intact.
It's flooded. All right. I'm gonna open her up.
OK. Get in there.
- Roger. Somebody get on that tether.
- Got it.
Sorry about this, little buddy, but better
you than me. You know what I mean?
Coffey, these are the missile hatches, right?
That's right. It looks like
a couple of the hatches have sprung.
Radiation's nominal.
Warheads must still be intact.
How many are there?
24 Trident missiles. Eight MIRVs per missile.
That's 192 warheads, Coffey.
How powerful are they?
Your MIRVis a tactical nuke.
50 kilotons nominal yield.
Say... five times Hiroshima.
Jesus Christ!
It's World War III in a can.
Let's knock off the chatter.
OK. I'm headin' into the reactor compartment.
- Getting a reading?
- It's twitching.
But it's below the line you said was safe.
All right. Let's get in there.
Flatbed, drop down starboard
of the sail and stay along the cliff edge.
OK. Copy that.
Keep heading for the bow.
OK, Flatbed. This looks good.
Just set it down here.
- We're solid.
- Let's go.
All right. Let's go.
OK. Let's just take it slow and easy goin'in.
Don't take any chances.
Where are we, Coffey?
This is the forward berthing compartment.
This way.
- You guys OK? Cat? Jammer?
- Right behind you, Bud.
Check your gauges.
How's your O2?
- I'm OK.
- Yeah, gauges are good.
OK.
16 minutes to go.
Jammer here. CO2 is up.
- Breathe slower, buddy.
- OK.
Come on. Let's keep up.
All right. Up this way to the control centre.
It's jammed! Gimme a hand!
Get up here with that pry bar.
It's moving. Pull!
Jesus!
All right! We knew we were gonna see this.
Just move on.
- Jesus!
- Come on, Jammer. Let's go.
OK. Let's stay cool.
Everybody stay cool.
We can't help these guys,
but we might find somebody further in.
Stay here.
Hey, Jammer. You OK?
- How you guys doin'?
- I'm dealin'.
Triple time sounded like
a lot of money, Bud. It ain't.
We're here. Let's get it done, OK?
Brigman, take your men and continue aft.
Split up into two teams.
Come on. Let's get moving.
We head back in 14 minutes.
Let's go.
You OK, Jammer?
Yeah, I'm fine.
- What's this?
- Should be the missile launch control centre.
- Don't touch anything.
- No.
This way.
I'm right behind you.
- Still with me, Jammer?
- Where are we?
Missile compartment.
Those are the launch tubes.
Shit!
Hey, Jammer.
Hey!
Hey! You OK?
Deep and slow, big guy.
- Deep and slow. Just breathe easy.
- Everybody's dead!
- They're all dead!
- OK. I'm taking you back out. Let's go.
I'm OK.
I just can't go any further in.
OK, Jammer. No problem.
You stay right here.
I've gotta check out this compartment,
all right?
We'll stay in voice contact.
You hold onto the end of this rope here.
You have any problem whatsoever,
you tug twice.
- I got it.
- Pull it hard. Five more minutes.
Just relax, all right? You'll be OK.
- It's OK.
- Be right back.
You still readin'me OK, big guy?
Read you fine, Bud.
OK. Just a few more minutes.
There's a couple of compartments up ahead
that might have air.
- OK. No problem.
- We gotta be sure, right?
Hang on, Jammer. Just hold onto that...
Shit!
Bud? Can you hear me?
Bud?
Goddamn it!
Oh, Jesus!
Bud, is that you?
Hang on, Jammer.
Lew! Cat! Hurry up, on the double!
I'm on my way!
Jammer!
- What's the problem?
- He's convulsing!
It's his mixture! Too much oxygen!
Gotta get the O2 cut down! Turn him over!
Crank it down, man! You're losing him!
All right. We've gotta get him outta here!
Let's go. Let's move it.
Easy, big fella.
That's it.
One Night, do you see the divers?
- Are they out yet?
- Negative, Lindsey.
Haven't seen hide nor hair.
Let's give 'em two minutes more max
and then I'll sound the diver recall...
Lindsey, do you copy?
Meet me at Flatbed!
This is a diver emergency!
- Lins, do you copy!
- Yeah, copy you, Bud. I'm on my way.
Look, I'm just a medic.
Which is mostly about patching holes.
This type of thing, it's...
There's not much I can do.
The coma could last hours or days.
So you didn't get anything on the cameras?
No, I didn't get a picture of it.
- What about the video?
- No.
We lost power right then.
Look, I just don't wanna talk about this, OK?
Fine. Be that way.
Look, I don't know what I saw, Bud, OK?
Coffey wants to call it
a Russian submersible-fine.
It's a Russian submersible. No problem.
Yeah, but you think it was something else.
What?
One of ours?
No.
Well, whose then?
Come on, Lindsey. Talk to me.
Look, Jammer saw something down there.
- Something that scared the hell out of him.
- His mixture got screwed up.
Jammer panicked. He pranged his regulator
and his mixture got screwed up.
But what did he see that made him panic?
Well, what do you think he saw?
I don't know.
- Did any of you see it?
- No, sir. The Brigman woman saw it.
Could have been a Russian bogey.
CINCLANTFLT's gonna go apeshit.
Two Russian attack subs, a Tango and a
Victor, were tracked to within 50 miles of here.
And now they don't know
where the hell they are. OK.
I don't have any choice.
I'm confirming you to go to Phase Two.
You'll recover one warhead, arm it,
and wait for further instructions.
- Have we got a problem with that?
- Negative, sir.
Come on!
- What'd he say?
- Turn it up, bozo!
...early reports that the Montana encountered
a Soviet fast attack sub prior to its sinking
and the Kremlin
continues to deny any involvement.
That's us! That's us, man!
Benthic Petroleum are participating
in the recovery operation,
but we have little information.
We want names!
Hey, that's the Explorer! We're famous!
There is a tremendous amount of activity.
With Cuba only 80 miles away,
the massive build-up of American forces
has drawn official protest
from Havana and Moscow.
Russian and Cuban trawlers,
undoubtedly surveillance vessels,
have been circling the area
- and Soviet aircraft have been warned away.
- This sucks!
- Hippy, what's the matter with you?
- What's the matter with me? Nothing!
We're in the middle
of some international incident
- like the Cuban Missile Crisis!
- Figured that out for yourself, Hip?
We got Russian subs creeping around.
Anything goes wrong,
they could say whatever they want happened.
Relax, will you?
You're making the women nervous.
- Cute, Virgil.
- You know,
those SEALs ain't tellin' us diddly.
Something is goin' on!
- Come on, come on.
- Hippy, you think everything's a conspiracy.
Everything is.
Coffey's splitting with Flatbed!
I showed him how to work the controls
and they're outta here!
- Didn't you tell him we need it?
- Yeah!
- Where the hell is he takin' it?
- I have no idea!
Shit!
Coffey! Come back! We need
the big arm to unhook the umbilical.
There's a goddamn hurricane coming!
- He switched off.
- It's unbelievable.
Go back down and tell those men
to get below and stay there!
We need to get unhooked
and get out of here now!
- All right. Do it, then.
- No problem, except your boys
went sightseeing with Flatbed. My people
need Flatbed to get unhooked at their end.
- Back in two hours.
- Two hours?!
We're gonna get the shit kicked out of us
by our pal Fred in two hours!
OK. Set cold tab fitting to 200psi.
- Set.
- There she goes.
- She's breakin'loose.
- Bringin'her up.
OK.
All right.
Clear the hatch.
Go on with it.
Go on. That's it. Up.
Sir, the missile looks intact.
Little is known about the events
leading up to the collision.
The US Navy guided missile cruiser Appleton
apparently struck the Soviet Udaloy class
destroyer in low visibility conditions.
In violent seas, little hope remains
for over 100 Russian crewmen,
still missing after the sinking an hour ago.
Soviet military spokesmen
have claimed that the collision
constituted an unprovoked attack.
- This was denied by...
- Bud, this is big time.
...who said that Captain Michael Sweeney...
- OK. It's clear.
- It's all yours, sir.
I'm gonna swing it away and drop it.
Check. OK.
Bypass the ground connection
on the separation sequencer.
- Got it?
- Separation sequencer disconnected.
Remove explosive bolts one through six
- in counterclockwise sequence.
- Check. Removing bolt one.
Negotiators have walked out
of the Strategic Arms Limitation Talks
in protest over the incident this morning.
The deterioration of relations
with the United States...
Soviet build-up of tanks
and aircraft has continued.
...this morning, all US and NATO military
forces have been put on full alert.
It's on every channel.
Well, you just feel so helpless.
You can see it coming, but what can you do?
What can anyone do?
Hey, I mean, they love their kids too.
So why are we doing this?
If it happens, it happens.
There's nothing I can do about it, right?
I just don't think about it.
All right! Let's get their gear off! Then
clear the sub! We gotta get it outta here!
Come on, let's go! Let's move it!
One Night, you're up!
Get ready to roll, baby!
- Don't touch that! Just back away.
- Excusez-moi!
Hey, Coffey. We're a little pressed for time.
Prick.
This ain't no drill, Slick. Make me proud.
Piece of cake, baby.
What's the problem, One Night?
All hell must be breaking loose up there.
This cable's pissin'me off!
- I can't get a grip on it.
- Well, keep tryin', baby. Just keep tryin'.
Son of a bitch!
Shit! We got a problem!
- What's going on?
- We're losing number two thruster!
Bearing's going!
It's not holding!
We're swinging out of position here!
Jesus!
Shit!
The rig is movin'!
Yeah, I can see that. Topside!
Pay out some slack! We're gettin' dragged!
Down on number one winch! Down on one!
We're headed for the drop-off!
What the hell...?
We just lost all the topside feeds!
Shit! Get 'em on the UQC.
- Any damage on the hull?
- Bud!
- We lost the crane!
- Say again. What?
The crane! We've lost the crane!
It's on its way down to you!
All right, everybody!
Everybody rig for impact!
Close all the exterior hatches!
Let's move it! Let's go! Go!
- Wait!
- Get in here!
- What the hell is goin' on around here?!
- I don't know!
You two help secure the rig! Let's go!
One Night! Get the hell outta there!
The crane's comin' down!
I'm OK. I'm clear, Bud.
I've got it! It's headed straight for us!
Oh, shit!
- Oh, God...
- No!
Bud?
Grab onto something!
Jesus!
- Battery room's flooding! Let's go!
- Cat, put that out!
- Bud! The drill room's floodin'!
- Get back down there!
Go! I'll take the battery room!
Jesus!
Shit!
- Get out of there!
- Close the door!
Seal the room!
Lindsey! Let's get outta here!
- Hold this on me!
- OK!
Lindsey!
I got it!
Let's get the hell outta here!
Let's go!
Hit the door!
No!
Bud!
Finler, cut the hose! Cut the line to the motor!
I can't open it from out here!
Finler, cut the hose!
Finler!
Hey!
- Come on, Sonny!
- Hey, Cat! Cat, help me out, man!
Hang on!
The hose! Cut the hose!
The line to the motor! Hurry up, man!
Come on, Cat!
Hurry!
Come on, Sonny!
Help me out! Come on! Push!
- Come on, Sonny! Let's go!
- Come on! Let's go! We gotta go!
Get outta here! Come on! Move it!
Go!
Get the hatch, Cat!
Get the hatch!
- You all right? Everybody OK?
- Yeah.
Son of a bitch!
Oh, man!
Benthic Explorer, Benthic Explorer.
This is Deepcore Two. Do you read me?
This is Deepcore.
Do you read me? Over.
Forget it, Sonny. They're gone, man.
- Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
- Hey.
They're gone.
OK?
I just wanna get out of this.
I'd just like to see my wife one more time.
Well, all right, then.
You'd better keep trying, huh?
Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
This is Deepcore Two.
Benthic Explorer, Benthic Explorer.
Do you read me? This is Deepcore Two. Over.
Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
Hey, Jammer.
- You got the shakes.
- I know what I got.
I'll deal with it, all right?
I'll deal with me. You deal with yourself.
Find your buddy?
- No.
- Tighter.
- Brigman.
- What?
I was under orders.
I had no choice.
How's it going, Cat?
- What's the scoop, ace?
- Well,
I can get power to this module
and sub-bay if I reroute these buses.
But I gotta get past the mains,
which are a total meltdown.
But there won't be enough to run the heaters.
In a few hours, this place
is gonna be as cold as a meat locker.
- What about O2?
- Yeah, well, brace yourself.
If we close off the sections we're not using,
we have about maybe 12 hours' worth.
The storm's gonna last
a lot longer than 12 hours.
Yeah, well...
I can maybe extend that. Maybe.
There are some storage tanks outboard
next to the wrecked module.
I'll have to go outside, though,
and tie onto them.
Hey, Lins.
- Lins.
- Yeah?
I'm glad you're here.
Yeah?
I'm not.
Hey. Found Cab 3.
Deader than dogshit, boss.
That girder went right through the brainpan.
Yeah, I see that.
- Where are you?
- Living quarters. Level two.
Jeez!
That's Perry.
That's it, then.
Finler, McWhirter, Dietz and Perry.
Jesus.
We just leave 'em there?
Yeah, for now. We got no choice. Our first
priority is to get somethin' to breathe.
Where are you now, Lins?
I'm under the starboard tri-module.
- Still with me, Hip?
- Right behind you, Lins.
- How's it look?
- Well, you guys really screwed up my rig.
- There's a lot of wreckage out here.
- Well, don't get fouled.
- Hit me with that nine sixteenths, OK?
- Yeah.
Thank you. So...
- There you were.
- Yeah, there we were.
Side by side on the same ship
for two months.
I'm a tool pusher and we're testing
this automated derrick of hers.
We get back on the beach
and we're livin' together.
Doesn't mean you had to marry her.
Well, we were due to go back out
on the same ship. Six months of tests.
If you were married, you got a stateroom.
Otherwise it was bunks.
OK. Good reason. Will you come over here
and tighten this for me? Then what?
Then it was all right
there for a while, you know.
Then she got promoted
to chief engineer on this thing.
- She went front office on you, man.
- Yeah, well, you know Lindsey.
She's just too damn aggressive.
Son of a bitch!
She didn't leave me. She just left me behind.
Bud, let me tell you somethin'.
She ain't half as smart as she thinks she is.
Get outta here.
Come on. Let's see those muscles.
Bingo! That's one.
Two for two.
Hey, hey.
Lindsey, do you read me? Over.
Copy you, Hippy. What's the matter?
Oh, shit.
The power's jackin' around with us again.
Lindsey, come back.
I just lost video. Lins, are you there...?
Hippy, do you copy?
Lins, you copy?
Oh, shit!
Oh, what the hell! Hippy, do you copy?
Damn it!
Bud, do you copy? Over.
I seem to be having a problem here.
Shit!
Damn it!
- That's a great shot, Lins.
- You drop your dive light?
Come on, you guys. That's the smaller one.
That's the smaller one here.
- You can see how it's zigging around.
- Whatever it is.
I'm telling you what it is.
You're just not hearing me.
- Now, Lindsey...
- There is something down there.
- Something not us.
- You could be more... specific.
- Something that zigs.
- Not us.
Not human.
Get it? Something non-human but intelligent.
A non-terrestrial intelligence.
NTls. Oh, man, that's better than UFOs.
But that works too.
Underwater Flying Objects.
- Are we talking little space friends here?
- Hell, yeah!
Hot rods of the gods! Right, Lins?
No, no, really. It could be NTls.
- The CIA has known about 'em for ever.
- Step outside.
- They abduct people all the time, man.
- Hippy, would you do me a favour?
Stay off my side.
- Will you step into my office, please?
- Certainly.
I... Come here.
- Jesus, Lins!
- Something really important's happening.
I'm trying to keep the situation under control.
I can't allow this kind of hysteria.
Who's hysterical?! Nobody's hysterical!
When you're hanging on by your fingernails,
you don't go waving your arms around.
I saw something. I'm not gonna go in there
and say I didn't see it when I did. I'm sorry.
- Please.
- You are the most stubborn woman I know.
Yes, I am!
But I need you to believe me right now.
Now, come on. Look at me. Come on.
Am I stressed out?
Do I have any symptoms of pressure -
sickness, tremors, slurred speech?
- No.
Bud, this is me - Lindsey. OK?
You know me better
than anybody in the world.
Now watch my lips.
I saw these things.
I touched one of them.
And... it wasn't some clunky steel can...
...like we would build.
It glided.
It was the most beautiful thing I've ever seen.
Oh, God, I wish you'd been there.
It was a machine.
It was a machine, but it was alive.
It was like a... like a dance of light.
Please. You have to trust me.
Now, I don't think they mean us any harm.
I don't know how I know that.
It's just... a feeling.
Jesus! I'm supposed to go on a feeling?
How can I go on a feeling?
- You think Coffey's gonna go on a feeling?
- Well, we all see what we wanna see.
Coffey looks and he sees Russians.
He sees hate and fear.
You have to look with better eyes than that.
Please.
I can't, Lins.
I'm sorry.
All I want is 24-hour surveillance
on exterior cameras.
- You've got six people. I've got...
- Comin' through!
Everybody just stop!
All right. I want around-the-clock manning
of the sonar shack and the exterior cameras.
That Russian bogey comes back,
- I don't think we should be taking a nap.
- Give me a break, Coffey.
Those things live three and a half miles down
in an abyssal trench.
Trust me, they're not speaking Russian.
Have you finished the repairs
- on the acoustical transmitter yet?
- Nope.
- Why not?
- I was having my nails done.
Well, get it done.
Kiss my ass.
All right.
Get something straight.
You people are under my authority.
Look, pardner...
we don't work for you.
We don't take orders from you.
And we don't much like you.
Hey, Cat!
Yeah.
Why don't you take
the first watch on sonar? OK?
Right on.
Sonny, you get a couple of hours' sleep.
Then you spell Cat, all right?
Hippy, you handle exterior surveillance.
One Night... Will you do me a favour
and see if you can get that transmitter fixed?
- All right?
- Give me a couple of hours.
Got it.
All right.
Come on, AJ Squared Away.
A little to the left.
What is...?
Oh, this is not happening.
I'm shaking, man. All right. Wait. And now...
Here's MIRV!
- Oh, come on, man! What else could it be?
- Why bring it here?
It's gotta be some kind of emergency plan
to keep it away from the Russians, right?
Look, they hot-wire one of the nukes.
They use some kind of detonator
that they brought.
Then they stick it back in the sub.
Fry the whole thing up. Bam!
Slicker than snot.
I'm tellin' you. And I'm not being paranoi...
Hi, Lins.
- Lins, will you just wait a second?
- If you don't do something about it, I will!
- Lindsey, we'll do something about it!
- Fellas?! Hello!
- Lins! Stop and think about this for a second.
- What?
You know, you've got some huevos
bringing that thing into my rig.
With all that's goin' on up in the world,
you bring a nuclear weapon
- in here!
- Mrs Brigman...
Does this strike anyone
as particularly psychotic, or is itjust me?
Mrs Brigman, you don't need to know
the details of our operation.
- It's better if you don't.
- You're right! I don't need to know!
What I need to know is that thing is
off this rig! Do you hear me, Roger Ramjet?!
You're becoming
a serious impediment to our mission.
Now, you either do an about-face and walk
out of here, or I'll have you escorted out.
I will not do an about-face and get outta here!
- Who the hell do you think you're talking to?
- Emergency! Maintenance Room B! Move it!
On the double!
Now!
- In here! Come on! We got trouble! Come on!
- What's goin' on?
All right!
- What's up? What's happening?
- You let her go, man. Do it.
Do it now!
Let her go.
The smartest thing you ever did.
- Coffey, you son of a bitch!
- Lindsey! Cool it.
- What's the problem?
- Nothing. We were just leaving. Weren't we?
We don't need them.
We can't trust them.
We may have to take steps.
We're gonna have to take steps.
Lins, I want you
to stay away from that guy. I mean it.
The guy is gone. Did you see his hands?
What? He's got the shakes?
Look, he's operating on his own.
He's cut off from his chain of command.
He's showing signs
of pressure-induced psychosis.
And he's got a nuclear weapon.
So, as a personal favour to me, will you try
to put your tongue in neutral for a while?
I gotta tell you. I give this whole thing
a sphincter factor of about 9.5.
You can just punch into his primary
guidance chip where you want him to go
- and he'll go there, right?
- No. Bad idea, Lindsey.
Why, Hip? Come on.
Because even if it could take the pressure
at that depth, which I don't think it can,
without the tether, you know what would
happen? It would just sit like a dumb shit.
Something would have to pass
in front of the camera for you to see anything.
But we could get lucky.
So we should go for it.
I really ought to talk to Bud about this.
No. This is between you and me. We get
proof and then we tell the others. Hippy, look.
If we can prove to Coffey
that there aren't Russians down there,
maybe he'll ease off the button a little bit.
I gotta tell you, that guy scares me more
than anything we're gonna find down there.
He's a goddamn
AJ Squared Away jarhead robot!
Give me a couple of hours.
I'll see what I can do.
Great. Thanks.
How's that?
Thanks.
Virgil, turn on your side.
All right. You're all set, big guy.
Hey, I told you to wipe that grin off your face.
Good night, little buddy.
Bud!
Get up!
Cat?
Cat!
Hey! Goddamn... Leave me alone.
Bud!
No, wait. It's OK.
Sweet Christ almighty!
I think it likes you.
It's trying to communicate.
It's Bud.
- It's wonderful!
- It's me!
- No. Don't...
- It's OK.
Is it alive?
Lindsey, no...
Seawater.
Oh, man.
Come on!
- Hurry!
- Where the hell's it going?
Hurry! I think it's headed for B module!
Lins, you see it?
So, raise your hand if you think
it was a Russian water tentacle.
Lieutenant?
No? Well...
A breakthrough.
Hey, ace,
- you done impressing yourself?
- No way that thing could just be seawater.
They must have learned to control water.
I mean, at a molecular level.
They can plasticise it, pulverise it,
do whatever they wanna do with it.
- They can put it under intelligent control.
- Maybe... their whole technology
is based on that-controlling water.
Was it the same thing
that you saw the last time?
No.
You know, I don't think that
that thing you saw was one of them.
- What are you talkin' about?
- I mean, I don't think it was an NTI.
I think it was like their version of an ROV.
Like Big Geek.
Hippy, you mean
they was just checkin' us out?
- Yeah.
- How come?
Curious, I suppose.
We're probably the first people
they've ever seen.
It went straight for the warhead.
And they think it's cute!
You need to get some sleep.
We have no...
...way of warning the surface.
And you know what that means?
It means whatever happens...
...is up to us.
Us.
So you think they're from down there
originally? Or from...
...you know.
I don't know.
I think... I think they're from "you know".
Someplace with similar conditions.
- Cold, intense pressure.
- Oh, man!
Happy as hogs in a waller down there,
probably.
Sniff something?
Did you, rat boy?
Hey!
Freeze!
Don't move!
That's right.
- OK, Hip?
- They're using Big Geek
- to take the bomb to the NTls.
- What?
We set it up to go right to 'em.
Oh, my God!
Take this. We're going to Phase Three.
What? We don't have orders for that!
I programmed Big Geek to go down to the
bottom of the trench and shoot some video.
- Now they got the warhead tied to it.
- Coffey.
Coffey... Come on, Coffey.
Just think about what you're doing, OK?
Just think about what you're doing!
Get back!
This is something I've wanted to do
since we first met.
Take it easy.
- All right! Into the kitchen! Let's go! Move!
- Get your damn hands off of me!
I know the way.
Your boss is fixin' to pull the pin
on 50 kilotons.
And we're all gonna be ringside!
He's havin' a full-on meltdown!
- What's the timer set for?
- Three hours.
- Shut up! Don't talk.
We can't get to minimum safe distance
in three hours.
We can't go to Phase Three.
What about these people?
Shut up! What's the matter with you?
Everybody just stay calm.
The situation is under control.
Anybody touches that door, kill 'em.
Shoenick! Your lieutenant's
about to make a real bad career move!
The guy is crazier than a shithouse rat!
- Can't you see he's lost it?
- Shut up!
- The shock wave'll kill us.
- Quiet!
It'll crush this rig like a beer can.
- Shut up, man!
- We gotta stop him.
Shut up!
This is not our mission.
We can't detonate without orders.
He's about to declare war on an alien species
just when they're trying
to make contact with us. Please!
- I don't know. I think I'm reaching him.
- Yeah!
I'll be damned.
- Jammer.
- Is everybody OK?
Oh, man!
- Don't move, jarface!
- Look, I'm the least of your problems.
Take it easy, Hippy.
How you feeling, big guy?
I'm OK, Bud. I...
I just... figured I was dead back there
when I saw that angel coming for me.
Yeah, OK.
Yeah. Why don't you tell us about it later?
- Come on.
- He's got it tied off with something.
Come on. Ready?
- We're not gonna be able to budge it.
- Now what? This is the only door to sub-bay.
- What are you doing?
- I'm gonna swim to hatch six.
What?!
I'm gonna get inside
- and open the door from the other side.
- Bud, this water is freezing.
Then I guess you'd better wish me luck, huh?
- Wish us luck.
- You comin' along?
Looks that way.
- All right, Cat.
- Come on, Bud.
- In case I don't die...
- This is insane.
Come on, Bud.
Let's go, pardner. I ain't got all day.
Come on. Yank on it.
We have to...
We have to go to the moon pool.
- It's the only way.
- I can't.
I can't make it, pardner.
I'm sorry.
OK, Cat.
You head on back, all right?
- What is he doing?
- He can't make it to the door.
- He's gonna try and take him out himself.
- No. God, he couldn't be that dumb.
That guy's a trained killer.
No!
Coffey... Coffey, listen.
Hey!
- Bud, you all right?
- Get him, Cat!
- He's dogged it, Bud!
- We gotta get this off of here.
Come on. Help me. Pull the gripper!
Cat, get the door!
Shit!
Come on!
Shoot!
You all right?
The safety's on!
Give me that!
Come on! Let's go! Help me out!
Gimme a hand. Let's move it.
- One Night, what about Cab 1?
- Ready to launch.
Go! You're better in these than I am.
You got air? Come on.
You got air.
Shit!
Bud, get out of the way!
Get in! Hurry up!
I'm comin', baby! Keep your pantyhose on.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah.
- Do you see Big Geek?
- Yeah. Right out in front.
Oh, my God! OK. Get on the arm.
- To the left. A little more.
- You missed. Try it again.
Steady.
- Grab it!
- Yeah, got it!
- Pretty slick, Slick.
- Hold it really steady.
- Hold it still.
- I am.
Shit! We lost Geek!
Where is he, Bud? Do you see him?
I'll take a look.
- He's comin' up fast. Step on it!
- Shit!
- Go to the right! Swing to the right!
Keep movin', baby!
Come here.
Son of a bitch!
Hard left, baby! Left!
Jesus Christ, lady!
If you think you can do any better,
you're welcome!
Son of a bitch!
- Is he right on us?
- Right on your ass.
OK.
- Where you goin'?
- Hang on!
Deepcore, this is Cab 1. Do you read?
Deepcore, Deepcore, this is Cab 1. Over.
I'm not getting any answer!
And we're flooding like a son of a bitch.
Yeah. You noticed?
You did OK back there, Virgil.
- I was fairly impressed.
- Yeah, well, not good enough.
- We still gotta catch Big Geek.
- Yeah, well, not in this thing.
Deepcore, Deepcore, this is Cab 1. Over.
Try it again.
Deepcore, this is Cab 1. We need a...
You all right?
Yeah.
Well, that's that.
Yeah, wonderful.
There's some light comin' from somewhere.
Off to the right.
Yeah, that's the rig.
It's a good 60, 70 yards, I'd say.
Well, they'll come after us.
Yeah, but it's gonna take 'em a while to get
here. We gotta get this flooding stopped.
- Can you see where it's coming in?
- Yeah. Can you hold the lamp?
There's a busted fitting behind this panel.
Problem is I don't think I can get to it.
- You got any tools?
- Uh, I don't know. I'll have to look around.
Yeah, well, I looked already.
Goddamn it!
All I need's a goddamn crescent wrench!
Come on.
Son of a bitch!
OK. Calm down, Bud.
- Calm down.
- OK.
OK.
We gotta get you outta here.
- How?
- I don't know how.
- All right. We've only got one suit.
- We gotta come up with something.
- Oh, my God! I'm freezing!
- Come here. Give me your hands.
Listen, you're smart. Think of something.
Can't you think of something?
OK. Why don't you swim back to the rig
and bring back another suit?
That'll take me about seven or eight minutes
to swim, get the gear, and come back.
I wouldn't make it.
By the time I got back, you'd be...
OK.
Let's look around. Let's look. Oh, my God!
Is that working?
Shit!
All right.
Here. You put this on.
- No! Are you growing gills all of a sudden?
- Don't argue with me, goddamn it!
- This is not an option, so forget about it!
- Lindsey, shut up and put this thing on!
- If you'd be logical...
- Fuck logic!
Listen to me. You've got the suit on
and you're a better swimmer than I am, right?
- Yeah, maybe.
- Right? Yes! So I've got a plan.
- What's the plan?
- I drown, and you tow me back to the rig.
No!
Yes! This water's only
a couple of degrees above freezing.
I'll... go into deep hypothermia.
My blood'll go like ice water.
My body systems will slow down.
They won't stop.
You tow me back and I can...
I can be revived after maybe
- 10 or 15 minutes.
- Lins, put this on! You put it on!
It's the only way! You just put this on!
Put this on. You know I'm right.
Please! It's the only way. You've got
all the... stuff on the rig to do this.
Put this on. Bud, please!
- This is insane.
- I know.
Oh, my God.
- Are you OK?
- It's the only way.
All right. Here. Hold this.
Son of a bitch. Hold on, Lindsey.
You can do this, you know.
- You can do this.
- God, Lins... I...
I know. You can tell me later.
This is maybe not such a good idea!
Oh, my God!
Bud! No!
I can't! Oh, Bud, I'm scared!
No!
I got him!
- Where?
- Oh, my God! It's Lindsey.
- Deepcore, do you read? Over.
- Yeah, we got you, Bud.
- We're here.
- Go to the infirmary.
Get the cart oxygen, defib kit,
adrenaline in a 10cc syringe,
and some heating blankets. You got all that?
- Got it.
- Meet me at the moon pool and make it fast!
Now! Come on! Let's go!
Hippy, get the hot packs!
Got 'em!
Here he comes!
- Watch her head.
- I got it. I got it.
Watch her feet.
Watch her head comin' down. Watch...
Clear it out. Is she clear?
Get the defib ready. Hurry up, Cat.
OK. Got it.
- OK?
- Yeah.
Three one thousand... four one thousand...
Breathe.
One one thousand...
two one thousand... three one thousand...
No! You gotta have bare skin or it won't work!
Three one thousand... four one thousand...
Here.
Is that right?
- I got it.
- Well, do it!
Breathe!
- Come on! Zap her!
- Clear!
- Come on, baby! Oh, Christ!
- Nothing.
Breathe.
- I'll jack it up to three hundred.
- Do it again, One Night. Zap her again.
It's going, it's going. It's charging.
Charging...
- Now!
- Clear!
- Anything?
- No pulse.
- Come on, baby!
- Charging one more time.
Zap her again. Come on!
- Come on!
- Clear!
God! No pulse.
It's flat. Goddamn! It's flat.
Get outta here.
One, two, three, four, five one thousand.
One, two, three, four... breathe!
Come on, baby.
One one thousand, two one thousand,
three one thousand, four one thousand...
Come on, baby. One one thousand,
two one thousand, three one thousand...
Come on, baby! Breathe! Come on!
Two one thousand, three one thousand...
Bud...
It's all over, man.
It's all over.
I'm sorry.
No pulse.
No!
No, she has a strong heart!
She wants to live!
Come on, Lins! Come on, baby!
- Zap her again! Do it!
- Charging.
Do it!
Clear.
Clear!
Get outta here!
Come on. Breathe, baby.
Goddamn it! Breathe!
Goddamn it, you bitch! You never backed
away from anything in your life! Now fight!
Fight!
Right now! Do it!
Fight, goddamn it!
Fight!
Lins? That's it, Lindsey.
That's it, Lins. You can do it.
That's it, Lins. Come on back, baby. Come on.
You can do it, baby.
Get her some air.
Breathe.
You did it, ace!
God!
Make sure her heart's OK.
Big boys don't cry, remember?
Hi, lady.
Hi, tough guy.
I guess it worked, didn't it?
Yeah. Of course it did.
You're never wrong, are you?
How you feelin'?
I feel better.
What did you do to me?
Next time it's your turn, OK?
Yeah, you got that right.
These are so your eyes can focus
in the breathing fluid. How's that feel?
If you can't see, you can't disarm the bomb.
OK. With this much weight,
you're gonna fall like a brick.
We've still got about an hour,
so you should get there in plenty of time.
When you get down there, all you gotta do is
cut a wire, drop the weights and come home.
- Hand me that wrench.
- Maybe I oughta check everything.
That's loose. I'll fix that up.
Bud, you don't have to do this.
Somebody's gotta do it.
It doesn't have to be you.
Who then?
So, what, I can hear you
but I can't talk, right?
The fluid prevents the larynx
from making sound. Excuse me.
- It'll feel a little strange.
- Yeah, no shit.
I gotta warn you all... I'm a pretty lousy typist.
The moment of truth.
Come on. Let's go.
Easy.
- I need it in the front a little bit.
- OK.
- Thank you.
- You got it.
- Set.
- Clamp?
Set.
OK, let's rock and roll!
Crack it.
Headset, please.
- OK.
- Relax now, Bud. Just relax.
- Bud.
- Relax now, Bud.
Watch me.
OK? Watch me. Watch me.
Don't hold your breath. Take it in.
Just let yourself take it in. Take it in.
That's it. Don't hold your breath now.
There you go.
Don't hold your breath. Take it in. That's it.
- There you go.
- Bud!
This is not normal!
It's normal! Lt'll pass in a second!
It's perfectly normal!
- It's not normal.
- It's perfectly normal.
We all breathe liquid for nine months, Bud.
Your body will remember. That's it.
That's it.
- Perfectly normal.
- Christ! He's breathing!
Give me that.
- Can you hear me?
- There he goes.
Yes? OK. Bud...
Try your keypad.
I already have.
Great.
Let's go!
- Hippy, you got that?
- Hold on, Jammer.
Easy.
Watch out. Watch his back. Watch the back.
Careful.
I redid Little Geek's chip
the same as Big Geek!
It should take you straight there!
All you have to do is hang on!
What's his depth?
- 3200 feet.
- Your depth is 3200 feet.
You're doing fine. Now,
you better watch out for crane wreckage.
You should be almost to it.
4800 feet. It's official.
Yeah.
Bud, according to Monk here, you just
set a record for the deepest suit dive.
Bet you didn't think you'd be doing this
when you got up this morning, huh?
One mile down. Still grinnin'.
8500 feet.
8500 feet, Bud.
Everything OK?
Ask him about pressure effects.
Tremors, vision problems, euphoria.
Ensign Monk wants to know how you feel.
It's starting. It hits the nervous system first.
Keep talking. Let him hear your voice.
OK, Bud. Your depth is 8900 feet.
- You're doing fine.
- No, Lindsey.
Talk to him.
Bud...
There's some... some things I need to say.
It's hard for me, you know.
It's not easy being a cast-iron bitch.
It takes discipline and years of training.
A lot of people don't appreciate that.
Jesus, I'm sorry
I can't tell you these things to your face.
I have to wait till you're alone in the dark,
freezing, and there's 10,000 feet
of water between us.
I'm sorry. I'm rambling.
Comin' up on the big ten thou.
12,000 feet. Jesus!
- I don't believe he's doin' this!
- Hippy!
Shut up! What's wrong with you?
Bud, how are you doing?
Signal's fading.
No! No, Bud, I'm not going away.
I'm right here.
Kill everything we don't need.
Knock out those exterior lights. Go! Go!
Run it through the digital processor!
Cook it as much as you can!
I am right here with you, Bud.
Bud, this is Lindsey.
Please. I'm right here with you.
OK? So try and stay calm.
I'm right here, all right?
Bud.
He's losing it.
- Talk to him. Keep him with us.
- Comin' up on 16,000 feet.
No, Bud, it's the pressure, all right?
You have to listen to my voice.
You have to try.
Concentrate, all right?
Just listen to my voice. Please.
17,000 feet.
Christ almighty, this is insane.
Bud? I'm not getting anything!
- Whoa! Come on! No!
- What?
- Little Geekjust folded.
- Jesus.
He can still make it.
OK.
Bud?
I know how alone you feel.
Alone in all that... cold... blackness.
But I'm there in the dark with you.
Oh, Bud. You're not alone.
Oh, God!
You remember that time...
You were pretty drunk.
You probably don't remember.
The power went out in that little apartment
we had on Orange Street.
We were staring at that one little candle
and I said something really dumb like...
..."That candle is me, like...
like every one of us is out there
alone in the dark in this life."
And you just... you just lit up another candle
and you put it beside mine,
and you said "No. See, that's me. That's me."
And we stared at the two candles and then...
Well, if you remember any of this,
I'm sure you remember the next part.
But there are two candles in the dark.
I'm with you.
I'll always be with you, Bud. I promise that.
How you doin', pardner?
You still with us? Come back.
You talk to us, Buddy boy.
- Come on.
- Bud?
Talk to me, Bud.
Now, come on. You hangin' in there?
You have to talk to me, Bud! Please!
I need to know if you're OK.
You... you see light?
What kind of light, Bud?
He's hallucinating badly.
- He made it.
- Oh, my God.
OK, Bud.
We'll go step by step.
Remove the detonator housing
by unscrewing it
counterclockwise.
All right, Bud. You have to cut
the ground wire. Not the lead wire.
It's the blue wire with the white stripe.
Not, I repeat,
not the black wire with the yellow stripe.
Quiet! Save your air.
Bud, give me a reading
off your liquid oxygen gauge.
What?
- It took him 30 minutes to get there!
- Bud! Do you hear me?
You drop your weights and start back now!
That gauge could be wrong. Do you hear me?
Just drop your weights and start back now!
Your gauge could be wrong!
You drop your weights and start back now!
You won't stay there. You drop your weights.
You can breathe shallow! Do you hear me?
Bud, please listen to me! Please! Goddamn it!
You dragged me back
from that bottomless pit!
You can't leave me here alone now. Please!
Oh, God, Virgil! Please!
Please!
I love you.
Howdy.
How are you guys doin'?
Attempts to convene a summit
between heads of state have collapsed...
The Soviet build-up of tanks and aircraft has...
All citizens to stay on their jobs,
restrict unnecessary travel...
...what officials are calling
an unprovoked attack.
Oh, shit!
Across the country,
National Guard units have been mobilised
and all civil defence volunteers
have been called to full-time duty.
You watch our TV.
That's what you're telling me.
- You know what's going on up there.
- Seismologists are reporting
an enormous disturbance
throughout the world's oceans
which apparently began
about 15 minutes ago.
They are acoustic shock waves like tsunamis,
but with no apparent seismological source.
The waves are propagating towards
the shorelines of every continent.
- I'm sorry. That's...
- Dr Berg, would you please...
Young lady. Young lady, listen to me.
I don't know. We don't know
what's going on yet. We don't have a clue.
The horizon has already grown dark.
People are running everywhere.
It's sheer panic.
Stay on me!
The wave... the wave is,
I don't know, maybe 1,000 feet high already.
Getting bigger as I'm watching,
still miles out.
- My God!
- Get outta here!
No! Stay! We're staying!
Give it to me, then!
I don't even know if I'm still broadcasting.
I can't be sure.
I'll just keep going as long as I can.
You guys are doing this.
You guys are doing this, right?
You can control water.
That's your technology,
but why are you doing this?
OK. That's enough. I get the point!
How do you know
they're really gonna do it?
Where do you get off passing judgement
on us? You can't be sure.
How do you know?
You could've done it.
Why didn't you?
Deepcore, do you read?
This is Benthic Explorer. Over.
Do you hear, Deepcore?
Deepcore, do you read?
Do you read me, Deepcore?
This is Benthic Explorer. Over.
Hell, yes, we read! Good of you to join us!
Copy, Deepcore. Hey, I've got 'em!
How's that storm goin' up there?
It just blew itself out all of a sudden.
Well, hell, son.
You'd better get a line down to us.
We're in moderately poor shape down here.
We've lost seven people, including Bud.
And we're about out of O2,
so whatever you're gonna do...
You make up your mind
how to get us outta here?
They're talking about
flying in a DSRV from Norfolk.
- I just wish I could've seen it.
- OK.
How long's that gonna take?
How do you stop
a half-mile-high tidal wave...
Hey...
- Hey! It's Bud!
- That's impossible.
- No, it's not.
- Do you hear, Deepcore?
Yes!
Wait. We've got a message from Bud.
- Bud?
- What's it say?
Here.
It says...
It says "Virgil Brigman back on the air."
"Have some new friends down here."
"Guess they've been here a while."
"They've left us alone, but it bothers them
to see us hurting each other."
"Getting out of hand."
"They sent a message. Hope you got it."
I'd say that's a big ten-four, Jack.
"They want us to grow up a bit
and put away childish things."
"Of course, it's just a suggestion."
Looks like you boys
might be out of business.
What the hell's goin' on?
One Night, get to sonar.
Good God almighty!
Fellas...
I'm gettin' some awful big readings here.
- Something's comin' up the wall!
- What is it?
Whatever it is, it's major!
Something is definitely going on down there.
Active is pinging back something really big.
It's huge!
- It's coming up underneath us.
- Where?
Where? It's everywhere!
There! Starboard bow!
There! Look!
Help, Cat!
We should be dead. We didn't decompress.
They must have done something to us.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I think you could say that.
Hi, Brigman.
Hi, Mrs Brigman.