Just tell them that.
Tell them my reasons.
Tell them why.
End of tape four...
February 22, 1974.
Testing.
One, two, three.
Mr. Maestro, Leonard Bernstein,
tape number one.
Mr. Bernstein...
I have the utmost respect foryou.
Your music...
is both pure and honest.
And that is why I have chosen you...
to present the truth about me to the worId.
My name is Sam Bicke.
And I consider myseIf a grain of sand.
On this beach caIIed America...
there are 211 miIIion grains of sand...
three biIIion on the beach we caII Earth.
If I am Iucky...
the action that I am about to take...
wiII show the powerfuI...
that even...
the Ieast grain of sand...
has in him...
the powerto destroy them.
These come in brown?
We do have that in a brown.
And a harvest goId. And an avocado.
Give me three of the brown and an avocado.
Are you interested in that chair?
This is a Naugahyde,
very good for avoiding stains.
I Iook Iike that big a sIob?
I can't sit on this pIastic stuff.
I get sweaty and stick to it.
This doesn't come in Ieather, huh?
Not this chair--
-Jack Jones.
-BiII WiIson.
BiII, what our new associate's trying
to expIain, I think is...
that this is Ieather
with a Naugahyde coating.
Coating?
ExactIy. Comfort of Ieather.
Just a IittIe easierto cIean.
No extra cost. How does it feeI?
It is comfy.
-You know what you Iook Iike sitting there?
-What?
You Iook Iike the boss. Are you the boss?
I got my own pIace.
What did I teII you?
Did you write the gentIeman up, Sam?
No, he didn't....
Write the gentIeman up.
Can we deIiverthis foryou Monday,
or is Tuesday better?
Tuesday's probabIy better.
Mr. Bernstein, sir...
there are times that l have felt alone
on this planet.
And that's how they want us, isn't it?
Alone. Divided. Weak.
-To our new cIoser.
-Hear, hear.
You smeII something? I do.
I smeII success. And you've got the odor.
AII right, Sam.
Why do I say that to you, Sam?
WeII, I certainIy am trying.
Got nothing to do with trying. It's beIieving.
When you beIieve in what you're seIIing,
you succeed.
Because then you're not seIIing.
You see what I'm saying?
You're taIking from somewhere here.
You've got to beIieve.
It's a gift. I've got it.
Marty's got it. You may have it.
I can beIieve in anything.
Isn't that right, Marty?
It's true.
You want to know who
the greatest saIesman in the worId is?
That man, right there.
He soId the whoIe country,
200 miIIion peopIe...
on himseIf. Twice.
And what was Nixon's saIes pitch in '68?
In '68, it was....
He said he wouId end the war.
He wouId get us out of Vietnam.
And what did he do?
He sent another 100,000 troops...
and then he bombed
the Iiving shit out of them.
That's what he did.
Now, what did Nixon run on Iast year?
Ending the war in Vietnam. And he won.
By a IandsIide.
That is a saIesman. He made a promise.
He didn't deIiver.
And then he soId us
on the same exact promise.
AII over again. That's beIieving in yourseIf.
These are foryou. Read them.
These, you Iisten to.
WhiIe you're driving. WhiIe you're shaving.
WhiIe you're taking a shit in the morning.
You gotta beIieve, Sam.
This book right here wiII reaIIy teach you
to beIieve in yourseIf.
This book right here
wiII reaIIy teach you techniques.
These wiII make you a saIesman.
I guarantee it.
The salesman who believes
is the salesman who receives.
Remember, power is a state of mind.
You have as much as you think you have.
lf you don't think you have any, you don't.
Talk about yourself as you see yourself.
And someday that will be yourself.
The salesman must see himself as a winner.
The salesman who believes
is the salesman who receives.
-For crying out Ioud.
-Hi, MeI.
Did you see your brother?
-No.
-He just waIked out, just now.
So, how's it going? What're you up to?
Ijust came by to give this.
This is what I owe him...
and if you couId just get that to him for me,
I'd appreciate it.
Come on, Sam.
JuIius feIt bad how things turned out.
Why don't you stick around
tiII he gets back?
He didn't go home?
No. He just ran out to the bank.
He'II be right back. Sit down.
-I reaIIy got to go.
-Sit down.
I can't sit down, MeI,
but it's very good to see you.
Don't be a stranger.
Look at you, man.
Look at that.
''Sam Bicke, SaIesman.'' Damn.
You can keep that.
They made a thousand of them.
-Athousand?
-One thousand.
Man, they got big pIans foryou.
You Iook good, Sam.
I feeI good. I beIieve.
Amen, brother. You've got to beIieve.
Sam Bicke, saIesman.
I was just thinking
that I wouId go see Marie.
That I wouId surprise her because
I have a IittIe extra for herthis month.
AII right, then.
You don't think it's a good idea.
You've got to know what's right, Sam.
Nobody thinks
that Sam Bicke is going to make it.
I didn't say that.
Hi, there.
How are my princesses?
-I got an A in SociaI Studies.
-You did?
That's great.
Go wash up, you two.
-Hi.
-Hey.
Looks good.
You can keep that.
They made a thousand of them.
-Thanks.
-It's good to see you.
You know you're supposed to caII first.
I know.
What's this?
I'm on a roII.
That's great. Maybe I can get the roof fixed.
It's done. Paid for. Do it.
-Job's working out?
-Yeah.
Marie...
I reaIIy think that
this is gonna change things for us.
Sam, job sounds good.
I've got dinner on the stove.
Thanks.
Ijust wanted to have a IittIe taIk.
-Mommy, JuIie's standing on the chair.
-JuIie, come on, down.
I gotta get inside.
I'm sorry. Just caII first. AII right?
-When?
-I don't know. Try Sunday.
-After 10:00, though, aII right?
-Okay.
I'II caII you Sunday after 10:00.
You Iook good.
Back to work.
Mommy.
JuIie, come on.
EIIen, go get your brother, pIease.
You Iook nice, Marie.
Hey, Tuffer.
Hey, boy.
Volume on the New York Stock Exchange
was 16,500,000 shares.
What happened, Mr. Bernstein,
to the land of plenty?
When there's plenty for the few,
and nothing for the plenty?
ls that the American dream?
Now remember,
the customer's weapon is money.
That's what he'll want to talk about.
Your weapon is quality.
That's what you'll insist on talking about.
Don't get caught in the price game.
you tell him how great it is.
How much?
This is a very high quaIity desk.
This one is 38 inches.
How much is it?
This is $529.
I reaIIy beIieve in this desk.
I want to show you something. This is....
It's aII right. I know pretty much
what to Iook for in a desk.
Sam, I'm gonna be buying a Iot of stuff...
and I'm just wondering,
what's your best price?
-I'II see what I can do foryou.
-AII right.
Give it your best shot.
I'II do that.
Okey-dokey.
What I can do is I can give you
10% off that desk, which is $476.
Jesus! Sam, that's it?
That's your best price?
It's our seIection of the month.
Excuse me. Can I see you
in my office for a minute pIease, Sam?
Yes, I'II be right....
I'II be right with you.
What are you doing?
Are you out of yourfucking mind?
Offering 10%?
Are you trying to give this stuff away?
-You said--
-It's aIready been marked down.
For Christ's sake, that's Iess than we paid
forthe damn thing.
You know I think
there's been a misunderstanding--
I'm not interested in what you think.
I'm interested
in what you're gonna do about it.
I guess I couId teII him--
You can't teII him shit.
You've made the offer.
That's it. Go out and hope he doesn't take it.
AII right, Mr. Jones.
Sir, can I show you
some of our other very nice....
AII right, then. Yes.
You Iooked Iike
you're gonna shit your pants.
You're on the board.
-You see him write that check?
-He did it to me, we do it to you.
Fifty-fifty aII right with you?
-Sure.
-Good job, Sam.
It's not Iying. It's business.
But it's not right.
I shouId have said something on the spot.
No, you shouIdn't have.
What are you saying,
that I shouId swaIIow something Iike that?
It makes me sad that you wouId
accept something, of aII peopIe.
Sam, I'm just saying it's not that big a deaI.
It is a big deaI.
Bonny, if we're going to be partners...
we have to get this kind of thing straight.
Sam, I get it. Okay? I've been there.
But this guy's your boss.
If he wants to be an asshoIe,
you might just have to Iet him do.
-But, Bonny--
-There's no ''but,'' Sam.
-What about my rights?
-You've got a right to be mad, sure.
ExactIy. That's what I'm saying, partner.
That's aII I'm saying.
Sam, it's a job.
This is what I mean.
A man doesn't give up his rights at a job.
A man doesn't give up his rights anywhere.
You of aII peopIe shouId know that.
What shouId I know? 'Cause I'm bIack,
I shouId mouth off to my boss?
AII this rights shit. Rights this, rights that.
Rights, my ass. It's a job.
You got a right to pay your biIIs,
pay foryour kids.
I'm just saying you can't keep quitting jobs.
We aII gotta work somehow.
Come on. You're a saIesman, right?
Iike you do.
Explain this to me, Mr. Bernstein.
All l want
is a little piece of the American Dream.
Like my father and his father.
ls that too much to expect?
Hey, Tuffer. Hey, boy.
You miss me, don't you?
Of course you miss me.
This is a good country, Maestro.
Filled with good people.
But what good is good...
in times like these?
I've been trying to caII.
DoubIe Scotch, Scotch and soda,
doubIe bourbon.
It's not a good time, Sam.
Oh, no. I know. Ijust came to say hi.
-You want to see a menu?
-Yes, pIease.
-Here you go. I'II be right back.
-Thank you.
...great change, at the same time.
One change is defense spending
is on the way down now.
For the first time in 20 years,
the Federal government is spending more....
That's too much saIt.
I know. Sorry.
How is it?
It is good. Remember Sam Jr.
used to caII these ''mashapotos''?
That's right. Is everything okay at work?
Top of the charts. Top of the saIes board.
I'm doing very weII.
That's great.
Maybe I'II be driving a CadiIIac soon.
He was a friend of yours?
Who?
The one with the CadiIIac.
I drove by Iast night.
-Jesus, are you spying on me?
-No.
What you doing
Iurking around the house for?
I wasn't Iurking, Marie. Ijust....
You toId me to caII.
I caIIed and nobody answered, so--
I said, try me, okay?
You know what?
I don't want to taIk about this.
I respect that.
Ijust want you to know
I'm not seeing anyone.
Okay, that's your business.
It's important to me that you know that.
Fine. Now I know.
TabIe four wants their check.
I'm sorry. Okay? I didn't mean....
Can I caII you Iater?
Look, if I get off at a decent hour,
I'II caII you.
-AII right?
-AII right.
Mr. Bernstein, sir, there are people
who sit and wait their lives away...
on the promise of a dream
that will not come.
They are the sheep.
We have a great deal to be thankful for
as Americans tonight.
You've chosen El Dorado,
with front wheel drive. lt's our most-
But there are also
many more like us, Maestro...
-who will not be pushed around.
-The time has come when the masses...
...have been pushed to the wall.
When they cannot any longer
address their grievances through the legal...
political machinery of this country.
We're not the decision-makers,
the masses are.
lf they think it's time to overthrow
the system, there's nothing you...
or anyone eIse can do.
Hi. I'm Sam Bicke.
HaroId.
-How are you?
-Yeah.
Are you with the poIice?
I'm not poIice. I'm Sam Bicke.
Yeah, I got that. What can I do foryou?
As a matter of fact...
I've seen you on teIevision.
I mean, the Panthers on teIevision...
and I'm in compIete agreement
with your stand.
Except that I'm white.
We've aII got to be born something.
Do you know what that means?
It means you're not getting
to your whoIe audience.
I mean, I'm white, but I'm in the same boat.
You own the boat.
No, I don't own the boat.
I'm not the man in the CadiIIac.
That's not me.
May I?
-HaroId.
-Yes.
I feeI Iike I can taIk to you.
I sort of knew it wouId be Iike that.
I know what it's Iike to not be respected,
and be Iied to...
and be treated Iike a great, big nothing.
And I want to do something.
You want to do something?
Like the BIack Panthers,
I want to do something....
The system is not right.
I have to go,
but I want to throw an idea at you.
Zebras.
Zebras?
See, they're bIack and they're white.
The BIack Panthers become the Zebras...
and membership wiII doubIe.
I don't want you to answer me right now.
Just think about it.
This is $107.
I wanted to feeI
Iike I was starting to do something.
Sam.
It's a great start.
Take a Iook.
-You see what I see?
-What's that?
You're famiIiar with Carnegie, right?
I gave it to you.
DaIe Carnegie.
How to Win Friends and lnfluence People.
Oh, yes. I know the book.
No, you don't.
You've seen the book.
Maybe browsed through it.
But you don't know the book.
If you knew the book,
you'd know what I mean when I say...
''AIways give a dog a good name.''
AIways give a dog a name.
A good name. Damn it.
You've reaIIy got to Iisten better.
You're right. I'm sorry.
It's a Carnegie technique
for deaIing with peopIe.
When somebody's performance isn't good,
you don't criticize them.
You don't say, ''Your work's shit.''
Right? Instead you say:
''Your work used to be great,
now it's not so great.''
And then you ask them a question Iike:
''Everything okay at home?''
Are you asking me?
I'm teaching you.
You just Iearned a management technique.
Don't mind me teaching you, do you?
sir.
-Good. Just one more IittIe thing.
But, Marie, he wants me to cut it.
It's a job, Sam. Shave it off.
You'II forget you ever had a mustache.
I won't forget. I'II neverforget.
Marie, don't you remember?
Remember what?
Daddy, do you Iike my picture?
Yes, honey, it's very nice.
I grew it foryou.
Sam, pIease.
Mom!
You've got to see these peopIe,
they just Iie to make money.
And then, I'm the sIeazy one
of these so-caIIed businessmen.
God damn it.
I mean they don't have any right...
to say haIf of the things that they say to us.
I mean, Iook at the way
they make you dress.
I dress Iike this so I can support my famiIy.
Can't you see what they're doing to us?
You're going to Iose this job, aren't you?
What? I'm not going to Iose my job.
Just teII me now,
because I can do it on my own.
I'm doing great.
I'm so tired of this.
I don't want you
stopping by Iike this anymore.
I reaIIy mean it.
I think it Iooks good.
And it makes me Iook
a IittIe oIder and trustworthy.
You wouId trust me.
That's not reaIIy the point, though.
What I'm saying is--
I'm surprised you wouId say that, Bonny.
I reaIIy am.
Because I wouId think
that you wouId have more feeIing.
Joey, Iet's get some of these dishes cIeared
and get you to bed.
No. You sit.
Joey.
Yes, ma'am.
That's a good kid. That's a reaI good kid.
His mothertaught him weII.
I bet she did.
No offense, but I wouIdn't be surprised...
if his father had a IittIe something
to do with that.
He probabIy got something from me.
What do you think?
If yourfather went away...
wouId that make you sad?
He's not gonna go away.
Of course he's not. If he did?
If your mommy wanted him to go.
She wouIdn't say that.
Why don't you just Ieave those there.
It's past your bedtime.
Give yourfather a kiss.
-Good night, Daddy.
-Good night, baby.
Things wiII work out, Sam. You'II see.
-Good night, Mommy.
-Good night, baby.
Say good night to your UncIe Sam.
Good night, UncIe Sam.
Good night, son.
I know it was important to you, Sam.
I want to thank you forthe sacrifice.
I think it was a good decision.
Now you can smiIe.
You Iook Iike a famiIy man instead of
some schmuck with a pussy on his face.
-Marty?
-Yes.
Get up to the spic's pIace
and get me an egg saIad...
and whatever eIse you want.
ls independence too much to ask,
Mr. Bernstein?
l mean, you're your own boss, right?
You don't have any idea what it's like
to work for somebody else...
like some kind of a slave.
But l'm telling you,
slavery never really ended in this country.
They just gave it another name. Employee.
Remember power is a state of mind.
You have as much as you think you have.
lf you don't think you have any, you don't.
Talk about yourself as you see yourself...
and someday that will be yourself.
The salesman must see himself as a winner.
Say it along with me.
I'm not sure I understand this business
about the schooI bus.
That's just it. The bus is the business.
It's a movabIe store.
-A movabIe tire store?
-ExactIy.
You see, we take out aII of the seats,
just gut the whoIe bus...
and put the tires. FiII it up with the tires.
Then you bring the tires to the customer,
at his convenience.
You're a deIivery service.
That's just the beginning of it,
because I wouId bring the tire...
and change it, I'II put the tire
on your car whiIe you're mowing the Iawn.
Or anything eIse that that you want to do.
And we'd paint the bus a bright red
because that wouId give the company...
its own individuaI identity
and make it memorabIe. A sort of trademark.
And you have the bus aIready?
My friend, my partner, Bonny,
has the bus and he has the tooIs.
And I bring the management experience.
And that you have as weII?
That I do, sir. Yes, I do.
It says here you're currentIy empIoyed
as an office furniture saIesman?
That's correct. But I'm ready to move on.
And priorto office saIes,
you were a tire saIesman with yourfather?
JuIius Bicke, that's my brother.
Brother. Okay,
and why did you Ieave his empIoyment?
He expected me to Iie.
I don't beIieve that someone
shouId have to Iie to make a Iiving.
AII right.
Over and over he wouId teII me...
that 15% is rock bottom.
SeII beIow that, we Iose money. That's a Iie.
In the retaiI tire business,
the markup is aIways at Ieast 30%.
So, 30 is rock bottom.
What one shouId teII the customer....
Let me show you.
Good morning, Mr. Ford.
I think I understand, Mr. Bicke....
Let me just show you.
Good morning. Sam Bicke.
You're here to buy tires.
Yes.
Let's get down to brass tacks.
This is the deaI.
The markup on aII of my tires is 30%.
I wiII show you the company invoice
to prove that to you.
I'II do that foryou, Mr. Ford.
I'II make you my best offer.
I'II spIit the difference with you.
I'II take haIf the markup as my profit...
and you'II take haIf the markup
as your savings.
Even Steven. Fair deaI.
What do you think?
What do I think? Or....
Yes. No, I'm back to normaI now.
-It's 15%.
-ExactIy.
But it's the same thing,
what your brother offered.
No. My brother...
wiII go to 15%,
but he wants you to hoId at Iist.
5% if you have to...
10% if you're gonna Iose the customer
out the door.
But the saIesman who offers 15%,
he's a faiIure.
He's a man who doesn't know
how to hoId his ground.
And who do you think,
at the end of the month...
gets the promotion, gets the bonus?
The one with the biggest profit margin?
The biggest Iiar.
I'm sorry.
Ijust want you to know that I wouId run
an honest business.
That I wouId not ask my saIesmen to Iie...
or make them feeI Iike a faiIure...
or some kind of a piece of garbage.
WeII, that's....
I admire that.
-Your idea?
-Yes, sir.
WeII, that's it.
That's it?
Mr. Ford, I want to thank you, sir,
because this Ioan isn't just for me.
I think it can change
the way we think about American business.
Mr. Bicke, I'm reaIIy very sorry.
That's it for now. I have to send
your appIication on to Washington...
and they wiII review it.
And it's a whoIe process.
Of course.
Mr. Ford at the SBA...
Bonny, I gotta teII you,
he was very impressed.
Did you teII him the bus don't run?
I didn't.
Did you teII him your partner was bIack?
I did, yes. I checked the ''Negro'' box.
That was stupid, Sam. This isn't working.
No, Bonny.
The government is Iooking
for bIack businessmen.
I've been here 16 years,
and they haven't found me yet.
EIIen, sit next to JuIie. Sam. Come on, son.
EIIen, can you just sit. That's great, JuIie.
EIIen, sit next to your sister.
Come on, Sam Jr.
EIIen, honey, sit next to JuIie.
Come on, you guys. Dinner's ready.
Daddy's taking a picture.
That's aII right, honey, I got it.
-See you next Sunday, Sam.
-Yeah, I'II see you next Sunday.
Tuffer! No.
$125 is yourtotaI. I Iet the tax sIide.
Thank you.
You remind me of my ex-wife.
She's got the dimpIes, aIso,
when she smiIes. They're nice.
CompIiments and a good deaI.
I shouId shop here more often.
You shouId, miss, or is it missus?
Miss.
-Is this the current phone?
-Yes.
WouId you Iike me to deIiver it?
No. That's aII right.
I'II have someone from the office stop by.
It wouIdn't be a probIem.
I'II be just fine.
You aIready are.
I don't want you to deIiver it.
I'II have it picked up.
I didn't mean me, personaIIy.
We have peopIe who deIiver.
I think there's been a misunderstanding.
I Iove my wife very much.
We are aII married men. FamiIy men.
Yeah.
Because...
what's odd about your aborted fIirtation
with that woman today...
according to Marty's recoIIection,
correct me if I'm wrong...
is that you referred to her dimpIes...
as being Iike those of your ex-wife's.
-I don't think I did that.
-He sure did.
I think there's been a misunderstanding.
As I toId you when I took you on...
I onIy hire married men.
A singIe saIesman is distracted.
A divorced saIesman faiIs at seIIing,
the same as marriage.
It's aII right for a guy to...
Iie to some broad
about not being married when he is.
That's fine. That's to be expected.
But you wouIdn't expect that guy
to Iie to his boss, wouId you?
I guess I did try to pick up on that woman.
I didn't want you to think
that I was being dishonest to my wife.
You did try to pick her up then?
Yes.
My son was correct
in his estimation of your character?
Yes.
And if I were to ask
you and your wife to join...
me and Marty and our wives for dinner
in, say, a week ortwo...
that wouId be okay with you?
Yes, I think that...
she'd Iike that very much.
When l was little l was taught
not to be rude, Mr. Bernstein, but...
what am l supposed to do
about the people who won't respect me?
What I wanted to do is just check
on the status of my appIication.
Sorry, Mr. Bicke.
Mr. Ford shouId have toId you,
but processing takes eight to ten weeks.
No, he did not teII me that.
Perhaps you couId check back,
say, September 1.
-September?
-Yes.
I do understand your position.
I'm sure that you deaI
with a Iot of incompetence.
But I am a businessman...
and a businessman can't wait.
If you gonna have a future,
you gotta make it.
So I wouId reaIIy appreciate it
if I couId see Mr. Ford.
What was yourfirst name?
SamueI J.
I wiII taIk to Mr. Ford...
and if he has time for a meeting,
we'II caII you next week.
Since I'm here, maybe I couId just see him--
If he has time,
we'II caII you next week. DeaI?
DeaI.
Least you couId do is discourage him.
DoubIe bourbon and a vodka martini up.
It wouId heIp if you wore your wedding ring.
For God's sake, Sam, aren't we done yet?
WouId you consider going to the dinner?
You couId drive your own car.
I'm not gonna put on some charade.
If you're theirtop saIesman...
what do they care
if you're married, divorced, or queer?
Sir, you shouId be ashamed of yourseIf.
That woman is my wife.
They make her wearthat.
Sam.
ReaIIy, it's aII right.
I'II just wait here. I'm fine here.
Mr. Bicke, pIease....
He'II understand. He'II Ieave at some point
and he'II be going to his car.
He'II Ieave at some point,
I'II waIk him down. That's aII the time....
-Mr. Bicke.
-Mr. Ford.
It's good to see you, sir.
Why don't we step outside
and get a cup of coffee? How's that?
Coffee. In the cafeteria.
ActuaIIy, there's a machine in the Iobby.
The Iobby's fine.
Have a seat.
Now, how exactIy can I heIp you, Mr. Bicke?
Yes, weII, sir....
FunniIy enough, my situation is
that I reaIIy....
It's very urgent that I get this thing roIIing,
if you know what I mean.
No, I don't.
The bus thing. The tire thing.
Yes, I rememberyour appIication
and I sent it aIong.
Now there's reaIIy nothing more I can do.
You can't teII me anything eIse?
No, I can't.
I toId you in our meeting,
and I beIieve you were toId again...
that the process wiII take eight to ten weeks.
You'II be notified by maiI.
You can't expedite that?
It wiII take eight to ten weeks
and you'II be notified by maiI.
Now, I have to get back.
Is there some way
that this couId be speeded up?
Is there some way that couId happen?
No, there isn't. And if you come back again,
I wiII have to add that to yourfiIe.
Impatience is not a virtue, Mr. Bicke.
Okay. Good Iuck.
In the maiI then?
Yes.
A nation, like a person, has to have
a certain inner drive in order to succeed.
ln economic affairs that inner drive
is called a competitive spirit.
Whether this nation stays number one
in the world's economy....
...over 40 rounds from the hotel's rooftop.
The sniper, former Navy seaman...
Mark Jimmy Essex,
had testified in his court- martial-
For his part,
Allende vowed he would not give in.
He would not, he said, ''Betray
the working classes.'' ln the end he found....
Who are these men, Maestro...
who keep us waiting at their feet?
The meek shall not inherit the earth.
The earth belongs to the bullies
who do not care how they get to the top...
as long as they arrive.
l am an honest man, and if that
is to be my undoing, then so be it.
But l will not go quietly.
You've just got to have
a IittIe more patience.
It's aII about money.
It ain't aII about money.
Now what?
-You got a probIem?
-Yeah, I got a probIem.
I paid you to fix the Ieak.
-You've stiII got one?
-I've got haIf-a-fucking-dozen of them.
What kind of rip-off joint
you running here, anyhow?
-You sound Iike you're having a bad day.
-I'm having a bad day with this fucking car.
-You have a nice day, now.
-Yeah.
What is the matter with you?
This thing is Ioaded.
Nobody shouId taIk to another person
Iike that.
So you start swinging
this fucking thing around?
-You out of your mind?
-He didn't respect you.
So what? You think I'm Iosing sIeep
overthat buIIshit?
But how can you take that racist crap?
Just because I didn't cuss his ass out
doesn't mean I took shit off of him.
AII I took off of him
was the money that he owed me.
And I sure as shit ain't some UncIe Tom,
if that's what you're trying to say.
Are we cIear on that?
Yes, we're cIear.
Jesus Christ!
I didn't mean you were a Tom.
I didn't mean that.
I'm so sorry, Bonny.
Are we stiII friends?
Yeah, we're friends.
Last night near the site of that massacre,
some 200 lndians...
took control of two buildings
on the Pine Ridge Sioux reservation.
The lndians attacked at midnight...
fully aware of the cliche
that lndians don't fight at night.
We have bet our lives
that we can make change...
for the American lndian,
whether we live or die.
And l'm prepared to die.
l would rather die than submit to slavery.
...lnternal Security Division
of the Justice Department of the FBl....
And I apoIogize, Ma.
She's your daughter, but she's my wife
and you have to teII me where Marie is.
Okay. Mrs. Anderson, where is Marie?
Then I'II just have to keep caIIing.
9082. Thank you.
Marie Bicke, pIease.
Yes, I know exactIy what time it is.
It's 3:27 in the morning
and I demand to speak to my wife.
That's right, this is Sam Bicke,
and who is this?
Who is this, sir?
Marie?
Wait. No, you hoId on.
Marie, I got a divorce decree today...
and we're supposed to be separated,
we're supposed to be working on this.
It's onIy been one year.
It certainIy has not been two years.
No, it has not been aImost two!
I have a Iife. Why wouId you say that, Marie?
When you're-- Marie?
God damn it!
l could stand here before this audience,
and make all kinds of excuses....
I appreciate aII the time you've taken.
I have spent a Iot of time, but it's okay
because I know you're gonna be happy.
I need to measure the space.
So we can deIiver it this afternoon,
or is Saturday better?
As I said before,
I have to stiII measure the space.
I'II have the boys come over.
They can measure the space.
You're not gonna
Iet me down, are you, Stan?
This doesn't have to be done today
because we'II be here in the morning.
Turn that down.
God damn it!
What did you just do?
You out of yourfucking mind?
ActuaIIy, I have some bad news
because I'm not going to....
This is my Iast day.
-What?
-ActuaIIy...
I'm not going to be abIe
to finish today because...
I have a very important Ietter
that's coming in.
I'm starting my own business...
and I have an enormous amount of pIans
that I have to make.
Have your desk cIeared in 10 minutes.
AII right.
...'cause people have got to know
whether or not their president is a crook.
Well, l'm not a crook.
l've earned everything l've got.
l sold all my stocks for $300,000.
lt's all l owned.
l sold my apartment in New York....
It's about money, Dick.
...and the testimony you gave us last week...
was that you had dispersed some $69,000...
in what you might call a sabotage program.
And that you also perjured yourself
at the trial...
at Mr. Magruder's request.
Would you explain to the committee
how you dispersed the $69,000?
l don't think that was gone into
with much detail.
Roger ZeffIer, pIease.
Sam Bicke, Bicke Tires.
Speaking to Haldeman and Ehrlichman
l said ''The boil had to be pricked.''
No.
...prick the boil and take the heat.
You're the prick.
HeIIo, Roger. No, I wasn't saying that.
This is Sam Bicke.
Yes, that's right, JuIius' brother.
As a matter of fact,
I'm back with JuIius now.
I'm handIing shipping and receiving
for him. I have a purchase orderthat...
we sent in a coupIe of days ago.
It's number 3765.
WeII, it is a Iot of tires.
We're opening an outIet in the HiII district.
BIack peopIe have to have tires, too, Roger.
Yes, that's the correct address. If you couId
just drop-ship those, that wouId be fine.
Monday's fine.
The operation they're talking about
is the burglary of the Watergate.
That's correct, sir.
Mr. Magruder,just one very brief question.
Did John Dean prepare you
for your grand jury?
...by making their lives better at home,
for themselves and their children.
That key is in your hands.
Every action l have taken tonight...
is designed to help us
snap out of this self-doubt...
this self-disparagement
that saps our energy.
She declared
it was all part of the national plan...
to bring an end to the Black Panther party.
Darn it.
l want the American people...
l want you to know
beyond the shadow of a doubt...
that during my term as president...
justice will be pursued fairly, fully....
Please let them know, Maestro...
let them know l was nervous...
that unlike the powerful,
l was not so arrogant...
as to be sure that my actions
were righteous.
Certainty is the disease of kings, Maestro.
And Sam Bicke was many things,
but not a king.
He just wanted to make a change.
To stop the lies.
And he aimed high.
HeIIo, SamueI.
The IandIord was kind enough
to aIIow me in.
He stopped by. I see you received his note.
JuIius.
We have some things to discuss,
don't you think?
To discuss?
-Good seeing you, of course.
-Cut the crap. Sit down.
You're a very strange man, SamueI.
I've aIways known this.
I've aIways tried to heIp.
So why wouId you steaI from me,
your brother?
-I didn't steaI--
-You did.
I had to baiI yourfriend, Bonny,
out of jaiI this evening.
Bonny?
For receiving stoIen goods. My goods.
Did you think Roger ZeffIer wouIdn't
become suspicious of yourfriend?
That somehow this deIivery was kosher?
That 550 tires beIonged to that address?
Roger ZeffIer is a racist.
Perhaps that's so. Shame on Roger ZeffIer.
But you are a crook.
So, you teII me, Sam.
Which shame is greater?
-I am not--
-Look at me.
This is your brother.
Do I deserve this now, foryou to Iie to me?
JuIius, pIease.
No. No ''pIease, JuIius''. No!
I have been to the poIice.
Begging forgiveness for a mistake
that was not a mistake.
Because I took responsibiIity, SamueI.
So that no one wouId go to jaiI.
So that this man, Bonny, yourfriend,
wouId not go to jaiI.
And my famiIy caused this.
So you must teII me, Sam, pIease...
which is the greater shame?
I'm sorry, JuIius.
What is your name?
I had an idea.
For a tire business. Like you.
I wanted to get a head start untiI
my Ioan came in, and my Ioan was denied.
Because they're racists. Nixon.
AII of them. Like ZeffIer.
I didn't get the money
because my partner is bIack.
I was gonna pay you back.
I'm just trying to keep my famiIy together.
And the IittIe guy just can't do it anymore.
Because there's a cancer in the system.
The whoIe system has a cancer,
and I'm being punished because I resist.
But somebody has to resist.
You're my brother.
As of this moment, SamueI...
I wash my hands of you. No more.
That's it. Nothing.
And if you steaI from me again,
brother or no brother...
I wiII send you to jaiI.
You can pick
the only luxury convertible made in America.
But no matter which of nine Cadillac models
you are to select...
they're all part of the Cadillac tradition.
Tonight, February 17.
Good evening. Secret Service officials
are still puzzling over...
the landing of an Army helicopter
early today...
on the south lawn of the White House.
lt all started
shortly after midnight last night...
when Army Private First Class,
Robert Preston...
stole an unarmed helicopter...
from Fort Mead, Maryland.
The joy-riding pilot was identified
as 20year-old PFC Robert Preston...
an Army helicopter mechanic...
who was reportedly unhappy
over flunking out of flight school.
He was charged with unlawful entry
into the White House grounds.
l sincerely believe that if his attitude
was to crash into the White House...
he could have accomplished it
without any problem.
Do you think his attitude
was to crash into the White House?
l do. l really do.
lt wasn't like a light bulb really.
lt was more like an old candle...
just a plain, simple idea.
But in that moment, Mr. Bernstein, l knew...
the die was cast.
Mr. Bernstein...
I have the utmost respect foryou.
Your music...
is both pure and honest.
And that is why l have chosen you...
to present the truth about me to the world.
$120, 40, 60, 80, 200.
One, two, three, four and 33 cents.
There you are, Mr. Bicke. AII cashed out.
I'm sorry.
lt's a shame innocent lives
are going to have to be lost, Maestro.
And l will do my best
to prevent as many deaths...
as l possibly can. But that won't be easy.
lf history teaches us anything...
it's that you have got to get
the seat of government.
The whole goddamned chair,
you just kick it out.
Let the system dangle till it doesn't breathe.
lf you destroy the seat of government,
then you've made a change.
A real change.
And l am going to do it.
No, this is.... I'm sure it's just....
I have an injury.
It's okay. Thank you.
Good morning, gentIemen.
My name is Sam Bicke.
If you do what I say, no one wiII be hurt.
I want you to fIy this pIane,
and I want you to fIy it Iow.
I want you to fIy it very Iow.
I have to take controI here.
lt's a shame
there aren't more people like Bonny.
What a beautiful man.
l hope that he will forgive me
for stealing his gun.
They Iet you in Iooking Iike that?
I wanted to taIk to you.
I'm sorry things didn't work out.
No hard feeIings.
I wanted to thank you forteaching me...
that to be a saIesman...
you don't have to be a good man.
You got a fever, Bicke?
You're sweating Iike a pig.
Here, wipe yourforehead, for Christ's sake.
I'm trying to eat a meaI.
You aII right, son?
You Iove me. Don't you, boy?
Because I wouId never Ieave you.
Come on.
Good boy.
Sir? Excuse me.
You Ieft your case.
TWA skycap with wheelchair,
please come to TWA ticket counter.
l have received reports
from various parts of the country...
of many instances of sharp increases
in the price of gasoline.
Ladies and gentlemen, we are about
to begin boarding Flight 523 to Atlanta.
ln accordance with our security measures,
we do ask you to begin to form a line.
Please have your tickets and
any carryon baggage with you at this time.
This is the general boarding call
for Flight 523 to Atlanta.
Nobody move. I'II kiII you.
I've got a bomb, I'II kiII you.
You, come here. CIose that door. CIose it.
Sir, pIease just caIm down.
-What?
-Just caIm down.
We're gonna take care of anything you need.
No!
Write down that my name is Sam Bicke.
If you don't move, then no one wiII get hurt.
You understand?
I want you to fIy this pIane.
I want you to fIy it Iow.
I want you to fIy it very Iow.
I hearyou, Sam.
Ijust need to caII the tower. Okay?
I'm gonna caII the tower.
I'm gonna reach over here
and get my headset.
I'II put it on and then caII the tower...
because I need them to come
and take the tugs out in front of the wheeIs.
You have to heIp him to fIy the pIane. Okay?
She's gonna heIp you fIy the pIane.
You have to move him.
Sam, I can fIy the pIane myseIf.
Just Iet her go.
PIease Iet me go.
I don't want to die.
Look at me, Maestro. Am l smiling?
Tell them why l did this, Maestro.
History needs to be clear on this.
They can rebuild the White House,
but they will never...
forget me.
Not ever.
l was here, Maestro.
l did this.
And a man is only remembered for his work.
Just tell them that.
The first hijack attempt
in the United States in more than a year...
was made today in Baltimore. lt failed.
There had not been another hijacking
attempt in this country until today.
And it happened at the same Baltimore
airport, but with far worse consequences.
Forty-four-year-old Samuel Bicke
walked to the departure gate...
carrying a harmless-looking attache case
which contained gasoline and a detonator.
He was running and acting
like he was crazy. Out of his mind.
Bicke ran through the boarding bridge
yelling for passengers to get out of his way.
A policeman ran after him, but by that time...
Bicke was inside and had forced
the stewardesses to close the door.
The policeman
fired through the door's window...
and killed the would-be hijacker.
His motive may never be known, but
authorities say that there's no question...
the hijacker intended to destroy himself
and everyone else aboard Delta Flight 523.
Neil Strauser, CBS News, at the
Baltimore Washington lnternational Airport.