Smoke rises over the
mountains to the north.
It is a sight that man makes
the blood run cold in the Adam.
more than 400 years beginning
people lived in this area in peace.
But that's over now The evil spirit
has returned to the Shoukata
And he will not rest until
he has subjected all mankind.
There is only one man, the
may oppose the darkness.
a man whom even the ancient
prophecies of the ancestors boast.
the chosen warriors.
Hail, Ranger.
do not speak Can you? Did you
about someone cut out the tongue?
What just happened here
Yes but you can not speak?
For a modest mite, I'll
tell you everything I know.
Perhaps even more, my friend.
I'm not your friend And as a
reward I give you your life!.
Agreed?
You've probably really need it?
I only tried a little
bit strike out for me.
is in times like these,
but totally normal, right?
What is this place? A City
's was certainly times.
Her name was Amandu.
once lived here thousands, but now
they are all dead Who did this?
Warriors of Shoukata.
And you'll end up the same
way if you not soon disappear.
nowhere one can see. The
dive on already, no question.
Come, we must go.
Can you tell me what you're
doing I will fight with them!.
And why the only reason why I am here
This Ranger is really good!
Maybe he's there...
I ask forgiveness.
very determined you are the chosen one
standing again. What did you call me?
What does that mean
Please, let's get out!.
Then I'll tell you
everything I know. Comes.
I would not have guessed in life,
that I get to meet the chosen warriors.
something is really not!
Most of these stories are
prophecies or just fairy tales!
Because you never know. what is
true of them believe what you can...
Who would have thought
that I, Brutus Generavxra,
stride on the side
of the chosen warrior.
And then I got in
trouble because I played.
drank too much wine,
you know how that is.
What man does not know
that And then the women...!
How should a man keep
away from the women?
I am sure that will not do is
predetermined, do not you think?
For me at least I can
not stay away from them.
Unless you're more
on boys or something.
We are talking only...
And thoughts are free
It goes...
It goes that way.
After almost a year I
think in the Golden City
it was time to move on to see
what the world has to offer you.
To tell the truth, they
put me out the door.
And so I end up just landed there
where we met two of us And I realized
I now must fight!
What is not my strong Not really.
And, thus, the chosen
warriors on the way
Shoukaia to the Lord
of Darkness, to defeat..
Look, a lake Since we'll
have to mix around drum..
This done with the left. No,
we will spend the night here.
A good place for us
what we hunt for dinner.
If you can keep your mouth shut while
Is that clear, I do my best, my lord.
run of it, my friend Otherwise
you'll unsren silent hunger..
You have attained the
magic of swift sword.
least the gossips not
come back emptyhanded.
What do you mean with empty hands?
man, where did you get that?
can surely be no coincidence
you for such a wonderful weapon
in the woods find That was a fish..
fish Ask not just continue?.
Well, I wonder no further.
That would be a true miracle.
Did you hear that noise I know
What noise? The Swords
What swords The enchanted
swords of Demaclus
They were never defeated
we must get out of here.!
No, I'm ready. We stay here
Let go of the thing
Impossible, My Lord!
Was that all? More
you have not 'on that?
If you want to defeat me, you give
more effort! Much more trouble!
You did what any
successful in reaching] e!
You besiegtest the enchanted swords
of Demaclus! The other tried already?
Oh Yes. How many?
Many, My Lord, on them every failed
to challenge the Shoukata wanted.
What is it?
I think this is a of magic
stones of the ancient gods.
It means they enable the wearer
special power. Exactly what power?
Each stone is good for
something else, those
things are rare. Since
I'm really stumped.
I feel stronger, This is the
stone of strength, My Lord.
We need to make our
way we have to do much.
No question. Come on, my friend.
After his glorious victory
over the vervvunschenen swords,
the chosen warriors is now
ready for new challenges.
What is our next task
Good question, my lord.
But I do not know.
because before you, did
not defeated the
enchanted swords. Really?
Otherwise I would certainly
find it... You sure?
Sure, what do you think?
Are you hurt, my lord: no. All good.
That was a real spectacle
how you defeated the Giants.
Come on, let's go.
The bird is delicious.
Not bad
Tell me about the way
ahead of us. By the way?
Yes, our way of...
In ancient prophecy says
the chosen warriors
must move towards north,
in the home Shoukatas and defeat him.
And you know what else Hard to say?.
Want to be in the forbidden land,
need to log in seven tests set
Of the time are difficult to
date, the time no warrior survived.
Is that all Some say
this and others say so?.
But these are the main points.
We need a little rest, I
'll take the first watch.
power that you get back in your holes!
Who are you? Do not worry,
I am the ruler of the forest.
I came because I want to
help you Why did you help me?
Because we have common interests.
Thou shalt conquer the
evil spirit of darkness
and I hope that you succeed.
Please, take a seat
And what were the just for creatures?
The guards of the six kingdom
ready to destroy anyone
opposes the black rulers.
They will report Shoukata
about your successes.
He will send others
to kill you stronger
and more powerful than you may know.
Protects your me also facing. My Lady
I have protected you not know that.
back Since there is no doubt at all..
But I guard your sleep till morning
and'll help you on
your journey if I can.
Now you have to sleep good
advice I will give you even more..
The nearest village
enters only from the east,
My Lady?
My Lady!
what War The most amazing
creature I ever saw?.
You are the ruler of the
forest have met Yes, exactly?.
No mortal she got more previously seen.
As you can imagine what you
excited If you're mortal.
But the chosen warriors
must remain vigilant.
because the path on which
he walks, is paved with lies
and lined with treason
How far is it? even to the next
village I'm not quite sure, my lord.
But I do. it is here very close.
Then we go from the
south to enter? Exactly
Then we have beat an arc we
have to come from the east.
But this is the shortest way!
The ruler of the forest said from
the east we have to clean.. Good
We sneak carefully and see.
what she was trying to warn us.
Agreed, but be on the lookout
What a monster
Aha! And you claim the
chosen warriors to be?.
No, I never said moment you
talk with the animals there?
For whatever reason, I understand
you I'll let you read my mind
How do you know who I
am Questions, questions!
your man is constantly questions.
man. across the country
you will soon sung in songs!
I understand. Should the chosen
warriors fight a duel with me?
I wish not then you're
smarter than I thought..
But you come one step closer, we
need to fight, there gives no quarter.
Is that your last word I
have nothing more to say?.
I have no choice. Did you exceeded
the limit. I must attack you.
Then we go visit
Because you're a coward.?
No. Because I kill such
a majestic creature not.
Come on, Brutus
Good luck... Thank you, sir.
You spoke with the
dragon, is that true?
Yes. And what did he so the story?
Come on, what did he tell you?
that it was wise to follow the
advice the ruler of the forest.
Are you sure that the dragon
not following us? Trust me.
He does mom. Come on.
Sorry but you are dead.
Now you have three ways you
can begin your search by from,
your weapon and all
that you are carrying.
Or you go on, because where you
were but then you lose your sword.
And the third possibility
You stay here with me?.
for ever
Make your choice. Or
I meet them for you
What's In the second option?
lady choice is made, so be it.
You're alive yet!
Sure You're healed,
it's like a miracle...
This is the second chance
Yes but you yourself know..
What I know myself You are
here, and thus a part of that web.
You speak in riddles
Never mind, Brutus..
So let's continue...
So far r. Please.
It's so cozy here.
Brutus? It's not serious.
But please. Well, come on,
A small piece just yet That's
not true... well. Thank you.
Who are you? Claudius. Pass yes to what
you words tumble out
of the tongue, you dog.
Otherwise I cut it out yourself!
Say. I Claudius.
This is Teradon We are
from the village Samarin
In the penultimate
night we were attacked
by the soldiers of evil Shoukata,
all killed.
men, women, children,
the cattle...
The few that have survived
are fled to the mountains.
But there they will not survive.
Shoukatas were warriors? Exactly.
A complete company his demon
soldiers. Then I'll help you
What then is ins?
Forgive me, Lord...
But you alone against the
soldiers how will you do that?
Do not you understand. you
fool? He is the chosen warrior.
You are the chosen one?
Can you hear bad He is
the warrior, to which
we have been waiting for!
Forgive me, sir, I did not know.
Forgive me, please.
I beg you.. Get up,
Where is your village?
two days' journey to the south.
south We were going
west, right, Brutus?
Yes, My Lord, that is true.
And we can not deviate from the path!
Please, My Lord, help me.
Help my relatives.
Are women and children in danger
Yes, most will not survive.
Then I'll protect these
people But... My Lord.
The search will have to wait a little
This decision was not difficult..
Well, let's go
Waits. You're coming with me...
Comes...
On your knees, you pig but we
wanted to help you, but just!
yes Hold your tongue, yes
Otherwise I cut it out to you?
Fessle him.
Are you a servant of
the Lord of Darkness?
And what are you going to
Wanna kill me with bare hands?
Reptus Tannous, a magic potion.
Mixed from snakes, pigs and dogs blood
wild flowers and roots.
Deadly poison It will
flow through your veins.
The body is shaken by Krämpíeri.
sallow purple And
then approaching death.
But...
a sip of this drink and you'll be okay?
And if it's the last breath
I would you solder with joy.
The Demon Slayer is already go.
No, I'm not the chosen one
You're a pretty stupid
Demon Slayer, right?
? What you gonna do with me?
I'm going to kill for. No, the guy
is in there as feast for the beasts
to live in the forest. I can not
and I will not perish in this way.
Unfortunately, you have no
choice But I'm a Demon Slayer
And my life is ending
I have to die in combat!
will happen perhaps even
Brutus Come, let's go.
me to leave here, but it is not fair!
Art thou a coward?
Tell me, you're a coward
Get on it not, My Lord!.
But I will.
Promise this man you if you kill me
Lets him get away not you
promise, he leaves you in the hole.
And it has all been for nothing.
You are well on it from,
me to spoil all the fun.
Agreed so good, I should beat you
I let the dwarf alive.
You must swear to me, you let
me go and krümmst me no hair.
I swear, clear?
Great, the word of a Demon Slayer
Is worse
Brutus! Throw the rope timesdown
Want to solder not the guy
No, not today, Brutus?.
Throw the rope down,
The giant had Achilles heel,
and the Demon Slayer pride was fatal.
But Shoukata this kind
human weaknesses are foreign.
My Lord I have news from the forest!.
Then tell 'what you have to say.
The Chosen Warrior is still alive.
And he defeated the
warriors from the villages
and enchanted swords of Damaclus
And now he's got <br /
defeated> the Demon Slayer.
And he comes the fortress ever closer!
Who is this man, who
dares to challenge me?
I do not know, My Lord.
You have no idea?
your sword,
Is it too hot? Of course, My Lord.
Very good.
Let the "Six" of the chain. let
them bring me these stupid people.
possible in very small,
appetizing pieces. Yes, My Lord.
How good that you could
overcome the pitfall Claudius.
I was just lucky
happiness.? It was masterful!
Once I defeated the rulers of
the darkness, I will reward you.
was very friendly but I wonder
what prince of darkness
well planned next for us.
The black prince is consistently
powerful We must hurry.
It's getting dark, we be staying here.
Then I'll get us something to eat
And I'll take care of the fire.
My Lady, I had so much
hoped meet you again.
I'm you never left the side
You have always accompanied me.?
course. I told you, I hope
that you end up 're successful.
reason alone You keep me
in mind No, not sure?.
But for this issue we have
no time Here, take this sword.
You'll need very soon.
This is a wonderful sword One of
the most precious in our world..
It was forged by the gods personally.
Thank you. What do I owe you
for this gift? Nothing at all
And yet it is too early to thank me.
To carry the sword of the gods and out,
does not mean your victory.
And what do I have You have
to find the magic of the Samurai
Only then are you ready for the
next task. And where do I find it?
You'll find him when the time
is right, the gods are with you.
Good luck to you my chosen one
My Lady...
My Lady.
My Lady? The mistress of the forest
you already visited again? Yes.
And why the woman always
comes when I hunt now?
What I know you gave
me the sword here?.
Six..,
Please? The Black Prince
has sent the six samurai.
Samurai find us so you
And who are these six samurai? The
nastiest fighters that you can imagine.
yet never defeated.
The enchanted swords
were also undefeated.
Samurai nasty surprise Yes, may be..
the Lady Did you anything else?
you said I must find
the magic of the Samurai
Then we immediately set off.
We have no time to lose
we hurry. All right.
Do not worry, my friend,
you we eat then just later.
you Has the lady might tell where
we find the magic of the Samurai?
She said when the time is
right we find him already.
Typical woman, you ask politely,
but 'll never get a straight answer.
Now I know why the lady appears never
when you're there. That could agree.
Maybe. If you's right, I'll do the
six samurai existed even before supper.
That's a plan.
Brutus, did you hear
that What is it, my lord?
Someone laughed.
There! You hear that?
I can not hear anything
Who's laughing because since.?
Who's there Show yourself,
or are you a coward?
A squirrel is not.
What do you want from me
We are just passing through?.
want With whose permission
to pass her my kingdom?
We did not know that the
forest is your property.
We simply want to wander through
Please go away and hits the road.
You must not happen,
it unless you pay a fee.
I want to hurt you hate,
magicians, but if I have,
I will cut off your head.
It will not come as much Believe
me, Tree Man, he's serious..
So what do you propose?
What you got? I warned you.
How did you do the That
far exceeds your mind?.
If you want to happen but you
have to me solve a mystery.
And what happens if we go ahead?
Do you listen to my riddle?
What is probably harder A pound of
goose feathers or a pound of gold?
Well, both... Yes?
feathers And why?
you weigh gold in troy ounces...
have the troy weights only
twelve ounces per pound.
The springs there are
sixteen ounces per pound.
Thus they are probably harder.
You're right, you clever Meier
And I must say that
it is a pleasure for me
. Acquaintance <br /
make> a sowellbred man.
Wade, is that it?
That's the key! the gods!
Either it was you made of the
mistress of the forest as a gift
or you're a thief, of stole
it. He is not a thief.
Then almost seems to me
you're the chosen warriors...
in search of the magic of the
Samurai Exactly what I look for.
Why did you say not the
same from the beginning?
Then we had but can save
this whole shindig here!
Then you have the magic? Sure,
course I have to spell it
But better that you learn
him weasel speedy heart.
The Six Samurai are already here
You have attained the
magic of the samurai.
The Six Samurai were defeated
No man can do it, no one!
And yet it is true, my lord.
How is one man who
can defeat six samurai?
I do not know, My Lord
He's a good fighter.?
Only fools mouth make known
this kind nonsense. My Lord?
but has to do with the
fighting strength of nothing!
Someone helps him determine
he has received support!
Exactly. The man got help,
Spionier the man out, find
out from whom he gets help!
go early. Yes, My Lord.
Well done, My Lord!
Mistress of the forest
is absolutely right.
You are indeed the chosen warriors.
And you should someday
on your quest my need help
you only need to call on me
That works but only once.!
Thanks.
But hurry, young man!
Wait! What is your name?
Merlin. As usual
You have attained the magic of healing.
chosen warriors, no doubt.
Los, Hamlet,
I was always on the side of the rabbit,
me too.
What are you, My Lord An idea
does not go out of your mind?.
What do you think, as I
was the chosen warrior?
You gives you so chose I decided?
I just remember, that
I woke up in my village,
heard loud screams, and
nothing was the same again.
They were all dead Sounds to me like
you've got yourself since decided.
Anyway determined nobody except
ourselves, about our fate.
decide which route we take.
You really much smarter
than I thought, Brutus.
Thank you, My Lord
trying to sleep a bit..
I'll take the first
watch Whatever you want.
My Lady! Sit.
Samurai are beaten Yes.
I was sure you can do it
your makes me happy with
your visit I've missed you.
I missed? Yes.
Will you talk about
the topic possibly? No.
Awake The Amazons are on the march!
Awake We get visit. What to visit?
Who is coming? The Amazons
the lady warned me just now.
Amazons? Not good, not good at all.
Come we disappear,
Los, drop your sword or
you will die on the spot
Drop it!
No, just not Hall mouth!
Or I Consume your tongue for breakfast.
better choice, you do what she says.
With whom I have the pleasure
I'm Hethera, Queen of the Amazons?.
That's all you need to know
sisters, obviously we have caught
this time a magnificent specimen.
He will give us heaven on earth
he is better than its predecessors.
So, I think we... Cubes
of it, who is the first turn.
The Chosen Warriors won on his
quest of power and strength.
But that will not help him against
the unbridled fury of a woman
who feels scorned.
Where am I? We brought
you in our Amazon kingdom.
And what have! you done with my friend?
Seems pretty happy right now
What do you want from me?
The only thing that we women of
want you men, of course, your seed.
I will not do.
In your place I would think
the more difficult times.
your mate says you're the
chosen warriors. Is that true?
it.
So warrior, you have two options
either, do you live with us, so often,
pregnant until we are,
and that each of us!
Then we let you and your friend alive.
Or do us the honor verweigerst
and we fry your soft
parts on skewers, warrior.
No, attend you is me
impossible for what reason?
Because my heart already belongs to
another We would not want your heart.
Will you think about it Will not I?.
What a waste of pure lust.
Wait! Waits.
What do you want? Fight with me.
Why bother? I'll let you
kill and I'm done with you.
defeated all who came in Shoukalas name
you I was also defeated.
You beat yourself brave, but for
me it's absolutely irrelevant.
You have no honor, girls No
man would let me die like this..
But every woman has, in your
opinion It is what it is.
As you wish, we just fight.
Come on, finish him!
set your new king to be a man?
I thought 's me.
Thank you, My Lord! I think
I never want to eat goat meat.
Brutus... Although it
actually tastes great.
Brutus! Yes, My Lord Was
that also Shoukatas work?
Assume we have, he wants to no
case that you see him coming.
Then I want to search my not
rest until I've finally defeated.
Again a magical stone, My Lord.
Fate but says good cry with you.
Fate would have us today both
nearly killed. No, no, no.
That was just a challenge.
What did you I do not
know where we are, My Lord?.
We ask the lady of the forest,
the helps. Yes, she is.
But how do we find this woman, then?
Then we'll just keep
marching and keep an eye out.
we have pork, they will
perhaps us. Whatever you say.
The guy is good.
This man who dares. to call themselves
before world "'s chosen warriors."
He is better than his predecessors
before him wanted my head.
But he's not good enough
Because now I know his secret,
I know that he by the mistress
of forest is protected.
The woman is absolutely crazy!
Cursed be the day she was born!
I promise you, they will learn
what a high price must be
paid for this insolence!
Come here. you whore
doves, My Lord?
No. What do you hope
this of the chosen ones?
I know...
The warrior is your strength
not cope in life, My Lord.
your Craves the spirits
of Mandinas, sire?
No. I have planned for
him something much better.
What awaits me now? The Legend
after probably the ghost of Mahdinas
The ghosts of Mandinas
What do you mean again?
From Shoukatas warriors
they feared most.
And why These ghosts
can not be killed.
as they're already dead
not worry That's the
good news.. Oh yeah?
We need to find out just
how we can they kill again..
Very good. My Lord, so slow you
get out, how the wind blows here.
What is it? A monument to the
gods, a place where one prays.
A prayer for the lady of
the forest, what you mean?
You my ruler of the
forest I beg you for help!
Who else should I ask?
victims, My Lord... You
have to offer her something.
Sorry I made you an offer.
I can only offer one namely myself
What do I do with joy
if you help us again.
Now How can I help
you, my brave warrior?
It's about the spirit of
Mandinas No one can kill them.
No, they are invulnerable
because they are long dead.
But I know a spell that
of them back to life.
And then.. Then I make them ready.
Maybe Where can I find
this spell, My Lady.?
There is only one way you have
the mountains to the cavemen..
If you have the defeated
you also get your magic.
Where can I find the cavemen
Hike south to the mountains?.
There you'll find the cave
entrance But go quickly.!
The ghosts are already
underway Thank you, My Lady!.
You fool! No man can survive
a visit to the cavemen.
Even du
You know something about this man cave?
little Unfortunately, in the Book
of Wisdom is nothing about it.
also not in the book
of people. Strange.
How far do we have to The mountains
are about one and a half days.
But I do not know if we are there
Well What's next then?
Do not worry if we are
close enough find us.
Sure, My Lord will be all right.
What do you do when
this is over, is Brutus?
I have not quite understood the
question When everyone is defeated...
... together Shoukata
when the search is over
I'm not sure That's
never happened so far..
But I miss my family you have family?
Nothing special... A woman
and two small children.
But I want to see when
everything is over.
You were in this adventure have
frequently, right? That is true.
But it was never too late to...
Beating Shoukata
Exactly. The story will
run differently this time.
Do you believe me Yes, to who else?
Then we find out what is your destiny
Maybe you'll return to your family..
That would be nice.
We are probably there,
My Lord. We are where?
At the entrance to the cave
They live under the mountain.?
Yes, at night they come out
Until then, we wait here comfortably.
No, if there are more
inputs we miss them.
My God, I do not want to wait!
I make them the hell. was
already clear that you say that.
Should I go with No, wait here?.
And you'll kill everything which
leaves the cave. Can you do that?
Yes, I get to go there
already Thank you
Wonderful the chosen
warrior comes to die.
My Lady! My Lady! Get up, Brutus.
Please tell me: what are you
doing here Comic question?.
your self but we have
sent into the mountains.
You speak in the plural,
though you're here all alone?
chosen warrior came with me.
And where is he? Because in the Cave
What does he want
only with the cavemen?
I want an answer! Instant My
Lady, You gave us yet even guess
to hike in the mountains
and kill the caveman.
ways of life spell against the spirits
of Mandinas! I advised you before!
Then it was probably... Shoukata!
Please be brave you fear
the light.. Yes' My Lady.
nice. to see I'm just.
're sinister fellows
Yes, very true, thank you..
My pleasure What's the magic?
No magic, My Lord '
we both were cheated
From me out can we
go Good idea, Brutus.
My Lady The Lady of the
forest was here? Yes.
I learned Shoukatas of deceit
and could come to your aid.
Again she gave me folded
life In the valley.
Now he defeated even the cavemen.
That can not be a mere mortal.
Maybe he's really the
chosen one, My Lord.
And maybe you wearing tonight
still the head on your shoulders
sending the spirits of
Mandinas immediately!
Yes, My Lord. We'll see how it's
chosen warriors now been made.
Already very soon we will see it.
He wills. you can free them, What?
You listening hard You
should the spirits blank
moment.
This should inherit my
wife and children. Please!
Agreed.
Come on the door.
Yes.
The Chosen Warrior is forewarned
And yet the question remains:
like that! He kill the
ghosts are already dead?
What are you, My Lord
I feel something?.
the breath of death.
Thank you.
A little bit of fear exciting, huh?
Yet another magical stone, My Lord
Fate says again good with you.
We owe the Lady of the
Forest no question.
Now I feel even more strongly That
was not to be overlooked, my friend.
And now we are looking
by the Lady of the
Forest. Have tracked Soon the ghosts Us
to ask whether she knows
a spell of the power of
the spirits of Mandinas
breaks. Yes, let's go.
We have little time, my lord. Right.
My Lady! I need you needed more
than ever! Please! Come to me.
I am here, my chosen one
Now you need from me to spell
to defeat the ghosts of Mandinas.
You might as well be
Shoukata and fooled me again.
Shoukata probably does
everything to avoid defeat.
But what is it?
No, My Lady, the little well.
Please excuse my suspicion
You've only acted very wisely.
Shoukata your death
would be a feast of joy,
The ghosts of Mandinas are
already broken from his stronghold.
So we must hurry But My Lady!
The fortress lies a half days from
here This is not true for spirits.
This is the magic of Second Life,
he will breathe life into the ghosts.
This life can be taken from them,
it gives you exactly two minutes.
That means if you were
not fast enough to defeat
Your search sealed unfortunately
and your destiny. You have the magic
obtained of Second Life.
me I give my life not mess of ghosts
you are already there!
you die Do you not hope you will today.
Thank you.
You did it but only
with your help, My Lady!.
Greif, this is your reward.
The last of the magic stones, My Lord.
You have achieved far more
than any man reached before you.
It is still not the time to celebrate
It is time for the undisputed victory..
You can not defeat me, warriors Not you
Especially not today Woe
to you on what you're doing.
So what? Then what?
Then you'll kill me?
But before I die I'll cut her throat..
Then I am indeed dead but
the woman is there too!
Do not worry about me, my
love, I will live forever.
Let's bring it here to
the end of you and me.
I promise you, we will.
What is this? Where have they gone?
you go, My Lord Presumably
they are in Shoukatas fortress..
You know where that is? In the north
. Then we need also to the north.
No need to rush, My Lord the
lady said, it will survive.
She said it will survive, but
Shoukata could use a torturemagic
That would be possible, my lord.
I have no choice I must save her.
There would only be
a small thing What?
It is written Shoukata
can only be defeated
a fighter with a flaming
sword! Where can I find it?
According to legend it is kept
between the heavens and the earth.
This means on top of the mountain
Sounds convincing, My Lord...
How long will it take to the summit
The journey is arduous and dangerous?.
We need at least ten days, I'm afraid.
This is not a good plan
We need another way..
You make me fun and
we would need hill.!
You're absolutely right, my friend.
I have an idea as I have
absolutely right? With what do?
Although 'the adventure
comes to an end,
although the warrior
his victory gets closer,
Shoukata keeps the whole
obviously still for a game
There's he.
My Lord, he could destroy
you I do not think.
Take the sword And wish me luck,
Okay.
Who dares come so close to me?
I am he, the chosen warriors.
You're back around you
put me in battle, or.?
Very brave me anyway was a bit boring.
No, I do not even want to fight you.
but plays no role step one step closer.
And I attack you Thus
happens to be the rules..
Look at me. I am unarmed Now what?
man, what do you want from me '?
Now, I ask you for a favor fly
with me to the mountain top!
I absolutely need the flaming sword.
You really beat that a perfectly
ordinary mortal Shoukata can, or '?
I think. I can
assumed time, I could
, why should I help you?
No, I am not convinced yet
Because my noble reasons, are.
And now get out! Otherwise I crush
you right there where you stand.
Shoukata the mistress
of the forest took
hostage, I have to
save them necessarily.
Why? Well, Classify..
Because I love. You
said it beautifully.
Those were the magic
words my young warriors.
because only love has the power
to break the most powerful spells.
I'll fulfill your request,
get on We must lose no time.
Thank you.
Thank you, my friend You're
welcome, good luck, my friend.!
Wade! And as I come
back Get the sword!
magician! I need your help!
Merlin! I call you to me, please!
Sorry. I considered taking a
nap What do you want from me?
Shoukata took the mistress
of the forest as a hostage!
That sounds not good.
But my help you need
not it not really?
No. the sword has magical powers, son.
You must! do no more
than to ask for it,
And then it takes you
to your destination.
Take me to Shoukata!
Shoukata!
Shoukata! Shoukata!
mom works well against me.
The time has come Shoukata.
Let's get this over.
the first of all warriors,
you've come this far.
You're really good, but you know what?
You will never defeat me in life.
What would have to be
proven Yes.. How true.
My Lady!
can How dare you just
a lady to treat '?
Very soon, they will play in it
because with your head cut off.
you regret difficult still.
Do you really think I will
submit you? You'll have to.
me and the sword,
forged by the old gods personally.
from your gods, not mine
I Should not be merciful fate,
you cut the woman's throat since.
Yes, My Lord.
What are your last words
Now Advertisement just fit?.
image! you yourself
a you had already won?
Yes, the game is over.
I wanted but also
still participate a bit.
Hi, Mr. Wright. Awaits you.
Thanks Sharon, we see you tonight?
But of course, with me? Very much.
Good morning, ihrTeamchefs.
I played last night, our video game.
Did I really liked only
the logic in the end
I find to be problematic.
Bob, we've already discussed it.
I'm really sorry, Boss
way, you're fired