Planning a vacation, Mr. Sullivan?
No. No. Just - just some
reading to pass the time.
Step ahead, Mr. Sullivan.
You're expected in Room 102.
Down the hall and to the right.
Thank you.
- What is your name?
- Um- Morgan Sullivan.
- Where were you born?
- Madison, Wisconsin.
- Are you a spy?
- No.
Are you an undercover
operator for Sunways Systems?
No.
Were you paid by Sunways Systems
to steal data from
Digicorp Technologies?
No.
Have you ever worked at any
capacities at Sunways Systems?
No.
This is a technology firm, Mr. Sullivan.
If we choose to employ you
as an agent of Digicorp,
you will spy on other corporations,
inform us of their business plans,
research programs, and
counter-intelligence operations.
Thus far, your determination
has been very impressive.
Well, if there is anything more
I can tell you about myself,
anything that has not been
already checked by Digicorp.
Your personal records are fine. You've
passed our neuro-graph five times.
I'll take the test again
if you'd like me to.
You've been married four years.
You live in a respectable neighbourhood.
You've always had stable jobs.
You have an excellent credit history.
No drug habits. No drinking problems.
- You don't smoke?
- No.
No other vices to speak of?
Is there anything else
we should know about you?
Well -- It might
have taken me
quite a while to get to
this point, Mr. Finster,
but now that I'm here, I'm
going to make the most of it.
This is who I am
and this is what I want to do.
The stakes in this line
of work are very high.
Yes, I understand.
It will be like nothing
you've ever done before.
Oh, I'm prepared for that.
You will be sent to
conventions across the country.
You will record the speeches.
That's been made very clear.
You'll have to deceive other people
about what you do for a living.
- Yes.
- Even your own wife.
Yes.
You don't mind lying to your wife?
No.
No, I don't mind.
That was a good one. Move
on ahead to the next station.
- Hello, Mr. Sullivan.
- Hello.
Keep it out of view
until the convention
speeches actually start.
Press the back notch.
You see the flash? It's now on.
Press it again. It's now off.
Easy, isn't it?
And the transmissions are really clear?
Within fifty yards.
Just keep up front for good reception.
Where do the signals go?
Up to our satellite systems,
then back down to our data banks.
I guess the speeches
must be pretty important.
The speeches are not your
concern, Mr. Sullivan.
Just do your job.
Follow our instructions,
nothing else. Do you understand?
Yes, Mr. Finster.
Ready!
Jack Thursby? That's what
you'll be called from now on.
As far as Digicorp concerns,
Morgan Sullivan doesn't exist.
We've never met him. We never will.
- What's he like?
- Pardon?
What's his personality?
He's whoever you want him to be.
Buffalo? Why do they need you
to go all the way to Buffalo?
They want me to tutor them
on that spreadsheet software
I was using at my last job.
And you'll be paid freelance for this?
Sure. Independent contract.
You know, if things work out, there
could be more trips down the road.
I thought we agreed you
weren't going back to work yet.
Not until that position at
my father's firm opened up.
I can do this in the meantime, can't I?
I really need you at
home right now, Morgan,
with me being so busy
with the Williams case.
It's only temporary, honey.
I won't be gone for long.
Hello.
After the convention, you will confirm
the transmission on
your returning flight.
Yes.
Do you remember the
location of the briefcase?
Uh, yes.
Good luck, Mr. Thursby.
We're counting on you.
Thank you.
I left it in the stall.
Something to drink, sir?
I'll have a ginger ale.
- Actually, I'll have a scotch.
- Scotch?
Hmm. Single malt.
- On the rocks.
- Yes, sir.
Welcome to Buffalo, Mr. Thursby.
This is our new mascara line.
- It's hypoallergenic and it's
vitamin enriched. - Really? Mr-
- Fred Garfield.
- Hi. Hi. Jack Thursby.
Fairway Fragrance. Where
are they located exactly?
Uh
- Tulsa. Tulsa, Oklahoma.
You don't say? I've
got family from Tulsa.
You don't have much of an accent.
- I didn't grow up there.
- Oh, where did you grow up?
- I said, where'd you grow up?
- South Pacific.
- I'm sorry, where?
- The South Pacific Islands.
The Tuamotu Archipelago. French
Polynesia. Tahiti. Papeete.
Wow. That's pretty unusual.
Yeah, I plan to go back
there someday when I retire.
Water, sir?
- Thanks.
- Well, see you around, Jack.
Sure thing, Fred.
The conference room will
be open in five minutes.
Good morning, everyone.
My name is Robert Tuttle.
I'll be your first speaker.
I will first discuss shaving
cream distribution outlets
in North American markets.
Let me begin by acknowledging
what has become axiomatic
in the field of shaving
cream distribution.
Mainly that shaving cream,
indeed almost all personal
hygiene products for men,
is what we call fashion resistant.
The overwhelming majority
of shaving cream users
will adopt a brand
and remain loyal to it.
It is especially interesting to note,
the difference in methods
used to penetrate that market.
Because these two methods employed
by the respective companies
really illustrates the essential
strategic choice that faces-
- The Mediterranean.
- Yes.
The Mediterranean is beautiful, of
course; but if it's real sailing you want,
I recommend the Sunda Islands in the Banda
Sea. I was there on a trip last spring.
- Your cigarettes, sir.
- Thank you very much.
Hmm, Cohibas, my
favourite brand. Thank you.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Thank you.
Would you excuse me?
Good evening, sir. What'll it be?
Give me a scotch. Single
malt, on the rocks.
You got it.
Haven't we seen each other before?
You'll have to come up with
something more original than that.
I'm here for the convention.
That's fascinating.
- You're in marketing, right?
- Uh-uh. Sales.
- Is there a difference?
- What about you?
I do health inspections
of hotel restaurants.
- That sounds interesting.
- No, it doesn't.
- Do you have an answer for everything?
- Yes.
Rita Foster.
Jack Thursby.
So what do you do besides
travel to dull cities
and talk to women in hotel bars?
- I- - uh- play golf.
- Are you any good?
- No.
- Honesty. I like that.
What else do you like?
No commitments. No bullshit.
- And no rings.
- No rings?
You might want to take yours off?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll leave you alone now.
Your transmission came
through, Mr. Thursby.
The signal was clear.
I can do something else on my next trip.
I think I'm ready to
handle a bigger assignment.
We'll be sending you
to Omaha next Wednesday.
Omaha?
You'll perform the same job
that you did in Buffalo.
Omaha? Why can't they
find someone in Omaha?
Why do they need to fly you all the
way out there? It doesn't make sense.
Morgan.
Morgan, are you listening to me?
Since when did you ever care about golf?
You're not going on this
trip, Morgan. I'm sorry.
What do you mean, I'm not going?
My father wants you to
come to his office tomorrow.
Getting a position with his company
is more important than
a silly freelance job.
I said I'd go.
You're not going,
Morgan. End of discussion.
You're staying here. I'll call
my father tonight and we'll-
Tell your father to go fuck himself.
What did you just say?
Say you're sorry, Morgan!
Morgan!
If you don't apologize, I
want you out of this house.
Morgan! Are you listening to me?
What in God's name has gotten into you.
Since when did you
start smoking? Morgan!
Morgan, what's going on? I
think I deserve an explanation.
Your scotch, Mr. Thursby.
Turn around slowly, please.
What is your transmission device?
I thought you were a health inspector.
I'll ask you again:
what is your transmission device?
The pen, in my jacket pocket.
Do not turn the pen on.
What?
When you're inside the convention
room, keep the pen turn off.
Do not send the
transmission to Digicorp.
If you tell Digicorp you
met me, they'll kill you.
Take two every six hours,
it will get rid of the
nightmares you've been having.
Your headaches will go away, too,
and the pain in the back of your neck.
How do you know
that I'm having nightmares?
We'll be in touch in Boise.
What will they do if
I don't turn on my pen?
Just remember who you are. You are
Morgan Sullivan. You are not Jack Thursby.
Wait!
Good morning, everyone. I'm Alex
Chen. I'll be your first speaker.
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm
here to address the controversy
that's been raging around new techniques
in the preparation of process cheese.
Now at the risk of oversimplifying
the question facing the average
manufacturer of process cheese is this:
Given an increased consumer prejudice
against chemical additives,
how do we stem the tide away
from natural or organic based products
and instil in the cheese buyer.
I'm glad to hear that there were no
problems at the convention, Mr. Thursby.
I'll call down to the lab to make
sure the transmission went through.
Excellent work, Mr. Thursby.
Thank you.
Your transmission
came through perfectly,
just as clear as the last time.
I want you to take
another trip. Boise, Idaho.
Boise?
We scheduled a connecting flight
for you to board when you landed.
You won't have time to go home.
That's not a problem, is it?
No. No problem.
Room 1493, Mr. Thursby.
The convention room
will be open in an hour.
Thank you.
Mr. Thursby! One last thing:
the first letter from each word
is the phone number to call her.
Hello, Mr. Sullivan.
You dialled a special number that
can't be traced or monitored.
Now, listen carefully.
Take the service elevator at the end
of the hall down to the basement level.
You'll be clear for
the next five minutes.
Wait a minute, wait!
Keep moving.
Roll up your sleeve, please.
We don't have much time.
Are you insane? You're
not sticking that into me!
He has medical training, Mr. Sullivan.
I don't care if he's a
fucking brain surgeon!
You're not gonna drug me.
We're undrugging you.
The shot will block out
the Digicorp narcotic.
What?
The chemical they're putting in
your bloodstream at every convention.
Do you normally drink something
inside the convention room?
Mineral water.
The drug is tasteless and
odourless. You wouldn't have known.
Did you take the pills I gave you?
Had the noises in your
head started to go away?
- And the recurring dreams?
- Jesus, what is this?
W-w-why didn't Digicorp check
my transmission in Omaha?
There was no transmission in Omaha.
Or in Buffalo. Or anywhere else.
Why do they send me
to these conventions?
- The conventions are charades.
- Charades?
You and the other convention guests
all work for Digicorp. You're all spies.
You're given phoney
assignments, phoney identities.
You think your pen
is a transmitting device,
another guest thinks it's
his tie clip or her watch.
The whole thing is just a ploy
to keep you all distracted,
to not realize what's really going on.
What is really going on?
If you want answers, take the shot.
When you're inside the
room, act as you always act.
Order the mineral water. Drink it.
Don't make them suspicious.
The shot we gave you should protect you.
It should protect? What'd
you mean? What if it doesn't?
Listen to me carefully.
Whatever happens in that room,
show no reaction, no
emotion, no surprise.
No matter what you see, do not move.
What will I see?
- Who sent you?
- A friend.
I don't have any friends.
- When will I see you again?
- Soon.
I promise.
There are several points of interest
here. First of all, the fact, that
by an impressive margin,
new home purchases
took most of the brunt of that decline.
By this I mean that sales of older homes
are done on an individual basis
where there's considerably
more room for negotiation.
Therefore, in those sales
we're more likely to find
that the official rise in
mortgage rates has been offset
somewhat by the ...rates of
return on high tech investment,
which led to a surge in
business capital spending
and significantly increased the
underlying growth rate of productivity.
The capitalization of these
higher than expected returns
boosted equity prices
generally beyond even that expected
by the enhanced rise in real incomes.
The elevated level of light
vehicle sales, for example,
has put more vehicles on the road
than the industry could sustain.
And even though demand for
the number of high tech products
was doubling or tripling annually,
in many cases new supply
was coming on ever faster.
Overall capacity in high
tech manufacturing industries
rose nearly 50 percent last year,
well in excess of its
rapid rate of increase.
Accordingly the slowdown in the economy that
began in the middle of last year intensified,
perhaps even to the point of growth
stalling out around the turn of the year.
As the economy slowed,
equity prices fell,
especially in the high tech sector,
where previous high evaluations
were being re-evaluated,
resulting in significant
losses in some investors.
Clearly some slowing in the
pace of spending was necessary,
if the economy was to progress along
balanced and sustainable growth.
With the process likely to intensify
with the rise in the cost of energy
that has strained business
and household purchasing power,
purchases of durable
goods and investment
in capital equipment
declined in the fourth quarter.
Because the slowdown
was not anticipated by business,
it induced some backup in inventories,
despite more advanced technologies...
Inventory sales ratios
rose only moderately,
and even after the policy
actions taken in January,
the risk continue skewed toward
the economies remaining on a path
inconsistent with satisfactory
economic performance.
Crucial to the assessment
of the outlook and the understanding
of recent policy options,
is the role of the technological
change in productivity
in shaping near-term transcyclical forces
as well as long term
sustainable growth,
perceptible for sustaining
slow advances in quality...
Just a reflex.
...Managers appear to be more generally
sanguine about the potential for innovation.
You are not Morgan Sullivan. You are Jack
Thursby. You are not married to Amy Sullivan.
Your wife is Diane Thursby.
You live in Redmond, Washington.
Accordingly to foster
financial conditions,
the federal reserve has quickened
the pace of adjustment for its policy,
and in conclusion, a cautious
approach is always the best strategy.
Thank you for your attention.
Excuse me, do you have the time?
- The time? Your watch?
- Yeah, it's 3:30.
Already? Gosh, the last
speech just flew by.
Yeah.
Did you enjoy it?
Oh, yeah. Very much.
Hello?
It's for you.
Digicorp will approach you at the
airport. Tell them you are Jack Thursby.
Tell them you've never
heard of Morgan Sullivan.
Make them think you're brainwashed.
If you're exposed, they'll kill you.
What happened back there?
You're feeling the side effects of
the neutralizing agent in your system.
Don't worry. You'll be fine.
Mr. Sullivan. There's been a
change of plans, Mr. Sullivan.
You need to come to Digicorp's
local office right away.
Mr. Sullivan?
Are you all right?
I think you're mistaken.
My name isn't Sullivan.
You're not Morgan Sullivan?
- You don't work for Digicorp?
- No. My name is Thursby. Jack Thursby.
I think you're looking
for somebody else.
I'm sorry, Mr. Thursby. My mistake.
That's okay.
Hello, sir. How are you?
I just need to see your
boarding pass, please. Thank you.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Excuse me.
- No problem.
Your turn. There's not
much hot water left. Sorry.
Could you make dinner a
half hour earlier tonight?
Sure.
I wrote down a list of
errands I need you to do today.
Okay.
Your car keys are in the
foyer next to your briefcase,
right where you left them.
Planning a trip?
Just some reading to pass the time.
You're expected in
reception, Mr. Thursby.
Down the hall and to the left.
- What's your name?
- Jack Thursby.
My name's Frank Callaway. I'm head
of security for Sunways Systems.
According to your
neuro-graph, you're lying.
You're lying when you say
that your name is Jack Thursby.
You're lying when you say that
you are not an undercover agent.
You are lying when you say that
you do not work for Digicorp.
And I cannot tell you
how happy that makes us.
No way. I am not going
back to that house.
You are in a unique
position here, Morgan.
Digicorp thinks that you're
brainwashed as Jack Thursby.
They think that you passed
our neuro-graph
and they want us to hire you
as one of our agents.
I don't care what they want.
Your counter intelligence work
for Sunways will be very simple.
Digicorp will never suspect
that you're working for us.
So they won't watch you too
closely while you're in the house.
All you have to do is to
place one bug in each room.
You don't fucking understand. I'm
going home. I'm going to my real home.
Your real home is gone, Morgan.
What are you talking about?
Your wife put your house up for sale.
Her lawyer has been trying to
contact you for the last few days.
She filed for divorce three days ago.
I'm sorry, Morgan.
- Look, Morgan, I know this is hard.
- I want to see Rita.
- Who?
- Rita Foster.
- She pulled me out of the brainwashing.
- No, Morgan. You cannot see her.
- Why not? She works for you.
- She does not work for us.
But you sent her to find me
at the hotels, right?
No.
But you know who she works for?
Who does she work for?
- She works for Sebastian Rooks.
- Who's Sebastian Rooks?
Sebastian Rooks is a freelance
operative who we hired
to find out how Digicorp was getting
their agents past our neuro-graph.
Then we asked him to send us
an agent who wasn't brainwashed.
He delivered you.
He's the best in the business, but he's
also very dangerous and very ruthless.
I advise you to stay away from him.
Stay away from him and her.
Look,
we are offering you
a very good deal here.
When your work for us is finished,
we'll give you a new identity
and a new home, somewhere very
far away and safe from Digicorp.
I'm sorry, Mr. Callaway,
but you'll have to find
someone else for your job.
You won't last long out there.
Anywhere you go outside this complex,
Digicorp will have agents watching you.
If you try to run,
if you behave like Morgan
Sullivan instead of Jack Thursby,
they will eliminate you.
Quick. Efficient. Ruthless.
You're fortunate, Morgan. If we hadn't
interrupted the brainwashing process
you'd be like the
other convention guests:
programmed with a new identity and
sent to companies across the globe,
disposed of when you're
no more useful to Digicorp.
You have a chance to fight back.
So, are you ready to be a spy, Morgan?
I'm gonna get some more broccoli.
Phone lines are tapped.
We've got visual in all the rooms.
There they are in the dining room.
The salt shaker gives a
nice angle, doesn't it?
Very well. He believes
he's Jack Thursby.
He believes I'm his wife.
He's adjusted to this house.
- Who's she talking to?
- Digicorp agents.
She's giving them a report on you.
He spends much of his time indoors.
Of course he has no friends and he has
little contact with the outside world.
We've got the internet lines tapped too.
Excellent work, Morgan. Excellent.
My God.
My life is the same as it ever was.
That's because Digicorp monitored
your old life and then duplicated it.
It helps ease the transition
of becoming another person.
That's not who I am anymore.
I
- I smoke cigarettes.
I like to drink scotch.
I play golf.
I'm not supposed to live in the suburbs.
I'm not supposed to be like that.
I'm sorry if you're
disappointed, Morgan.
But that is your vision of Jack Thursby.
It's not Digicorp's.
Can you guys clean up the
camera reception in that hallway?
Yes, Jamison?
This isn't Jamison. It's
Morgan Sullivan. Bitch.
- What do you want, Mr. Sullivan?
- I need your help.
I want to hire Sebastian Rooks.
- Are you still there?
- Goodbye, Mr. Sullivan.
- I'll pay him for his service.
- He doesn't work for individuals.
Ask him to make an exception.
- I'll do whatever it takes.
- You're on your own, I'm sorry.
No. No!
- Listen, you gotta help me.
- There's nothing I can-
You gotta help me, please.
You said I could trust you. I
believed you when you said that.
Meet me at the carwash at Fourth
and Jefferson in three hours.
Morgan! We'll be sending you on
your first assignment next week.
Our surveillance of your
house has already paid off.
We know exactly what sort of data
Digicorp is trying to steal from us.
So tonight you will say that you're
going out of town on a business trip.
Now, you know how to
tell her that, right?
- Morgan?
- Yes.
You will stick
to the script, Morgan.
You won't try anything risky,
do you understand me?
Sebastian Rooks has agreed to help you.
- When does he want to meet me?
- Not yet. He's in the car behind us.
- How much money does Rooks want?
- He's not interested in your money.
It's your situation. He thinks
he can use it to his advantage.
- How?
- I'll be in touch with you in Wichita.
Wichita?
That's where Sunways will be
sending you for your last assignment.
How do you know that?
They haven't even told me.
Rooks knows. He knows everything.
- Can I trust Rooks?
- I can't give you guarantees.
But he has the resources to provide
you with a new life, a new identity.
It's your choice, Mr. Sullivan.
What do I have to do?
Sunways will send you on
a series of assignments.
You'll receive a courier
disk on each trip.
Digicorp agents will be
following you wherever you do.
Let them, that's what Sunways wants.
At each destination you'll
be met by a Sunways contact.
They'll download data onto your disk.
Digicorp's agents will assume you're
receiving valuable information.
As you travel to more cities,
collect more data, and
complete more assignments,
your agent status will rise.
Digicorp will then assume you
have become one of
Sunways top company men.
Jack?
Each disk you bring home will
seem more important than the last.
As they copy the Sunways files,
Digicorp will think they have won
a major victory against
their greatest rival.
In reality, Digicorp is the loser.
Sunways is feeding them corrupt data
that will sabotage their operations.
But make no mistake, Mr. Sullivan.
Sunways is just as ruthless as Digicorp.
Once this operation is complete,
they will eliminate you.
Rooks will protect you.
Please. You can trust me.
We're sending you to Kansas. Wichita.
It's almost over, Morgan.
After this trip to the vault,
your work for us will be finished.
- The vault?
- It's our data warehouse.
It's completely isolated from the outside
world, but we send in agent couriers
if we need to retrieve or add a file.
You will be our next courier.
And Digicorp will they
have hit the mother lode.
Shh! We need to keep our voices down. Switch
this disk with the one in your briefcase,
before you go to the
vault. Take off your ring.
- What?
- Your ring.
This is a tracking device. We'll know
your precise location at all times.
Does this mean we can
see each other again?
I pick you up after you leave
the vault, deliver you to Rooks.
- I mean, after that?
- We can never see each other again.
It would compromise your identity.
I'm never getting out of this, am I?
500 Horse Creek Road, please.
I know where to go.
Settle down, Mr. Sullivan. We
have a long ride ahead of us.
You don't have to pretend to be Thursby.
I know you're not brainwashed.
I know that Sunways has been using
you as a double agent against Digicorp.
Are you going to kill me?
Not if you turn your loyalties to me
instead of Sebastian Rooks. Oh,
yeah. I know that you work for him.
As a matter of fact, we both do.
I'm Rooks' inside source at Digicorp.
- His what?
- He paid me to hire you
so you could be his pawn once
you were sent off to Sunways.
You didn't think I hired you because
I was impressed by you, did you?
It's a good plan, really.
Rooks knew that you'd end up here in
Kansas on the way to the Sunways vault.
He knew he could convince you
to switch their disk with his.
- That was his scheme from the very start.
- It's not possible.
Rooks' disk contains a search program.
It penetrates the vault's secure network
and quietly steal a data file
without triggering any alarms.
What data file?
Who knows? But if Rooks has gone
through all this trouble to get it,
it must be extremely valuable.
The plan was foolproof.
Except for one factor
he failed to consider:
me.
What do you want?
When you come out of the vault,
deliver the disk to me, not Rooks.
I've been loyal to Digicorp all along.
Why should I trust you or Digicorp?
Because we'll let you live and
Rooks won't. It's as simple as that.
No one sees his face and
lives to tell about it.
No one sees his face?
He's a deep cover operative.
A Yuri in cyberspace.
He's a phantom. Companies hire him
without actually knowing who he is.
If they did, they'd kill him.
The moment you give that disk to
Rooks is the moment he eliminates you.
There's only one person Rooks
trusts with his identity:
Rita Foster, his lover.
She's completely loyal
to him. No one else.
I'm the only person you can trust now.
I'll be nearby when you come out.
Just in case we get separated.
No charge for the ride.
Good evening, Mr. Thursby.
My name's Virgil Dunn.
Welcome to the vault.
Your first time?
Hope you didn't have a big dinner.
Step ahead, please.
Now that we know you are bug free,
I can call you by
your real name, Morgan.
Dunn, Virgil C.
I need your disk now, please.
Good, good.
Digicorp will cream in their pants
when they copy the bogus data
that I just cooked up for them.
You wouldn't believe
the number of times
they tried to jack
into the systems down here.
- Have they ever succeeded?
- Hell, no.
This place is tighter
than a nun's asshole.
Uh, snort while we wait?
Sure.
I distilled it myself down here. One
of my little hobbies to pass the time.
- Thanks.
- Here's to the information agent.
I used to be an agent like you once.
I was the best mole
spotter in the business.
You put me in a room with
a possible double agent,
let me ask him a couple of questions,
and I could tell you right there
whether he was a spy or not.
That was before Sunways sent me
down here. That was three years ago.
- What happened?
- Those fucking machines is what happened.
They said the neuro-graphs were
100% accurate, but I wasn't.
That a really good spy, a really
good liar, could trick me every time.
It's bullshit, I told them.
But they wouldn't listen.
You see, there are things that only a person
can know about another person, Mr. Sullivan,
things that a machine
could never pick up.
For example, let me ask you
a couple of questions.
Excuse me?
What is your favourite drink? Go ahead.
Answer. I just want to prove my point.
What is your favourite drink?
Er, scotch, single malt, on the rocks.
You're telling the truth.
- Are you married?
- Yes, I am.
Truth again. See, you're very
- very easy to read.
Now
- Are you in love with your wife?
- Yes.
- There, you just lied. Am I right?
Yes, I lied.
It's more than just questions, however.
For instance, I'm sensing
a kind of tension in you.
It's been evident ever since
I put your disk in my computer.
Now why would that be? We both
know the disk is from Sunways.
That's nothing that
should make you uneasy.
- One last question, all right?
- Sure.
Are you a double agent?
Where's Mr. Dunn?
He decided to stay in his office.
- Right. You can go ahead, Mr. Sullivan.
- Thank you.
Open the door!
Emergency crews are on their way.
For your safety, please
remain inside the elevator.
Emergency crews are on their way.
For your safety, please
remain inside the elevator.
Jump!
Now!
I told you I'd know where you'd be.
- Is this Rooks?
- I can take the disk now.
Jamison, one of our operatives.
Rooks is back at the hotel.
He's looking forward to seeing you.
The car's waiting downstairs.
Call me when you get to the lab.
- This is where Rooks lives?
- For now. He moves around a lot.
- But you know where he is at all times?
- We have a special relationship.
Your assignment is nearly
finished, Mr. Sullivan.
I'll be back in a moment.
Finster.
- It's Morgan Sullivan.
- Sullivan! What happened to you?
I'm in the penthouse suite of an old
building. I don't know where it is.
We're tracing the call. We'll
be there shortly. Where's Rooks?
- I'm just about to meet him.
- Get off the phone before he sees you.
He will kill you, understand? Hold
on to the disk. We're on our way.
- Don't come any closer.
- Put the gun down, Mr. Sullivan.
I'll break it. You come
any further, I'll break it.
I gave you the Sunways disk. This
one is yours. The one Rooks wants.
Stop!
- You really don't want to do that.
- You used me. You and Rooks.
- You used me from the very start.
- Wait, let me explain.
No. Finster already
explained everything.
- When did you talk to Finster?
- He's on his way. I just called him.
If Rooks wants this disk
before Finster arrives,
you better unlock that
door and let me go.
Listen to me. Sebastian Rooks is
not the person you think he is.
Sebastian Rooks is a ruthless spy
- and so are you.
- No, you're wrong. He's-
I know about you.
I know about the two of you. I know
about your special relationship.
Please, just hear me out. I-
I don't want to hear any more lies!
God! I can't believe I thought
you actually cared about me.
- I can't believe I was such a fool.
- I do care about you.
No, no.
Just go see Rooks. It'll be okay.
Hurry. Find him.
I tried stopping you, but you insisted.
You said it was the only way to
steal the data from the vault.
Welcome home, Mr. Rooks.
Come on. Finster will
be here any minute.
No, no. No more lies. You
can't trick me anymore.
Listen to me. You are
not Morgan Sullivan.
You created him out of
your own imagination.
Your life in the suburbs, your
miserable marriage-- Your wife, Amy,
was one of your own
operatives playing a part
you assigned her.
The more you fight the
truth, the more it'll hurt.
It's not possible.
You used the same brainwashing
technique Digicorp uses.
You were the one who sold them
the technology to begin with.
- This makes no sense!
- It makes perfect sense!
By turning yourself into Morgan Sullivan
was the only way you could pass
Digicorp's neuro-graph.
It was the only way you could get hired
to be their spy and get sent to Sunways.
- Why would anyone do this?
- For this.
- What's on it?
- I was hoping you could tell me.
You don't know?
I've put a lot of faith
into this assignment.
Clear! Freeze! Don't move!
Sunways Security! Identify
yourself! Digicorp Security!
- You're following me, Callaway?
- I'm here for Rooks, not you.
That's who I am here for.
- You've flown this before?
- No, never.
You know how to fly it. You designed it.
- I don't know what to do.
- Sebastian Rooks knows.
- I can't remember Sebastian Rooks!
- You remembered that you loved me.
Just think.
We're out.
Did you get a look at him?
Did you see Rooks' face?
Just Morgan Sullivan, our pawn.
Jesus! He's Rooks.
Is it what you want?
Yes.
Yes. It's you.
The file in the vault was
erased. And this is the only copy.
Now there's no copy at all.