Come on.
The problem is,
our economy is slowing down.
You all know that
as well as anybody does.
I bet you've got friends and maybe
yourself understand what it means
to have credit card debt, and when
you couple that with high energy bills,
there are some people
beginning to feel pinched.
It makes sense.
To take control...
John?
Honey, what's wrong?
- What are you doing?
- What's it look like?
- That's my car.
- That's not what the bank says.
- Come on!
- Try paying your bills.
What's going on?
I'm sorry. I talked to the bank.
They promised they'd work with me.
- John, that was two months ago.
- We're down to one last month's rent.
It's either the car
or the house, so I thought...
- You thought.
- You want them to throw us out?
I'm down to 20 hours at the plant.
They're shipping all the jobs to Mexico.
- What do you want me to do?
- John, my car is gone.
I understand. Now you see I'm trying
to find a second job, baby.
You want me to say it's fine?
All right, it's fine.
The car is still ours. We own it.
I got to wait for my next cheque.
In two weeks, we'll be fine.
Mikey!
Yeah! Ronnie Coleman.
Mr Olympia two year running.
- Sit down. Eat breakfast.
- I am eating.
- A doughnut isn't breakfast.
- It's the continental breakfast.
- We're not on a continent right now.
- Dad, what do you call North America?
You're not going to school
till you eat breakfast, so eat.
Both of you.
I can't believe those jerks took our car.
Can you, Mom?
- No, I can't.
- What are we going to do?
You're going to do something, right, Dad?
You know what I'd do?
I'd get so big and mad,
I'd go crazy and kick someone's butt.
- Watch your language.
- I would.
You been watching
too much WW Wrestling.
Not wrestling, Dad. Bodybuilding.
There's a big difference.
Get your books.
You're going to be late.
Hurry up, baby.
Can I get a ride to work?
п I love you ап
п Oh, you know I really do ап
- All right, all right. I got a good one.
- ап If I ever seen a girl ап
п That... ап
Go ahead.
п That you needed ап
- Radishes.
- No, it's...
Reddish stick.
- I swear.
- It's "radio station."
Radio station. Okay.
That's a good one. You got me.
Honey?
- Hundred dollars?
- No, we talked about it this morning.
- Continent.
- Got you, right? Mom?
- How about you, Mom?
- Come on, baby.
- You just laugh at me.
- I don't like it. I'm no good at it.
- All right, something in the car.
- We won't laugh.
Please?
- All right.
- We can't know what you're saying.
What? What did you say?
I said...
What?
- Come get this woman, please.
- What, it's no good?
Come on. Come on, baby.
I'll thumb-wrestle you.
- All right.
- One, two, three.
- One, two, three. She wins.
- You got it.
I am queen.
- All right, I got one.
- I got one for you. You're going to school.
Get your lunch.
Dad, I got $46
I saved from my allowance.
- You can have it if you want.
- Yeah?
We're a family.
We got to stick together, right?
That's right. But you earned
that money, so you keep it, okay?
All right. See you later.
- Bye, Mike.
- Not good-bye. I hate good-bye.
- Remember? "See you later."
- All right, see you later.
Flex Wheeler...
275 pounds, 2% body fat.
Yeah, baby.
- John! You take my grinding wheel?
- What?
My grinding wheel!
- I do, don't I?
- You do?
- Yeah, I have sex appeal.
- No, it's not in my locker.
- My grinding wheel.
- Do you want mine?
Only two people know
the combination to my locker.
That's my grinder and you know it.
- John! Smoke, all right?
- All right.
- What's with the tie? Somebody die?
- You like that?
That's the tie I'm wearing to my funeral
if I don't get this job at Otisville today.
- There are no jobs.
- I saw it in the classifieds. They're hiring.
- Forget about it.
- I got to go, though.
- How come?
- They repo'd our car this morning.
Oh, boy.
- You want me to go with you?
- Come on.
Fifty cents!
This is a frigging waste of time.
Four hundred people for one job?
Give me a break.
Guaranteed somebody's son, cousin,
uncle already got this job sewn up.
Why did they put it in the paper
if they're not hiring?
It's a frigging run-around.
Mark my words.
It's either, "We'll keep your application
on file" or, "You're overqualified."
- Either way, they screw you.
- Archibald!
I've been working heavy machinery
for 15 years.
I really want the job.
Anything you want, I can do.
- I see.
- I can start today if you need.
Your rжsumж is very impressive.
You've certainly got the experience.
Frankly, you may be overqualified.
We'll keep your application on file.
п Jesus loves me, this I know ап
п For the Bible tells... ап
Dad, the game starts in 15 minutes.
We're going to be late.
п... to him belong ап
п They are weak, but he is strong ап
п Yes, Jesus loves me ап
п The Bible tells me so ап
Knock it out, baby!
Come on! To the fence!
Come on, Tommy!
Ball four!
Go, Mikey!
Let's go, baby.
Let's go, son. All right.
- Come on, boy!
- Knock it out!
- Keep your head down on the ball, son.
- Knock it out for your mama, baby.
Come on, Mikey!
- Sometime today, pitcher.
- There you go.
- Strike!
- Don't worry about it, son.
- You blind?
- Keep your head down on the ball!
- I hate this pitcher. How old is he?
- He's supposed to be twelve.
Twelve, my ass. Look at him.
His beard grew an inch between pitches.
- For your mama, baby.
- Put your elbow up, son.
- Go, baby!
- There you go, baby!
Safe!
- Safe?
- Tie goes to the runner.
Run!
Second base!
- Michael?
- Mikey, baby.
Somebody call an ambulance!
Somebody call
a frigging ambulance!
- Get the door!
- Get the door, Jimmy.
- Got it. Come on, let's go!
- It's going to be okay.
- Take him, baby.
- Give him to me.
It's Mama. Come on, Mikey.
We got to get out of here. Go!
- Help us!
- Help! Please, somebody.
- Calm down.
- He's not breathing.
All right, come with me.
He was just playing baseball,
running to second base.
- I don't know what happened.
- I need a doctor right away, please!
No. Jesus.
- What happened?
- He collapsed playing baseball.
- Get him on oxygen.
- Look at Mama.
- He's going to be all right, isn't he?
- Wake up.
- Anything like this ever happen before?
- No, ma'am.
- Any allergies?
- Nothing.
- No medication within the past year?
- Nothing!
- Allergies to medication?
- He's fine. He just fell down.
His liver's enlarged. Flip him.
- He's going to be all right, isn't he?
- Pulse is 150, pulse ox 78%.
- B.P. 68 over 34.
- What is the matter with him?
Would you come with me?
There are procedures we need to go over.
- What kind of procedures?
- We're admitting your son.
- You need to fill out the proper forms.
- What kind of forms?
Your son may need a transfusion.
We'll need to test you both for blood type.
- We're coming right back, baby.
- Wait a minute!
- First name, Mr Archibald.
- John.
- Middle initial?
- Q. Quincy.
Name of your insurance company?
- Where is he? Is he okay?
- We don't know. They're running tests.
- We're waiting to find the results.
- Is there anything we can do?
- Your card, Mr Archibald.
- I'm sorry.
Your insurance card.
I'll need to make a copy for our files.
It's okay. You can go in now.
Sweetheart.
How you doing, slugger?
I can't talk.
Don't worry about it. Get your rest.
We're going to be out of here in a while.
- We love you, son.
- I love you, too.
What is all this?
This? This is so we can
monitor Mike's vitals.
Respiratory rate,
pulse oximetry, heart rate.
And this one is blood pressure...
diastolic and systolic.
We'd like this top number
to stay above 90.
If his blood pressure drops,
we're going to have to do something.
We can't have him going
below 70 again.
Why? What would that mean,
if he went below 70 again?
70 and below, he's in heart failure.
- If you need anything.
- Thank you.
- How's the company insurance?
- He works part time.
- She works as a grocery store clerk.
- Can we do anything?
I got to go.
Mr and Mrs Archibald.
I'm Rebecca Payne, Hospital Director.
Hi there.
It's nice to meet you.
This is Dr Turner, head of Cardiology
and Michael's doctor.
- How do you do?
- Good. My wife.
How's our boy doing?
Please sit down.
This x-ray shows
a normal nine-year-old's heart.
This x-ray is that of your son Michael.
There are septal defects
here, here, and here
which have induced myopathy,
resulting pulmonary edema,
and malignant ventricular ectopy.
Michael's heart is approximately
three times larger than normal size.
I'm sorry.
I didn't understand what you said.
Could you put that in layman terms?
Basically, there's not enough blood
being pumped by Michael's heart,
so it backs up in the lungs
like a sponge getting wet.
His heart is trying,
but it's working too hard.
What, does he need
an operation, or...
We're considerably beyond
corrective surgery, Mr and Mrs Archibald.
Mike's heart is useless.
He's going to need a transplant
or he's going to die.
Wait a second.
There are other options.
- What options?
- To do nothing.
Medicate him. Make him feel
as comfortable as possible.
You're going to have to start thinking
about quality of life now.
I don't understand.
We were just with him
and he seemed fine.
He's going to seem fine,
but as his heart gets worse,
he will become increasingly fatigued,
and he will sleep more and more,
until one day he will fall asleep,
and he won't wake up.
I know this is difficult,
but you have to face the fact
that your son
may not live much longer.
You might want to make it
a happy time, say good-bye.
God.
Transplantation is a high-risk operation.
You could lose your son on that table.
You might not want
to take that chance.
If he doesn't have the surgery...
If he doesn't have the surgery,
how long would he live?
Not long. Months, weeks.
Days.
Come on. All right.
Come on, now.
I'm sorry.
This is a lot.
All right.
If he was your son,
what would you do?
- I'd do the transplant, absolutely.
- Okay. Okay?
Let's do that. Let's do it.
First we've got to get Mike's name
on the organ recipient list.
He's B-positive, so his name
should go right to the top.
It's not so simple.
There are other considerations before
a recipient can be placed on a donor list.
Transplant surgery is very expensive.
In most cases, prohibitively so.
We got insurance, major medical.
He's covered.
We've already checked
with your carrier, Mr Archibald.
There are no provisions in your policy
for a procedure of this magnitude.
That's a mistake.
Not that you're making a mistake.
I'm just saying that I'm insured.
My son's covered.
Mrs Archibald,
do you have coverage?
No. I've only been working
at the supermarket a couple months.
- You don't get benefits until...
- Doesn't matter. We got insurance.
I can see here
that you don't own your home.
You have no stocks,
no bonds, no investments.
- You have a little over $1,000 in savings.
- But we got insurance.
That may very well be. You're going to
have to check with your carrier.
In the meantime, we're going to
have to treat this as a cash account.
- What?
- How much does a transplant cost?
Wait a minute.
How much does it cost?
Transplant surgery,
doctors' fees, postoperative care,
immunosuppressant drugs...
you're looking at a minimum of $250,000.
If you opt for transplant surgery,
that is your choice,
but the hospital maintains a very
strict policy with regard to cash patients.
We require down payment before we put
a patient's name on a receivers' list.
- How much?
- What kind of down payment?
30%... $75,000.
$75,000...
- To put my son's name on a list.
- Our son is upstairs dying.
- All you can do is talk about money?
- It costs money to provide health care.
It's expensive for you,
it's expensive for us.
You're going to
have to guarantee payment
before I can put
your son's name on the list.
Mr and Mrs Archibald,
please wait!
If you people don't want to treat our son,
we'll take him over to County Memorial.
- You don't want to do that.
- They have to treat him.
Heart transplantation is
always considered an elective procedure.
- You're in the right place.
- What are we supposed to do?
Talk to your insurance company again.
Check with our human resources
department for medical assistance.
There's money. There's Children's
State Services and Medicaid.
You find a way to keep him here.
You just don't take no for an answer.
Your policy has changed,
Mr Archibald.
Changed to what?
We've recently switched carriers
from a PPO to an HMO.
It's a less expensive policy.
Unfortunately, there are some restrictions.
- What kind of restrictions?
- Here's how it works.
Non-management
part-time employees such as yourself
only qualify for second-tier
catastrophic coverage.
I'm not part time, I'm full time.
It's just slow right now.
Sure, but your coverage
is based on hours worked.
Like I said,
you only qualify for second tier.
That has a maximum
payout limit of $20,000.
What?
You have been taking money
out of my cheque every week.
I've been paying into
this policy for years.
That's why we're going to cover you
for the full $20,000.
You're kidding me, right?
Come on.
You have dropped me from full time
to part time. You switched carriers.
Now you're telling me I'm not fully covered
even though I got a policy that says I am?
- It doesn't seem right, does it?
- No, it doesn't. My son is very sick.
If I'm not covered,
I got a serious problem.
I understand that,
but there's nothing I can do.
- You can file an appeal.
- Yeah?
Here you go. That takes
about seven working days.
Says here you already have
medical insurance.
- Not enough.
- What little we have is already used up.
You on welfare?
- You should be on welfare.
- We both have jobs.
That's too bad.
I'm sorry. I can't help you.
Try County Medical.
Yes, ma'am, I need to speak
to somebody in Financial Aid.
No, I don't want to hold.
I've been holding for 15 minutes.
We don't have enough money!
Should I get another job?
- I'm not yelling.
- You're yelling in here!
Next, please.
- Wrong line. Window 15.
- What?
Window 15.
- No.
- No, what?
No, you don't qualify.
My son is dying, I'm broke.
If I don't qualify, who the hell does?
I'm sorry.
I don't need you to be sorry!
I need you to help me!
No, this is an appeal.
An appeal is for an already existing claim.
You needed to file a grievance.
- You filed the wrong paperwork.
- Wait a minute.
You're going to have to resubmit.
It could take 30 days.
- I don't have 30 days.
- I know.
I'm getting sick of the run-around.
I need my son's name on that list.
Your account is in excess of $30,000.
The hospital has bent over backwards
to help you out.
- Is that right?
- Yes, it is right.
But there is a limit to our generosity.
Once and for all,
your insurance does not cover this.
Take it.
- Watch your step.
- This thing is frigging heavy.
Get out of the way.
Friends, one among us
is suffering in great pain today.
This is a good man.
"'You can't say
that you're not going to pitch. '
Bernie frowned,
puzzled by Babe's answer. 'Okay, Babe."'
Let us pray.
God of mercy, into his hands
Your son Jesus Christ
commended his spirit
at his last hour.
Into those same hands,
we commend Your servant...
You should try that news guy
does all them special investigative reports.
You know the one,
the guy with the frigging hair?
- Pretty boy. What's his frigging name?
- Lampley.
- Tuck Lampley.
- I'll give you $20 for the TV.
- It's a colour TV.
- $20.
Call him up, Jimmy.
You don't mind if we walk and talk.
I'm up to here today.
- Not at all.
- What can I do you for?
My son Mike, he fell into heart failure
at this Little League game.
I got full insurance from the job.
Now they're telling me they won't pay.
What about the hospital?
Don't they have to cover it?
- That's what I was saying.
- They're telling me I got to pay cash.
Otherwise I got to take my son home
and watch him die.
We was thinking you can do
one of them special interest pieces.
Send donations,
write your congressman.
Anything you can do,
Mr Lampley, would help.
I think what's happening to your son
is outrageous. I want to help.
I got to run this by my producers.
I got bosses like everybody else.
- Right.
- Leave your number with Karen up front.
Thank you very much.
Give me $100.
Come on, it's a diamond ring.
All right, $90.
Give me $90, then.
He's going to die.
- What?
- They're releasing him.
- Who?
- Dr Turner just left here.
They are releasing Mike this morning.
They're not going to send him home.
I gave them money yesterday.
It doesn't matter. Listen to me.
They are releasing him.
I talked to the hospital.
They said... I'll take care of it.
You always take care of everything,
but it's never enough, is it?
You need to do something,
do you hear me?
Do something!
You're doing great. You really are.
You've gained what, five pounds?
You're the only patient I have
who eats the food in this place.
Doc, let me ask you something.
How long before I'm able to play tennis?
You couldn't play before you had
a new heart. Take up knitting.
- I play tennis.
- We don't care.
Would you please
get back to work? Thank you.
Heidi, make an appointment
for us to have dinner next week.
I'm going to cook.
No, and you're not wearing lingerie
around him the next month.
You're not in his will. He told me.
Don't push your luck.
I gave the hospital $6,000 yesterday.
- Can I talk to you?
- Yes, sure.
- Take care of him.
- Take care. Thank you.
My wife Denise says you're going to
send Michael home. Is that true?
I'm a physician.
I don't make policy decisions.
- That's handled by the board of trustees.
- You're the head of cardiac surgery.
You make a recommendation,
they're going to listen, aren't they?
I make recommendations all the time.
The final decision rests with the board.
- That's it? Send him home.
- I'm afraid so.
Can we take a little walk?
It won't take long, I promise you.
Fine.
I'm looking at the brochure last night.
It says this hospital
does over 300 heart surgeries a year.
300 surgeries, $250,000 a pop.
You know how much that is?
I did the math.
That's $75 million worth
of heart surgeries.
You're telling me
you can't do one for me in good faith?
I waived my fee in your son's case.
I know you're not asking...
Nobody asked you to waive the fee.
I can raise the money.
I already came up with $22,000,
and I swear to God on my life
I will pay for this
if you give me the opportunity.
I'm only getting 20 hours on the job.
I can do this. I can pay.
I swear to God,
I'll pay you the money back.
I don't know how,
but I promise you I will. Trust me.
I give you my word
as a man. Please.
Could you take your hands
off me, please?
- I've done everything I can. I'm sorry.
- No, you haven't.
- Yes.
- Let's go inside and talk about it.
I'm not asking anymore, Doctor.
I'm telling you.
You are going to give my son
a new heart, you understand me?
Don't move.
Don't even think about it.
Put your hands down.
- Mr Archibald, I...
- Shut up.
I know how upset you are,
but this is not the way to handle it.
You can't go through this way.
Put your hands up.
- Put them up.
- Oh, God.
- Give me your gun.
- I don't have a gun.
They don't have guns.
They're not armed.
All right. Put your hands down.
Sit down. No, get up.
- You fail to realise the jeopardy...
- Get over here. Shut up!
- We have got to talk about this.
- Shut up. Don't move.
John, wait.
Just stop. Stop!
If you do this, you're on
an irreversible course of action.
Put on the brakes
and think about this.
- We really need to talk.
- Mr Archibald, I hope...
- Back up, please.
- What?
- Do as he says.
- Would you please back up?
- What are you doing?
- I'm not taking no for an answer.
- Back up.
- That guy's got a gun!
Stay right there.
What are you doing?
Get back over there.
Sit on your hands over there!
Get over there!
Turner, everybody, get down!
Sit on your hands!
Put your hands under your butt!
Don't anybody move.
What are you doing?
I'm bleeding. Trying to get
my goddamned finger sewn back on.
Mr Archibald, these people
have nothing to do with this.
Let them go.
They need treatment.
This is a hospital. You're a doctor.
Why don't you treat them? Start with him.
What's the matter, Doctor?
You want to see his insurance card first?
- I'll do it.
- Okay, you do it.
Wait a minute.
I got a pregnant wife here.
Listen, all right, wait.
Listen, everybody.
The hospital's
under new management now.
From now on, free health care
for everybody. How's that?
Righteous, man.
Don't have to squeeze it like...
You crazy?
- What's your name?
- Max.
You and Dr Turner come with me.
- You got keys for that elevator?
- Yeah.
I want you to kill the power.
Turn it off.
- Keep an eye on him, Max.
- You got to sit still.
- I can't do this with you moving around.
- You remind me of Doogie Howser.
- We were here before the black guy.
- Everybody's going to get their turn.
We're not going anywhere
for a while, so just sit tight.
Just relax, okay?
- Is this Hope Memorial Hospital?
- Yeah, emergency room.
Could you give me directions?
I need to get over there.
No, ma'am.
We're closed for repairs right now.
You're going to have to call...
- This is an emergency!
- Have you tried Mount Angel?
No. That's too far.
My husband usually drives.
- I'm going to need directions.
- Which way are you coming from?
Go down Flower, make a right turn,
go all the way to the end, make a left.
- You understand?
- I'm asking you to do something.
You're welcome.
Miss, come from under there.
Come from out of there.
Come on out.
What? No, what?
Go sit over there.
Unbelievable.
This place is a joke.
Good thing I'm not cut.
I'd bleed to death in this joint, am I right?
Excuse me, brother man!
No. You need to do something,
Steve, all right?
You need to get your butt up!
- I want you to do something.
- Would you please sit down?
- I don't want to sit down!
- What is wrong with you?
Wait a minute.
Relax. Don't have the baby yet.
When is it due?
- Any minute.
- Don't have it.
- I'm having it.
- Not yet. Hang on.
- Brother.
- She's having a baby. Hang on a second.
- Excuse me, brother man.
- The woman's having a baby!
- When is she going to see a doctor?
- Sit down!
- That's cool.
- Dr Klein!
- I'll be there in a minute.
- You and me, we got no problems.
That's right.
Just stay in your seat.
I don't understand
what you're saying, ma'am.
The ear? Ear infection?
Can you help her with the ear infection?
- Me? I can't.
- Why not?
I don't know anything.
It's my first day.
Everybody, in the other room.
Everybody, in the other room right now.
They're going to take
great care of you, I promise.
- What? Open up!
- It's dropping.
We've got a gunshot victim out here.
He's lost a lot of blood.
- Go to another hospital.
- Let's go. Open the door.
You know these guys?
You sure?
- They're here all the time.
- Open the door.
- Take your jacket off.
- What?
Open it up. Take it off.
Put it on the ground. Walk away.
Just leave him right there. Go!
Just go.
- What's wrong with him?
- He got shot.
All right, come on.
Wait a minute.
I want to see what's in that bag.
What happened to you, buddy?
I gave them all the money in the register.
They shot me anyway.
Jesus Christ.
He needs to go into surgery right now.
Can I take him to Trauma One?
- Thanks.
- What do we got?
- Gunshot wound to the belly.
- Anything from the EMTs?
No. Dr Turner,
we're going to need your hand.
- I just bought this suit.
- Can you give me a hand?
On three, two, one, lift.
Thank you.
I can't handle a gut shot.
I'm a cardiac surgeon,
not an emergency room physician.
It's like riding a bike, Doctor.
Just pretend you're getting paid.
- This is apples and oranges. I can't.
- The man is dying. Help him.
- I'd like to. I haven't done this...
- Do it!
75 milligrams Demerol I.V.,
lidocaine 2% local.
I'll scrub now.
When I get out of here, I'm suing
this hospital and your security company.
What makes you so sure
you're getting out at all?
Right behind you!
Here we go.
You've got to stand
behind the line, sir.
Move this out of here for me, please?
Thank you very much.
- Lieutenant, we got a real problem here.
- What's that?
This guy's in for the long haul...
locked down the E.R.,
barricaded himself in,
killed power in the elevators.
We can bust down the door, but this
son of a bitch might start killing people.
There's two pinpoint cameras
hidden in the E.R.
- The hospital's own surveillance.
- We got a video tap being set up.
- Are you in charge of security?
- No, that would be Wally Pitoniak.
- He's at home. It's his day off.
- Not anymore, it ain't. Get him here.
All right,
can you get me a secure line?
We've got one of our guys inside.
He's got a walkie-talkie.
You might want to try this.
Put a clamp on all phone lines
to the emergency room.
If this guy picks up the phone,
I want him talking to me.
- Done.
- Who's in charge here?
Rebecca Payne, sir.
It's her day off, too.
Jesus Christ, does anybody
work at this hospital?
- It's Saturday, sir.
- So what?
People get sick
on Saturday, don't they?
Seыor, no cry.
Mr Archibald, I need to do
an internal examination on her.
- Where you going to take her?
- Examination room there.
Good. Go.
- Just remember, it ain't your fault.
- Excuse me.
I think my fiancжe
might have broken her arm.
I was wondering if we could
get somebody to look at her.
- Sure. What happened?
- A drunk ran a red light...
Ran a red light.
He slammed into us. Right?
- It was an accident.
- Yes, it was.
This is the police depantment.
I'm speaking to the man in charge.
Please pick up the walkie-talkie.
The building is surrounded.
There's no way in or out.
If you hear me.
I advise you to respond.
Hello. Is anyone there?
This is Lieutenant Frank Grimes
of the Chicago Police Department.
Are you the man in charge?
- That's right.
- Who am I speaking to?
John...
Q.
All right, John Q.
Again, I'm Lieutenant Grimes,
but I want you to call me Frank.
- Can you do that?
- Sure, Frank.
I'll be the hostage negotiator.
I've been a cop for 35 years.
This is all I do.
I don't play games. I don't fool around.
If I say something,
you can take it to the bank.
Let's get down to it.
Is anybody hurt?
It's an emergency room.
Everybody's hurt.
Right.
- They're fine.
- Good.
As long as it stays that way,
we can keep talking.
What is it you want?
Find Rebecca Payne, Hope Memorial's
Administrative Supervisor.
You find her. Tell her I want
my kid's name on the donors' list.
- Kid boy or girl?
- A boy.
I got two boys myself.
Two girls and two boys.
Don't handle me.
I don't want to be handled.
It insults my intelligence
as a human being!
Take it easy. The idea is
not to get too excited, all right?
I'm going to take it
any way I can get it, understand?
If I don't get it, there's going to be
some dead bodies on your hands in here.
I hear you loud and clear. I'm going to
jot that down. Rebecca Payne, right?
All right.
There's a lot of cops
out here, John.
Are you sure you want
to go through with this?
I'm sure.
All right, sit tight.
You're in a tough spot, a lot of trouble.
If you work with me,
if you're reasonable,
we'll figure a way
out of this, okay?
We have to have a little faith
in one another.
- Why is that, Frank?
- Why?
Because that's what faith's all about...
believing when you don't want to believe.
Besides, what else
are you going to do?
- I want my epidural.
- Too late for that.
- Something for the pain.
- Out! She'll be fine.
- First child?
- Yeah.
Just kind of nervous.
You know how it is.
I was, too. What do you want,
a boy or a girl?
Doesn't matter to me, man,
as long as my kid's healthy.
That's all I want.
Listen, I didn't mean
anything by that.
Who was driving?
The car... who was driving?
I was. What's that
got to do with anything?
Why is your girl
all banged up and you're not?
What do you call this?
- What are you laughing at?
- Somebody get this fool a Band-Aid.
- I don't want you to bleed to death.
- Screw you. That shit hurts.
- His air bag went off and mine didn't.
- What kind of car you drive?
- Mercedes 500.
- You drive a Mercedes 500?
- What year?
- 1986. It's a classic.
Mercedes didn't make
passenger-side air bags till 1988.
- Busted.
- What's your point, John?
- What's yours, Mitch?
- You from the Slap-a-Ho tribe.
You like to beat on that young lady,
and everybody here knows it.
I was drunk, all right?
- Don't smoke in here, Mitch.
- Give me a break. Work with me here.
- I'm trying my best.
- Mr Q, could I get some water?
- I need to tinkle.
- I got missed-meal cramps.
I'm hungry. Let's get a bucket
of chicken or something.
In a minute.
- How's it going in there?
- He's going to make it.
You have any idea how much blood
this guy lost? It's incredible.
He saved this man's life.
- What's that?
- Lasix.
It's a diuretic to help get rid
of some of the fluid build-up.
It's potassium-depleting,
so he needs this one to supplement.
And those?
Dopamine for his blood pressure,
Dig for his heart, Primacor.
- It seems like so much.
- Yeah, it's a lot.
- This is antibiotic.
- What for?
It's prophylactic, just in case.
- And those?
- These two?
- They're for pain.
- I don't feel so good.
This is going to make you feel yucky
for a few minutes, buddy.
I'm going to get you some of those
crunchy ice chips you want.
How does that sound?
Mike, by the way, there was this guy,
he stopped by to see you.
He said he was a friend of yours.
I got him right here.
I didn't know if I should let him in.
What do you think?
- He's okay.
- He's okay?
Said he wanted
to hang out with you.
He's okay.
That's great.
Thank you.
Oh, my baby!
Let me hold my baby!
- Mom? Is Dad coming?
- Yeah, he's coming.
When? Where is he?
I don't know, but he's coming.
What are you up to?
Never mind me. You're worthless.
Some security guard.
You should have zapped the bastard
when you had the chance.
With what? Besides, I'm not sticking
my neck on the line for $8.50 an hour.
- Pay dirt.
- Are you nuts?
- What the hell are you doing?
- Looking out for number one.
You want to stay alive, sit tight
and wait for the cavalry to get here.
The cops are coming in shooting.
They don't care about his kid.
Once he realises that,
we're all history.
If he catches you with that scalpel,
you're the one that's history, asshole.
He don't look so bad to me.
"Ethyl chloride." Just like mace.
Put that stuff back
before you get us in trouble.
You listen, you stupid rent-a-cop.
I am not a slob.
I have a life.
It means something to me.
I'm not going down
in this shit-hole. No, sir.
Back it up.
How are you?
How you all doing?
Good. How are you?
How are you, fellows?
Is it true the man inside
wants an operation for his son?
Everything good?
Good to see you.
- Do you know what weapon he has?
- You'll talk to me, right?
I'll let you know when I know, okay?
You'll be the first.
- I'll let you know later.
- Gus, how are you?
- How you doing, Frank? It's hot.
- Yeah, it is.
- A little early for heavy artillery, isn't it?
- Maybe. Maybe not.
- You should tell me. What's going on?
- You're looking at it.
A very upset father inside. We'll give him
a couple of minutes to cool off.
Let's not give him too much time.
Let's end this quick and quiet.
- That's the plan.
- All right. Good.
In that case, I'm just here
to lend my support in any way that I can.
I don't need a babysitter on this.
It's under control.
- Is it?
- Yes.
All right. Can't have people
running around the street using guns.
Makes it look like the city's unsafe.
Besides, I got to be here.
Chief doesn't show up,
looks like he's asleep at the wheel.
Just stay out of my way.
The TV cameras are over there.
They should make you feel
right at home.
Right. Why don't you just relax?
- Why can't you relax?
- I'm fine.
- Why don't you just do your job?
- I'm doing my job.
We're both cops, right?
We're on the same side, remember?
- Right.
- Right?
It's good to see you. Thanks.
Yes, Mr Mayor.
I'll see you in a little bit.
No, we got it. I got it.
How are you?
The old man, looking for his Depends.
He leave them over here?
What I don't understand is why
they never found it, the doctors.
My son has had clean checkups
every year since the day he was born.
- How could the doctors not pick it up?
- He might not have been tested enough.
Why not?
You got an HMO, right?
There's your answer.
HMOs pay their doctors not to test.
It's their way of keeping costs down.
Say Mike did need additional testing
and insurance says they won't cover them.
The doctor keeps his mouth shut,
and come Christmas,
the HMO sends the doctor
a fat-ass bonus cheque.
- Is that true?
- Possible. Not likely, but possible.
These doctors may have known
what was wrong with my son,
and they could have
treated him all along?
- Who knows? I don't know.
- Don't take this personal, Doc.
- You're a bunch of crooks.
- You don't know what you're talking about.
- What about that thing you take?
- The thing?
That promise.
- It's called the Hippocratic Oath.
- More like the hypocritical oath.
How's it go, Doc?
"I solemnly swear to take care
of the sick and damn-near-dying,
unless they ain't got major medical."
- Something like that?
- You've got it perfectly.
It's funny, but it's not far from the truth.
This shit happens all the time.
Paramedics bring in
some accident victim.
When the boys in Accounting find out
they can't pay, they send them packing.
- Hospitals can't turn people away.
- Isn't there laws against that?
There's also ways around those laws.
We have to stabilise them.
After that, we're off the hook.
- That's not how it works.
- That's exactly how it works.
Maybe not on the fifth floor,
but in here if you don't have money,
you get a Band-Aid, a foot in the ass,
and you're out the door.
Enough already. I've heard all the bitching
and moaning I can stand for one day.
If you all want to regard me as some kind
of blood-sucking vampire, great.
I'll be the bad guy.
But who's holding the fucking gun?
Sir? Lieutenant!
This is Frank Grimes.
You pick up the phone, you get me.
- What can I do for you?
- What's going on with the list?
- I'm working on it, but I need time.
- Time I don't have.
- Let's talk about the hostages.
- What do you want to know?
- What's going on? How are they?
- They're fine. They're full.
We're eating candy bars
and discussing HMOs, waiting for you.
- I want you to let some of them go.
- For what?
I do for you, you do for me.
Show some good faith.
A lot of nervous people out here.
Make everybody breathe a lot easier
if we saw some happy faces.
I'll do for you when you start doing for me.
I want my kid's name on that list.
- I'm not kidding around here.
- Good faith.
- Good faith only takes you so far...
- What's that?
...merit system. So far,
you haven't earned any points.
Excuse me.
I need to talk to you.
This woman is six centimetres dilated.
The baby is breeched.
I've medicated her, but we have to
move her up to Maternity immediately.
- Hang on, Frank.
- Right down here.
- What the hell is going on?
- Do you know this man?
His name is John Archibald.
He has a son here in ICU.
Put people on the door.
Find the mother. I need to talk to her.
- Are you there, Frank?
- I'm here, John.
I changed my mind, all right?
I'm going to let some of the hostages go.
That's the right thing.
But when I do,
the clock starts, you understand?
It's 4:15. You got one hour.
You got till 5:15, you understand?
If my boy's not on that list by 5:15,
somebody in here is going to die.
- Don't be stupid.
- 5:15, Frank!
- 5-1-5, something happens for me!
- Got it.
You're a cop. Call the coroner.
This is bad, Frank.
This has just got to go away.
All right, Miriam...
And Rosa. Vamos.  Let's go.
Mr Archibald,
please let my husband come with me.
I need you to get out of here.
I will be okay. Just go.
- Shit, I'll go. I'm free.
- Steve, baby, no, please.
- What kind of man are you?
- Screw you, Tyrone.
What? Screw me, Tyrone?
Wait a second.
Wait a minute. Just relax.
That's right, tough guy.
Julie, baby.
Get the gun! Come on!
Go over there
and pick up that gun.
Shoot him! Shoot him
right in the face, Julie!
Get up! Get the gun!
There you go, baby.
What are you... are you crazy?
What are you doing?
Come on now!
Max, you got cuffs?
Oh, God!
You stupid bitch!
That's for beating the shit out of me!
And that's for being an asshole!
And this,
this is for calling me a bitch!
I felt that one.
And I'm not going to be
your Barbie anymore!
Goddamn! All that ass
and muscles to go with it.
- I knew damn well you wasn't no blonde.
- Give them to me.
Mitch! Look at me!
Come here.
Let's go, both of you.
Whatever happens, I want you to know
everything's going to be okay.
- You understand me?
- Yes.
Don't worry.
Don't worry about anything.
I'll always be there for you, baby.
Don't shoot!
I'm letting some hostages go!
All right, Steve. You, too.
Let's go, both of you.
- Thank you.
- Muchas gracias. Seыor.
- Thank you, Mr Archibald.
- You, too.
Take care of his ear.
The gunman has just freed
several hostages.
who will immediately be debriefed
by members of the crisis team.
Will the man known as John Q
get a heant for his little boy?
Only time will tell.
From Hope Memorial Hospital.
I'm Tuck Lampley.
Is it true an ambulance dropped off
a victim after the gunman took over?
He unlocked the door
and he let him inside!
- Can you comment?
- The man was critically injured.
If he hadn't let him in,
he would have died.
- Ma'am, are you all right?
- I feel good. We're having a baby!
Ma'am, any comments
about the gunman?
- John Q very good man.
- The gunman?
Very good man!
They got a camera.
They're watching a video feed.
- How do you know?
- They're looking at something.
- I want to know what. Can you get it?
- Boss, if they got it, I can get it.
You give in, there's going to be guns
in every hospital in the country.
You think Mr Archibald's
the only one who has a sick child?
Have you checked the HIV ward?
There's a whole floor full.
People get sick. They die.
That's the way it goes.
I'm faced with
decisions like this every day.
There's a man threatening innocent people
because you refused to help his son.
There are 50 million people in this country
without medical insurance.
If you'd like to change it,
call your congressman.
Excuse me. Why don't we just tell him
his son's name's on the list?
Doesn't that make sense?
How's he going to know, anyway?
Sir? Pardon me.
Can you come take a look at this?
Sarge, Chief Moroe,
this is Wally Pitoniak, head of security.
Nice to meet you.
I got your spot.
Here's your sight.
That's going to be your perch.
The X there, that's your phone.
- Which phone?
- Bring it up, Jeff.
The phone right there.
It is. Tom. But Chief Moroe maintains
the police will do whatever is necessary
to preserve the lives
and safety of these hostages.
- Thanks. Tuck.
- This country, man.
Can't go anywhere anymore without
getting mugged or murdered or stabbed.
Kids killing their classmates.
Drive-bys.
- I won't even go into a post office.
- Shut up, Mitch.
You shut up.
I hate the little bastard, but he's right.
You know how easy it is to get a gun?
Five minutes. Gun show.
I understand your kid is sick, John,
but what makes him better than me?
- I got a life, too.
- But you got insurance.
So what, are you going to shoot me?
That's what you're telling the cops.
If your son doesn't get
the very first heart available, we all die.
How's it going to end, John?
What's your move?
I got no moves, okay?
I don't know what I'm going to do.
I'm waiting on a miracle, okay?
I'm waiting on an act of God.
Could we have a word
with you, please?
This is all my fault.
When the hospital told me
they were releasing Mikey,
I called John and yelled at him,
told him to do something, anything.
But I never thought...
I understand.
Is he a violent man, Mrs Archibald?
No! He's sweet and gentle.
He wouldn't hurt a fly.
That's not what he's saying.
He's talking about killing people.
I may be fishing, but has he spent time
in the military or anything like that?
- What is this?
- What?
I see what's going on here.
You're trying to get me to say something
you can use against my husband.
He's in a lot of trouble.
We're going to need you to talk to him.
Let's get something straight, mister.
You cannot use me
to build a case against my husband.
I support him in everything he does.
I'm on his side, not yours.
And you don't talk to me!
I would tell you
what I think of you...
...but I'm a Christian woman.
Now you two leave me alone.
I have a sick child to look after.
I've decided to put Michael's name
on the recipient list.
The hospital will pay for everything.
Really?
Really.
Thank you.
Oh, God, thank you.
You're good.
- Excuse me?
- Quite the performance.
- What are you talking about?
- Comforting embrace, sincere look.
For a minute,
I actually believed you cared.
We go now to Hope Memorial Hospital.
live... Tuck Lampley.
As you can see. The crowd
in front of Hope Memorial is growing.
The S.W.A.T. Team has arrived.
The situation is becoming tense.
Standing next to me is James Palumbo.
friend of John Archibald.
Mr Palumbo. What can you tell us
about John Archibald?
You know. I got to be honest. Tuck.
This whole thing sucks.
It all could have been avoided
so incredibly easy.
None of this had to happen
if John had been a frigging millionaire
or if his last name was Rockefeller.
but sometimes John don't get it.
He don't understand that what
we hold sacred in this country isn't values.
It's value that's important.
We got haves. We got have-nots.
We've got white collar.
blue collar. And no collar.
Inside there we got surgery.
outpatient surgery. Out-of-luck surgery.
There's a lot of people out there
who don't got 250 grand in their billfold.
To shame a man like that
and back him into a corner.
seems to me that something
is out of whack. Not someone.
But what do I know?
I'm a factory worker.
I see this is making you upset.
but if you could look into the camera
and speak to John Q right now.
what would you say to him?
I'm there with you.
and you take care.
That's one man's opinion.
Live at the crisis at Hope Memorial.
this is Tuck Lampley.
What's going on?
Where's everybody?
We're sending one of our guys
in through the air duct.
If we can get the target
to this phone, we got a clear shot.
- Is that right?
- Yes, Lieutenant, that is right.
When you're ready, Chief.
- My wife's calling.
- Worse than that. It's Father Time.
Come over here!
Not one word.
I don't want to hear it.
You're going behind my back!
What do you want from me?
Look at the clock! Look at your watch!
The guy said at a quarter after,
he's going to start killing people.
- This is so goddamned stupid!
- What's your great idea?
There are no great ideas,
especially this!
I got a shot at this guy,
I'm going to take it.
You know the drill.
Always take the open shot.
The wife has agreed to speak to him.
Let her talk him down.
- That's exactly what I'm going to do.
- You used the wife to set him up?
I'm going to use whatever works.
Let me paint a picture for you.
What we have is a lose/lose. This guy
starts whacking hostages, that's bad.
If we give into this asshole,
it's also bad.
- Bad for who?
- Everybody. Me, you, everybody.
It's an election year.
However it goes down,
this guy's not going to make it.
- You kill him, that's a P.R. bonanza?
- I can live with one dead bad guy.
What I can't live with is one innocent
person being hurt, not on my watch.
You know what, Frank?
You're out!
- I'm out?
- You're officially relieved of duty.
- I'm going to handle this now.
- You?
Me. You think it's my first time
around the dance floor?
How do you think I got these?
And watch it.
I got a lot of pressure on me.
There's a lot of eyes watching.
Someone's got to make the call.
You're not going to do it, are you?
I'll do it.
What about the hostages,
the human beings?
Better keep their heads down.
- Great.
- What is it?
The air conditioning just turned off.
I'm counting on you.
Don't let me down, okay? I'll call you!
Right on. Excuse me. Sorry.
Don't touch me!
Excuse me. Thank you.
Tuck Lampley, Channel 8?
Right. You got it.
Thanks, Officer! Excuse me.
Where's my picture?
I got to unscramble the police encryption.
We're almost there.
Hurry up.
I got a contact in Cardiology.
The cops are going to set up a call
between this guy and his wife.
Are you with the wife?
All right, let's patch it through.
This better be good, Frank.
God, baby.
- We're on the list.
- What?
Payne just left here.
Mikey's name is on the list.
- Baby, you did it.
- What? We're on the list?
This is great, baby.
- We got sound.
- Where's the video? I need picture.
Boss, hang on.
I'm going to make you really famous.
I'm just...
That's great, baby.
How's Mikey doing?
Not too good.
I think he's going away.
What?
They've done everything they can for him,
but he keeps getting worse and worse.
Oh, God.
Our poor baby.
Are you praying for him, John?
Are you praying for our baby?
Yes, sweetheart.
You know I am.
Checkmate.
This is the White Rook. Copy.
I copy, White Rook.
It's going to be all right, sweetheart.
Listen to me.
He's going to make it.
I swear on my life, he's going to make it.
You understand me?
You just got to believe me,
you understand?
I believe.
Is he awake? Is Mikey awake?
Can I talk to him?
Hold on.
Oh, my God.
We got it! Boss!
The video's online.
- You are a genius.
- I got to get the monitor.
What are you doing standing around?
Move your ass! This is it!
Thank you.
Freddy, I swear to God...
Nigel, you're moving
like lava. Hustle.
How's my hair?
Never mind. Let's get this.
And three, two, one.
This is Tuck Lampley,
live at Hope Memorial Hospital,
bringing you exclusive coverage
between a father and his son
he's fighting
most desperately to save.
Honey?
It's your dad.
He's on the phone.
Champ.
How's my boy?
You hanging in there?
- How are you?
- How am I? I'm good.
Don't worry about me.
I'm good.
How come you're not here, Dad?
I'm tied up. I can't get away now.
But I'm close. real close to you.
Mom says I need a new heart.
That's right, champ. You do.
But what's wrong with my heart?
There's nothing wrong.
It's just that you...
You just need a...
They're going to...
You got to get a better heart
to be stronger, that's all.
They're giving you a new one
that's going to make you real strong.
Am I going to die?
No, you're not going to die.
Of course not.
How do you know?
What good would
the world be without you?
Oh, my God. This is
the greatest thing I've ever seen.
Without you there is no world.
This is my white Bronco.
Listen to me.
On your command.
You know I love you, don't you?
You know how proud I am of you?
I just wanted to make sure
you know that.
I just wanted to tell you that
in case I forgot.
Take the shot.
It's not clear.
Holding.
Why don't you give me
one of those Chris Cormeirs?
Chris Cormeir. He's great.
He's great and so are you, baby.
I love you, Dad.
Okay, son.
I'll talk to you later, okay?
With all my heant. Son.
I love you.
- I love you. Too. Dad.
- Oh, shit!
You're on TV, man.
Channel 8.
He's down. We got him.
He's not down.
Goddamn it!
Command. Yes, sir.
- This is very bad, Gus.
- Not now.
It's the mayor, sir.
We better kill this video feed.
The press hacked into our signal.
This went out live over national television.
- Mikey's not going to make it.
- What about the list?
What list? They're shooting
at me, shooting at us.
They're not going to help my son.
The sniper gained access
to the hospital through the venti...
- Are you going to bust me?
- Out of here.
You just shot an innocent man
on prime-time TV.
Where's Grimes?
Hang in there, man!
Where's Lieutenant Grimes?
- All right.
- All right what?
- Let's go see what he wants.
- You've got to be kidding.
Don't start breaking my balls.
I screwed up, all right?
I need you to save my ass.
I really stepped in shit. Please.
Come on, I'll buy you a steak.
Peking duck. Let's go.
A-R-C-H-l-B-A-L-D.
I'm faxing you
all the stuff right now.
Come over here.
- Hold your fire!
- Don't fire. Turn them down.
There's a lot of cameras.
I don't want anybody doing anything.
Who's that with you?
- Sergeant...
- Moody!
Police Chief Moroe.
What's going on here, John?
He's got no pants on.
You lied to me, Lieutenant.
You said you were going to
call me back, but you didn't.
I gave you your hostages,
but you didn't call me back. Why?
- Because you want me dead.
- Nobody wants to kill you.
Nobody wants to kill me?
None of these guys? Not him?
What is this?
What did you think would happen?
You want truth? Here's some truth.
This is going to end up bad for you.
There's only two ways out of here.
Jail or dead.
My son is very sick
and he needs some help.
It's hard to be a man these days,
hard to know what the right thing is.
- But put the gun down, John.
- You're not hearing me, Frank!
My son is sick! That's it!
There's nothing else. End of story.
When people are sick,
they deserve a little help.
Sick, help.
I am not going to bury my son!
My son is going to bury me.
You think these people
give a shit about you? They don't.
You're just the cause of the moment.
Nobody cares. That's the real truth.
Nobody cares. Only you.
And it's only you and me out here
and all these guns pointed at you.
What do you want to do?
It's your call.
I want my son.
- I want my son inside with me.
- Can't do it, John!
You give me my boy,
I give you your sniper.
It's all over.
You bring my son,
I give up...
...everybody goes home.
Everybody's safe.
You bring me my son.
Come on.
All right.
What do you think, Frank?
Give it to him. He's not going to
hurt anybody with his boy in there.
The object is to get hostages out,
not bring them in.
It's not a hostage.
It's his son.
Have all these people
been on the news?
It's your call, Frank.
All right, give it to him.
- Hold it!
- No, listen to me.
I'm his mother.
I need to be in there!
Stop! Stop right there!
Go! Beat it! Now!
We're in trouble. Mike's blood pressure
has dropped into the mid-40s.
His atrial blood pressure
should be in the low teens. It's 35.
I'm sorry, John.
Without a new heart,
he's not going to make it.
Then take mine.
- What?
- You heard me.
Take my heart,
and you put it in Mike.
- You done lost your damn mind.
- You can't be serious.
You bet I'm serious.
I'm dead serious.
Oh, my God.
- You'll be dead.
- And my son will live.
- You can't do this.
- It's the only way.
- Physically, you can't do this.
- I kill myself.
You open me up, take my heart.
- It's perfect.
- That's just crazy.
We can't just remove your heart
and put it into Michael's body.
There are too many unknowns.
Matching donor and recipient
is extremely complicated.
- Critical tests have to be taken.
- Like what?
Cross matches for blood type,
chest cavity measurements.
If blood tissues
are not completely compatible...
I know about compatibility.
We've been tested up the wazoo.
We're both B-positive.
Our tissues match.
His heart's three times the size
of normal, so mine will fit.
- You know we're compatible.
- Out of the question. Too risky.
- I'm telling you he will make it!
- Can't do it.
If I'm laying dead, you're not going to
take my heart and save his life?
You'll let two die instead of one
because of a technicality?
- I think what John is trying to do is right.
- Me, too. I think it's so brave.
What do you think Mike would want?
What about your wife?
Mike's too young to know
what's good for him.
It's my job to protect him.
Denise would do the same thing.
I know what's happening to Mike is bad.
Matter of fact, it's the worst.
But killing yourself
ain't going to solve a damn thing.
Sometimes you just
got to let go and let God...
Just accept it, brother.
Accept it?
Accept what?
That Mike is going to die.
No, I don't accept that. Ever.
I reject that out of hand.
All right, he's a patient to you,
I understand, but he's a good kid.
He loves bodybuilding.
He wants to be a bodybuilder.
Can you believe that?
He's funny. You'd like him.
- You'd like him if you got to know him.
- I do like him.
Then, please, I'm just begging you,
step outside the rules.
I'd like to, John, I really would,
but what you're asking crosses the line.
It is completely unethical.
I'm crossing the line? You're crossing.
The whole system is crossing the line.
Maybe you don't understand
what I'm talking about.
I don't give a damn.
My son's going to live.
Maybe you haven't figured that out by now.
I'll do whatever I got to do for him to live.
What are you going to do,
shoot me if I don't operate?
I'm going to kill myself.
All right?
Let's just see what happens.
That's what this is about, right?
He needs a donor.
Somebody's got to die for him to live.
I'm his father. It's me.
- All right.
- All right what?
I'll do it, if that's what you want.
- You're going to let him kill himself?
- Once he's dead, why not?
You are the finest surgeon
I have ever known.
You cannot throw your career,
your life away for this.
- If you do this, you're finished.
- What are they going to do, sue me?
Disbar me?
Evict me from the country club?
This is still a hospital.
If there's a heart available,
I'm not going to let it go to waste.
Doctor, Mr Maguire,
let's get ready for surgery.
- They're ready to harvest.
- All right, hurry up, guys.
Get her on the table.
- What's our time?
- All right, ready to lift.
- Count of three.
- Oh-four-five.
- Scalpels laid out.
- Where's his tray?
Got the other one ready?
Bring the cart around, please.
What do we have?
Female donor, 26 years old.
- She is 26 years old, 5'7".
- Liver, kidneys usable.
Liver and kidneys
are both usable. Lungs?
- Lungs are okay. Heart?
- Heart is good.
Blood type?
B-positive.
This is my...
...my will.
It says I'm leaving my heart to my son,
and I need two witnesses to sign.
I'm not signing it.
I ain't going to watch you kill yourself.
Me, neither.
The sooner you sign it,
the sooner you go home.
- I'll sign.
- Me, too.
You're just going to go in there
and off yourself?
- Only one thing will stop me.
- What's that?
If Mitch is B-positive.
Type O. Swear to God.
Thank you.
You be good.
Be careful.
See you in the funny papers.
Can I have a word with him?
Thank you.
How you doing, buddy?
Did you find me a new heart?
We got you one.
I guess you got a guardian angel.
Just try to stay awake
for a minute, okay?
I just need to tell you a few things.
You always listen to your mother.
You understand?
Do what she tells you to do.
She's your best friend.
You tell her you love her every day.
You're too young
for girls right now, but...
...there's going to come a time.
When it does,
you treat them like princesses.
'Cause that's what they are.
When you say
you're going to do something...
When you say you're going to
do something, you do it.
Because your word is your bond, son.
It's all you have.
And money. You make money
if you get a chance,
even if you got to sell out
once in a while.
Make as much money as you can.
Don't be stupid like your father.
Everything is so much easier
with money, son.
Don't smoke.
Be kind to people.
When somebody chooses you...
We talked about this.
You stand up. You be a man.
You stay away
from the bad things, son, please.
Don't get caught up
in the bad things.
There's so many great things
out there for you.
I'll never leave you.
I'm always with you.
Right there.
I love you, son.
I'll see you later.
Turner gets the other one.
Match with donor.
Oh, my sweet Jesus.
Let's do it.
Wait a minute. Are you telling me
that gun was empty the whole time?
I'm all talk.
The only one
I ever considered killing was me.
Maybe we should get some towels.
You're not going to believe this.
We got a match.
B-positive. Michael William Archibald,
the only status one in the country.
I'll be damned.
I'm thirsty.
We have very good news.
Jesus.
The safety's on.
- Is this for real?
- The jet landed at O'Hare.
The helicopter's
going to be here in 15 minutes.
You do the honours, okay? Go.
Baby. It's me.
It's not working.
Please. Baby. Pick up.
John. Can you...
It's a miracle, baby!
They found a heart!
The heant is here!
I repeat... the heant for little
Mike Archibald has arrived.
What an unbelievable ending
to this incredible. Tumultuous day.
- There they are.
- Okay. Here we go.
Yes. The hostages
are coming out.
One. Two.
They appear to be unharmed
but centainly exhausted
from what must have been
an excruciating ordeal.
More now! More coming out.
hands waving in the air.
Freedom. Freedom at last.
Police are esconting them
one by one to safety.
- How do you feel?
- Somebody else is coming.
It's John Q.
John Q has come out.
hands in the air.
He's putting the gun down.
He appears to be surrendering.
The police
are approaching cautiously now.
And they've got him.
They've subdued John Q.
The handcuffs are on.
and it appears to be over.
It's all over.
If pictures speak a thousand words.
then these images do speak volumes.
And now. As the bloody standoff
comes to an end. We remind you
that Channel 8 News was here first
with exclusive
moment-to-moment live coverage
of "Crisis at Hope Memorial."
I'm Tuck Lampley.
Open those doors!
Look out!
We're coming through! Come on!
We love you, John!
God bless you!
I'd do the same thing!
Heart.
Thank you.
Metzenbaums.
Prepare for cutting.
Put these on for me,
would you do that?
Take your time.
Lift it.
All right, done.
How beautiful was that?
- Pressure up.
And now one, two, three.
It worked!
The other big story...
John Q goes on trial today
for kidnapping
and attempted murder charges
all because an HMO denied coverage
for his son's heant transplant.
... more expensive for you in the future.
HMOs. To deny coverage...
There are still 40 million Americans
who are uninsured...
Tonight. As the trial continues.
John Quincy Archibald...
vigilante or heroic father?
... is to sue the pants off them
for millions of dollars to let them know...
We have known foryears
this is a crappy health care system.
We've known
we had to do something...
John Q was using one of those
faith-based health care plans.
You just pray.
and the government does nothing.
... not agree with that? The point is.
the enemy we're trying to identify is us.
We are the ones
who shot down national health care.
who don't want our taxes raised.
You have to look in the mirror
for this problem.
Back up. Come on.
Just one question, please!
How's your son doing, John?
A statement, please!
Out of the way.
Let's go.
- How are you feeling right now?
- Smile, John!
- Has the jury reached a verdict?
- We have, Your Honour.
As to count one,
attempted murder...
we find the defendant
John Quincy Archibald not guilty.
Quiet, please.
On count two,
armed criminal action... not guilty.
Quiet!
On the final count, the kidnapping
and false imprisonment
of Julie Byrd, Max Conlan,
Rosa Gonzalez, Dr Allen Klein,
Lester Matthews, Steve Maguire,
Miriam and Steve Smith,
Dr Raymond Turner,
Mitch Quigley, Debby Utley,
we find the defendant...
guilty.
Quiet, please. Sentencing will be
one week from today.
All rise.
- What are we looking at?
- He's going to do some time.
The judge is not going to give him
more than three to five.
I'll try and get it down to two.
I'm sorry.
You all right, slugger?
You take good care of your mother, okay?
You're the man of the house now.
You have any problems,
Jimmy and Gina will be here for you, too.
I'm so proud of you.
Give them frigging hell, Johnny.
Don't worry about nothing.
It's not good-bye, son.
See you later.
Take care, man.
You my hero.
Thank you.