It's him. Antwone.
He's here. Antwone's here.
That's Antwone. Look.
Antwone?
-
First call. First call to colors.
- First call. First call to colors.
-
Damn. Berkley.
- What?
- You been in there 10 minutes, man.
- Shut up.
- Yeah, okay.
You know, one day Chief gonna come in here
and catch you taking them Hollywood showers.
I should snitch on you.
Come on, move, man.
- Get out of my way, snitch.
- Come, move, man.
-
- Oh, yeah, yeah. Ooh!
I got you, man.
- Ooh!
-
Quit playin', man.
- What's crackin' Fisher?
- Your head, if you don't get away from me.
What is that on your face?
-
- Say something. Say something else.
- Say something, huh? You're always talking.
- Fish!
-
- Get off me. Get off me.
I'm cool, man. I'm cool.
Relax. I'm cool, man.
- Punk!
- Hey, hey, hey!
Petty Officer Fisher,
you've been accused of violating...
article 128— assault on a superior
noncommissioned officer.
- How do you plead?
- Guilty, sir.
Well, in your statement, you say
your attack on Petty Officer Berkley...
was provoked by a racial slur.
- Is that correct?
- Yes, sir.
Petty Officer Berkley, did you make
any racial remarks to Petty Officer Fisher?
- No, sir.
- Berkley-
- Stand at attention!
- Stand at attention.
This is the United States Navy, son.
I find you guilty.
There'll be a forfeiture
of $200 for two months...
you'll be restricted to the boundaries
of the ship for 45 days...
and you'll perform
45 days' extra duty.
I'm reducing you from ship's serviceman
petty officer third class...
to ship's serviceman seaman...
and I'm recommending
that you be evaluated...
at the psychiatric clinic
before our next underway period.
You're dismissed.
- So what happened?
- How'd it go?
Same old, same old. I got busted,
but now I gotta go to the psych clinic.
- You gotta go to the nuthouse?
- Farmer, shut up, man.
Give it up to the shrink? Damn.
See you next week.
Seaman Fisher.
Right this way.
I understand it's not
your first time here.
- You saw Dr. Williams?
- Nah. He saw me.
- That's your wife?
- Yes.
Have a seat.
I understand you like to fight.
It's the only way some people learn.
Hmm. But you pay the price
for teaching 'em.
- You wanna talk about it?
- About what?
Whatever's bothering you.
Why does something gotta be bothering me?
What, 'cause I jumped on a white boy...
something must be wrong with me?
"Send him to the psychiatrist.
Nigga tried to kill his master.
-
- He must be crazy. "
You looking for a discharge, Fisher?
- I ain't lookin' for nothin'.
- That's where you're headed.
- If I want out of the navy, I'll just leave.
- Unauthorized absence?
- Yeah, if that's what the navy calls it.
- Mm-hmm.
Running away how
you handle your problems?
- I don't have no problems.
- Hmm.
Where you from, Fisher?
- Where'd you spend your childhood?
- Cleveland.
Parents still live there?
I never had any parents.
They deceased?
I never ha—
I never had parents.
That would make you
a medical miracle, Seaman Fisher.
Where you from?
I'm from under a rock.
Okay.
Okay. All right.
I'm gonna see you... next week.
- I ain't comin' back.
- Why not?
- 'Cause there's nothin' wrong with me.
- I agree with you there.
See you next week.
See the receptionist
on your way out.
Next Wednesday, 1400.
- ♪♪
-
-  Whoa.
- Walker- Philip Walker.
- That was the name
of the last guy who stalked me.
- Oh, man.
- I'm busted.
- Yeah, you're busted.
- Yeah.
- What's up? Where you been?
- I'm on restriction.
- Again?
- Yeah.
-  How did you get off the ship?
Um, well, I just came
from the medic.
- Why?
- Oh, well—
I'm working on this high-priority paper
for this commander.
- Oh. What kind of paper?
- Well, I'm not—
- I'm not at liberty to talk about it right now.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
- Well, I was gonna invite you to a party.
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
- Well, I'm-I'm on restriction.
- Yeah. You told me.
Hmm. I gotta—
You know what?
I'm gonna get back to the ship.
They're probably
looking for me right about now.
So, you know- Talk to you.
Damn.
See you when you're off restriction.
Yes.
Yeah. Send him in.
Get your monkey hands off me, man.
I thought you may have
forgotten your way here last week...
so I took the liberty
of sending an escort team for you.
You may be able to make me come here,
but you can't make me talk.
Thank you. You're dismissed.
You don't want to talk to me, huh?
Let me lay this out for you, son.
This is how many cases I have, okay?
I don't have time to waste.
Now, I get three sessions only...
to make an eval and a recommendation
to your commanding officer.
You know he wants to throw you
out of the navy, don't you?
Now, you can sit here, and you can
not talk to me if you want to.
But our sessions don't begin
until you begin talking to me.
- I got nothin' to say.
- Okay. Then we'll sit until you do.
I got a lot of work to catch up on.
We can sit here until I retire.
- It doesn't matter to me.
- Doesn't matter to me either.
- All righty.
- What about the brig?
- What about it?
- Send me to the brig.
Here's the brig right there.
Lock yourself up.
What do you know? Time's up.
See you next week. 1400.
-
Some chips?
♪♪
-
- What?
- I didn't say anything.
- Thought you said something.
I was just clearing my throat.
Okay.
Maybe you're coming down with something.
I'm all right.
- It's just—
- Just what?
It's— It's just a waste of time,
sitting here week after week.
It's just wastin' time.
I don't want you to waste
your time, Antwone.
So what you want me to say?
It's not what I want you to say.
It's what you want to tell me.
Maybe you can start
by asking me a question.
- I don't know. Get things goin'.
- I can do that.
You said you come from under a rock.
What did you mean by that?
I don't know. That—
That was the first thing
that come to my mind.
What you think it means?
Well, it could mean that, uh—
That you feel under pressure.
That, uh, you feel a weight
pressing down on you.
That you're in the dark.
That you're alone.
- You said you had no parents.
- I had parents.
Okay.
- Only three sessions, right?
- Only three.
My father's name was Edward.
- So you knew him?
- No.
I didn't even know his last name.
- You know where he is?
- Yeah, I know where he is.
-  You ain't—
-
He went to his ex-girlfriend's house.
They got into an argument.
She killed my father.
- Where was your mother when this happened?
- Behind bars.
I see.
I was born in prison two months
after my father was murdered.
Why was she confined— Your mother?
I don't know.
All I know is what I told you.
- So you were turned over to the state?
- Yeah.
State placed me in this orphanage.
It was supposed to be until
my mother got out to claim me...
but she got out,
but she never claimed me.
- Hmm. How long were you there?
- Two years.
How's that make you feel, Antwone?
- I don't know.
- Come on. You must have some
feelings about it. What, you—
What did it feel like?
- Rainy days.
- Like rainy days?
Okay. Why is that?
You know, in Cleveland, it— it rains.
Not all the time, but, uh...
to a kid who wants
to go out and play...
it seems like it rains every day.
But, uh— Kids expect it
to rain sometimes, but—
One kid— It rained too much.
- Hmm.
-
Okay.
You want me to come back next week?
Yes, I do.
You ever try to find her— Your mother?
No, sir.
Okay. Next week.
Busy day?
Uh— No more than usual.
Hmm. Tomatoes are from our garden.
Yeah?
Hmm.
They're so much better than last year.|
I mean, I'm no green thumb,
or anything, but—
Who knows? Maybe I'm learning.
These tomatoes really are good.
♪ I don't know psychology ♪ Ha!
♪ I don't know astrology ♪
♪ I don't know zoology ♪
Ha!
♪ But l know this ♪
♪Jesus ♪
Ha!
When I was two...
I was placed in the Tate foster home.
Reverend Tate-
He was a fire-breathing preacher.
He had his own storefront church.
There was only a few members.
There was Miss Tate,
Cousin Nadine...
my foster brothers, Keith—
Keith was half white—
Dwight and me.
♪ Good God, yeah ♪
There was church three times on Sunday.
Bible study on Tuesday.
Y. P. W. W. meetings on Thursday.
Choir rehearsal on Friday.
We found out that if we caught
the Holy Ghost in front of Miss Tate...
- she'd give us vanilla wafers after church.
- ♪ Hallelujah ♪
So we'd catch it every Sunday.
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ Hallelujah, hallelujah ♪
♪ Hallelujah, hallelujah, Hallelujah ♪♪
Good God! Come on, church!
- Celebrate!
- ♪♪
- Reverend Tate—
He didn't like Dwight at all.
He said he had too much pride.
So he tried to beat it out of him.
Sometimes he would even try
to beat him to death.
- Did he beat you?
- No, sir.
I think he pitied me.
And I liked him for it,
but I was ashamed of him.
What about Mrs. Tate?
What about her?
I don't know which one of you no-good,
rotten, hardheaded niggas...
put your dirty hands on my walls...
but I bet I'll get the right one.
I took you in when your no-account
mammies threw you away.
And this is the thanks I get?
You ungrateful niggas.
-
Hmm.
Now I know I got the right one.
She used to brag about...
beating me unconscious.
Huh. She threatened to do it again...
but she never did.
Why do you think she never did?
Uh, maybe she was scared.
She found a new way
to get me though.
-
- So you like fire, huh?
No, m'dear. No, m'dear.
I don't like fire.
You... stay away...
from things that don't belong to you.
You hear me?
- Do you hear me?
- Yes. Yes, m'dear.
- You hear me?
- Yes.
Dumb nigga.
I tried everything I could to get her to like me.
Nothin' ever worked.
- Were you the youngest of the foster children?
- No.
Dwight was the youngest.
I was in the middle
and Keith was the oldest.
Miss Tate- She used to
put us against...
each other so much,
we started hating each other.
But I think deep down inside,
we really hated ourself.
- What do you mean?
- Keith was half white.
She would try to compare
Keith to me and Dwight.
You know, he had the good hair
and we had the bad hair.
She used to say how Keith was better
than us 'cause his father was white.
I wished I was Keith.
Hmm.
Not even Keith could escape
from being called a nigga.
She hardly used our names.
She said the word "nigga" so often—
called us nigga so often—
that we could tell
who she was talking to...
by the way she said the word nigga.
What happened to Dwight and Keith?
Dwight is in Lucasville
State Penitentiary.
Keith got taken by- by his mother.
He was raped by one
of her boyfriends.
Hmm.
- Did what happened to Keith happen to you?
- Hell, no.
Okay.
Was Mrs. Tate ever—|
- Was she ever nice to you?
- Yeah, there were times.
Sometimes she would
tell her friends that...
we were good kids and that
she was proud of us- Chummy times.
- Chummy times?
- Yeah.
I got to where I can tell
what kind of day it was gonna be...
by the scent in the air
when I awoke.
- How could you tell?
- Well—
If I awoke and there was
the smell of grits and eggs...
or water steaming off the pavement
as she hosed it down...
I had to look out all day.
But if I smelled pancakes,
everything was okay.
Did she make pancakes very often?
No, sir.
I can delay my next appointment
if you want to talk some more.
No, sir.
Hey, Slim.
- What?
- You goin' home next leave?
Hell, yeah. I gotta tend to the flock.
Hey, when I get leave,
I'm gonna be like a vampire...
comin' to town with his coffin—
Just a place to lay down
before I get down.
-
- What's that mean?
Man, shut up. People tryin' to sleep.
- Shut your grouchy ass up. Jesus.
-
Hey, when you goin' home, Pork Chop?
When your mama quit trippin'
and send me my money.
-
- What about you, Fish?
When you goin' home?
Fish.
Last night I had a dream about Jesse.
Who is Jesse?
He was my best friend.
When I wasn't at home, I was probably
wherever Jesse was, for three reasons.
One was, being his friend...
- he wouldn't beat me up.
- Hey, Jesse, look.
- I got a bug.
- And the other reasons were...
- so he wouldn't beat me up.
- I only got three.
- I liked him a whole lot.
- Gimme yours.
We used to drive
our friend Kenny crazy.
- Let's get Kenny.
- Kenny hung around me...
for the same reasons
I hung around Jesse.
- Hey, Kenny. Lemme see.
- Where's Jesse?
- Ugh!
-
Bugs! Bugs! Get 'em out!
- Bugs! Bugs! Get 'em out!
- Hey, Kenny, what's wrong?
Hey, Kenny, don't forget to write.
- Miss Tate- She hated Jesse.
- ♪ Oh, yes, ladies ♪
She hated seeing us together even more.
♪ My humpty nose'll tickle your- ♪
But for years she couldn't keep us apart.
I was so happy
when she kicked me out.
Twonny.
♪ Both how I'm livin'
and my nose is large ♪♪
That hoodlum nigga Jesse
called up here asking for you.
Said something about y'all
going to the picture show.
Now, that's the devil's work.
And who told you you could go
to the picture show anyhow?
I mean, where you get the money, nigga?
Did you steal it?
I already told you.
I've been raking lawns.
Well, you would have stole it,
so give me the money.
I said give me the money.
You don't know what to do
with no money nohow.
That's why I never
let you have none.
Why you always gotta
make things difficult for me?
Difficult?
Difficult. Where you learn
such fancy words at?
- Fancy? It ain't no fancy word.
- Don't sassy me, boy.
- Ain't no one sassin' you.
- Don't sassy me!
-
You are not beatin' me no more.
No more!
Lord Jesus.
I want you out of my house.
Hmm?
And who you think
gonna take you in, huh?
Retarded nigga.
Don't nobody want you.
Your damn mammy
didn't even want you.
Gimme my shoe.
Must have felt pretty good
when you took that shoe from her.
Yeah. I felt like I was gonna
go right upside her head.
- I just chilled.
- Why'd you chill?
I don't know.
- Well, I'm glad you did.
- Yeah.
How'd you feel?
I felt like I won a prize.
- But it scared me.
- Why?
It was the first time
I ever felt more powerful than her.
It was like a surprise.
- Whatever happened to Jesse?
- We lost touch. You know how it is.
Yeah.
It may be helpful to understand
the mentality of people like the Tates.
Here.
It's called The Slave Community.
- Why I gotta understand somebody beatin' on me?
- What you went through...
was in part the result
of the treatment...
that slaves received
from their masters...
and then passed on
to their own children...
generation to generation to generation,
right on down to the Tates.
Sir, that sounds like an excuse.
- I mean, I was a kid.
- I understand.
Sound like you takin' up for 'em.
I'm not saying what they did was right.
What they did was wrong.
We all have choices.
They made the wrong choices.
But this is not about them.
This is about you.
You were sent to me because
you have an anger problem.
Well, you've got the right to be angry.
But you also have to learn to channel
that anger- to use it constructively.
Instead of getting into fights, go to the gym.
Hit the bag. Lift the weights.
You have to use that energy
to better yourself.
- You say you're taking Japanese classes, right?
- Yeah.
Okay. You're already
on the right track.
Can we talk about this next week?
Three sessions, son.
Unfortunately, that's all I'm
given to make a recommendation.
And I'm gonna recommend
that you be given a second chance.
That is what you want, isn't it?
To stay in the navy?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay. Okay, stay out of trouble.
Antwone.
Antwone!
- So, how you doin'?
- I'm cool.
- You don't seem cool.
- I'm all right.
Well, what are you doin' in there?
You still working on that paper?
No, I'm finished. I just went
through there for a shortcut.
Oh. Where you going?
Nowhere.
I-I gotta go.
Cheryl, I'll talk to you later.
Why you always talkin' about somebody's mama?
Man, we ain't talkin' about somebody's mama.
- We talkin' about your mama.
-
Hey, Fish!
Yeah, I bet you won't be fightin'
no more honkies on this boat.
Man, this ain't no boat. This a ship.
This a ship.
Country-ass Negro.
Who let you in the navy?
Fish.
What's that book you readin'?
Let me see the cover.
"Slave Community. "
What you readin' that shit for?
'Cause I want to.
This ain't no slave ship.
And these ain't no slavery days.
I can't tell. You the only buck-dancin'
Uncle Tom on this ship.
-
- You a part-time brother.
Yo, Grayson, man, what—
Why you always talkin' shit, man?
- What I do ain't got nothin' to do with you.
- You better get out my face.
Either you tryin' to hang out with the brothers,
or you trying to hang out with the white boys.
- Sit your ass back down.
- You better make up your mind.
- What you goin' do? What you goin' do?
- Get out my face.
- Come on, Fish.
- Stop it!
- Let him go. You weak, Fish.
-
Thank you, sir.
Who's next?
So, uh, Dr. Davenport—
Sent him to the gym?
Hit the punchin' bags?
Ain't that what you prescribing?
So why are you here?
You feelin' under pressure?
You feel like, uh,
a rock is on top of you?
Come on, now. Speak the hell up.
You better make it snappy.
You only got three sessions comin'.
What are y'all lookin' at?
What you lookin' at?
You feelin' sick?
Do you need a healin'?
Huh? Do you need a healin'?
Some of y'all sick-ass sailors need
to come back after working hours.
See, that's when Dr. Davenport—
He'll be laying his hands on you.
Or he may have a book in there
that may have the answers...
to all your problems
and all your questions.
Ain't that right?
Would you like to step into my office?
Are you finished?
- I thought I was just getting started.
- Let me tell you something.
It may have slipped your mind, but you
are addressing a superior officer.
You understand me?
Do you understand me?
- Yes, sir. I slipped up.
- You better believe you did.
No, sir, I mean I slipped up
when I talked to you.
- What?
- Three sessions, right?
- That's correct.
- Can't be floutin' regulations.
- Well, what do I do, Commander?
'Cause I don't know what to do.
I don't know what to do.
Tired?
Hmm.
How was your day?
Long.
Not complaining, though.
Well, don't wait up.
I got a lot of work to do.
I know.
- Good night.
Well, it's nice to finally
be off restriction for a change.
- Yeah, I'm gonna be squared away from now on.
- Whoa.
Y'all want something
from the exchange?
Man, what's up with
you and the exchange?
You spend more time there
than you do on restriction.
- I'm just trying to be a good shipmate, man.
- I'm only kiddin' with you.
- Well, look, bring me back some Skittles.
- And a Snickers.
- And some pork skins.
- And a sandwich.
- Thank you.
- All right.
What are you doing here, sir?
I was in the area.
Saw your ship.
So you just saw this big old ship
moored alongside the pier?
I want to see you back in my office—
Next Wednesday after knockoff.
That is, if you want to continue.
I think I need to check
my calendar first, sir.
Okay.
- Well, you let me know, okay?
- Yes, sir.
Hey, Cheryl.
- Hey.
- Hey. What's goin' on?
- Nothin'.
- You just getting off work?
- Yeah.
- Uh—
You, uh— You mad?
Why would I be mad?
I'm sorry.
That's cool.|
- So you finally off restriction?
- Yeah.
- So you can hang out now?
- So what about now?
I'm off.
No. I gotta meet somebody. Well, I promised
I'd meet somebody in a few minutes.
- So—
- Oh.
What's her name?
No. It ain't like that.
- Okay.
- Not like that.
What about tomorrow?
Um, what- What about
the day after tomorrow?
Say, Wednesday after knockoff?
- That would be better.
- Okay.
Um, meet me in the lobby
of the female barracks at 1700.
- Hmm. Okay. All right.
- Okay.
- I'll meet you at 1700.
- All right.
- Yeah.
- It's a date.
-  Are we done?
- Yes, we are.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
Um—
Do you think it's—
Do you think it's possible...
for somebody that had
problems all their life—
You know, not to stay that way?
- You know, you think
it's possible they can change?
- Absolutely.
- Why do you ask?
- No reason.
- You want something to drink?
- No. I'm good—
- Okay.
- sir.
Uh— You know, you—
You know, when you
kind of meet somebody-
- You know, if you have problems, it wouldn't—
- Who is she?
What's her name?
Cheryl. She works at the exchange.
- That's a good thing.
- Uh-huh.
- Keep it navy.
-
- Right? So?
- Um, so, um—
Have you spoken to her yet?
Yeah, I've spoken to her, but, uh...
I get caught up— tongue-tied.
- I get caught up-
- Everybody's awkward at first. Okay?
- No, not like me.
- No, everybody is, Antwone. Trust me.
- Even you?
- Even me. Everybody.
- Mmm.
- So?
Well, we're goin' out tonight.
- Good.
- We were supposed to go out a couple days ago...
but, uh, you know,
I just wanted to clear my head.
Take some time. You know.
Talk to you first.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- So what should I do?
-
- Well— She's a nice girl?
- Yeah.
- And obviously you like her.
- Mm-hmm.
Okay. I think you should
just go out with her. I mean—
- Mmm?
- I tell you what.
You know, sometimes it helps,
just to take the anxiety...
out of a future meeting, to role-play.
- What's that?
- Like, you— You play yourself. I'll play Cheryl.
I'll ask you some questions.
We'll have a conversation.
And you'll see that you
have a good time, okay?
- Yeah, you play Cheryl?
- Okay, now. That's right.
That's right.
I'm man enough to play Cheryl.
Okay. Uh, you go first.
- Nah.
- I'll go first.
- Yeah.
- So—
- How you doin'?
- Fine.
Good. Good.
So where we gonna go?
Out.
- See?
- Uh—
- I'm hungry. You?
- I can eat.
- See? That's good. You got it.
- You think so?
Absolutely. I don't think you have
anything to worry about.
I'm gonna give you my phone number.
You have any problems-
any questions at all—
you can call me,
any time of day or night.
- Have fun. Gimme a call, okay?
- We're gonna be fine.
-  Okay.
- Yeah.
You never know, son. These things—
Sometimes they can escalate.
Escalate into what?
My wife and I went out.
It escalated into marriage.
- No, we're not escalating into marriage.
-
All right. Well, good.
You get out of here. Have fun.
Hey, have fun. Okay?
- I will.
- Okay. See you later.
No escalating.
- No escalating.
- Okay.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
- What is this?
- Frappuccino.
- Yeah. You like it?
- Six dollars?
-
What do you care how much it costs?
- Aw—
- All the money we're makin'.
That's why I joined
the navy, you know?
See the world, build a fortune.
I don't know what to do
with all the money I got.
- Okay, now tell my why you really joined the navy.
-
- For real?
- Yeah. For real.
All right. Well—
My father's a navy man.
Vietnam vet.
And, uh, his boys were gonna
grow up one day...
and join and serve,
just like he did.
Only one little problem.
He didn't have any boys.
- So you—
- Mm-hmm. So I.
Yep.|
It's worth it. You know?
I mean, even if I hated the navy...
which I don't...
it's worth just to-just to see
his eyes and the way they shine...
when I put on that uniform.
- So you and him are close?
- Yeah. We're close.
- Mmm.
Can't wait to go home
for Thanksgiving.
- You goin' home?
- I'm gonna go home.
Mmm.
Kind of hungry. How about you?
I could eat.|
- What?
- Nah.
- Nothin'.
-
- What?
- You sure?
- No.
Okay.|
- You should have ordered some.
- I just wanted one.
These are good—
You know, vegetables.
They're good for you.
Wanna try some?
Go on. Try it.
It's good. It's got, uh,
white cabbage, purple cabbage.
Yellow cabbage.
- Nasty cabbage.
-
- Man.
- It's not that bad.
Mmm.
So—
What do you like to do?
Or what do you want to do?
What would you like to do?
- What would I like to do?
- Mm-hmm.
Uh—
I'd like to— I wanna teach.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- My mother was a teacher.
- For real?
- Mm-hmm.
- Hmm. Yeah, teaching is, uh—
I think that's a powerful
position, you know.
Get to give to kids, and all that.
- I think you'll make an excellent teacher.
- Really?
Thank you.
I think, um—
I think you're beautiful.
Thank you.
- What?
- It's just funny-
I mean, nice-
What happens to your—
to your mouth when you smile.
One side curls up higher
than the other.
- Did you ever know that?
- No.
- It's cute.
- Oh. Thank you.
You shouldn't hide it. You know?
You should smile more often.
It's good for you.
- Yeah.
- Oh.
Here we are.
- You had a good time?
- Yeah.
I had a great time. Thank you.
Well, good night.
Good night.
- What is that?
- Japanese.
That meant, "It gave me
a great pleasure...
to spend this evening with you. "
Cool. That was beautiful.
Thank you.
So how do they say,
"Maybe we can do this again some time"?
- Uh, I don't know.
-
- Let me know.
- I will.
Good night.
- Hmm.
- Good night.
Good night.
Oh, yeah, I kissed her, man. Shoot!
But I ain't— I ain't getting into
all intimate details with you.
For real. That's just how it is.
That's my girl.
I respect her. Huh?
Mind yours. Mind yours.
God, they made me look like a pizza.
Hey.
-  Oh, shoot.
- Hi.
What ya doin'?
- Organizing.
These pile up.
Well, you could start off
by getting rid of that one.
- No.
- You'll make the pile a little smaller.
- No, you're gonna have to get in line.
- Yeah?
I remember that one.
- You can get rid of that one too.
- No.
- Lookit.
- Huh.
- Ohhh.
- Lifetime ago.
- Not to me.
- Huh.
Let me see this.
What?
How long are we gonna do this?
Are you gonna just keep ignoring me?
Come on, baby. Come on, now.
What are you talking about?
I mean, wh— We're just having
a good time. Why do we—
You're just gonna continue to act like
you don't know what I'm talking about?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
- You do know what I'm talking about.
- I'm hungry, you know?
I mean, I walk in—
-
- Talk to me.
Jerome?
She kissed me.
- What?
- She kissed me. I didn't even push her.
Only thing I did was, I walked her
to her door, I threw some Japanese on...
- and then she kissed me.
- Listen, Seaman Fisher.
Sir, I'm sorry for knocking
on your door, but I had to.
I had to talk to you.
Hello. I'm sorry
for busting in on you like this.
- You know, this is highly irregular.
- I don't know what I'm gonna do.
We're getting under way
to Mexico next week...
- and I'm starting to get serious with this girl.
- Okay, okay.
- She'll be here when you get back.
- How do you know?
Because if she has a fraction
of the bounce that you have, she'll be here.
- So you think I should just chill?
- That would be a good suggestion.
- Chill. Yes.
- Okay. I won't be doing this again.
- Thank you very much.
-
- Good night.
- Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
- Who was that?
- Patient of mine.
He was, uh, on his first date.
He was so excited
he couldn't wait to tell me about it.
Well, don't cure him.
- Yeah!
-
♪♪
Show me what you're working with.
Show me what you're
working with. Whoo!
I don't know about you,
but if my math is right...
we're a lady short at this table.
You didn't know? My man Fisher
just got himself a girlfriend.
- She's in the navy, right, Fish?
- Yeah—
Be writing to her every minute
he can find. Just so romantic.
-
- ¿Quieres bailar?
- I don't understand.
- Ah, you understand.
¿Quieres bailar?
Sí. Sí. Bailar.
- I don't—
- She wants to mate.
- Do the dance. You understand.
-  Come. Come.
- Venga. Venga.
- No, I'm fine.
Let her oil the old slave down. What
your girlfriend don't know won't hurt you.
-
- Hey, come on, man. Get up. Get up.
- Nah, I don't want to.
- You don't what?
- Why don't you leave him alone, Grayson?
- I'm not gonna bother him.
- Now he can answer my question.
- What question?
You don't what? How come
I never seen you with a girl, huh?
I mean, man says he's got
a girlfriend, right?
Well, anybody ever met her?
Huh? Anybody?
Don't worry about it, sweetheart.
You see, he's a cherry boy.
Never been to the sugar shack.
Too scared to go.
- Fuck you, Grayson.
- Huh? What you say?
- You heard me.
- Fuck me?
With all these women in here...
you want me?
See what I mean, brother?
Hell, I'm worried about you, Fish.
I mean, all this action up in here-
Why you don't want no woman?
Yeah. Faggot.
-
- Here we go again.
- Get off! Get off!
Davenport.
What time does his plane get in?
Okay. No, no. I understand.
I understand.
Okay, just let me talk to him first.
All right, thank you.
-
Thought we were all done
fighting, Antwone.
Let me in.
The X. O. wired the statements
of your shipmates.
Now, do you want to start
at the beginning?
You're gonna have
to talk to me, son.
You better tell me something,
'cause I'm all you got right now.
I'm trying to work things out
with your commanding officer,
but you gotta give me something.
- I don't know what to say.
- Just tell me what happened.
- They were frontin' me.
- What do you mean, fronting you?
Some of the guys- They were
baggin' on me, and I couldn't take it.
How so?
I don't know. Just, uh—
Just makin'— makin' jokes.
What kind of jokes?
Jokes about me with women.
I wasn't taking it.
What kind of jokes about you
being with women, Antwone?
Jokes like me being a virgin.
Are you?
I don't know. I might be.
Okay.
Why do you think
you haven't been with a woman?
Think about it, son.
Must be a reason. I mean, you're...
a good-looking young man.
Must have had many opportunities.
Maybe you don't like women.
- Do you like men?
- I like women.
- Maybe you don't care about sex.
- I care about sex.
I think about it all the time.
All right, we're right back
where we started.
How come you've
never been with a woman?
- I have.
- Okay.
When?
- When?
- When I was young.
Was- It was a kiss.
Okay. How was it?
I hated it.
It was t— It was terrible.
- Why?
- I threw up.
Why?
Because—
Because she put
her tongue in my mouth.
She- She always did.
- That's my mama.
- That ain't your mama.
- You said the other lady was yours.
- I changed.
- You changed?
- Boy, you can't change. That's my mama.
Nigga?
- Nigga, you hear me callin' you?
- That's you.
- I said nigga.
- Comin', m'dear.
- Dwight? Keith?
- Yes, m'dear. Here.
- Here I come.
- Get your behinds down here.
And I told you-all
not to mess up your clothes.
- Nadine.
-  Yes.
We're gonna be downtown
at the social service office.
- All right.
- Twonny, you stay with Nadine.
Yes, m'dear.
Don't you say nothin' unless I tell you to.
Twonny, what you
lookin' at out there?
Hmm?
What you lookin' at?
That's it.
Gimme some sugar.
Now get on downstairs.
What did I say?
Get on downstairs-
In that basement and drop 'em.
Hurry up.
Unbutton them all. Come on.
- I said come on.
-
Pull 'em down.
You heard me. Pull 'em down.
Pull 'em right over my feet.
Now, get over here close. Closer.
You don't have to be afraid.
Now touch me.
You know you wanna.
Yeah, that's it. Kiss me.
Come on. I said kiss me.
- Baby, gimme some sugar.
-
♪ Mack, Mack, Mack, She asked her mother ♪
- ♪ Mother, mother- ♪♪
- Antwone! Oh, I'm gonna tell on you.
-
What's up, man? You all right?
Come on in.
All right?
She did it again?
She hit you too?
It's okay, Antwone.
You can stay here.
I'll look after you. Come on.
Come on. Let's get you a shirt.
She made me—
She made me do these things.
And I was only a little boy.
If there was something I wouldn't do,
she would beat me.
And Jesse was the only one you ever told?
Yes, sir.
She's the only woman
I ever seen naked.
I'm almost 25 years old.
I never done it.
It's embarrassin'.
I hate it.
-
Yes, can I help you with something?
Hello, Mrs. Davenport.
I'm Seaman Fisher.
- Antwone Fisher, ma'am.
- What can I do for you?
I'm here to see the commander. I'm one of
his patients. He told me to meet him here.
Well, he's not home yet. But, um—
Well, come on inside.
You can wait.
- Would you like some cider?
- Sure. Thank you.
Seems you gettin' all ready
for Thanksgiving, ma'am.
Don't call me ma'am. You're gonna
make me feel old. Call me Berta.
So, are you going home
for the holidays?
No, but the chief cook on the ship, he's
plannin' a big meal. So I'll be there for that.
That sounds nice. Here you go.
Thank you very much.
Um, first thing I saw...
first time I was in his office—
It was you.
Yeah. It was your picture.
I thought you had a nice face...
a good face, and... maybe he's all right
if he married a woman like you.
-  You ready to get started?
- Yes, sir.
- Nice meetin' you.
- It was very nice to meet you too.
Okay.
I was just tryin' to be nice.
Why don't you try bein'
nice on that ship? Hmm?
Have a seat.
- I like your house.
- Thank you. Tell me about your house.
- Your house, the day you left your family.
- Sir?
The Tates. When they threw you out.
Tell me about that.
Oh. It was back to the orphanage.
Um, they, uh—
They told me I needed
to develop my social skills.
Nobody was into adoptin' teenage boys.
Uh, they sent me to a reform school
in Pennsylvania.
That's where I got
my excellent skills I have now.
Hmm. What then?
Um, I was on my own.
The social worker-
She took me to a— a men's shelter.
She gave me $67, and, uh...
she said good-bye.
How long were you at the shelter?
- Just till the next mornin'.
- And?
I slept on a few park benches,
and I came here.
- To my house?
- No, sir.
I joined the navy.
That's it. I mean, that's
the Antwone Fisher story.
Okay. That is it.
- You're done for today.
- Okay, sir.
Don't talk to my wife
anymore either. You hear me?
- Yes, sir.
- All right.
-  Seaman Fisher.
- Sir?
- Get up here.
- What I do?
Cut the jawjackin'.
Up here right now.
I don't know what you think
you're up to, but you better be careful.
- I didn't do anything.
- You didn't do anything?
My wife is inviting you to Thanksgiving.
She thinks you're very charming.
Do you have any idea where
she might've gotten that impression?
-
- Huh? Look at me when I'm talkin' to you.
No, sir. Maybe she responds
to nice people.
Okay, nice people. Next Thursday,
Thanksgiving, my house...
my family, my dinner table, 1400.
- Don't be late.
- Yes, sir.
Get outta here.
-
-  It's nice out here.
- How'd you find this place?
- It's a lighthouse.
I'm a sailor. It found me.
-
- You knucklehead.
You come out here a lot?
Sometimes I come
out here to think...
or to work out some problems.
Mmm. I know what you mean.
Well, um—|
Can I be honest with you?
- Yeah.
-
Remember when I, uh—
I told you that I was-
I was workin' on
that important paper?
Yeah.|
Well, I lied.
I know.
- You know?
- Yeah.
You're seein' a psychiatrist, aren't you?
Oh. You knew.
- Yeah, I knew. It wasn't that hard to figure out.
- Mmm.
- Are you tryin' to tell me I'm crazy?
- No.
So?
So I'll understand if you—
if you don't wanna
be bothered no more.
You're not the only person
that's seen a shrink before.
- Oh, you seen one?
- No...
but I told you
my dad's a Vietnam vet.
He has.
I guess he made it, huh?
So, why- why are you
seein' a psychiatrist?
My life before the navy
was kind of complicated.
- I was feelin' ashamed.
- Of what?
Of bein' unwanted.
And, uh...
I didn't have no parents.
- Mmm.
- You know, I was-
I was afraid to even approach you.
Would you believe...
that I was too shy to approach you?
- No.
- Yeah.
Um, until I realized
you were stalking me.
-  I wasn't stalking you.
-
Well, if there's anything
I could do to help...
I'm here.
You're doin' it already.
What am I doin'?
Just bein' you.
Happy Thanksgiving. Um—
Happy Thanksgiving.
Happy holidays, sir.
Happy holidays, ma'am.
I know.
It's... Berta.
Yeah. Come on— Come on in.
Hello. I'm Antwone.|
I, um—
Yeah, I'm hungry.
I could eat.|
1400, huh? What took you so long?
- Oh, I stopped by to get some cider, sir.
- Okay. Good.
- Happy holidays.
- Thank you. Come on in.
Everybody's here waitin' for you.
We're about to say grace.
All right, everybody. This is Antwone.
Antwone, this is my family.
- Hello.
- That's my mother Johnny Mae.
- That's my wife's brother, Uncle Duke.
- How you doin'?
- Hello.
- This is my dad, Howard. That's my sister, Gwen.
- How you doing?
- And her full-grown daughter.
- Hi, Antwone.
- Oh, you wanna come and sit next to her?
Gwen, Gwen. Come on, baby.
You come on over here and sit.
- Okay.
-
All right.
Duke, why don't you
lead us in prayer?
Okay. Everybody join hands.
Let's bow our heads.
Heavenly Father...
we come to you on bent knee
and body bowed...
as humble as we know how.
We are grateful for this opportunity to
share another Thanksgiving Day as a family.
We thank you for our health,
O Lord, and for our friends...
who honor us with their presence.
We also pray for peace
in the world and in our lives. Amen.
-  Amen.
- All right.
This looks good. Yeah!
- Here you go, Daddy.
- Thank you. Mmm.
- Honey, you want some more turkey?
- Oh, no, thank you, ma'am.
Oh, don't be actin' all bashful around me.
Especially at the dinner table.
- Dad, leave that boy alone.
- Shoot!
- Huh?
- I'm okay.
All right, then, let me see you dig in.
I mean, the food is free.
- Howard.
- You know, when I was in
the service back in the war-
that was before you was born—
Howard!
Anyway, I spent the holidays
in Europe on guard duty, and I— Oh!
I sure did miss my mama's
holiday cookin'. Whoo!
Howard, would you
leave the boy alone?
- Let him enjoy his dinner.
- I ain't botherin' him.
- You leave me alone, huh?
- Baby, he wants to eat!
Oh, no, look.
I'm just talkin' to the boy.
Gwen, give your daddy
some of those greens or somethin'.
Hey, listen. Let me ask you something.
Where you from?
-  Cleveland.
- Cleveland. Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Cleveland.
I bet you miss your mama's
holiday cookin', don't you? Huh?
Excuse me.
- Where he goin'?
-  I don't know.
See? That's what happens
every holiday season.
What are you looking at me
like that for?
- Why do you want to do that to the boy?
- Y'all ran the boy outta here!
- That's what happens every holiday!
- I didn't run the boy out.
- You okay?
- Yes, I'm okay.
I just never had a real Thanksgiving
at the Tates' before.
You didn't have a real one
over here either, I guess.
- You have a real nice family.
- Thank you.
I got this for you
for having me over today.
Oh, you got a gift
for me. Is it money?
- No.
-
- Oh, it's a poem.
- Mm-hmm.
I can't see without my glasses.
Why don't you read it for me?
I'd rather you read it. Please.
"Who will cry for the little boy...
"lost and all alone?
"abandoned without his own?
Who will cry for the little boy?"
"He cried himself to sleep.
"Who will cry for the little boy...
who never had for keeps?"
"who walked the burning sand?
"Who will cry for the little boy...
"the boy inside the man?
"who knew well hurt and pain?
"Who will cry for the little boy...
"who died and died again?
"a good boy he tried to be?
"Who will cry for the little boy...
who cries inside of me?"
Who will cry for
the little boy, Antwone?
I will.|
I always do.
- It's beautiful, Antwone.
- I know. I told you I was good.
Yes, you are. You are good
because you're honest.
You're more honest than most people,
even in your anger.
The only thing you're
not honest with yourself about...
is your need to find your own family.
- Your natural family.
- I don't feel like I need to look for 'em.
Mmm. It'd answer
a lot of questions for you.
I don't have any questions.
You're upset with them because
you feel they didn't come to your rescue.
- Maybe they didn't know.
- How could they not have known?
That's a question
you need to ask them.
"Regard without ill will
despite an offense. "
That's Webster's definition
of forgiveness.
- Why do I have to forgive?
- To free yourself...
so that you can get on
with your life.
Why I gotta go look for my family?
I got you, Doc.
I think that he had a good time tonight.
- Hmm?
- Antwone. I think that, uh,
he had a good time, don't you?
Yeah, seemed like it.
He did the sweetest thing at the door...
when he was saying good-bye.
He invited me to come
to his ceremony.
You know he's graduating
from his Japanese class.
- Yeah, I know.
- Well, he wants me to come.
- To be with you.
- What'd you tell him?
I told him that I would
be honored, Jerome.
Okay.
Congratulations.
Petty Officer Fisher. Good job.
- Thank you, commander.
- I was waiting. Cheryl, right?
- How you doin', Cheryl?
It's a pleasure to meet you.
- Sir.
- Heard nothin' but good things about you.
- Where's your wife?
She couldn't make it.
She sends along her congratulations.
- A small gift for you.
- Okay.
"The Philosophy and Opinions
of Marcus Garvey. "
- Thank you, sir.
- You're welcome.
Is there somewhere
we can talk in private?
Do you mind?
- That's fine. I don't mind.
- Okay.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you, sir.
Come on.
Hello?
-  What's up, Doc?
-
- How are you?
- I'm good.
Yes, you are, Antwone. You're good.
I'm hearing nothin' but
good things from your C. O.
Hear that you're gettin' along very well
with your shipmates. I'm proud of you.
- Thank you, sir.
- Have you thought anymore
about finding your family?
I don't know. For what?
Well, I just think that there's really nothing
more important than that, Antwone.
What are you tryin' to say, sir?
That I'm proud of you,
that I think you've come a long way.
Okay. You said that. What's wrong?
There's nothin' wrong.
You understand,
this is very difficult for me.
- Our sessions have ended.
-
Now, listen. Just listen to me, all right?
- I've taken the liberty of-
- What do you mean, they ended?
They ended, son. It's time for you
to move on. You can't stall here.
- But you and me are workin' out my problems.
- You and me can't work out—
- You told me we need to figure out my problems.
- Listen to me—
- Get off me!
-
- Hey, get out! Get out!
- Nobody ever stays! Everybody's always leavin' me!
People grow. People move on.
You've grown. It's time for you to move on.
- Hey, my mother left me! My father!
- I understand that.
- Jesse and you!
- Jesse? What do you mean?
- We should've never gone, that's what. Jesse!
- Jesse? Tell me something—
Cowbells ringin' in my fuckin' head!
- Cowbells? Tell me about the cowbells-
- But I keep trustin' people!
Trustin'—|
- What happened to Jesse, Antwone?
- Stay away from me.
Nobody's takin' anything else
away from me no more.
Who is it?
Man, I just asked
who was it. Fish! Oh!
- What's up, dog? What's up with you, man?
- Let go, man.
- What's goin' on with you, man?
- Hey, man, stop playin'.
- Stop playin'? Don't make me kick your ass now.
- Stop playin'.
- You know you can't fight worth shit.
- Man.
- What's up with you, man?
- What's up with you?
Where you been at?
Where you stayin'? What's up?
- Huh?
- I'm at the men's shelter.
On Prospect.
Where you stayin' at, man? For real.
- I'm on the street.
- What you doin' on the streets, man?
- I got nowhere else to go, man.
- You ain't got nowhere to go?
You couldn't come to my house?
No, man. Your mom ain't
gonna let me stay up in here.
You trippin', man.
She ain't gotta know.
I mean, she work all day,
sleep all night.
Besides, there's so many people
stayin' up in this house...
she wouldn't even know
you're here no way, dog.
- You can stay here, for real.
- Y'all got something in the refrigerator?
Yeah, we got something. You hungry?
- I'm hungry.
- You hungry?
- Yeah, man. Stop playin'.
- Come in here.
You smell like you been
on the streets too, man.
Dang! Slow down, man.
Ain't nobody gonna take your food.
Hey, you remember that time
Ms. Tate wouldn't let you use her lotion?
She made you oil up
with old cooking grease instead.
You walking around all day
smelling like a fried chicken dinner.
You like, "I sho' is hungry!"
Man, that was so funny.
That had me rolling for real.
- Not as funny as your mother
chasing you with that brick.
- Oh, okay, okay.
- You remember that?
- Yeah, I remember that.
- That was funny.
- Dude, that wasn't funny, man.
I still got the knot
in the back of my head.
Fish, you know you're
my best friend, right?
What you want?
I can't be happy
my dude back on the block?
you back here at home, man?
- I want you to do something for me, though.
- What?
- Just look out for me.
- Somebody after you?
Why somebody gotta
be after me, man? Huh?
I just want you
to look out for me, dude.
- All right.
- You my best friend, right?
Yeah, man. Stop trippin', man.
Man, come on. Let's get you
cleaned up and hit the streets.
Yeah. You know Brenda.
I used to like her.
The Brenda you used
to like, dog, got about three kids now.
- Gettin' all "swole. " She big for real, dog.
- ♪♪
Ain't no little booty
Brenda no more.
Hey, how's your mother?
Aw, man, she got knocked up.
- For real?
- Yeah.
It's bad.
- Go ahead, man. Get you something. I got you.
-
- Break it off, old man! This ain't no riddle.
- Jess, what you doing?
This ain't nothing you got to figure out.
Hey, hold off, Fish.
- Hey, you better break off my loot!
- Hey, Jess, man—
- Look out for me, Fish.
-
And by the end
of the next day, I was in boot camp.
I always felt like Jesse was
the lucky one, and I envied him for it.
How could he be
the lucky one? He's dead.
Yeah, well, he left me,
and he knew he was the only one I had.
So you're angry at him
because you felt he abandoned you.
Yes. A little bit.
How is he the lucky one?
'Cause he don't
have to fight no more.
Neither do you.
- So, you think I'll make it?
- I think you already have.
What do you think?
I think, uh...
maybe in another life or time...
I would have been king.
When you locate your family...
I want you to contact me.
All right? I want to hear all about it.
Yes, sir.
I love you, son.
I love you too.
- Who's this?
- Guess who.
- Antwone.
- No, this is Phillip Walker, the late-night stalker.
- Aw.
-
So—
I, um— I'm going on leave.
- When?
- As soon as you put your
request in and come with me.
You serious?
Yes.
I just came back.
They're not gonna let me
leave again this year.
Can you ask for emergency leave?
Tell 'em somebody close to you
is in desperate need.
Cheryl, I— I really want you
to come with me.
I got these, uh, two open tickets.
To Cleveland.
You're gonna try and find them.
Yeah. I need to find them.
But not without your help.
All right. Let me see what I can do.
First the light-skinned
girls. They got adopted the quickest.
Then the light-skinned boys,
and then the dark-skinned girls...
and then, last but not least,
the dark-skinned boys.
I'm really sorry.
All birth records since 1980...
have been moved to Social Services.
-
Last contact with your mother?
I was two months old.
- And with father?
- Never.
Place of birth.
Ohio State Correctional
Facility for Women.
I'll be right back.
I need you to sign for me.
- Best of luck, Mr. Fisher.
- Thank you.
There's nothing in here.
- Why don't you go see your foster mother?
- Who, Miss Tate?
- Yeah.
- I'm not— I'm— I'm not going back.
Well, why not? I mean, she might know
something about your family.
No.
I haven't done this before.
Take a ride with me.
If you selling shit,
just keep on walkin'.
Oh, my God. Is that you, Antwone?
- Come here, baby.
- Don't touch me.
Yeah, it's me, and I'm all grown up.
I'd like to speak to Miss Tate.
- Well, you want to come in?
- No.
Would you like to get her?
'Twon's here.
Lord have mercy. Where's the child?
Oh, nigga! Hug my neck.
Oh, nigga.
I— Don't you know how to come home?
Where you been?
I came for one thing: whatever
you can tell me about my real family.
I don't know nothing
about your real peoples.
A name, number, anything?
I said I don't know.
Now, come along. Come on.
I remember everything. Everything!
You could have helped me.
But instead, you beat me
to dust. And you—
- Boy, I don't know what you're talking about—
- Yes, you do. I was 6 years old!
- Now, you just listen—
- No, you listen to me!
- I think you done forgotten—
- I think you forgotten. I said listen to me.
This is my time.
You understand me?
It don't matter...
what you tried to do.
You couldn't destroy me.
I'm still standing.
I'm still strong!
And I always will be.
Antwone.
Elkins.
Your father's name
was Edward Elkins.
You take Shaker Heights
and East Cleveland...
and I'm gonna take
Akron and Cleveland.
- Yeah. 1976.
-
Hello. Hi, um, I'm looking
for the family of Edward Elkins.
Edward Elkins.
Hello.
- Hi. I'm looking for the family of Edward Elkins.
- No. Edward.
- E-D-W-A-R-D.
- Yes, Edward.
What? I'm speaking clearly. You can't—
- Okay—
- Okay. Well, thank- thank you.
I'm looking for the family
of an Edward Elkins.
You should have said that
in the first place. Why- Why you—
Forget it, man.
Yeah, well, we're from California.
Yes, it's very nice there.
Okay, well, thank you
for your help, ma'am. Thank you. Bye.
- Any luck?
-
What you got?
- Chinese.
-
- Hello?
-  Hello, ma'am.
- Yes?
- I'm looking for the family of an Edward Elkins.
Edward? Who is this
calling about Edward?
My name is Antwone Fisher.
I didn't mean to disturb you.
I'm just trying to locate my family.
Honey, Edward Elkins
been dead a long time.
Yes, ma'am, I know, a long time,
but he was my father.
Wait, wait, wait.
Who is this calling me up out of nowhere?
- How'd you get this number?
- I got your number out of the phone book.
I been calling Elkins all day.
Got no reason to lie to you, ma'am.
Well, honey, Edward never mentioned no—
What's your name again?
- Antwone.
I don't think he knew my mother
was pregnant. She was away in prison.
- You know how he died?
- Yes, ma'am.
He was murdered by
one of his girlfriends.
My God.
Wait. What made you
decide to show up...
20-some-odd years later
in the middle of the night?
Mmm, it's a long story.
But I'm in the navy, and, uh,
I'm stationed on the West Coast.
I gotta get back in a few days.
- Well, I-I want you to come
by my house before you go.
- Okay.
Okay, look. Y-You have a— a pencil?
- Take down my address.
- Yeah.
- It's 1089 Drexel.
- 1089 Drexel.
- You know where that is?
- Yes, ma'am.
All right, well, come by
my house tomorrow, hear?
- Okay. Um, ma'am?
- Yes?
You mind if I bring
my girlfriend with me?
Yes, fine. I'm-I'm looking
forward to meeting her.
I'm sure she's looking
forward to meeting you too.
You— Listen. You know, if-
If Edward was your father...
then you talking
to your auntie, son.
You are talking
to your Auntie Annette...
your daddy's baby sister.|
- Well, I'll see you tomorrow.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Good night.
- Bye.
I found them.
- Hmm?
- I found my family.
- You did?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, baby.
Mmm.
I don't know. What do you think?
Well, he does look like Eddie.
- I do?
- Yeah, you look just like him.
Mm-hmm.
I brought my birth certificate.
Born in '76.
That's the year Edward died.
Yeah, he-he died in June,
and I was born in August.
And your mother's name is-
- Eva Mae Fisher.
Eva? I know Eva.
That's Jess's sister.
- Who?
- Jess.
- You mean Fish?
- Yeah, Fish. Jess Fisher.
The boy's name is Antwone Fisher.
That’s Jess Fisher's sister, Eva Mae.
You know, Mae-Mae.
- She live over there on Hodges Street.
- I don't remember no Mae-Mae.
Y-You know where she lives?
You don't know her, do you?
No. I—I—
No, no.
You want to meet her?
Uh—
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
You sure? 'Cause we can take care
of this right here and now.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Let me get my hat.
Want me to go with you?
No, why don't you just stay
here with us, baby?
Okay, let's ride.
Bye.
You're not gonna let nothin'
happen to me, are you?
No, Antwone.
I won't let nothin' happen to you.
-  Who is it?
- Eva, it's James. James Elkins.
Edward's brother.
Did you hear me, Eva? This is James.
- What you want?
- Can we come in?
- Hey, Eva.
- Hey.
It's all right, son. Come on.
- Who's that, Eva?
- That's Johnny.
No. That's Antwone Quenton Fisher.
Who's Antwone Quenton Fisher, Eva?
That's my firstborn son.
Oh, God.
There's nothing going on around here.
You wanna stay?
I'm gonna stay.
I'll be in the car.
- You want something to eat?
- No.
Why'd you never come for me?
Didn't you wonder where I was...
or what I was doing,
or what I'd become...
or even if I was still alive?
Didn't you?
I've taken care of myself. I have.
I've never been
in trouble with the law.
I've read hundreds of books...
written poems...
painted pictures.
I've traveled the world.
I serve my country.
I speak two languages...
and I'm working on a third.
I never fathered any children.
I've never done drugs
or even smoked a cigarette.
I used to dream about you.
My mother. My mother.
You know, what you'd be like...
how you look...
your voice and your smile...
even your scent.
For all these years
I wondered about you.
I dreamed about you.
Didn't you miss me?
On the way to school each day...
I imagined you were just
around the next corner...
and when I'd get there,
you'd be there.
And in my mind...
you was always there.
You just couldn't find me.
So I'd race to the next corner...
and you'd be there.
I'd know you would.
Then you would...
buy me ice cream.
And then you would take me home.
I'm a good person.
I'm a good man.
Hey, boy, how you doin'?
I'm your Uncle Horace.
Get out of the way, Horace.
Come on, baby. Here he is!
Oh, look at you! Look at you!
I'm your Aunt Eda, baby.
Oh, I'm your cousin Jeanette.
Welcome home!
And I'm your Aunt Anna.
How you doin', baby?
Oh, my Lord Jesus. Oh, goodness.
-  This is my wife, T.
- How you doin', good-lookin'?
I'm your cousin Eddie.
My dad named me after your father.
- An this is my brother Ray.
- What's up, dog? What's crackin', man?
Hey, I'm your cousin Jason,
man. Much love. Much love.
All right, boys, open up.
Welcome.
All right.
- Come on! Let's eat!
-
You want some pancakes? Ooh.
Here we go. How about some sausages?
I'm not a virgin anymore.
I'm glad to hear that.|
- How you doin', son?
- I'm great, sir.
All right. Good. Good, good.
Very good to see you.
- So?
- I took your advice.
I found my family
and I found my mother.
- Good.
- Yeah.
- So?
- Well, in my heart I forgive her...
but if I never saw her again—
I understand.
It's funny to feel that way
about your mother, but I did it.
And I owe it to you to tell you
that you were right.
- You owe it to me?
- Yes, sir.
- I needed to find her.
- Yeah.
Well, if I was right, it was
for all the wrong reasons.
Sir?
This stays between you and me, okay?
Yes, sir.
My wife and I, we were gonna have a bunch
of kids, when we found out we couldn't have any.
And it rocked her to the core.
I knew what to do for her
though. She needed help, treatment.
I made sure she had it. The best
psychiatrist, the one that trained me.
But I, the well one,
the strong one...
at the same time I went about
the business of shutting down.
Very subtle, very quiet.
It was my little secret.
Until one day, a young man came
into my office and into my life...
and he blew up that little secret...
right in my face.
And he put me to shame in a way
I never thought possible.
Because of you, Antwone,
I'm a better doctor...
and I'm learning
to be a better husband.
You don't owe me anything.
I owe you.
You're the champ, son.
You've beaten everybody
who was beatin' you.
I salute you.
You hungry, sailor?
I could eat, sir.
Let's go.
- Oh, yeah.
- All the way.
- Dedicated.