Turn it up!
Turn up the radio
I need the music
Give me some more
Come on, Boots,
you have three minutes left.
You can do this. You
came to me, remember?
It's not about losing weight.
It's about a lifestyle change.
Nick, you have a customer.
Like we practiced.
Right away, Terry.
'Sup, dawg?
Oh. Ha! Funny.
It's the name
of the store.
What can I do
for you, man?
Bono has been doing
this for three days.
It's fucking
disgusting.
Bring him up here.
Bono, Bono, come.
Bono, up!
Don't yell at him
like that.
Okay. Okay. Cool.
You're gonna...
I might just look...
Do I know you?
I know you.
You're the singer
from Chocolate Lipstick.
You guys used to play at the
Jam Shack on Friday nights.
Damn!
You remember that?
You were so good.
Yeah.
Oh, my God,
you still singing?
Nah. That was
a long time ago.
Wow! What are you
doing now?
You get shit
out of dogs' asses.
That's great.
You own a BMW?
Yeah, can you tell?
Good boy.
Adam, it's Lou.
Don't hang up, okay?
It's not about money.
It's about making money.
You and me, buddy.
Hi, it's me.
So, I did everything according
to your stupid fucking plan.
I took everything
with the yellow stickers
and I left you everything
with the red stickers.
There was some stuff in
your closet with no stickers,
so I threw that in a pile
and burned it in the backyard.
Seemed like
the right thing to do.
And thank you for claiming
that empty plastic bottle.
I was prepared to
fight you on that one.
Anyway, I left you
something on the counter.
It's from the heart.
Oh, and one last thing.
Um...
The TV had a red sticker
on it, but I took it anyway.
Bye.
Just keeping
my head down.
Not getting shivved today. Let's
knock these reps out. Mmm! Mmm!
Turn on a light, Jake.
Open a window.
Go outdoors.
Jesus Christ!
Why don't you get out of
the house this weekend, huh?
What should I do out of
the house, Uncle Adam?
I don't know. Anything that
corresponds with reality.
Apply for a job. Maybe
try to go to college.
I don't know. That all
sounds kind of overrated.
You don't like it, you can
move back in with your mom.
No, I can't actually. She
moved in with her new boyfriend.
I will not be
anywhere near that.
She moved in with him?
Yeah, the taxidermist.
The taxidermist is
stuffing my mother.
Ugh! Kelly.
She's your sister. You should
call her once in a while. Check in.
Well, maybe she should check
in with me. Ever think of that?
Yeah.
That's interesting.
Listen, I've got a big
court date in a few minutes.
If I miss it, I'm kind of
screwed. Why do you waste your time
with that
Second Life bullshit?
Look at you, you're still in
jail. You were in jail last week.
Yeah. I'm a prisoner. It's
called "doing hard time. "
Can't you be like
a warrior or a shaman
or an Orc or some shit like that?
No, no. In life,
you make choices,
and if you screw up you have
to pay for those choices.
You're 20 years old, you haven't
made an important choice in your life.
What are you mad about?
What is this?
I don't know if you noticed,
but Lily moved out.
Is that what all
the shuffling was?
Uh-huh.
What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
No fucking way!
You know I'm a dreamer
But my heart's of gold
I had to run away high
So I wouldn't come home low
Just when things went...
...song And you'll
never be left all alone
I'm on my way
Home sweet home
Tonight, tonight
I'm on my way
Home sweet home
Even among the gentle
prairie squirrels,
The mate-less male is subjected
to a humiliating ritual.
Hello.
What?
Fuck!
Hey. Adam.
What's happening, man?
Hey.
You all right?
Hi, Courtney.
Hey, how you doing?
Nice to see you.
You, too.
Yeah.
Not here.
Long time.
Yeah. You know...
Work's been crazy and...
I know.
I called a couple of times.
Yeah. Yeah.
Very, very busy.
You think this is
a real situation
or just one of his
bullshit episodes?
I don't know.
You never know with Lou.
Well, hey, Adam,
how's your girlfriend?
Oh, really bad.
Okay.
Happy times.
Hi, folks. I'm Dr. Jeff. Lou's resting.
He's denying that it was a suicide
attempt and medically he's stable,
so legally we can't
keep him here.
But we do think that he should
be monitored for a few days.
Does he have any family?
Lou's family all
kind of hate him.
Okay. Well, then I guess it's
up to you guys, his friends.
You are his friends, right?
It's like that friend
who's the asshole.
But he's our asshole,
you know?
Right.
Yeah.
Dr. Jefferies to radiology.
Lou.
Why would he do this?
Why? I mean,
make a list.
He's an alcoholic,
he's divorced.
Wife ran off with
that Jamaican guy.
He's failed at every jive-ass
money hustle he's ever tried.
He's in
a mountain of debt.
He hates his mother.
He hates himself.
He hates everybody.
He has erectile
dysfunction.
He's got halitosis.
He's got
that runt ball.
Huh.
He said one of his balls
was shriveled up...
Oh, yeah.
...like a spoiled grape.
Wasn't it that
quarterback on the Bears
who had his ball crushed
on the field. Right?
Yeah.
Right, right.
'82? Yeah, yeah.
He came back
from that, though.
Strong as ever.
Fuck yeah.
But I don't know about Lou.
It's just like...
No.
It's just like an
accumulation of punishment.
Fuck you guys.
Oh!
Hey!
There he is. Hey.
I can fucking hear everything
you're saying, all right?
Look who's awake.
What's up, man?
Hey.
Hey, man.
What's up?
You look just
like my friend Nick.
And you look
like my friend Adam.
But you wouldn't be
those guys because
I've been calling
and calling them,
and they haven't
returned my calls.
So, listen, Violator.
Me and Nick got a
little surprise for you.
Something special that
the three of us can do.
Come on. You guys.
Are you curious?
No!
I didn't fucking try
and kill myself.
If I wanted to kill myself,
I'd fucking kill myself.
I'd be awesome at it.
A shotgun to the dick.
I'm glad you didn't do it.
It's good to see
you guys, anyway.
So, just out of curiosity,
what's the surprise?
Tell him.
Ko-di-ak...
...Valley.
No fucking way!
Yes, sir.
Yeah.
Fucking K-Vals?
Holy shit!
Yes, sir. Bang!
We fucking ski, right?
We fucking rage.
Chimney Point
at the end of the night
with a bottle of scotch
to wash it all down. Oh!
And you guys are paying
for the whole thing?
Sure.
Yep.
Let's go tonight.
We go tomorrow.
Let's go now.
I just got to get rid of this
thing. It's really uncomfortable.
You should wait for
the nurse or something.
I got it. I got it.
Hold on, Lou.
No, no, no, no.
Let somebody
do that for you.
Oh, shit.
God.
Did I get that on you?
Yes, you did.
Damn it!
It's only pee.
Relax, it's only pee.
There's Lou.
Good,
he's drinking already.
Look at this shit.
Do you remember when I was 12
and he tried to bite me?
Yeah, but he...
You had that coming.
Hey, Violator.
Lou.
What the fuck
is he doing here?
It's nice to
see you, too, Lou.
"Nice to see you, too, Lou. "
Fuck you, Jacob.
You suck and you know it.
You just ruined
my fucking weekend.
Hey, Lily will come back.
Trust me.
No, she won't.
She basically thinks
I'm an asshole, you know?
Like a completely
self-absorbed, delusional...
She's got a point.
... narcissistic.
Fuck you.
You're better off.
Take my word for it.
Look at me.
Fuck wives, man.
Fuck kids.
Lock it down or they will
take everything from you.
God damn it! Who the
fuck are you texting with?
Just a friend of mine.
Male or fucking female?
For your information, I've
had a lot of girlfriends.
Hot ones.
You have had lots of
boyfriends. Gay ones.
Hey, hey, hey,
check this out.
I brought a regulation bar
for tubbing tonight.
Nice.
I've got vodka,
fucking Tequilles O'Neals.
You guys are gonna love
this. Check this out.
Chernobly.
It's like
the Russian Red Bull.
It's got shit in it
that's not even legal here.
Like what shit?
How the fuck am I
supposed to know, dude?
But it's illegal.
Hey, why didn't we
just go to Pinnacle?
It would have taken,
like, half the time.
You wanna go to Kodiak Valley, trust me.
You're at
the right age for it.
Really?
Yeah. Nobody gets carded
and everybody gets laid.
K- Val! K-Val! K-Val!
Oh, shit! K-Val!
This? This is
the coolest town ever?
Fuck! That used to be Papa Enzo's.
I broke up with
Jenny Stedmeyer there.
What made you break
up with her, again?
I don't know. We swapped
virginities junior year.
All we did was listen
to records and have sex.
And she was epic, I mean
she was... She was epic.
Yeah, man.
She was hot.
And then when I broke up
with her, she was so mad,
she practically stabbed
me in the eye with a fork.
Actually, she did stab me
in the eye with a fork.
She was a one-percenter, man.
Yeah.
All downhill from there.
That was a big one.
First love.
The one that got away.
The great white buffalo.
Yeah.
The great what?
Great white buffalo.
Why are you guys
whispering?
Great white buffalo.
That was really helpful,
you guys. Thank you.
Look at this place.
I'm gonna make
a prediction right now.
One of us is gonna
start writing a novel,
and then we all
get snowed in,
and then Lou's gonna
ax murder all of us.
Motherfuck.
What's that smell?
Fucking cats.
Kind of a lot of cats.
This sucks.
Hi.
You got a reservation
For Webber-Agnew?
Sorry. What was that name again?
Webber-Agnew.
Webber and Agnew.
I got a "Nick Webber-Agnew. "
I'm sorry, excuse me. What?
What did you just say?
Webber-Agnew?
Webber-fucking-Agnew?
You took your wife's last name?
You're a fucking hyphenate?
A lot of dudes are doing
it. It's progressive.
No. No dudes
are doing it.
You look like a progressive
guy. Is that progressive?
Would you do that? No.
No.
And he has a goatee.
Does this guy seem a
little imbalanced to you?
No. Come on.
He's right there.
Shut up.
Let me give you
a hand with that.
Hey!
I am not going
to tell you again!
I can handle it.
This guy's
a fucking dick.
Shh. He's disabled.
He can hear you.
So what? He's exempt from
common fucking courtesy
'cause he can't start
a round of applause?
He's gotta jerk
off one-handed?
I mean, I certainly
don't take my hands
and I put them together
and oil them up...
Hey, 420. Our old room. Check it out.
That's okay man.
Oh! Those are mine.
I'll just get those.
This is the part where you tip
the guy that helped you out.
I'm not the guy that...
Nick, pay the man
something.
I got it.
Don't worry.
This place
looks like shit!
What happened
to that guy?
Check this shit out.
It's still there.
Adam sucks cocks 'n' dicks.
It's your best work.
Fucking burned you.
Burned!
Hey, guys,
come take a look at this.
We got a hot tub.
Sweet Jesus!
Poor little fella.
This is obviously
unacceptable, right?
We call downstairs,
get somebody to fix this?
Is anybody else hungry?
A little school spirit
this time, huh?
We're in, man. Just play
it like you fucking mean it.
Like that.
Yeah.
Yes, I would like to get a
hooker to fuck me and my friends.
What? Adam,
I'm not doing that.
Whatever, semantics.
I want an escort to escort
our penises into her vagina.
I want the girl
in the picture, too.
No tomfoolery. Wake
her up, I don't care.
Will you listen to him?
Does she do four?
What about three?
Okay. Jacob, you're out. Okay. Good.
I need $3,000.
I'm not in.
I'm married.
Adam, I need $2,000. Me
and you, buddy. Come on.
I'm out there, Violator.
Can I call you back, sir?
Okay. Thank you. Bye.
Sir?
Let's do something fun.
Let's create a memory, huh?
Let's get some cocaine
and break into a school.
Or steal a cop car
or some shit, huh?
Do you have Ritalin?
No.
Don't fucking lie to me. Every
one of you people have Ritalin.
No, I don't.
I'm sorry. You probably do have Ritalin.
I have some Ativan,
but it's different.
Let's stick it up our
asses. Just give it to him.
No. It's not
a suppository.
It doesn't matter. You crush it,
you put it in a warm paper towel,
run it under warm some water and you
stick it right up your ass. That works.
You put the paper towel
up your ass, too?
You crush up the...
Hey, I got an idea,
why don't we just play quarters? What?
I don't know what the fuck I'm
gonna do. I'm getting really sad.
You know what
I'm talking about?
I'm gonna go to the bathroom and
be alone with my own thoughts.
Who knows what's
gonna happen up there.
Who knows
what's gonna happen.
You better plan
something fun.
Jesus!
Pussies.
I'm going dancing.
I don't know, man. Maybe
coming here was a bad idea.
Yeah. If he kills
himself, can we go home?
Hard to believe
this is the very room
we had some of the best
weekends of our lives.
Really?
In this room right here?
How?
We were young. We had
momentum. We were winning.
We were best friends.
What do you mean,
"were" best friends?
You know what I mean, man.
Everybody seemed to care more.
Everything seemed
to matter more back then.
Whatever.
Check it out.
They must have fixed it.
Come on!
How's the water, Violator?
Oh, man.
You guys gotta get in here.
It's gonna fucking change you.
Wait, why are you naked?
You're all getting naked?
Yep.
You don't think
it's a little weird,
a bunch of guys
just piling up
in a big bathtub
together, naked?
Are you afraid that some of
these people might see you?
I'm sorry.
If I'm being honest,
I'm not totally comfortable being
around a bunch of other naked dudes.
It's called
male bonding, okay?
Haven't you even
seen Wild Hogs?
Fine, get us some snacks.
You know what? Fuck it.
I'm leaving
my underwear on.
Yeah. Yeah. Very nice. Shut up!
Damn, it's good to be here
with you all again, man.
It's good to be back
here with you guys. Yep.
I want to toast
to the good times.
And you, too, young blood.
Come on in, here.
Yeah!
This style seems wild
Wait before you treat me
like a stepchild
Let me tell you why
they got me on file
'Cause I give you
what you lack
Come right and exact
I stand accused of doing harm
'Cause I'm louder than a bomb
Come on
Come on, louder
Go, Violator!
I'm gonna throw up.
Snap out of it! Out
the tub! Out the tub!
I'm good. I'm good. I'm good.
I am a rock hard trooper To
the bone, the bone, the bone
Full grown
Consider me stone
Once again and
I say it for you to know
The troop is always ready
I yell "Geronimo"
Your CIA,
you see I ain't kiddin'
Both King and X
They got rid of both
And not the braggin'
or boastin' and plus
It ain't no secret why
they're tappin' my phone
Although I can't
keep it a secret
So I decided to kick it, yo
And yes it weighs a ton
I say it once again
Tappin' my phone
They never leave me alone
'Cause I'm louder than a bomb
Hey, little buddy.
Dude.
Where did the squirrel go?
Yeah. Yeah!
This is the black diamond? Shit.
Terrifying. That's all you got?
I don't remember this.
What do you think, boys?
Tips down.
Tips fucking down,
right away.
Let's ride.
I feel 19 again!
What is that?
Stop it, Lou.
Stop it, Lou!
Whoo!
Coming through!
You goddamn kids!
Slow down!
Hey!
Yard sale, bitches!
Fuck!
We dead.
Are you guys alive?
Holy fuck.
By all counts we should be pretty
fucked up right now, but I...
I kind of feel great.
I feel crazy right now.
I feel fantastic!
I wanna fuck something!
There they are.
I see it, Chaz. Thanks.
What is that one plank
thing that guy's got?
I don't care.
It's going up his ass.
Way to go, rookie!
Wow! Nice.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa...
Those are the kind of ski shenanigans
I don't allow on my mountain.
Yeah. Come on, guys.
What are you
looking at, Nancy?
No. I mean...
Hey, look, it's the douche
bag from Karate Kid III.
I know that guy.
Hey, guys.
Is there some kind of weird
retro thing going on this weekend?
Can't get any bars.
Morty!
Yeah, it's Chuck.
You're never gonna believe
where I'm calling you from, man.
I'm on a mountain
on my phone! Yeah.
Yeah, well, a bet's a bet.
I want my $2.
I'm telling you, something
weird is going on.
Demand your MTV.
I want my MTV.
S- A-F-E-T-Y
Safe, dance!
I love your hair.
I have a question.
...can still
tell me that's true.
But the facts and the
evidence tell me it is...
Dude is rocking
a cassette player.
Just relax. I'm sure there's
a reasonable explanation
for all this shit. Don't
fucking tell me to relax.
I said relax
for a minute.
Leg warmers?
Jheri curl?
"Where's the beef?"
Excuse me, miss, what
color is Michael Jackson?
Black.
Hold on! Sorry.
Excuse me. Sorry.
Nick, come on, man!
Nick! Nick!
Who the fuck is that?
That's probably
Ashton Kolchak right now
telling us we've been
punked or whatever.
Okay.
Come on. Come on.
Hey. Hey, guys.
I've got your luggage.
He's got both arms.
Get him!
What?
Check his arm.
Are you raping? Wait!
Hold on! Are we raping him?
Nobody's raping anybody!
Where's your missing arm,
motherfucker?
Hey! God!
That's my arm!
It's fake!
It's real!
It's got freckles on it
and shit!
Do I really got to be
the asshole that says
we got in this thing
and went back in time?
It must be some kind of
hot tub time machine.
Wow, my old stuff.
Look at this
shit, man.
You have a bong?
I did.
"Eddie Lives. " This shirt
got me so much fucking pussy.
You wanna see
what got a lot of pussy?
What's the tape recorder for?
Recording tape.
I gotta take a piss.
This jacket right here, baby. Holy fuck!
What are you,
Hunter S. Thompson?
I thought I was.
Is that coke?
What the fuck you think
it is? Baby powder?
Wait. How is
this happening?
Can we talk about this
for a minute?
Holy fuck! Winterfest '86.
We were here, man.
Guys.
We are here.
What if we run
into ourselves?
Guys!
We see ourselves and we blow
up and explode or some shit.
Get in here!
Didn't you all
fucking see Timecop?
God damn it! Get the
fuck in here right now!
Nobody wants to see
your giant shit, Lou.
What, man?
Yeah, we're not gonna
run into ourselves.
We are ourselves.
Why are we in our young bodies
and you in your regular body?
I don't know.
Shouldn't you
be invisible?
Or swimming around
some guy's ball sack?
I know. Because you guys
exist here and I don't.
Hey, why are you
flickering?
What? What? What? Who flickered?
He did.
He's flickering.
I need you to touch
my arm or something
to see if I'm
still real, okay?
Just see if you can put
your hand through me.
Okay.
That's good.
I'm physically still here.
That's good, I think.
You look like Kid 'N Play.
That's actually two people.
I knew this trip
was a bad idea.
Every time I hang out with you,
man, it's some kind of shit storm.
I got guilted into
coming on this trip
and now I'm back
in the fucking '80s.
And I hate this decade!
Maybe it's your
fucking fault!
You're a fucking insurance salesman,
you're practically the devil.
Guys! This is
scientifically possible.
Oh, my God. Okay, Professor
Hawking, tell me in your robot voice
how this is
scientifically possible.
All right,
I write Stargate fan fiction,
so I think I know what I'm
talking about right now.
I seriously almost passed
out, you're such a dork.
Okay. The tub is obviously some
kind of energy vortex, right?
Like a black hole.
But, instead of
being in space,
it's in a hot tub.
Time is not linear, we
just perceive it that way!
What?
Like The Terminator!
It's cyclical, right?
The machines send Schwarzenegger
back to kill Sarah Connor
so that John Connor
could never be born.
But if John Connor don't send
Michael Biehn back to protect her,
then they never fuck, and John
Connor ain't born in the first place!
It checks out.
Yeah, that's pretty good.
Wait, wait, check the fucking
drawer. See if the carving's there.
Check the fucking drawer.
Fuck!
It's gone.
This shit is real.
The carving you
made 20 years ago,
about me sucking
cocks and dicks,
it's not there.
Wait.
Is "cocks" still there?
Nothing.
I mean, it's not there.
What about "dicks"?
Neither "cocks,"
nor "dicks," nor "sucks. "
Oh, God!
That's it. We stuck in the fucking '80s!
How am I supposed
to get a job?
I'm so scared.
Looks like you
burned out your...
Heck, you fried
your timing crossover.
Would you mind
putting that down, sir,
that coal shovel,
before somebody gets hurt?
Did somebody call you?
Excuse me one minute.
Who ever calls us?
And who answers when the
call comes from within? Huh?
I thought maybe I could pull the
part from one of the other tubs.
But it turns out this is a very
special model that you have here.
You've got to be
very careful, I tell you.
One little thing is changed,
the whole system can go haywire.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
The whole system
can go haywire
if you change
one little thing.
Wait a minute. We need
that to get back in time?
Well, you're back here.
I mean, I can tell you've all
been to Kodiak Valley before.
I haven't.
Maybe not her,
but I know that
you were here.
You know what's going on
here, don't you, old man?
Yes, I do.
Your tub is on the fritz.
It'd behoove you to fix it.
What?
It's working.
Damn.
I think it's still broke.
Shit.
Where'd he go?
That motherfucker's
in on it, man.
What was all that
cryptic shit he was saying
about not changing
one little thing?
I know exactly what he meant. He was
talking about the butterfly effect.
That was
a great fucking movie.
One little change
has a ripple effect
and it affects
everything else.
Like, a butterfly
floats its wings
and Tokyo explodes, or there's
a tsunami in, like, somewhere.
Dude, yes, exactly.
Or you step on a bug
and the fucking
Internet's never invented.
Then you have to talk
to girls with your mouth.
Yeah. I was more concerned
about bigger consequences,
like me not being born.
Oh, yeah. No, I don't care about that.
The point is, what
did we do 20 years ago?
Let's figure it
out right now.
We gotta do
the exact same thing.
I had that gig.
That's right.
You got up on stage and
you were wildly mediocre.
And that led to
nothing of a career.
Okay, first of all,
fuck you, motherfucker!
I could have had a career, but I got
married and I went a different way.
Which way is that?
The way that sucked?
Didn't you also
bang that groupie?
What was her name?
Tara.
You banged her. You
got to go do that again.
I did do that. But,
fuck, no, I'm married!
I can't go around
banging girls in hot tubs.
Nick, it's 1986. You can't cheat
on someone you don't know yet.
You haven't
even met Courtney.
Lucifer,
itinerary please.
Uh... Nothing
really happened.
I actually fucked a chick,
too. So I'll just do that.
I seem to remember
you getting your ass whooped.
Oh, yeah.
That's right.
That ski patrol dude pummeled
you like it was his job.
Yeah, no. I don't remember it that way.
I do.
Yeah. He fucked you up.
You cried and peed.
Fuck this, man!
This is fucking bullshit!
Would you just think of somebody
other than yourself, man?
There's four of us.
It's the fucking '80s, guys!
Let's do what we wanna do.
Free love!
That's
the '60s, dipshit.
No, we had, like,
Reagan and AIDS.
Let's get the fuck
out of here, okay?
Do the right thing, Violator.
God damn it!
This is fucking bullshit!
Tonight's the night you
broke up with Jenny Stedmeyer.
Shit.
Yeah, you got stabbed
in the fucking
eyeball tonight!
Hey, man,
do you want backup?
I can't, the butterflies won't let me.
Yo, Adam?
You guys in there?
Oh, shit.
There you are. Hey!
How come you guys didn't meet us
at the chair lift this morning?
You were going to
show me some moves.
Hi, baby.
I missed you.
I must have forgot.
Perv. That's from Mandy.
Hey, new guy. What's up? Hey.
So we're in 214.
I'm gonna go get ready.
Okay. Meet me in my room, okay?
Okay.
Love the PJs, Nick.
You look hot.
Poison's tonight.
Wow!
I don't remember her
being that fucking beautiful.
And tight.
She's so tight.
She's really
fucking tight!
She's the great
white buffalo, man.
Great white buffalo.
Don't start that.
Why did I ever
break up with her?
Why would I
Doesn't matter.
'Cause you have to
do it again. Right?
Right, right, right.
All right. We're
all gonna meet back here.
Hopefully that hot tub's fixed and
we can get the fuck out of here.
Okay, let's party
like it's 1986.
All right. On three?
One, two, three...
Hot tub time machine!
Wait...
What are we...
What's the...
Who said,
"Hot tub time machine?"
We didn't tell you about the
new thing, with our hands?
No.
On three, we always...
From now on, we're gonna
say, "Hot tub time machine. "
I told you, I think
that's fucking stupid.
You were in
the bathroom.
No, but this is a real
bonding event for us.
This doesn't happen
all the time.
Come on.
I'm telling you, it's stupid.
Do it once.
Do what you want to do.
It would have been
3- to-1 anyway.
One, two, three...
...hot tub time machine!
It felt good. Admit it.
Hey!
Let's get
this party started!
Who is carrying
me home tonight?
Mom?
Sweet fucking Lord.
Kelly.
Hey, bro, Nicholas.
Hey, girl.
Who's the geek?
He's your son.
That's not appropriate.
I'm sun...
Sunshine.
'Cause I'm here to
brighten your day.
That's Jacob.
Your...
He's totally cool.
He doesn't look cool.
He's not that cool.
Hey, Kelly.
Lou Dorchen. Yeah...
You don't remember this?
I don't remember
everything.
What the fuck, man? This
is freaking me the fuck out.
You freak out every time
you leave the basement.
All right, kiddies,
get your snow boots on
because tonight there
is gonna be a blizzard.
Really? It looked
pretty clear out.
Anybody wanna go
for a little sleigh ride?
You can't do cocaine!
It's so unhealthy for you.
Kelly, in public?
Whatever.
I'm gonna go to a party
at the ski patrol house,
I'm gonna find
a sexy instructor
and I'm gonna wax
his fucking pole.
Later, homos. Don't
drink my fucking drink.
Ugh!
Hey, Adam?
What she means is that she works
at the ski rental place, right?
And that's her job,
is cleaning the poles.
I could be off, but I think it's
in reference to blowing a dude.
Thank you, Nick. But
that's... You don't need to...
Or fucking a dude.
Because the wax,
it can be interpreted either way.
She was a free spirit,
you know?
Or maybe she's the pole and
there's two dudes that she's waxing.
Let's just get it done, man. Come on.
Hey, Lou.
What?
Did my mom, like, sleep
with a bunch of dudes?
I don't know.
Shut up.
But she seems kind of slutty, right?
Does she seem
that way to you?
It's just, she never
told me who my dad is.
It could be any
one of these guys.
'Cause I was born, like,
nine months from now.
Yeah? So what does that mean?
It means do the math,
dipshit.
I could have been
conceived this weekend.
Oh, shit.
Check this out.
That's that fucking bellhop.
I hate that guy.
This must be where
he loses the arm!
Shit!
Thank you!
I think we should tell
him. This is gruesome.
Don't you dare
fucking tell him.
You'll screw
the time thing up.
Yeah!
Yes!
What the fuck?
Yeah!
Boo! We just got
fucking robbed.
What are you
talking about?
He's great, man.
Come on!
Jenny.
Jenny?
I'm in the bathroom.
Come in.
What do you think?
Oh, my God.
What? Do I look fat?
No. You look
really beautiful.
Aw! Thank you.
How about me,
do I look different?
Do I look kind of older?
No.
You look cute, though.
God, I can't stop
thinking about last night.
It was like frigging hot.
It was? What did we
do? I don't remember.
You lasted,
like, 10 minutes.
Oh!
Good, good.
And I was good.
I think I came. I think. I can't
even tell you what it was like.
I got some vague
recollection of that.
Wanna maybe just sit
and talk for a minute?
"Talk. "
Well, I mean, you know, it's
just so good to see you again.
It's not you. It's me.
Lamp.
You know what, I think we
should go to Poison now.
You're weird today.
I know.
You are funny.
Let me just get dressed.
Okay.
Wow!
Oh, man!
This is trippy.
What's up?
Man, I can't even remember
the last time I saw you guys.
Yesterday.
Oh, yeah. Yesterday.
Yep.
It's not cheating. It's
not cheating. It's 1986.
You don't even
know Courtney yet.
You know, it's okay
if you're scared, Lou.
I'm not scared, idiot.
I'm fucking pissed.
I have a full head of hair
and a functioning penis,
and I'm looking for some guy
to drill me in the fucking jaw.
We're not gonna
find him here, anyway.
I don't even remember
what he looks like.
Walk much, faggot?
Sorry.
What? No, don't touch me.
The fuck, you're sorry.
You scuffed up my Jordans.
You wanna go for it? Come on,
take a shot, pussy. Wanna party?
Wanna be a hero?
And here it comes.
Yeah, you gonna cry?
You gonna cry, titty baby?
You gonna fucking cry?
Look at him he's crying.
Your fucking bag
is mine now.
Is that it?
No.
No, I yell back at him
and I challenge him to a
rematch at midnight saying,
"You bring your friends
and I'll bring mine. "
And my friends
don't fucking show up.
So I get pummeled
by six guys instead of one.
All right, fantastic.
Let's do this.
Lou, come on.
You have to.
Hey, Blaine.
Is that all you got?
Pussy.
Oh, God. Yeah.
I'll never go back.
Are you crying?
No.
It's the water splashing my
face from all the fucking.
Okay, good.
Because I thought you were
crying, and I was like...
Yeah!
I'm sorry, Courtney.
It's Tara.
Courtney!
Tara. Tara.
Courtney! Courtney!
No, seriously,
my name is Tara.
No, my wife, my wife.
You're married?
No, I'm not married.
Not now, anyway.
I will be.
She's nine right now.
Can I tell you something
that I haven't told anybody?
She cheated on me.
I found a e-mail.
And now every time
I look at her,
all I can see is
her getting rammed by
some faceless dude with a
better body and a bigger dick.
Truth of it is, I can't even
bring myself to say anything
because I just love
her so fucking much.
I don't even know if I can
live without her cheating ass.
Hey, what's an e-mail?
That's not the point!
Seems like you might've took
one defensive swing against him.
I mean, honestly, what
the fuck, man? That was...
I don't know how you've lived
with yourself all these years.
It was pathetic.
It was pathetic. You couldn't
have kicked him from the ground?
What happened?
Uh...
This is a crazy story.
I got hit by a truck.
Yeah, yeah.
Trying to save a baby deer,
if you can believe that.
Oh, my God!
Is there anything that
I can do? Are you okay?
Oh, my God. No, I'm
fine. This is nothing.
You know what? Come with me.
I'm gonna take care of you.
And bring your friend.
No, we can't.
We'd love to, but we
can't. We can, we can.
We should probably go check
on that deer, actually.
No, we can go.
We can go.
I know you cannot wait
Wait to see me, too
Oh, my God!
This is like
the best song ever!
Maybe not ever.
At the drive-in
God, he's so hot!
In the old man's Ford
Behind the bushes
Can I get 3,000 beers?
Until I'm screaming for more
Down the basement
Who's next?
Who's next for the beer luge?
This guy! This guy's
next! He wants it so bad.
You can do it, man.
He wants it.
Luge! Luge! Luge!
That was so lame. That wasn't,
like, even violent a little bit.
Who are you, and why
did you do that to me?
Why? Because you looked
like you needed a luge.
I'm Adam.
I'm April.
How are you doing?
All right.
What brings you here?
Hot tub.
Huh.
You?
Poison.
Right.
That band. Poison.
I'm a journalist. I'm covering
the band for Spin magazine.
You don't really look
like you're the type.
The Poison type? God, no.
I'm not. I'm really not.
I basically just
got onto this bus
and it took me here,
to goddamn Winterfest.
Adam!
Whoo!
You know what?
I can't talk to you.
You can't?
But I'm awesome.
I can guarantee that.
I'm sure. You see, I have to
walk in the exact same footsteps.
This didn't happen.
Well, it kind of
happened.
I wish it did.
I just saw it happen.
It really didn't.
Yeah. No, I contributed.
I wish it did.
All right.
See you.
I brought you some ice.
It'll make you feel better.
Let's see that.
Feel better?
That ice does
make me feel better.
Butterflies.
Hey, you know what? I just
remembered I gotta meet a guy.
No, no. Wait.
No, you can't go.
'Cause guess what?
What?
I only do two at a time.
What do you mean?
What do I mean?
There those are.
Yeah, let's do this.
Him first? Okay.
It's your thing. I don't
wanna tell you what to do.
Hold on,
I gotta get the phone.
Hello? Mom?
What?
I wanna know what
the doctor said.
Lou? Lou,
we can't do this.
Yes, we can.
No, this didn't happen.
We can't do this.
Yes, we can.
This didn't happen in the
past. Yes, it did. Shut up.
This did not fucking
happen in the past.
You shut the fuck up,
please.
We're gonna make, like,
Hitler president or something.
We can't do this.
Look, can you be fucking normal? Please?
Every young man's fantasy
is to have a three-way.
Not with another fucking
guy. It's still a three-way.
What about the policy
of the butterfly effect?
The butterfly effect
can suck my nuts!
Look, we're gonna have sex
with this girl, okay?
You, me, together.
Enough of this queer shit.
Let's get the mood right.
All right.
Look, right there.
What?
You don't wanna seem
overzealous with a full-on rager.
You don't want to
insult the woman, either.
You're gonna wanna get at least
a half-a-chub going, right?
Look at me.
No.
Look at that.
Look at how, like,
perfect that is.
I'm not gonna
fucking look.
Look, look. Here.
What the fuck, man?
I'm out of here.
Come on, Jake,
I was just getting you
started. Don't care!
Guys do that.
No one does that!
Hey. Onesies?
Sorry.
Okay, cool.
I'm out of here.
Hey.
How did it go
with Jenny?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Whoo!
Why aren't you dancing?
Whoa! What's your name?
That's Jacob.
That's Jenny.
What the fuck
are you doing?
You're supposed to break
up with her! I know.
No, no, no.
Just check it out, okay?
Maybe she's
the key to something.
And I messed it up when I
broke up with her before,
and now the universe is
giving me another crack at it.
And if you thought
you could really start over
and do something
totally different,
you wouldn't
even consider it?
You're absolutely right.
You think so? Really?
No. Fuck, no!
Come on!
What do you mean,
you didn't do it?
I'm getting to it.
No, we were supposed to do
everything that we did.
That's what I remember.
Yeah, Adam,
what the fuck, man?
You were supposed
to fucking dump her.
You think I liked getting my ass
fucked up and down the entire street?
Because I didn't. It's not
that I'm not gonna do it,
I just haven't done it yet.
There's a big difference.
Look at my face, dude.
Look at my fucking face!
Drink me in.
You think I wouldn't have
liked to have changed this?
Shut the fuck up, Lou. You tried
to rope me into a three-way.
What?
Did you?
No.
Yes.
Lou! Did you?
I didn't fuck that girl.
Okay?
Because I'm committed
to not changing the past.
Right. It had nothing to do with her
wanting to be
a Chinese finger trap.
And I'm not saying that
because she was Asian.
So you're telling me I cheated
on my wife for no reason.
Just relax, okay?
I'm gonna do it.
I just haven't done it yet!
You're unbelievable.
Hey, Nick, can I ask
you a question? Yes.
Does this seem like
it's all about Adam again?
Yeah, just like
Cincinnati.
What?
You gonna bring that up?
We said we weren't gonna talk
about Cincinnati ever, okay?
Is this why you have that shoebox in
your closet that says "Cincinnati"?
Yeah.
What?
That's fucking admissible!
You keep it
in the closet?
What was I supposed to do with
it? You can't bury those things.
And you wrote
"Cincinnati" on it?
How do I know which one
it's supposed to be?
Is it a fetus?
My friends
are ridiculous.
Why are we still
talking about this?
Okay, we said we would
never talk about that.
By the way, where does it say in
the fucking friendship handbook
that you are the only one who
is allowed any fucking problems?
I forgot that it says
in the asshole handbook
that you can just fuck over
your friends whenever you want!
Actually, it would say that
in the asshole handbook
if it was, like, guidelines
for being an asshole,
that's what it would say.
Why wouldn't it say that
in the asshole handbook?
Yeah, it would say
to fuck your friends.
"Fuck over your friends. "
No, no, no.
Have you ever read a book?
You're right. I'm sorry,
my bad. You guys are right.
But if you're changing
the fucking past, okay,
then I'm changing the
fucking past, all right?
No! Lou!
Okay! We're in the game!
I like this.
I didn't change anything yet,
I just didn't do it.
And if we're
changing shit,
you better be there at
midnight to get my fucking back.
Done.
I'll be there.
Guys! Guys! Come on, man.
Talk to me about this!
Fuck off.
Fuck!
I'll be back in a minute.
Where are you going?
I gotta go.
I'm getting out of here.
No, no, Adam,
listen to me, please.
Jenny Stedmeyer is not
your fucking destiny, okay?
She's just some girl.
Some girl you dated
in high school, okay?
I know! I just got
some emotions coming up.
I got some feelings
that I got to deal with.
I'm gonna do it. I believe
in you. You're awesome.
You know what? That's fine.
Everybody just take off!
I don't need to be born.
I'll just go find the repairman
myself and fix the time machine.
That's the dumbest thing
I've said in a while.
You made the best
decision of your life,
choosing me as
your friend over Adam.
I'm pretty sure that's
not what's going on here.
Don't be afraid.
I'm gonna treat you right.
Daddy's gonna take care of you. Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa!
Here we go. It's like
a slow-motion guillotine.
What the F-ing fuck?
Here we go.
Here we go. Round two.
Should we help him?
No. No.
This is his destiny.
Fuck you!
Did it happen?
No.
If that guy doesn't
lose his arm soon,
I'm gonna fucking
take it from him myself.
Man!
Blaine!
Come on down, man.
Have a brewski with us.
There's a party.
"No foreign army has ever
occupied American soil.
"Until now. "
Watching Red Dawn again,
or...
Wolverines!
They're Ruskies.
And these are their
secret Commie weapons.
What are you
talking about?
Look at this stuff, man.
They could be
spies or something.
I don't know, Blaine. I
mean, they seem a little young
to be spies, you know.
Come on, Chaz.
They could be some
kind of 21 Jump Street
spy battalion-type dudes.
Yeah. Yeah. Or not at all,
you know? There's also that.
What the fuck is this?
There's something I
wanna talk to you about.
It's something I'm supposed
to do but I don't wanna do.
You know why?
Okay, Adam. But...
Because I was thinking about
how good we are together, right?
Don't you think? I
really think so. Okay.
And I was talking about the
future and I was thinking about,
well, my future is this way
and maybe it could be this way.
I know I'm rambling now.
God, you're so beautiful.
But we got along
so great and...
What is that?
It's a note I wrote to
you. You should read it.
Right now? Okay.
Yeah.
"Dear Adam, you're a
super-terrific guy and I love you.
Aw!
"And that's why
this is so hard for me.
"You're one of the most amazing
people that I've ever met. I can't... "
Are you breaking up with me? That's
what this... This is a break-up note?
I'm sorry, Adam.
All these years! You stabbed me
in the eye with a fucking fork
and you were gonna
break up with me anyway?
Is that what
you're saying to me?
I did what?
Why are you breaking up with
me? That's not how this works.
You're such a great guy and
you're gonna find the right girl,
but it's not me.
And everybody knows what a big
deal you're gonna be some day.
No, I'm not. I'm not. I'm not anybody.
Adam, okay.
It's not you, it's me.
I say that to you.
You don't say that to me.
That's not how this works.
Do you know what happens
to you if we don't go back?
You end up with
Billy Lavatino.
I like him.
You may like him, but then you end
up pregnant with, like, trucker hips,
and you have a baby
with Billy Lavatino,
and you're addicted to Weight
Watchers, you little bitch.
What did you just call
me? Take this fucking back!
Don't you... Jesus!
I don't get fat!
Gross!
If we're changing shit, we gotta
be taking advantage of shit.
No.
Mulligan.
No mulligan.
Come on!
You had, like, five mulligans. Dude.
I'm not talking about
bad stuff, either, okay?
I'm just talking
about good stuff.
Like keeping Manimal
on the air, you know?
Or preventing
Miley Cyrus.
Preventing her
from what?
Just preventing her.
And there's the catch!
First down!
Oh, shit!
I know this game.
Yeah?
Yeah. This is the
Denver-Cleveland playoff game.
This is
the fucking Drive, man.
Yeah?
I know what
we're gonna do.
Adam, hey. You're back. Awesome.
What's going on here?
Where are the guys?
What's this?
Read it.
"Dear Adam, you are a
super-terrific guy and I love you,
"which is why this is so hard for
me. I cherish our friendship. "
She broke up with you?
And you still fucking
got stabbed in the eye?
Leave me alone.
Get out of here.
What are you doing here?
You writing poetry?
Just leave me alone
and get out of here. No.
You're writing
fucking break-up poetry.
All right, I'm writing
break-up poetry, okay?
Because my heart hurts.
She stabbed me in
my heart and my eye.
Holy shit, you're wasted.
Look, I've had like two wine
kills, Captain Buzzcooler.
God.
You're fucked up.
"Jenny's eyes, like a gypsy's
lies Cut right through the night
"Now those eyes are another
guy's And I'm alone with my pain"
That was clean.
Are you shitting
me with this, Adam?
Look, you can
recite it straight
or to the tune of
Sweet Child O' Mine.
It doesn't matter.
Are these mushrooms? Did you
eat these mushrooms, Adam?
I like to eat them, you
know? A couple of them.
Holy fuck, man,
you gotta stay straight!
You gotta help me get
the guys back! Just relax.
You know, it's not always
about my emotional journey.
It could be about yours.
Put the coke down!
God damn it, you little
fucker! Give it to me!
Don't you fucking get it?
I'm not gonna be fucking born!
How much worse
can it get?
What? The '80s?
New part shorted
out another part.
I hope we can get that
thing working before dawn.
Wait, wait, hold on,
is that when the time
portal closes, at dawn?
That's when
the party's over.
Fuck you, man. Listen.
I am at my wit's end with him,
so you gotta level with me.
Are you the mystical
time-travel guide-guy or not?
Don't you put your
hands on me, young lady!
I'm just trying
to do my job, here.
Fuck, hold on.
Quit eating mushrooms, man!
I wanna have a few more.
What the fuck is
happening to me? I can't...
Dawn.
Hey, Adam.
All right, so anyway, the
repairman's doing his thing.
I'm gonna go
find Nick and Lou,
and you stay right here.
Okay?
I'm gonna stay.
You got it,
but you can't leave.
I can't move,
because I'm broken.
Man, you and my mom
are so fucked.
Hungry.
Evening.
You've got two arms.
But you're not going to.
You're gonna lose one.
What?
You're gonna
lose that arm.
You're one of those
joker guys.
Right. Right.
I don't care if you put that
arm in a steel fucking vault,
that arm's coming off!
You're gonna
lose your arm.
lose your arm!
I'm gonna rape you.
I'm gonna rape you!
Have a great night.
Okay.
...to the end zone.
Touchdown Cleveland!
Pay up, suckers!
Pay up!
How does he do it? How
is he right all the time?
Let me ask you
something, McFly.
How you getting so lucky?
I know the fucking future,
douche bag.
Really? One more bet.
Ricky, come on. You said one
more and then you'd be done.
I also said to shut the
fuck up. Remember that?
Okay, I love you.
Shut the fuck up.
By the way,
I love your coat.
I don't give a shit about
animals, either, so...
One more bet.
High stakes.
All right. All right.
Bring it on, Spader.
Bring it on, Jo-Jo.
I bet Elway throws
a touchdown pass
with 37 seconds
left on the clock.
Fat chance, asshole.
Elway's done nothing all day.
Well then, in the spirit of high
stakes, let's make it interesting.
Let's make it
interesting.
If I win, your wife gives me a blowjob.
Really?
A classy one.
Hey, screw you, kid.
Hey, okay,
and if you win,
name your price.
Touchdown pass at
37 seconds, exactly?
Exactly.
Fine.
You lose,
I take all your winnings.
Done.
And you give your
buddy a blowjob.
What? Hell, no.
Wow!
Deal.
Deal?
Well done. I like your
style. I like your style.
He's very creative.
I don't like you taking
liberties with my dick.
Relax, okay?
We know the fucking future.
We can't lose.
Hey. Hey, there.
What are you doing?
Hi.
Hey.
Okay, how's the view
from down there?
It's nice.
Adam, right?
Yeah.
Why are you
bleeding in the snow?
That? No, I...
I got stabbed in the face with a fork.
I saw it coming and I avoided
it. I mean, I didn't avoid it.
It just happened again to me
in a slightly different way.
Boy, I really wish I knew what
the fuck you were talking about.
All the choices we make in
our life, they're pointless.
There's no escaping
the inevitable.
I don't know, man.
So, you're saying that your whole
entire life is predetermined to suck,
no matter what you do?
It's not the way
I want it, but...
Kind of seems like
a really, really good excuse
to do something totally
amazing right now, tonight.
Like what?
Like perhaps hang out with
a girl that you just met
before her bus has
to leave in two hours?
Right-o.
I thought you said we were
going to get some food.
We are. We're about to get some food.
I'm pretty hungry,
actually.
Damn it. They forgot to leave the key.
Who did?
Carol and Stan Stapleton. They're
my friends. They live here,
and I housesit for them when
they go to Nepal, sometimes.
I thought you said
you came in here on a bus.
They usually do leave,
like, a side door open.
They do? So let me...
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Yep, it's unlocked.
Cheers.
So which one's Carol?
Carol's on the left.
Elway's last stand.
45 seconds left on the clock.
I'm really good at
getting head. You'll see.
Elway takes the snap.
Go, baby.
He fades back. Elway fires.
He's got Jackson open.
He's impossibly open!
Wait, what's this? Vermin?
No, no, no!
I know this squirrel.
That's a magic fucking
squirrel. This doesn't count.
He's distracted
by a wild squirrel!
What the fuck?
Incomplete! Game's over! Cleveland wins!
The Dawg Pound is going
to the Super Bowl.
Oh, yeah!
I've never seen
anything like it!
He did it. Got to go!
Congratulations.
Look at all that money.
I was kidding about the blowjob
thing. Obviously, we're comedians.
Hey, guys. Guys.
A bet's a bet.
Motherfucker!
So you're a Time Lord?
Mmm-hmm.
And a Jacuzzi is
your spaceship?
That is correct, madam.
That's the only part
of this whole thing
that doesn't
make sense to me.
You're not the only one.
Believe me.
I mean, the whole thing
is just totally insane.
Ew!
So, how's the future
working out for you?
I mean, are you like a happy grownup?
Not particularly, no.
Yeah.
My friends actually
think I ended up being
a completely selfish,
fucked-up person.
And they may have a point,
actually, if I think about it.
Hmm...
I'll tell you something I haven't
told somebody for a long time.
When I was a kid,
every Friday night, my father
used to take my sister Kelly and me
to this place called
Flatirons for steak sandwiches.
It was a family tradition.
That's sometimes
a good thing.
But one year,
we saw this commercial
for this place called The
Enchanted Forest of Pizza.
So the next Friday, my dad's
loading us up into the car.
We're like, "Daddy, we want to go
to The Enchanted Forest of Pizza. "
And he's like,
"What are you talking about?
"We always go for
steak sandwiches. "
But we just stay at him
and we're whining, and we're
badgering, and finally he relents.
Nice. So, you win.
You deviated from the plan in
a really big way. That's good.
33 people died of E. Coli.
Including my father.
Before he died, he
looked at me and he said,
"Adam, you did this. "
No, he didn't.
Yes, he did,
with his eyes.
I don't think that that's
what he meant with his eyes.
The point is that Kelly and I dealt with
the guilt of this in very different ways.
She went wild, right?
She didn't want to have
control over anything.
But I vowed
to master the chaos,
to impose order.
Adam, I really don't think
that you can let a poison pizza
ruin the rest of your life.
You got to embrace
the chaos. You have to.
That way, life might just astonish you.
I had so much fun tonight.
I know!
Fuck! Game on.
You look so hot, by the way.
Thanks.
I said,
start sucking, gaylord.
Yeah! Suck!
Suck that shit, man!
Suck! Suck! Suck!
Who are you people?
God, who are you people?
Let's get on with this.
My fondue's getting cold.
Choke on that horn, man!
Oh!
Wow, good for you.
I know, right?
It's like Gary Coleman's
fucking forearm.
It's so black!
It's so impossibly black.
I love you, buddy.
Don't say that!
I'm sorry, I do.
No, no, no!
Hey, you.
Maybe what you need
isn't in here, after all.
has always been in here.
Really?
No.
The tub?
Is it fixed yet?
Can be. Ready to go?
Wait, go where?
To the room, check it out.
I've got the part right here.
Yeah. Yeah, let's go.
Let's go.
Right.
Where did he go?
Who?
This fucking guy.
Nicholas.
Nicky. Nicholas.
Hey! There he is!
What?
What the fuck?
What? What?
What, do I still
have some on my face?
Oh, God!
Damn!
Did you have
pineapple today?
I can't go home.
What the fuck?
I'm fucking with you, dude.
It's hand soap.
Oh, my God. Relax.
It's like you haven't
seen a little come
on your friend's face before,
or something.
What the fuck is
wrong with you, man?
I'm just kidding.
It's what friends do. God!
You didn't?
Gargle your hog?
No, man.
After they pulled you off of
me, me and Rick talked it out.
He's actually
a pretty cool guy.
We have a lot in common. We
both love tits and Mtley Cre.
It's cool?
Yeah, I just told
him a bunch of shit
that's gonna make
him rich in the future.
I saved
the good stuff for us.
Let's go to the bar,
plan our empire.
Fucking iPods, you know?
Fucking Prius.
Match. Com. Anything. Com.
Fucking Internet. Com!
Fucking Zac Efron.
Nobody invented him yet.
What about Twitter?
Whatever the fuck that is.
Hey, we could combine
Twitter with fucking Viagra.
Twitt-agra.
What's the matter, dude?
Come on.
I'm sorry, man.
I'm just preoccupied.
You just kind of down about
being black and out of shape?
What the fuck is
wrong with you? No.
Because you look good,
you know?
This is a great time
for black people.
I mean our time,
not this time.
This is a terrible time
for black people.
I don't see one other
black person in here.
Talk to me, man.
I found out she
fucking cheated.
What? Courtney's
fucking cheating on you?
I gave her my life,
I gave up my passion.
And she's just
out there...
Why the fuck didn't
you say something, man?
That's just it! I never
see you guys anymore.
I don't have my music,
I barely have friends.
Without Courtney,
I'm nothing.
You're just fucking
Courtney's bitch right now.
You need to be your own man, you know?
"Nick Webber-Agnew"?
What the fuck is that?
It's terrible.
It doesn't work.
No. Nick Webber,
that's who you are.
That's who I was.
Maybe you gotta
find him again.
You know, she's getting
hers, you go get yours.
I can't, man.
It means something
to me to be married.
You're not fucking married.
It's 1986.
In my heart I am.
Your heart's
a fucking liar.
You know what? You
know what you got to do?
What?
You gotta get your
ass up on that stage.
You're right.
I'm gonna do it.
Yeah. Do it.
Hey, hey, hey. Do it
fucking quickly, okay?
You better be at
that fight with me.
Don't leave me
hanging this time.
I won't. I promise.
All right.
Hey, Adam. Fuck.
Guys?
You're good to go.
Holy shit. Really?
Some sort of
sticky liquid got into
the crossover housing,
I don't know.
Must have had some
nitratriminium in it.
It's Chernobly.
Whatever it was, it ravaged
the hell out of the electronics.
Worked out for you
and the boys, though.
Wait, hold on,
are you saying that
that's the key to
the whole thing?
We need the Chernobly
to get back?
All I'm saying is, whatever your
poison, I wouldn't tub without it.
Especially after dawn.
It'd kill you to give
me a straight answer?
You know,
you're kind of a dick.
Hey, everybody,
you ready to jam?
All right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
help me welcome to the stage
Nick Webber!
Hi.
It's been a long time.
No, I'm never
gonna dance again
Guilty feet
have got no rhythm
Jessie is a friend
Yeah, I know he's been
a good friend of mine
But lately something's
changed It ain't hard to define
Jessie's got himself a girl
And I want to make her mine
These guys are dangerous.
Look at this stuff.
Blaine, it looks
like a skinny soda can.
No, a soda-can bomb! This
stuff's straight out of Moscow.
Let's go kick
that Commie's ass!
Chaz.
Shouldn't we call the cops
or the FBI or something?
No, we're gonna
handle this internally.
I wish that I had
Jessie's girl
Yeah
This song is from the future,
but since you've been good,
you get it early.
Just like we rehearsed.
Let's get it started
in here
And the bass keep runnin'
runnin' And runnin' runnin'
And runnin' runnin'
In this context
There's no disrespect
So when I bust my rhyme
You break your necks
We got five minutes
For us to disconnect
From all intellect
Collect the rhythm effect
So lose your inhibition
Follow your intuition
Free your inner soul
And break away from tradition
'Cause when we beat out
Girl, it's putting heat out
You wouldn't believe
How we wow shit out
Burn it till it's burned out
Turn it till it's turned out
Act up from north,
west, east, south
Everybody, everybody
Let's get into it
Get stupid
Get it started
Let's get it started
Let's get it started in here
Everybody, everybody
Let's get into it
Get stupid
Get it started
Get it started, get it started
Let's get it started
Hey, where's
the Kodiak Club?
Down the street, dude.
Okay. Okay, thank you.
Listen, me and my boys
got some shit-kicking to do.
But this
Ain't over.
Get out of my way, stool.
Transmit hits
with no delusion
The feeling's irresistible
And that's how we moving
Everybody
Let's get into it
That's my boy,
right there.
The singer?
Yeah.
Let's get it started
I'll be back. My friends are
over there. I'll come right back.
Lose control
Of body and soul
Don't move too fast, people
Just take it slow
I'm caught right in the
middle of a thing right now,
but can I text you later?
Can you what?
Are you online at all?
I have no idea
what you're saying.
How do I get
a hold of you?
You come find me.
That just sounds
exhausting.
With no delusion
The feeling's irresistible
And that's how we moving
There he is.
Where are your boys?
I thought they were
gonna hold your sack.
Let's kick his ass, Blaine.
Where are my fucking friends?
Whoo-hoo!
Let's get
In here
Whoo-hoo!
While I get
You like that song?
Yeah, it's great.
It's gonna be a hit.
And runnin' runnin'
Thank you. Thank you.
Yes.
That was sweet.
All right.
All right, man.
Good to have you back,
see you back up there, man.
Hey, it's coming back. I
should have done this years ago.
Guys. Adam. Guys!
About time.
Did you see him?
Did you see him rock out?
Shut up! Okay, we gotta find
the Chernobly to get out of here.
Chernobly? Why?
I don't know, exactly.
But the repairman said
it's got nitro-trainium...
Nitratrinanium.
Thank you.
Or some shit in it
that'll fix the time machine.
That makes sense.
Where's Lou?
Where is...
What time is it?
Fuck! Fuck! Shit! Shit!
Lou!
Where is he?
Fuck.
Oh, my God!
We missed it again!
Well, where do you think
he went?
Same place as last time?
Keeps me together at the seams
I'm on my way
Shut up, you flamer!
Hey, go home! Loser!
Hey, John Lennon gets shot!
Wait, did that
already happen?
Lou!
Whoo!
They made it, everybody! Whoo!
Best friends in the world!
Almost just in time!
My buddies.
Fucking Chimney Point, right?
Here we are.
Bottle of scotch,
end of the night.
Where were you?
We were just...
We came...
Not tonight.
Every fucking night.
Huh? What happened? We were
gonna do shit together, man.
We were gonna conquer the
fucking world. Me and you.
And then you cut me off.
What was I
gonna do, man?
I was gonna let you drag me
down into your bullshit, Lou?
Yeah. Yes, because
that's what friends do.
No, they don't, man!
Because then there's two
people stuck in the bullshit
instead of your sorry ass.
You should stick by your
friends through thick and thin!
Okay, great. I got two
things to say to you.
Okay.
Okay?
Number one, I hate you.
Got it.
Our friendship
means nothing.
All right, is that the first
thing or the second thing?
What? No, clearly that's
still part of the first thing.
I mean, am I the asshole?
Did you get that?
No, I didn't get it. I
thought... He didn't get it.
He said A and B...
Let's agree to disagree
about the "first" thing.
Lou, where is the Chernobly?
We need it to get back.
"Where's the Chernobly
at, Lou?"
That's all you ever
fucking care about.
It's the first time
he mentioned it.
Yeah, and even if we had
mentioned it before,
it's kind of a fucking big
deal, okay? I wanna go home.
Come on, Lou.
Let's talk about this inside.
You got no shoes on.
It's cold out.
Who took my fucking shoe?
Blaine apparently beat
your shoe off of you,
which I don't even know how
that could fucking happen.
Okay, fuck it! Fuck you,
fuck you and fuck you!
Easy, man.
Whoa, Lou!
I got you.
Oh, my God!
Is Lou dead?
Shit!
There he is.
I can't hold on.
Yes, you can!
Yes, you can hang on!
I'm slipping.
No, hold on.
No, Nick.
Hold on. Guys!
Phil! Phil!
Oh, fuck!
We're dead! This is how it
happens! This is how he loses it!
Fuck it!
Fuck it, we're dead men!
Just let me go.
Lou, be positive.
The roof is
scraping my nut!
Damn, you strong.
All right.
You're all right? I'm glad
you guys are all right.
My fault.
Why do you do
shit like that?
I'm sorry! Jesus!
Thank you, Phil.
All right, here's the
second fucking thing, okay?
Blaine's got the Chernobly.
Let's just get it from him, so
we can get back to the present
so I can start never seeing
you bitches again.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Hey.
I was looking for you.
Where'd you go?
I had to go... My friend got
in trouble, but I had to...
I'm leaving right now.
You're leaving right now?
Yeah.
That's not good.
I told you, I had two hours. I gotta go.
Uncle Adam, come on!
Who the fuck is that chick?
Do you wanna come with me?
Get her fax number
and let's go. Come on.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
You can do whatever you
want, man. It's your life.
I want to.
Good. Then come on.
But I can't because my friends need
me and I gotta show up for them,
so I really can't.
Okay.
So what are we...
I mean, do we...
What happens?
I don't know.
I'm not really
making any plans.
I'm just sort of letting the
universe surprise me, right?
I like that.
I like that a lot.
That's the sign
of a happy man.
April, let's go!
Shit.
Maybe the universe will
bring us together again.
I hope.
Casanova, let's do this!
Just turn it around
and keep it running, okay?
Yeah, sure thing.
Okay. You go this way, I'll go this way?
No, I'm gonna do the opposite
of everything you say.
Great.
Wonder which
one's Blaine's room.
Housekeeping.
Go, go, go.
Let's try in here.
Where is it?
Come on! Come on, come on.
Panties, panties, panties!
What the fuck are you doing?
Why don't you shut
your slut mouth
and mind your own
fucking business?
You disgust me.
I love how much
you hate you.
Thank you.
They're here, come on.
Fuck!
"Fuck" as in, "The Chernobly's
here and we're all good"?
No, "fuck" as in, "fuck!"
Where's Nick?
Admit it! You sucked his
balls, you licked his booty,
you sucked his toes.
Was his dick
bigger than mine?
You wore the heels,
didn't you?
Admit it, bitch!
There's gonna be
some changes, all right?
First, I'm dropping
"Agnew" from my name.
No more hyphenate.
Next, I'm getting
back on stage.
I'm going back to music
because I jam.
But you wouldn't know
nothing about that
because you're probably somewhere
sucking a motherfucker's dick!
Excuse me?
Hang up the phone, Jerry.
This shit don't concern you.
How do you know my name?
Hang up the phone,
motherfucker!
This is between
me and my wife!
Hey! Give me that phone!
Give him the phone, Nick.
I know what I'm doing.
I know what I'm doing!
No, you don't, man.
Let it go! Let it go, man.
Wrong number. But you're a
bad girl and you hurt him.
Were you just yelling
at your 9-year-old wife?
Yes.
God damn it. I'm gonna
go nuclear on these guys.
They couldn't
have gone far, man.
Lou! Come on,
we gotta go.
Hey.
Mom?
Hey, did you find
the Chernobly?
You motherfucker!
Where did he go?
Jacob?
What the fuck?
What's happened?
Oh, my God. I get it.
I'm his father.
What?
Wait, so what do we do?
Oh, my God.
Hit that.
You finish this.
Okay.
Lay down. We got a stupid
baby to make right now.
I'm back inside of you.
I can't believe I'm
fucking Adam's sister!
I'm doing it!
It's gonna take me a while
'cause I'm a little drunk.
Oh, no, it's not.
Here I come.
Oh, my God, I'm gonna come! I'm gonna...
Oh, Shia LaBeouf!
Dropping loads!
So much fucking semen.
Little tiny Jacobs!
There's my boy.
It was so beautiful.
You sack of shit!
I knew there was a reason
I fucking hated you.
And now I know why.
I'm gonna tell everybody in
prison that I traveled back in time
to kill my own father!
Jacob, get off him. Come
on! Time out, young man.
Get the fuck off of me!
You're a fucking dead man!
Jacob!
Nobody fucks my mother
in the past!
I feel pregnant.
You're welcome.
You Commies looking for this?
Yes, actually.
Yes, we are.
That's what
we're looking for.
You think we could
get that back?
No, you may not.
But bad news for you,
sport. I'm a patriot.
And I'm not about to let some
Ruskie fucks come into my town
and blow shit up with
some red-soda-can bomb.
Just give it to us,
turtleneck.
Yeah, okay,
you can have it back.
As long as that sack over there
comes and takes it from me.
I think he's talking about
you. He's talking about you.
He's obviously
talking about me.
Blaine, hello.
Um...
Can I please
get the soda back?
Yeah, sure you can.
Oh.
Okay.
Fuck me in the face.
Get him
a body bag, Blaine!
Give us a minute, okay?
Listen to me, man.
That guy, that guy has
pummeled you again and again.
He made you
his little bitch.
He's humiliated you,
emasculated you.
The wheel of fate has stopped
and dumped you here again,
utterly defeated.
None of this is
helping me at all.
I know, it's coming.
It's coming right now.
Patience.
Maybe you're supposed to do
something different.
What is this, girl talk?
Let's go here, come on.
You're better than him.
America!
Maybe not by a lot,
but a little.
You're the patron saint
of the totally fucked.
You're completely toxic.
There's nothing you can't kill.
You're the fucking Violator!
The moment's over.
Let's go!
You can do this! You can
get us the fuck out of here!
You can be the hero!
Enrique-fucking-Iglesias.
You love that song,
don't you?
I love that fucking song!
Give me your best shot.
Come on, buddy.
I can be your hero, baby
I can kiss away the pain
I will stand by you forever
You can take my breath away
Shit.
God damn it! None of what
you said worked at all.
Let's kick these guys' ass,
get the shit and go home.
Done.
No, no!
Fuck you! Feels so good!
The Chernobly.
Martina Navratilova.
Smirnoff Ice.
That's right, we are Russians! Spies.
Yeah, because I was
just speaking Russian.
He pulls that top, and this
whole fucking place blows.
You guys count backwards from 50, then
pull up the carpet and jump around.
Or I'll fuck you up.
Hi, Phil. Can we go
back to the hotel, lodge?
Sure.
Thank you so much.
Five, four, three...
Blaine, please stop counting.
Chaz, this is
an Acorn 5 situation.
If we stop counting, they're
gonna blow us sky-high.
Look, if it is a bomb, they've
got it with them, all right?
If anyone's gonna blow up,
it's them.
Chaz, stop!
How long did
our talking just take?
I don't know.
I wasn't keeping track.
Fuck it, let's risk it!
Move out!
Now that you're with me,
you gotta cover up your belly.
Let's get
the fuck out of here.
What are you talking about?
We only had sex once.
Let's go. Come on. Kelly,
you can talk about it later.
You guys are all right?
Thank you, Phil.
Enjoyed it.
Have a good rest
of your vacation.
We'd love to have you come back
here to the Silver Peaks Lodge.
Thanks. Bye-bye.
Thanks, Phil. Take care.
Be careful.
Hey, watch out!
God, you guys see that?
Come on, man!
Why would you fucking take that from me?
I didn't take it from you.
You guys...
Oh, my God!
It happened!
Why the fuck are you laughing? Gross!
Man down, man down!
Code 11.
All right, everybody grab
your gear, we gotta move!
Later, Kelly.
Bye, Mom. Love you.
Don't do drugs, okay?
Hey, bye.
Aren't you coming
to my room with me?
No, I gotta take
my clothes off
and get in a hot
tub with these guys.
Then I'm totally
over you.
Kelly, listen. It's
been an interesting trip.
You're my sister
and I love you.
I love you, too.
And don't steal that Caboodle
makeup thing from JCPenney
and you won't do
any hard time.
I'll see you in 20 years.
Uh. You're giving me a ride
in the morning, right?
Hallelujah!
Cannonball!
Yeah! Let's get
this party started!
Young blood.
Holy shit!
Hey, look,
it's happening.
Here it comes!
Hurry up.
I can see the '90s.
Why are you taking
off your clothes?
I don't know, man. It
just feels right, you know?
Fuck it.
Adam! Adam!
I'm not gonna go!
What?
I'm gonna stay!
Don't fuck around, Lou.
Let's go!
I'm good here, man.
I had a good day! I beat the
shit out of that guy, finally!
I fucked your sister!
I could be a good dad!
I love you, Jacob!
Fuck you!
Little scamp. They say
the damndest things, man.
Come on, Lou, let's go! We'll
talk about it when we get home!
I was trying
to kill myself!
I know, man.
That's why we came here!
If I go back, I'm just gonna
kill myself all over again, man.
I can't.
You're gonna stay?
Guys, let's go.
All right, well, if you're
gonna stay, I'm gonna stay!
You'd really
do that for me?
We're best friends! If
you're staying, I'm staying!
Your bullshit's
my bullshit, right?
I'm your best friend?
You are one of
my best friends!
I'll take that!
Where you going on me?
Thank you!
Oh, my God!
All right, man. Come on!
Holy shit.
This better be the last time
my ass travels through time.
Oh...
It is so good
to see you.
Are we rolling?
Welcome back, bitches!
Is that Lou?
What took you so long?
All right, zoom out.
Yeah, that's
a weird hair choice.
Uh-oh. Look what Daddy did.
He looks like a lion.
Oh, hi.
Didn't see you there.
Here's a question.
Was it morally wrong for me to
exploit my knowledge of the future
for personal financial gain?
Perhaps.
Here's another question.
Do I give a fuck?
That's my father.
Hey, check out my girl.
You burned the fucking crab cakes again.
No, I didn't burn them
because I like them that way!
I fucking hate you, Louis.
I hate you, too, baby.
I love that woman, man.
Those are my parents.
But seriously,
a lot has changed.
So, whatever happens,
stay the fuck calm.
It'll all make sense soon.
Good morning.
Holy shit, Phil, you got both your arms.
Oh. Yeah, I do.
That's incredible.
Yeah, what happened was
a snowplow came along
and it took my arm right off.
But the ski patrol came along
and they put it on ice.
Blaine and Chaz. Blaine
and Chaz saved his arm!
We got 15 minutes before
that thing dies, all right.
We're gonna put
that back on you!
I'm pretty happy.
It looks great.
Anyhow, I have instructions
on how to get home.
We know how to get home.
Yeah. We know...
Mr. Dorchen anticipated
that you might say that,
so I took the liberty of printing
up some Lougle maps for you.
You mean "Google"?
Lougle maps.
What's the matter
with you guys?
Fuck me.
So, Phil, if you wanna find,
you know, like porno
or a restaurant review or
anything like that, you use Lougle?
Correct.
I bet he's on the Statue
of Liberty and shit, too.
You want me
to go in there?
That's what
it says on the map.
Call me later.
Hello.
Welcome back, Mr. Webber.
How was your time away?
Uh...
Hey, how was the trip?
Good.
Letting the days go by
Let the water hold me down
Water flowing underground
Into the blue again
After the money's gone
Once in a lifetime
Water flowing underground
Motherfucker.
Nick?
Baby, how was your weekend?
I wasn't expecting you today.
Baby. Baby. I got something to tell you.
I know about what you did
with a guy named Steve.
Steve?
Our receptionist?
That Tyrese-looking
motherfucker out there?
Baby, wait a minute.
What are you talking about?
You think I'm
fooling around?
First of all, I would
never screw around.
And you remember I told you about that
crazy wrong number I got when I was nine.
That man was so...
I love you, Courtney.
I love you so much.
I love you, too,
Nick Webber.
Nick Webber?
That's your name.
Yeah, it is my name.
Yeah.
You know my name.
Say it again.
Nick
Webber.
Yeah.
Grab that.
I'll take this one.
Hey, Mom.
I made you a drink.
Is there alcohol in that?
Yeah, I believe there's
still alcohol in scotch.
Talk about your
lost weekend, huh?
I know, right? Man.
Hey, family.
What are you faggots
talking about?
My two handsome men.
Let me get you
another drink, Dad.
Daddy's little buddy.
You know what
I can't believe?
I can't believe
we're all here.
we all made it.
Made it together.
A toast.
Approximately three
days ago, or 20 years,
depending on your understanding
of the time-space continuum, Jacob,
sitting here with you guys would
have been my worst nightmare.
It's true.
But I can honestly
say right now
I'm very happy to be right
here in this moment with you,
my best friends.
Hear, hear.
To friends.
And family.
All right. Cheers!
To past, present and future.
Cheers!
So, "Lougle," huh?
Yeah.
Lougle. Just this multibillion-dollar
thing I did for a while.
My real passion's music, though.
So pissed the band broke up.
Band? What band
were you ever in?
You know I'm a dreamer
But my heart's of gold
I had to run away high
So I wouldn't come home low
Just when things went right
Doesn't mean
they were always wrong
Just take this song
and you'll never feel
Left all alone
Take me to your heart
Feel me in your bones
Just one more night
And I'm coming off this
long and winding road
I'm on my way
Home sweet home
Tonight, tonight
I'm on my way
Home sweet home
You know that I've seen
Too many romantic dreams
Up in lights
falling off the silver screen
My heart's
like an open book
For the whole world to read
Sometimes nothing
keeps me together
at the seams
I'm on my way
Home sweet home
Yeah
I'm on my way
Just set me free
Home sweet home
English - US - PSDH