Previously on The Vampire Diaries...
- I'm Sybil.
- We are talking
about a living, breathing siren.
Damon is completely devoted to me.
This thing, it was delivered
with your vault inhabitant.
I think it was made in hell.
It's a tuning fork.
Damon, it's over.
You're free now.
I wish that were the case, Stefan,
but my work with her is
just getting started.
I really hoped that
when we put Sybil down,
it'd break whatever
control she had over him.
But somehow, some way,
she still has ahold of him.
What else is there to do?
You still have too many attachments.
Too many people willing to fight for you.
We should work on that.
Lockwood.
Damon, wait!
Sirens use mind control
to lure their victims to their death.
Some say they're messengers of the Devil.
I suppose every story
has to start somewhere.
Tell me a story.
What kind of story?
Something happy.
A long time ago,
in a village
built on this very spot,
lived a man.
Arcadius.
Cade, to his friends,
of which he had many.
He was a gentle man,
loved and respected.
But Cade could do something
that no one else could:
he could see into the minds of others.
He was psychic?
The first psychic.
It was this power that gave him
so much empathy towards others.
And it was this power that
would cost him his life.
The thing you imagine, brother...
It is impure.
It's forbidden.
If you allow me deeper into your mind,
perhaps I can help quell your urges.
Cade had only wanted to help.
But he had overstepped.
And the men, fearing his power,
turned even Cade's friends against him.
And it was then that
Cade came to know
the thing inside men
that even his power
had not been able to divine:
true evil.
I asked for a happy story.
But it is, dear sister.
For in death, Cade was triumphant.
From that moment onward,
evil men would be forever punished
for their wicked deeds.
Cade had his revenge.
And someday,
so will we.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
Hey.
For future reference,
just because I spend
the night with Bonnie
doesn't mean you can't
sleep in your own bed.
Right, yeah, no.
I-I crashed at the Armory.
I figured I'd give you two some space.
How's Bonnie doing?
Glued to Enzo's side,
despite all the awful
things he's saying to her.
It's gonna take another
day or two of starving him
before she can get started
with his humanity switch.
Well, if anyone can bring him back,
Bonnie can.
Hey, you know what,
I should probably get going.
Alaric and I
have a little date with a siren.
Be careful.
You've seen what Sybil can do
when she gets inside your head.
As long as this tuning fork
is ringing, she can't.
Is there some sort of engaged person
shorthand for "Good luck and...
I'm with you in spirit"?
Yeah, I think it's "I love you."
I love you, too.
Hey, thanks.
Oh, thank the nanny.
She's the unwitting enabler.
Oh, hey.
Uh...
I thought I told you
not to come in today.
Well, I heard there was a coffee shortage
and came running.
Well, actually,
we're in the middle of a major project.
So why don't you take the day off...
Major project? Sounds sketchy.
Got a girl tied up in the basement?
Jokes.
Okay, I'll leave you to it.
I can only deal with
one temptress at a time.
Anyway, any word from Damon?
None. And that's what worries me.
Hey!
Hey! Earth to Planet Redneck.
Are you Peter Maxwell?
No, Pete owns the place.
I'm just the hired help.
Name's Lou. What can I do for you?
I really need to talk to Pete.
Well, have it your way.
He should be back in a bit.
Hey, what exactly brings you out here?
You know, it's hard to say.
To be honest, I'm not even the one
that cares about finding your boss.
There is a woman...
and I use that term loosely...
Named Sybil, who wants to.
So, inexplicably,
here I am.
Sounds like that gal's
screwing with your head.
Oh, you have no idea.
You'd be surprised.
I've been married five times.
Oh, I take that back.
You do get me, Lou.
See, the catch is:
Sybil and I had a thing,
but it's done.
In theory, I'm a free man,
but I still find myself
doing whatever it is
I think she'd want me to be doing.
Hell, between you and me,
I'd probably kill for her.
Pete'll be back soon.
I should get back to work.
No,
you should do everything I say.
Just answer one more question for me.
What's the worst thing you've ever done?
I murdered one of those
wives I told you about.
Made it look like an accident.
Don't move.
Oh, damn. I was rooting for you, Lou.
I really was.
Now, like you said...
get back to work.
The all-powerful siren.
Imprisoned by a fork.
Says the man who can
be killed with a stick.
What is it about this thing
that hurts you so much?
And why does it hurt my kids?
And here I thought you
had me all figured out.
Guess not.
If this dis upts your psychic ability,
then why is Damon still your puppet?
I tinkered with the deepest
reaches of his subconscious.
If Damon's still serving me,
it's because deep down,
he wants to.
Why are you doing this to him?
It's all Damon, Damon, Damon.
Aren't you even a little curious
about who I am?
No, actually.
All I care about is how
to save my brother.
Well, fortunately,
the answer to your question is...
a story. About me.
You like stories, don't you, Professor?
I prefer nonfiction.
Well, then you'll love this one.
A long time ago,
in a little Mediterranean village,
there was a girl.
As she came of age,
the village girl began to
manifest psychic abilities,
a trait that had been
forbidden in her land
for as long as anyone could remember.
Help me, please!
The fate of psychics
was exile.
Which is how our poor,
innocent, forsaken village girl
ended up on a raft...
The current carrying her
into the rocks of a cold
and distant shore.
But abandoned though she was meant to be,
alone she was not.
There she met
the girl of the island.
Exiled together,
connected in psychic ability,
two sisters in everything but blood,
destined from that moment
to one day become...
...the sirens.
So you see, Stefan,
I understand why you would
do anything for your brother.
Because my sister
will do anything for me.
Will do?
Present tense?
Oh, did I forget to
mention there are two of us?
Me in here.
And her out there.
Ugh!
Would you please stop doing that?
It is complete overkill.
What do you mean, two sirens?
I thought you were a scholar.
Every single mythological
interpretation of who I am
mentions sirens... plural.
Well, those same myths
also say that you should
have the lower half of a bird.
Well, luckily for us all,
you can't believe
everything that you read.
Enough.
Who is she?
Patience, Stefan.
I promise you'll find out soon enough.
Oh, crap.
Oh, yes.
Don't move, or I call the police!
Oh... it's the intern.
Oh... the nanny.
It's Georgie, right?
Do you break into houses often?
I got to get into Alaric's bed somehow.
Uh, okay, the boss man just asked me
to bring this journal back to the Armory,
and like a dumbass, I didn't
think to ask him for the keys.
I just figured I'd save
myself an embarrassing call.
Well, the call I'm about to make
is probably even more embarrassing.
Okay.
Maybe you better stay put.
Maybe you should stick
to naps and snacks.
Okeydokey. Calling Ric.
I really wouldn't do that if I were you.
You must be Peter Maxwell.
Who the hell are you?
Damon Salvatore. AKA...
the guy that barbecued your
little grease monkey over there.
No offense, Pete, but I don't think
that extinguisher's gonna work.
Lou's got a date for an eternal burn.
Uh, before you make that
phone call, I want you
to ask yourself one question.
If I just murdered your
faithful manservant
in cold blood, why would I have
any problem murdering you?
Good boy.
But that was a trick question, Pete.
I can't actually kill you... yet.
Well, that's comforting, I guess.
You ever meet a girl named Sybil?
About yay high, hot as hell.
Face rots off when she
doesn't feed on human flesh?
You're insane.
I'm gonna take that as a no, Pete.
Then again, you could be lying to me.
Now tell me the truth. Do you have any idea
- what I'm talking about?
- No.
Everything you're saying sounds crazy.
Damn it.
I'm gonna make this as simple as I can.
You have something Sybil wants,
I'm gonna deliver it.
You can take whatever it is and just go.
That's not an option, Pete.
I don't exactly know what I'm looking for.
Then how are you supposed to find it?
We, Pete. We.
Here's the deal.
All I consciously know is that it's
a Maxwell family heirloom.
But subconsciously, I'm pretty damn sure
I'll know it when I see it.
Okay? So where should we start looking?
I-I have no idea.
Look, the only family I have is my son.
I need you to think real hard,
'cause your life depends on it.
A couple years ago,
my grandmother died, all right?
She left me a box of stuff.
Sounds promising.
What kind of stuff we talking about?
I don't know. I never opened it.
Family's a bit of a sore spot with me.
Trust me, I know the feeling, man.
Where's this box, Pete?
It's somewhere in the storage room.
My son was looking for it a while back.
- Maybe he found it, all right?
- Oh, good.
Call Junior. Get him over here.
Now.
It's Seline. You got this?
Yeah.
Seline? Suspicious name.
Very siren-y.
How about we just focus
on you and your sister?
I think I'll just wait
for Alaric to get back.
You're stalling.
Who is she?
You think hurting me
is gonna speed this up?
Thank you.
Now, despite enjoying
each other's company,
the girls had another
constant companion...
hunger.
The one who had survived
on the island this long had a plan.
Call out to them with me.
They will never hear us.
Raise your voice,
and your mind will soar out to meet it.
Help!
Over here!
Help! Help!
Please. Over here.
Help! Here!
They heard us.
The ship is coming our way.
We are saved.
Over here.
But the girl of the island
knew better.
She had done this before,
called out to passing
sailors with her mind.
But no matter how keen her psychic reach,
the shoals around the
island were sharper.
So you beached the ship.
Try annihilated.
Dashed upon the rocks,
dooming its sailors to death.
But, silver lining,
their sweet, sweet provisions
would soon wash up on shore.
The tides were not in our favor today.
This is all that washed up.
You knew this would happen?
The island is barren,
save for berries and wild boar.
This way is easier...
and more fun.
Sister, do not weep for them.
Those sailors were from our village.
The same men who banished us here to die.
Never again.
If we cannot live off of
what God has provided for us,
then we are not meant to live at all.
Promise me?
Stop me if this sounds familiar.
One good sibling,
determined to live like a monk,
and one selfishly evil sibling,
willing to murder to
satiate their hunger.
Oh, come on, you get it.
The parallels are too good.
Our story is your story, Stefan.
So now here's the test.
Which girl are you?
So, uh, what do you think?
I think it's a hood ornament, Pete.
Vintage Rolls-Royce.
Aah! I also think
that you're in danger
of losing a real life.
I'm doing what you asked.
Oh, are you? I compelled you
to find what I needed.
You keep bringing me a bunch of junk.
Where'd you get that watch?
My son gave it to me.
What difference does it make?
Considering that it's a family heirloom,
quite a bit... Hand it over.
Aah!
You're on vervain.
I don't know what you're talking about.
You lied to me, Pete.
And you know what happens to liars.
They go straight to hell.
Donovan?
Dad.
Don't move, don't move. Let me see it.
All right, look, it's not that bad, okay?
Just keep some pressure on it,
you're gonna be fine.
Don't lie to me, Matt.
Look, you're gonna be fine
if you do exactly as I say.
- What are you doing?
- I need you to drink his blood.
Why? I'll explain later,
but right now I need
you to trust me, okay?
- Drink.
- N-No...
Wha-What?
- What just happened?
- I told you I'll explain everything.
But first I need to understand why
Damon was trying to hurt you.
Wait, you're telling me you,
you knew this guy?
I'm telling you that I know him.
He's not dead. Not exactly.
I know. None of this makes
any sense, and I know.
I tracked you down a few months ago
and I didn't tell you about any of this.
Okay, I'm sorry, but I promise,
if you go to the truck right now,
I'll explain everything.
I just don't want you to
see what happens next.
Look, I... I feel silly calling.
It's probably nothing.
Why, what's going on?
Well, your intern Georgie,
she broke into the house.
Wait, she what?
And she took a book.
Some dead guy's journal.
Said that she was
bringing it back to you?
Well, are you okay? Are the girls?
Yeah. Why?
Should I be more worried?
I mean, she's just a
little weirdo, right?
It's, uh, it's fine.
Hey, thanks for calling.
I-I gotta call you back, okay?
Hello?
Georgie?
I'm here. Sorry.
Wait!
Look, we don't have to be enemies.
Damon and I had nothing
to do with the Armory
until you possessed him.
If we're enemies, it's because
you chose this path.
- I didn't ask for any of this.
- God.
You sound just like her.
A victim to the last.
She insisted the island
would nourish them.
And when it didn't, her faith was shaken.
God did not provide.
That was up to her sister.
The other side of the island
was the wild boars' domain.
It was dangerous,
but she knew she must hunt.
And behold.
God was good.
Or maybe there were
no boars on the island.
You kept luring ships into the rocks.
Killing for provisions.
And do you want to know
the sickest part of all?
There were no provisions on the ships.
Only sailors.
And so, an innocent
girl became a monster.
All because
her older sibling forced
her to adopt her lifestyle,
even if it meant
killing and eating men
to stay alive.
So, I ask you again.
Which girl are you?
Here's all you need to know.
Whatever Damon and I have done
to one another in the past,
it has been forgiven.
He is my brother,
and there's nothing you can
do that will ever change that.
I think you've overestimated your sibling.
And clearly, I have underestimated mine.
Hey, sailor.
What did you do to me?
I'm in your head.
Well, our head, kind of.
My memories, your noggin.
Your silly fork stopped ringing.
There's nowhere to run.
So walk with me.
Oh, so is this where you attack my psyche?
Try to break me down?
Normally, yes.
But the boss has other plans for you.
- The boss?
- Mm-hmm.
What are you talking about?
He thinks you're worthy of
hearing the whole story.
Shall we continue?
For years, my sister
and I lived as cannibals.
One willingly,
one blissfully ignorant.
Until I discovered this.
Where my sister had buried
the sailors she had murdered.
Only visible at low tide.
It was the perfect hiding spot.
You discovered?
You're not the girl from
the island, are you?
You're the village girl.
I tried.
I tried so hard to be good.
My sister forced this existence on me.
What, you expect me
to have sympathy for you?
After everything you've done?
Maybe, maybe not.
It all comes down to the same question:
which siren is your
spirit animal, Stefan?
Oh, come on, man, drop the act.
We both know you're not gonna kill me.
Why not?
That seems to be your
solution for everything.
Maybe I should give it a shot.
I'm sorry, Matt, I know
this is supposed to scare me,
but fear is an emotion,
and ever since I flipped my switch,
I'm kind of operating without them.
All I'm getting from you
is desperation.
You're right, Damon, I am desperate.
And for once,
I don't care about your drama.
I don't give a damn if you
shut your humanity off.
All I want to know is why
you tried to kill my father.
Look, man, in my defense,
I didn't know he was your dad.
I always thought you were a bastard.
Shut up, I'm done playing games.
Well, Tyler Lockwood is gonna
be very sad to hear that.
Because if you don't play along,
he dies.
Maybe you care about that?
Not even you're that stupid.
Humanity or not,
nobody'd forgive you for that.
Especially Elena.
Well, that's the whole point, you idiot.
Apparently, you've been out
of the loop for a while, Matt,
so allow me to bring you up to speed.
Elena and I are through.
In fact,
I've been seeing another woman.
You're lying. Last time
I knew, Tyler was up in, uh...
In New York?
Am I lying or being completely truthful
when I tell you that I ripped
into Tyler's throat last night?
And then I took him on a road trip.
Left him bleeding in the
back of a green Mustang
at the Park 'N Go off I-20,
right across the border.
Now, is that too specific for a lie?
It's your move, Matt.
Ticktock.
If you hurt Tyler,
I swear to God, I will kill you.
Well, you can swear to God all you want.
He's not the one listening.
Hey, uh... Stefan.
Or Caroline.
I guess this is my modern-day version
of a dead man's journal.
P.S. I believe Georgie
is the second siren,
in case you haven't figured it out.
Ironically, Georgie is how
I know the way out of here
is through a tunnel system
behind one of these walls.
Anyway, to find that
wall and pass through it,
I have to deprive myself
of sight and sound.
Now, while blindfolding myself is easy...
the hearing part,
it's gonna be tough.
Anyway,
nothing a little vampire blood
can't fix on the "B" side.
At least that's what I keep
telling myself, so,
on that reassuring note...
over and out.
I couldn't believe it.
All those years,
my sister tricked me
into eating human flesh.
But I had to hear the
truth from her mouth,
so I confronted her.
You should've seen the look on her face.
Oh, wait, you will.
Here she comes now.
No.
Stefan, you've met my sister.
Seline.
Get it tucked in for you.
Oh!
One second, chickadees.
- Hello?
- Alaric is trapped.
Why did you make me do that?
Just pull over wherever you are
and stay there, I will find you.
We'll talk about it then.
Will you tell us a story?
Sure, sweetie. What kind of story?
Nothing sad.
Hmm.
Okay.
I know just the one,
but we'll have to keep it between us.
No telling Mommy or Daddy.
It is called
"The Legend of Arcadius."
Hello?
Little help in here.
Guess it's time for plan B.
The bad news...
Plan B always sucks.
Hello, beautiful.
I've been looking all over for you.
Don't ask me how I know this,
or what the hell you're supposed to do,
but Sybil's gonna be
very happy to see you.
Seline is the other siren?
What's more shocking? That she
secretly fed me human flesh?
Or that she's now masquerading
as a friggin' nanny?
Get out of my head. Now.
Why, so you can go warn Alaric?
You're assuming that I'm
gonna let you remember this
when you wake up.
Sorry.
Orders from above.
Well, below.
What did you do to me?
You tell me.
What do you remember?
You confronted your sister.
She turned you into a
cannibal against your wishes.
And who exactly is my sister?
I don't know.
How frustrating.
Why are you still here?
I was out cold, you were in my head.
Why didn't you escape?
And leave you with such
a dramatic cliffhanger?
I'm not that evil.
I was about to answer your question.
How you can save your brother.
But for the last time, I need to know:
are you an island girl or a village girl?
Wait!
Answer me, Stefan. This is important.
Who are you in this story?
The victim, who tried for years
not to feed on human blood,
only for his selfish brother to
blow into town and ruin it all?
Or are you the monster,
who sealed his brother's
fate the day you forced him
to turn into a vampire?
Who doomed his brother
to an eternity of misery
because you were afraid of being alone?
There you go again.
Old history.
You'd be surprised how
fresh it is in Damon's mind.
Answer me.
Who are you?
I'm both.
I was wrong about you, Stefan.
You are worthy.
You're ready for the truth.
When I learned the truth
about what my sister had done
for me,
I did the only thing a
decent person could do.
I threw myself off the cliffs.
As I lay dying,
I prayed. For mercy.
For love. For forgiveness.
Oh... help... somebody help...
But God never answered me.
Instead, he did.
My beautiful, broken children.
Who are you?
You know.
Arcadius?
Everyone calls me Cade.
You are supposed to be dead.
Rest assured.
I am.
My sister.
Can you help her?
Yes.
But...
there is a price.
Anything.
My sister...
She made a deal with Cade.
Immortality,
beauty and youth, for the two of us...
if only we served our
new Lord and master.
We feast on the flesh
to keep us beautiful,
and he collects the souls of the wicked.
In hell.
Hell?
As in, literal hell.
Come on.
Just tell me the truth.
Who's Cade?
What is he?
He's the answer to all
your problems, Stefan.
You want to save your brother?
All you have to do is kill the Devil.
I don't believe you.
Which part? We covered a lot of ground.
Hell. The Devil. None of it exists.
Did you believe in vampires
before you fell in love with one
and became one yourself?
That's the trouble with facts, Stefan.
They're true whether you
believe in them or not.
I promise you,
just as my sister promised me.
There was a man named Cade.
The people he loved damned him.
And only at the very end did
he finally give up on them,
only when the smell
of his burning flesh
was searing his nostrils,
did he see them for
what they really were.
Monsters.
Just like you and me.
So, Cade damned them in return.
With his last breath,
he let loose a psychic blast so powerful
that it created its own world.
Call it hell if you want.
It doesn't matter what name you give it
or whether you believe in it or not.
Either way, that is where Cade feeds
on the souls of the damned.
It's where he waits for you, Stefan.
Stop making this about me.
I'm trying to help my brother.
Oh, but this is about you.
Did you really think
all your pathetic attempts at atonement
would save you from the
fate that, deep down,
you know you deserve?
A fate befitting the
glorious Ripper of Monterey?
No.
That was almost 100 years ago.
I'm not that person anymore.
It doesn't matter, Stefan.
That stain will always be
on your soul, no matter
how hard you try to wash it away.
So, stop fighting.
It's easier that way.
Maybe I do deserve it,
but Damon doesn't,
because I made him what he is.
So, if it's my fault,
damn me.
Not him.
Damon's fate is already sealed.
I reached into his mind and gave him
a look at what awaits him,
and even that little spoonful
was enough to make him flip
his little humanity switch.
He chose to serve Cade for all eternity,
rather than experience another
second in that kind of torment.
Damon believes in hell.
And soon you will, too.
Because you're just as doomed as he is.
So Mystic Falls is overrun
with supernatural creatures,
and... vampires are real.
They feed on human blood
and can even control people
if they want to.
Okay, so why couldn't
Damon compel me, then?
It's because of that watch I gave you.
It's full of something called vervain.
A glass of vervain every day
keeps the vampires at bay.
Yeah. How'd you know that?
Something your
great-grandmother used to say
when she was making tea.
She was senile
at the end, and...
leaving her behind,
that was the hardest part
about leaving Mystic Falls.
Look,
Matt, I don't expect you to forgive me
for abandoning you.
I had my reasons at the time.
They don't seem good enough
now, not even to me.
Honestly,
we all should've got out of that town
when we had the chance.
Hey, listen, Matt. Why don't you, uh...
You know, why don't you take
a walk? Let me do this.
Ah! The intern.
Where is my sister?
I tried.
I tried to free the girl in the cell,
just like you asked.
And?
And, um,
she told me to tell you...
...to piss off.
She doesn't need your help.
Well. I tried.
Look,
I'm sorry to have to involve you
in this, sweetie.
It's just that, in this case,
I really do have to kill the messenger.
By the way. That girl you
killed in a car accident
a few years ago?
Kind of a deal breaker.
Send Cade my regards.
What...?
What are you doing?
What's happening to me?!
No! No!
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --