What happened to you?
Fuck!
We don't have much time...
Tick tock, this man got rocked...
I have an appointment.
My assistant was supposed to reschedule.
She didn't.
Better call her then.
Mom said you're not allowed
to reschedule with me.
Please, just this once.
Don't be a putz.
Putz?
I worked 80 hours this week.
What did you do?
Come on Dad, we don't have much time!
We have to build a wall so the monster doesn't
break through!
What ever happened to tea parties?
Don't little girls have tea parties anymore?
You dig the moat.
Dig the moat before the monster comes.
It will slow him down.
Can't your mom dig the moat when she gets up?
I'm not really prepared for any kind of...
...moat digging.
Hurry up, we don't have much time!
Emma.
I just don't do this... okay?
Your mom can play these games with you,
okay?
I've never been any good at this anyhow.
You can do this Dad.
Oh no!
What?
It's coming! It's too late for the moat!
Get down Dad!
Ah! It's got me!
Ah! Save me Dad! Save me!
He's pulling me into his cave!
He's really ugly Dad!
It's got me. Come on save me.
Get away from her you big asshole!
Get 'em Dad! Get the bastard!
You mess with my daughter, you mess with me!
Fort! Fort! Back to the fort!
Get down! Get down!
You did it Dad! You got 'em!
Hey...
When did you start saying... bastard?
28, 37, and 53.
So good luck to everybody out there who played
last night's lotto...
Dad?
I thought you were gone.
I went to your funeral.
No, no, no. I'm here...
I'll always be here for you.
Bingo! Bingo! Bingo! Bingo!
It's bedtime Princess Moomba.
It's time to get your beauty rest.
Your majesty has blessed the land with your
beauty today.
But it's quiet now and the journey will continue
tomorrow.
The rebels have infiltrated the base!
Bam! Boom!
Sir Lawrence, Sir Lawrence!
Send in the cavalry quick!
Sir Lawrence? Sir Lawrence?!
What happened to you?
No!
Why?!
Whhyyy?!
He was so young!
Emma? You're not in there playing are you?
That's a very convincing snore, but you'll have to
turn your light off young lady.
Thank you.
Good night Grandma.
Good night sleep-talker.
Help!
She buys her friends.
She bought that body too.
Stop!
Stop talking about me!
Stop it!
You idiot!
- How could you be so frivolous and stupid?
- Hello?
You're just like your father!
He was an idiot too.
You're disgusting! You're disgusting to look at!
Even your own children are embarrassed to be
with you!
I made a mistake the minute I met you!
I should have known what a loser you were
gonna be!
Unemployed and penniless!
Someday I'll find a real man.
How many nights are you going to do this?
This has got to stop.
You can't be absent all the time.
You have a whole other life...
You can't change that now.
...that you are forgetting.
No! No!
Grandpa!
No, the girl!
Go get the girl!
Help!
Well, it's one of the most anticipated IPO's of the
year.
Apollo Systems, the market leader in the
emerging technology of mobile delivery systems
will be choosing a lead underwriter sometime
this week.
Word on the street is that Hannaway Capital,
VanBuskirk Black and Company...
and Hamilton Partners are all in the front-
running for the bid.
It's going to be quite a beauty contest and we imagine one of
these firms will emerge with a registration statement sometime soon.
David... do you...
John!
No, not this morning.
Please Roger, I hate that look.
I hate that pants-shitting terror look.
What is it man? I'm not going to kill you.
- You know you are gonna survive the morning.
- We're in a serious crunch here John.
We're never in a crunch Roger, ever.
Word is that Apollo is leaning toward Hamilton.
Hamilton came in last night and they low-balled
the fee down to six and a half percent.
- Hey, hey, hey!
- What, what?
- Six and a half percent John.
They snaked us early.
Hamilton? On the Apollo-
- Are you talking about the Apollo account?
- Yes!
- Hamilton did six-and-a-half on Apollo?
- They came in and they low-balled us.
Where did you get this?
Carl's contact.
Yeah.
- Who the fuck let them do that?
- It's anyone's guess.
You know personally I thought it was a little bit
too far fetched, but then-
Fucking bucket shop!
Apollo wants Hamilton?
Hamilton couldn't find a fat man in a county fair.
Fuck Hamilton, fuck em.
They want to win the bid on a percentage play?
- They're gonna have to do better than that.
- John...
- Good luck!
- Sorry.
This is desperate, I know these guys all too well.
This is a desperate fucking move.
Listen Roger.
This deal falls through this morning...
and I will kill you with my own bare hands.
One... two... three... four
Ha!... two... three... four
Yah!... two... three... four
Wah!... two... three... four
One... two... three... four
One... two- Ohh!
Branch!
Son of a bitch!
One, two, three, branch...
One, two, three, branch!
Hello dirt. And how are we today?
Nope.
Don't have the face of a fighter do we?
You're Jacob?
My name's Allel.
I'm told I'm supposed to assist you. You're able to help
with the girl.
- Who was taken...
- Wait.
You're the one who got your ass kicked.
- What?
- Yeah I bet that doesn't sit too well with you.
'Course a good ass kicking doesn't sit well with
anyone.
Are you mocking me?
Real sharp too aren't ya.
I get it! I get it! I'll play along!
You don't want word to get out do ya?
- What word?
- About your ass kicking!
Yeah no one knows you're actually a priss.
They're all fooled, but...
you really are a priss.
Is it your policy to let adorable little girls
disappear into the night?
- That's enough!
- Ohhh!
Cord has been struck...
Do we have a guilty child neglector here?!
There it is!
The fighter!
Just had to be sure you know.
'Course she's roughing up the handicap, but
who's counting?
We meet again!
Look, is this a joke?
Do you actually have a purpose or do you just
talk trash?
You lost the girl right?
- No I didn't lose the girl!
- Sure, sure she was kidnapped.
There's still time...
before all is lost.
You have a way to track him?
Hell no and who wants to? Remember he
kicked your ass.
We'll go around the other side. We'll find the
physical girl.
- And do what?
- Shake the shit out of her!
Shake the shit out of her!
We'll wake her up.
That's just great!
Last time I checked there's no way to physically
affect them unless you're a...
you're a pathfinder.
Ow!
Help!
Help me!
Please!
I need help.
I have a delivery.
My key was broken.
Are you a failure Ink?
No.
Because failure is not an option with us Ink.
Only perfection.
You can help me?
Yes I can. Would you like help Ink?
You need it.
With that shame...
That stench!
The code isn't here.
It's broken into two.
The carriers are drifters.
But they are loyal.
Find each of them and you'll have access to the
assembly.
Best keep your pacing.
You only have a few hours.
Fail now and you need not go on.
You only have one opportunity...
...to become... numb.
No Phil. All things considered I think I'd rather
be rich, man.
Uh huh...
Hey Phil... yeah... I gotta go.
Yeah, I gotta get to the pitch. Okay?
I'm sorry. He said it was an emergency.
What are you doing here?
I couldn't get you on the phone.
If I wanted to talk to you Ron,
I would have taken your call.
Emma's in the hospital.
They say that she's had some kind of seizure.
Is she okay?
She's alive...
but she's not been responsive.
She's in a coma now.
What are they doing for her?
Well they're trying to keep her stable but they...
They said it's possible that...
this has weakened her heart.
They say it's... it's possible...
that she could just cycle over into cardiac arrest.
Emma needs you.
Kathy and I are with her but...
but she does... she needs her father.
That's not my place anymore.
We have to let that go.
For your daughter.
What can I do now?
He wanted to manipulate you.
I'm asking you Ron, what can I do now?
I'm good enough to be her father now?
We have to let that go.
It's in the past now.
Is it?
Well it's very fucking present for me Ron.
You know, you convince the world I'm the anti-
Christ and you take her from me...
You can't throw that in the past Ron...
'cause that's where I live now!
-I know that you've suffered with this, we all have.
-Oh no... please.
-Look, I am pleading with you...
-I don't want to hear it... I don't want to hear it!
I don't even have a daughter... anymore...
remember?
Those words ring a bell?
John, I'm sorry - Mr. Hudson is asking for you.
I know Judith, I know.
You need to go.
This is not the time.
I didn't come here for that.
You want to talk about lives Ron?
Well I'm at the point of life and death...
on a multi-billion dollar deal.
And thousands of lives are at stake.
And that's important.
And that's my family now, that's all I have left.
We did what we thought was best for her but...
but she needs you now.
Consider your obligation as her father.
This insignificant man.
Obligation?
What's obligation to you?
You don't talk to Shelly for fifteen years...
and then you show up at her fucking funeral!
Is that the obligation you're talking about Ron,
huh?!
You know, taking care of Emma doesn't
somehow absolve you of all that shit!
You could have killed him.
You're still a fraud!
You live with that every day, don't ya?
-I'm trying to keep you from making the same
mistakes.
Oh fuck you Ron! I am not you!
Do you understand me?!
Don't play the old wise man with me.
This is not about me and you John!
This is about your daughter.
Get out.
-I'm asking you John.
-I will not wait for security to throw you out.
She's at Lutheran Hospital.
They all grovel now.
Thank you for your order sir, confirmation's in
the mail.
I just sold five million of our new Bowman
Pipeline junk bonds!
Hey, you work for me don't ya? John Sullivan?
Scott Hamilton.
Yeah.
Heard you moved some big money down in the
pin. Five million is a big ticket.
Oh yeah... yeah... got lucky I guess,
I don't know.
Hey Todd.
Do you remember the Sable high-yield account
you threw back into the pot?
I just sold them three million of Rumney Casino.
I hate you.
Johnny! Hey buddy... how are ya?
Word is that Scott Hamilton has his eye on you.
Huh... you might be moving into a corner office
soon, huh?!
Unbelievable... you're here two-and-a-half years,
and you get a view of downtown.
You know what I got? View of my own demise.
Hey! To the talk of the town... John Sullivan!
To John!
This is ridiculous.
How many nights are you going to do this?
Hey...
we had a great day today.
I mean... we... we just had to celebrate.
You know.
Look at me.
What?
This has got to stop.
You can't be absent all the time.
She hated your success.
You have a whole other life...
that you are forgetting.
You can't change that now.
You were so ashamed.
Mr. Sullivan, your family has already suffered an
immense amount of grief.
So it saddens me to have to create any more.
However I feel with your history of drug abuse and
your negligent behavior regarding your daughter...
it's important that you be given some time to
re-examine your life.
I see you are currently unfit to care for your
daughter.
-Therefore it is the order of the court...
-They stole her.
-The custody of Emma Sullivan...
-Please! Please Stop!
-Be awarded to Ronald and Katherine Evans.
-Stop!
Damn it!
Oh! Let me help you.
No don't touch a..!
Don't touch a thing... please.
Asshole.
Two... three... four... one... two... three... four...
step... two... three... four
So uh... I'm a little confused about the plan
here.
Yeah, you and me both.
As far as I know, we're supposed to try to recover from
the other side, physically wake her and pull her back.
And we do that how?
I don't know. Today we're just escorts for him.
He's a Pathfinder.
You're a Pathfinder?
Yeah, I wouldn't try to have a real rational
conversation with him Sara, or even a pleasant one.
Oh, and he has wandering hands.
Ouch... two... three... four.
Alright.
We do this carefully and quietly.
We pack light so... uh... don't fight. Mmmk?
Okay, he just needs to observe right now.
He studies the scene and we watch his back.
Now we have no idea if thisgirl is being guarded
so it's imperative that we keep quiet.
We get seen, we have more heat than we can
handle.
What do you see?
It's her... Emma... the girl's body, she's
unconscious on the bed.
What else?
Her Grandmother's in the room.
She's doing what?
Standing.
And she's looking at?
She's looking out the window.
Keep describing.
Her Grandmother's looking at Emma now.
She's touching her forehead.
Doesn't sound right.
Where are this girl's parents?
You'll wear her guts!
You'd murder her, rather than hand her over?
Is she that expendable to you Ink?
That's it!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Let's talk about this.
Leave her.
Take me.
She's done.
Okay, I yield.
Morning.
Someone want to fill me in?
Our inside man says Hamilton put in an after-
hours wine and dine.
Says they offered up six-and-a-half at
seventeen.
Our inside man, have mercy. We've turned into
the CIA.
Fuck! Fuck!
It's okay, okay.
Hamilton's a joke. They're on their last legs.
We can beat this.
John, how the hell are we going to beat this?
We all know they're going to bring the offer to
market using the usual syndicate...
-and now they're making sure Apollo knows it.
-That's been the problem all along...
we simply cannot compete with their trifecta.
For the love of fuck people! Why do we want to
forefit before the game?
Huh? Let's pick up the bat, and take a few
swings.
Look, letting this one slide is just not an option.
It's not on the table.
Okay? We are there, we will take it.
We can always work the numbers.
We could substantiate an offer at... eighteen?
Be a little creative.
I love this woman. I love this woman.
That's what I'm talking about. A little creativity.
It's bullshit.
This was nothing to you.
This has got to stop.
You can't be absent all the time.
It's about self-image guys.
It's just about how they perceive themselves.
Apollo is high as a kite right now.
So we indulge that.
They want numbers, we'll give them some
numbers.
How solid is this?
Solid.
Okay.
So we meet Hamilton's six-and-a-half.
We offer up a firm commitment. Eighteen
dollars, fifty cents.
No one's gonna fuck with that.
John that's a pretty big stretch.
Dan!
I will sell this. I will sell this.
I just affirm what they already believe.
These guys think they're God. Let's give them
some numbers that agree.
They worship you.
Hey John!
How many generations of trash do you come
from?
Don't listen to them John.
Don't listen to them John!
You are better than that!
It'll be $10.80
I'm um... paying with food stamps today.
Humiliation.
What are they're staring at?
They'll all burn John.
In case we need the big guns.
If all goes peachy, we will.
Quiet. Get back.
Damn it!
Oh! Let me help you.
No don't touch! Don't touch a thing, please!
He's ahead of us.
He's walking to his car and there's an Incubus
shadowing him.
What does the Incubus look like?
Large. Collected.
One... two... three... four...
What is an Incubus doing with him during the
day?
What does it mean?
It means this guy is fucked.
Two... three... four... one... two... three... four...
One... two... three... four.
Are you good?
Yes.
And he's bad?
He's not good.
What do you think? Does he seem bad to you
Emma?
You know my name?
I know a lot about you.
How?
When you go to sleep at night, do you like
having dreams?
Well, when you sleep, people like me come.
And we give you, and your family, and everyone
you know good dreams.
Does he give nightmares?
Not yet he doesn't.
Quiet!
Can you take me home?
No, I can't. Why do you want to go home?
I'm scared.
That's strange.
I didn't think a lioness could get scared.
-What?
-A lioness.
Don't tell me you don't know.
Know what?
Ink didn't tell you?
You know you're not a little girl anymore, right?
In this world, you become something else.
And as soon as you came here you started to
turn into a lion.
A lion?
Well you still look like a little girl but...
you started turning into a lion as soon as you
woke up here.
I did?
Yeah, see that's why I'm so surprised.
'Cause usually lionesses are big, brave suckers.
I'm sure you can tell.
You're full of it.
Am I?
Just what I thought.
You know you might start working on your roar
though.
It's tough to be a noble lioness without a good
roar.
Storytellers! Liars!
I'll be rid of you soon.
Intruders!
Stay back... stay back!
This is mine! This is all mine!
Roar!
This... this is all mine! It's all mine!
-Th... th... that's mine!
-Aaagh!
I'm here for a code. I have a delivery for the
Assembly.
There are... there are... there are codes.
They are codes that belong to me and they will not be
taken unless they are replaced by somthing of greater value.
You want payment?
Payment will be your life!
No my life... my life... no, no! No!
For my things to be taken, must replaced and
doubled.
My life?
Mmm... nah. No, that's... thats, that's not of
adequate value.
-Ooooh... those are mine.
-Two!
Yeah... three of those are mine.
So. Assembly codes?
This way.
So... you've uh... come here for codes have
you? Well!
I have codes!
Some... some... uh... somewhere... um...
Assembly codes!
Umm... somewhere... uhhh...
Assembly codes.
How did you get the big prize?
Oh, she... she... she's worth quite a lot I hear.
I can take her off your hands for you.
Liev... the Storyteller.
Liev.
The Storyteller.
Get down now!
I have a $10,000 PowerPoint here. All the bells
and whistles.
Showing you why we are the greatest, the most
reliable. Yadaa Yadda Yadda.
But this meeting isn't about us.
This meeting is about you.
It's about how you guys are going to be the biggest
company in the world in mobile delivery systems.
I've given them an hour. They agreed to
eighteen fifty and everything we set forth.
As long as I show up with the final paperwork
and a bottle of Champagne.
We're in business.
One hour... you've got to be there.
Wake up!
Your whole life is gonna crumble.
We don't have much time.
Tick tock. This man got rocked.
Two... three.. four... one... two... three... four.
One... two... three... four...
What exactly are you doing?
I need links.
Links.
A chain needs links.
Chain... chain reaction?
You've got it, tell her what she's won Bob!
You know what, I don't get this! I don't get you!
I don't get this mission!
What are we even doing here, we're wasing our
time!
A child is going to die and you're burning her
Death is the least of her troubles.
That's right! You know what, you're right! So
let's help her.
You know the downward spiral is essentially a
chain reaction?
And nothing that comes out of your mouth
makes any sense!
They're all reactions!
One thing begets the next. A man has a
weakness, he's flawed.
That flaw leads him to guilt. The guilt leads him
to shame.
The shame he compensates with pride and
vanity.
And when pride fails, despair takes over and
they all lead to his destruction.
What will become his fate.
Something's got to stop the flow.
He's on his way.
The girl needs her father...
and we're going to deliver him.
One... two... three... four...
One...
Something's got to stop the flow.
One hour, you've got to be there.
Wake up! Your whole life is gonna crumble!
Wake up!
He's running for help!
We don't have much time.
Tick tock. This man got rocked.
It's okay...
it's all going to be okay John.
Doesn't sound too good.
Yeah, usually I can get it to start.
Unfortunately I'm not to good with cars, but...
this is the engine, right?
Okay, alright.
-Oh, look at this. Yeah, right here.
-What?
-This is your problem right here.
-Oh thank goodness.
Ah, check this out.
Yeah, try starting her up.
Sorry... that was bad. Sorry, that was bad.
-No... it was good.
-No, no. That was bad.
You were so cute.
I was so nervous.
Why?
I don't know... I guess I was humbled by you.
-No! No!
-Shelly! Come back! Shelly!
-No!
-I love you Shelly!
-Shelly! I love you I want the kisses!
-Get away from me you freak!
-Kisses!
-No!
-I love you Shelly!
-No! No!
-I want the kisses! I want the kisses!
-No! No! No!
Oh baby! Oh baby!
I know...
I know I don't... uhh... say...
I just want you to know...
I just... I want you... I want you...
-John.
-Yeah.
I love you too.
This is who you were.
Why are you here?!
What do you mean?
I know who you are Storyteller. This is a trap!
You set me up! I'll kill her! I'll kill us all right
here!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! I'm the one in chains here, remember Sparky, I'm the one who's un
- armed.
Liar!
-You're confused by your own paranoia.
-Who is this girl? Why do you care about this child?
You are in complete control.
What is it you're so afraid of?
Why the scars Ink?
Do you even remember how you got them or did
you lose your memory when you came through?
It was suicide wasn't it?
I can tell from your scars your entry was painful.
Remember.
You can see nothing.
They'll be gone soon.
At the assembly...
When you become one of them?
You've been given promises of beauty and bliss
in exchange for your soul.
This girl...
she's your ticket?
They told you bring her to the table and you
become one of them?
Numb to your pain.
They told you to take her as a sacrifice?
That's all she is.
There's nothing in you that sees something
else?
I have no sympathy for their kind.
Don't try to manipulate my emotions, I don't
have any.
I'm not interested in manipulation, just in
revealing the truth. But you can't accept it.
I accept what's real!
You can't even accept yourself!
Why do you hide under that cloak?
You wreak of guilt.
Guilt comes from somene with a soul.
Words.
A Storyteller.
Where is your army?
I have no army Ink.
I'm alone.
No one is coming for me, there's no trap.
You are in control.
Yours, hers, my fate, are in your hands.
You will not stop me.
This girl will go to the assembly.
Hello!
You've come to visit Sadie?
Sadie loves visitors.
And they love to visit me.
They love to take my picture.
Love to see me smile.
They ask about me all the time.
What is she doing? Who is she with?
Where have they all gone?
But here you are... my... audience.
My name is... Ink.
Who is this?!
Her ugliness disgusts me!
I am Ink.
These are my prisoners.
I have a delivery for the Assembly.
I need part of a code.
I will speak with you.
But not in her presence.
Ooohhh... a kiddie!
Roar!
It's gettin' there.
Guess we're not well liked here.
Who's she?
She's a drifter.
She was once a person.
And when she died she came here.
But she wanders around not knowing her place.
She's not a Storyteller like me. Or an Incubus.
She refuses both sides. Like Ink.
How long have you been a Storyteller?
How long?
Well, that depends on how you measure time.
For us time doesn't work
the same as it does for you.
We live in two different timelines.
She's cutting your hair.
She wants your hair for part of the code.
You'll give it to her.
It's yours.
Filthy! Probably worthless!
Of course I won't tell anybody I took it from some
cheap bag!
Of course, in the right light...
in the right light, no one notices anything.
When they light me, it's as though I were silk.
Shimmering almost!
Reflecting every gaze.
That's enough.
There's a bigger picture.
What?
Liev says we can't see, but...
there's a bigger picture.
Should we send for help yet?
Not yet...
she needs more time.
How are you able to do what you do?
It's all about the beat.
God may have taken my sight.
But I can hear the beat.
The beat?
Beat of the world.
We're all part of a song, I just hear the music.
You can physically change the path of people's
lives?
That's what they say.
You think he'll be okay?
Sure. A little physical damage can be good.
Shake the shit out of ' em.
That's what I always say.
He's convinced himself he's God.
We're just reminding him he's not.
Takes humility to remember who we are.
If he embraces his shame...
she has a chance. If not, the girl will be lost.
That can't happen.
Better get movin' big boy...
she doesn't have much time.
Shelly... baby... baby... stay awake... baby...
Shelly... Shelly... Shelly...
Stay... stay with me... stay with me...
stay with me.
Stay awake... stay awake... just stay awake...
-Sir come with me.
-Wait!
-Sir we need to get your leg checked out.
-Wait! Wait! Wait!
-Come on sir.
-Wait!
Come on, she's going to be okay.
Sir come with me.
She's going to be okay.
-Let's get your leg checked out.
-She's going to be okay.
Let's go over here.
That's when I lost you.
But it wasn't your fault.
I didn't know what to do.
I know.
I came home, and you were gone.
But your things were there like you... like you
were just coming back.
I didn't... I didn't know what to do.
'Cause I couldn't for the life of me wrap my mind
around the fact that...
you were never coming back.
It's okay.
This wasn't your fault.
I miss you so much.
I miss you too.
Why don't you fight?
You're letting this happen.
You're a warrior.
You should fight.
Fighting would only blind you further.
Do you like my hair?
It's all the rage right now.
Makes no sense.
What do you care about her?
There's billions of children out there.
Her life means nothing.
I believe it means something to her.
Yet you push forward.
I have nothing to lose.
I'm damned regardless.
You've convinced yourself of that.
You're desperate now.
I know my fate is determined.
I don't believe the rumors about you.
What are you doing with her?
She's an extra... gift... for the acceptance.
Dangerous, but he will be happy.
-Get her Dad!
-Feet! Feet! Feet!
Go! Go!
This is who you were.
How do you feel?
Lost.
You were in a car accident. You have a nice
little concussion.
Just go ahead and relax and the Doctor will be
with you in a moment. Okay?
Where am I?
You're at Lutheran Hospital.
Lutheran Hospital.
There's not much time.
Come on John.
Come on John!
Shit! We need help I'm launching the pop!
Do it!
What's going on?
The remote... it's... it's not working.
Damn it!
It has to be launched from the base then.
Go Allel! We'll hold them off as long as we can.
He won't make it without me!
I'll go.
Wow!
Crazy blind bastard on the loose!
One, two, three, four...
I'll stay with him.
Buy me as much time as you can.
It's not going to be much!
One, two, three, four...
Uh, hey, hey, excuse me...
If I wanted to find a patient...
...a little girl?
Little girl? All children are in pediatrics which is
one floor up and to the left.
- Okay?
- Okay. Yeah.
One, two, three, four...
One, two, three, four... one...
three, four, one, two, three, four...
Emma...
Emma, look at me.
Oh my...
What?
I think the change is complete.
I see a lioness.
At first I wasn't sure, but then suddenly...
I noticed something.
Look how brave you've become.
The little girl I met is no more.
She's now the most ferocious creature on Earth.
I knew I was right.
When I die will I be a Storyteller like you?
No, you'll be far greater than that.
You'll be much more beautiful.
Will I get to see my Mom again?
Yes you will Sweetie.
The real prize today... is Ink.
You have proved your loyalty.
Those scars, they will be gone now.
No more shame.
Because pride...
is what we are made of.
You will be our greatest asset.
Roar!
Ink...
Incredible Ink.
You hide yourself ashamed...
but you can't see how beautiful you are.
I don't understand.
Why are you here?
What have you done?
I'm here for you Ink.
I'm here for you.
Why?
What do you want from me?
I am ruined.
Why can't you see that?
Because I choose to see you...
for what you were intended to be...
not for what you've become.
When will you recognize her?
Has your mind become so corrupted?
Who?
This is what you could become.
This is what you will choose to be.
You don't have to choose this.
I don't understand.
You know my name...
but why?
Because you're a great warrior.
Because it's said...
you can undo what's already been done.
When will you recognize her?
Has your mind become so corrupted?
This is what you could become.
This is what you will choose to be.
You don't have to choose this.
It was suicide wasn't it?
I can tell from your scars your entry was painful.
For us time doesn't work the same
as it does for you.
For me, a day is like a thousand years...
and a thousand years is like a day.
You see now John?
You see now?
He did it.
One... two... breathe...
four... one... two... don't die!
Forgive me.
Dad?
Yes baby.
What happened to you?
Dad...
Dad?
Emma.
Is that you?
Yeah baby... it's me... it's me.
I'm not dreaming?
No... you're not...
you're not dreaming.