Yeah.
Shit.
Where is he?
Gotta go.
What's the latest?
Nothing, they say the first
24 hours...
Did she understand?
It's not their fight.
Where are Tess and Isabel?
Any change?
He's in critical condition,
but he's still alive.
- You know, if he doesn't...
- Is Stan there?
- Yeah, he's been there an hour.
- Stan'll us what's going on.
cardio infarction.
He's endured an incredible shock
to his system.
- Can he recover?
- Yes.
Will he recover?
It helps if they have
something to live for.
Family.
Friends then.
Maybe that'll be enough.
Reuben, when it comes
to Willie Bank
you can't rely on contracts.
My lawyers say...
the ironclad.
Gimme some credit for
my business.
But you'll still think it's a good idea
neither does Rusty?
Well, I'm doing it.
It's done.
And you tell Rusty that
I won't have to pull jobs...
to keep my hotel
solvent.
Hey, Reuben...
You fellows are young.
You don't understand.
Did you know that
the Inuit people...
put their elders out
on a ice foe to die...
when they're too
old to hunt?
- Thanks.
- That's just a myth.
Well that ain't
gonna happen to me.
I can still hunt.
This is it.
It's my chance.
I used to mean something in this town.
I would walk into a restaurant...
if it was full, they'd snap out
a new table for me...
like that.
Listen Reuben, if you're worried
about your place in history...
then let us get a
street named after you...
or a boulevard.
We can talk about that
when I'm dead.
Danny, I appreciate you coming
this far to see me...
but I gotta do this.
Reuben!
- Partner!
- Reuben!
So good of you to come.
Of course. Of course. I get
more items for my punch list...
I got so much energy, I can...
hardly sleep from the excitement.
Where are you at on
the visas for the chefs?
My man in Washington says...
they'll be stamped
by the time we open.
- No, no, no, not good enough.
- That's what I said.
That's good.
And the chandeliers?
My ex-wife's new brother-in-law...
You don't need the details.
It's done.
Half priced.
They're already at the warehouse.
And because I know it mattered to you...
I appeared before the
City Council.
The one-way street leading
away...
from the rear entrance, now...
leads toward the rear entrance.
All roads lead to the "Midas".
This is perfect.
Great views up here.
Where's the partner's desk gonna be?
No partner's desk.
- Two desks.
- No two desks, one desk.
One chairman's desk.
One.
The arrangement is changing.
Was changed.
As a matter of fact
there is no arrangement.
Everybody said that you would
try to screw me.
But you've done it to everyone
of your partners.
But I defended you.
I said:
No, me and Willie Bank
been around long enough...
that we both shook Sinatra's hand.
And there's a code amongst guys
that shook Sinatra's hand.
Screw Sinatra's hand.
- Screw?
- You're deadweight.
Do you think I'm gonna carry you
and pay you at the same time?
Reuben...
you're out.
Never.
This is my land.
Was. Was your land.
- You signed it over to the corporation.
- For 50% interest.
Which I'm gonna ask you
to sign over to me.
For a small cash payment.
- I'm not signing that.
- Yes.
Get outta here.
I'm not signing that.
What are you gonna do?
Throw me of the roof?
No, I don't want to.
This is wrong. This is all wrong.
You're leaving me with nothing.
You know you're right.
And it's rude.
Here.
It's the first badge.
Just got made.
You changed the name.
I like it better.
Don't you?
Reuben...
he always was too
trusted.
Is Saul.
Is.
Of course.
He tried talking him out
of it next time.
Look,
Bank hurt Reuben...
I know how that makes
me feel.
- I know what that makes me wanna do.
- Well, I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna get close to Bank
and I don't care if it gets messy.
I'll drive you...
and get him leaving his barber.
Good, then I'll inject him.
Yeah and I'll find a spot
to get rid of the body.
All valid ideas.
Great initiative.
But...
Even though Bank stepped
over the line...
we have to do what's best
for Reuben.
Which means
we offer Bank...
a "Billy Martin".
Wait a minute? And then what, he goes
for it? And that's it, he gets off?
- That's the rule.
- No, that's the rules...
for someone who understands the rules.
which Bank don't,
because he already broke them.
So he don't get the chance.
For Reuben...
I think we give him a chance.
I need answers before
I ask questions.
You get that?
Alright. Do it!
So...
some guys I take
seriously...
tell me you're a serious guy.
Right.
What I want...
what's most important to be is that Reuben
gets his share of the hotel restored.
I'm here to give you a chance
to do that.
You're gonna give me a chance?
Okay.
It's a Billy Martin?
I pass.
Last time I looked
and I look every morning...
it was my name listed as owner
on more valuable property...
in this state than anyone else
in history.
Which means you gotta
lot more to lose.
Well I don't lose.
People who bet on me
to lose, lose...
and they lose big.
You come at me
you better know...
I move quick
and when I do...
I slice...
like a goddamn hammer.
So you're not gonna make Rueben?
If Reuben was too weak
or too stupid...
to see what was coming down...
then you know what?
He didn't belong here.
He's made the right choice:
roll over and die.
Let him be.
How long do I have to
wait for a conduit?
I don't want the labor pains
I just want the baby.
Six months later.
Well...
thanks for coming.
Thanks for the 100 Grant.
This takes longer than
a day though.
Gonna have to re-negotiate.
That's fair.
I'd like some Sen Cha
or Genmaicha.
Green tea.
Yes, sir.
And don't burn it.
Pour it just before boiling point...
- not after.
- Green Tea. Si signore.
Graci.
Just us three?
- For now...
- Figured we talk to you first..
Good lord.
How stuck I am?
Stuck.
Stalled really.
Run it from me.
Don't leave anything out.
Give me the big picture.
- You wanna?
- It's all yours.
- Where shall we start?
- Start with the hotel.
Bank really put
on this one.
Forget weekenders
and conventioneers.
He's built this place for the whales.
of a Five Diamond Award.
The marble was handpicked in Italy...
and the chefs stolen from the highest
rated restaurants on the Michelin guidebook.
In the villas
big players
the silverware is
actually gold.
Bank's greatest strength
is also his weakness.
Ego.
He's been spending his days checking
and rechecking every inch of the property...
getting ready for the grand
opening celebration.
It's a compulsion.
Bank's right-hand man
is a woman.
Abigail Sponder.
We're gonna have to let you go.
Turn in your uniform.
I only gained 4 pounds.
You can't.
Yeah, well your body mass index
is not what its supposed to be.
- But miss Sponder...
- Oh no, babydoll,
it's your butt that's the problem.
You can't find a waitress
based on appearance, man.
That's just unconstitutional.
If they were waitresses.
Yeah, they're actually hired
as models who serve.
So that Bank can monitor their
physical appearance.
It's a cruel practice.
So between Bank and Sponder
they got the place covered.
- When is opening night?
- July the 3rd.
Got fireworks the stroke of midnight
the whole charade.
Are we going in now?
It's already open.
No, it's a soft opening.
To test the place
before the grand opening.
Yeah it's kinda like an
out of town preview...
on the town.
Soft opening? Grand opening?
When they opened the Flamingo...
one day it was closed
the next day it was open.
End of story.
I know, I was there.
Well it's different now.
So when is opening night?
July the 3rd.
Now the top casinos can clear
$3 million a day...
just on the floor.
Bank with his high level players...
and no limits is projecting 5.
Upon exchange for the loans
he had to give up...
six of the nine seats
on the board.
So he doesn't control his company.
The guys he brought in aren't friendly.
So he has to clear 500 million
in the first quarter...
or he gets dumped out of
his own hotel.
Bank wants another
Five Diamond Award.
Every hotel I ever...
has one: a Royal Review
Five Diamond Award.
The Cigarou Inn:
five diamonds.
The Peloponnesian Monte Carlo:
The Grand Saphir, Singapore:
cinco diamantes.
Atomano Crest, Tahiti...
I never not won one.
So, how are you gonna get the diamonds?
- We're not.
- We thought about it for a minute...
- Then we decided... It was...
- Impossible.
- Tell him about Debbie.
- Yeah, tell him about Debbie.
Debbie is a concierge at the Bank.
She's very ambitious.
In a good way...
for us.
As soon as I said the words:
general manager...
she was in.
I put a cherry on top
to make sure.
We found out who'd be
reviewing the hotel.
We're gonna get to him
before Bank can.
I feel bad.
Like torture.
This is war, kid.
There's gonna be collateral damage.
lar restul se va întâmpla
at the airport.
- No, he doesn't know that.
- So what?
He has to know why you won?
You enjoy it? Who says?
Alright so you go through that
for 10 million?
No. I do it for eleven mille.
Now, we found out
Bank is tapped into
the federal fingerprint
database.
Highly illegal.
We came up with a way
to piggyback his system...
in between
firewall checks.
Very interesting stuff out there.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, what else?
We're gonna get his whales.
How?
He talked to Denny Shields.
Denny Shields?
After he bragged about you guys
into talking about how?
We need him.
I should have kept my mouth shut.
And then I saw that guy walking around.
I didn't know who he was.
And I... Just some guy to me.
- And I guess I pissed him off.
- Denny, look...
you know what you gotta know who he was.
Just forget it. Let it go.
The other stuff I got taken
care of...
is all straight.
I got 18 whales,
I spoke to their handlers,
I spoke to their managers,
I spoke to their assistants.
Everyone of them is gonna.
We're gonna do it in two.
I'm gonna leave first
they're gonna follow.
- Okay.
But you gotta make sure they win
because these guys usually lose.
- And when they lose, they get.
- They're gonna win big.
- How big?
- 500.
- One million.
- That night just a group of you
No, it's a reverse
Big Store.
Right...
- Doesn't matter if we win...
- As long as the casino loses, yes...
That could actually work.
So you need to rig...
Craps, Black Jack,
roulette, slots.
This polymer reacts to
ultrasonic pulses...
but it's not metallic, so the compasses
on the table won't detect it...
and it don't effect the way
mark the dice.
Now this...
Not really a lighter?
The dice are controlled from the
manufacturer all the way to the floor.
Which is why we went
all the way to the manufacturer.
Could the air conditioner
be switched on?
The air conditioner? You're crazy.
Look...
You know?
It's dangerous.
Dangerous, is my middle name.
That's not your problem.
So you're jammed on
Black Jack.
We've embedded Livingston in
the Shuffle Company.
Now the tap will stimulate your EKG
much in the same way a lie would.
But you have to step on it
during the control questions.
Your name, birth date, so on.
So those levels will match the stress level
with your false answers.
I got it.
How much is this gonna hurt?
If you're doing it right,
it should be pretty excruciating.
Is your birth date February 11, 1965?
Yes.
Are you wearing a white shirt?
Have you ever been involved in
the commission of a crime?
Oh, no.
Have you ever defrauded or attempted
to defraud the gaming industry?
No.
- Alex...
- Solid.
I love technology.
- I guess to look at you I'd swear
you would be evasive... - But?
the machine says you're clean.
I'm just a little nervous.
I really want this job.
You can relax now.
Welcome to Shuffle Royal.
The Shuffle Royal.
I doubt I've heard
the last of that one.
So if Black Jack is
not your problem...
it must be slots.
Progressors run of computer
chips now.
You're gonna have to program in a trapdoor.
I can probably find you
someone to do that.
Thanks Roman, we got somebody in
on the inside.
A great kid
named Eugene.
Who's got a little
too much downtime.
He's run up a nice little online gaming tap.
He won't be able to keep
it a secret much longer.
Now I have no...
Uh yeah, it's crazed.
How bad is it?
Uh, it's bad...
I owe $30,000.
- So it may as well be a 100.
- Alright.
Let's call it a 100.
Thanks Danny.
Eugene. My pleasure.
Now tell me how you're
gonna program that trapdoor.
So if that's not the problem,
it must be roulette.
Having it in that game is in for a scanner
on the shoe...
wired to a microcomputer
somewhere on your person.
It figures the probability where
the wheels will end within 3 digits.
Yeah, we-we tried that.
No offense, the way he
was dressed, didn't help.
Not very subtle, this guy.
- So you're stuck on roulette?
- No.
We're going lo-fi we think we can
get some loaded balls in there.
Kidding?
How are you gonna deliver?
Two stages.
First we position a man of our own.
There's a gaming Expo the day
of the grand opening...
which Bank is committed to attend.
To show what a regular
guy he is.
Frank's suiting up as The Game.
The men who make the decisions
are very hard to impress.
That's why I'm asking each and
every one of you to help me so...
by being the most classy, gentile...
ladies.
The image that we're looking for...
are tasteful elegance.
What exactly do you want us to do?
Raise your skirts up about 3 inches.
Second part.
We tie Frank to one of theirs.
A pit boss with sticky fingers.
How much for these?
Is Willie Bank know
you're stealing his gold flatware, Neil?
How do you know my name?
Well we know a lotta names.
Your wife, Mary...
your kids, Leanne and Dolly.
We know that you are
the pit boss at the casino.
You don't wanna...
- I mean, I don't...
- We don't wanna hurt you.
We wanna help you.
We wanna double your salary.
All in one night.
What do you need me to do?
Right now, nothing. Go home,
do your job.
And at the appropriate moment
somebody'll present himself to you.
- Enough said?
- Enough said.
Who is the shill at the Expo
to rope Bank?
- We're still looking.
- We'll find someone.
Make sure it's somebody
he really despises.
Back to macro.
What is your exit strategy?
The players won't be on the scam...
so they'll all think
it's their lucky night.
But you never get them out of
the door with all their winnings...
they'll dump it all back.
That's Vegas
and that's your problem.
Well the exit strategy is A problem...
it's not THE problem.
The problem is security.
We're drawing a blank.
It's a little spooky.
The specs aren't on the grey market,
the black market...
or any other market.
And all I keep hearing, is there's
never been a system like this.
Now I've found out where they designed it,
but I can't even get in the building.
I've blown all my buy money,
my bribe money...
4 of my best ideas and
I am nowhere.
But not only I'm nowhere,
I'm pretty sure I'm being followed.
Do you have anything?
Yeah, I think I have a name,
but I don't even know if it's right.
- They're calling it...
- The Greco.
The Greco Player Tracker.
They've put it in Vegas.
- Well I give you back the 100 Grant.
- Why?
Danny,
I like you.
And you, Rusty.
I mean you got style.
You're brilliant, got loyalty.
You 2 were remarkable minds of
a thievery but even they went
off to borrow.
You're analogue players
in a digital world.
You're done.
Believe me, I would love to
go up against Greco...
and crush him.
But it can't be beaten.
It can't be hacked...
and it can't be beaten.
Not even by you?
Oh with 18 months...
nothing else on my plate
no other jobs, no women or distractions...
maybe.
- You know everything about this thing.
- Everything.
Except where it was being
deployed.
The inventor is an old schoolmate of mine.
His name is Greco Montgomery
The pompous ass named
it after himself.
Greco?
Roman?
Yeah, you've obviously never served
time in a British boarding school.
So what's so tough about this thing?
It's an artificial intelligence
security system.
He must be field-testing.
You mean it has a brain?
A hell of a brain.
It doesn't only think...
it reasons.
It reads every permutation in every weight
in every seat in the entire casino.
Hand by hand.
That's why this
security cameras
that measure pupil dilation.
And determine if a win
is legitimate or expected.
It gathers biofeedback...
player's heart-rates,
body temperatures...
it measures on a second by
second basis...
whether the standard variations
of gaming algorithm...
are holding...
or are being manipulated.
The data is analyzed in real-time...
in a field of exabytes.
Exabytes?
- You know what a terabyte is?
- Yeah. It's a...
- An exabyte is a million terabytes.
- Right.
MacGreco is housed
in an impregnable room.
Shock mounted...
temperature controlled and it locks down
if it even sensors it is under attack.
If it locks down, there wouldn't
even be able to get out of the room.
Couldn't we just shut it off?
You know, cut the wires?
That could work.
Better still you'd just kick
the plug out of the socket.
- Seriously.
- No, short of walking into that room...
with a bloody magnetron around your neck.
You know what a magnetron is?
Something that screws up the Greco.
Aha...
short of that.
I'm kinda shocked this is
where we are, because...
- This is a problem.
- That's what I said.
But if we could somehow...
No there is no if...
It can not be shut off.
I mean you'd need a real natural
disaster an actual act of God.
- But if we could...
- You can't.
- But if we did?
You could.
Don't flatter.
If we could, how long
would it take to reboot?
Because it's so sophisticated
3,5 minutes.
Would be enough.
Pick a natural disaster.
Get me a laptop.
Now the drill access is through
a sewer main of Paris Drive.
Grind along here into the
northwest corner of the hotel.
Here.
Probably about 6,00 Rpm
so you won't wake all the neighbors.
When it reaches the resident's frequency...
the building acts like a tuning fork.
To the people inside it will
feel like an earthquake.
That should knock out
the Greco.
And that's your exit strategy.
- Hey Bash?
- I'm up here.
- Hey!
- Here you go.
Hey, where the mags?
- Linus...
- I can't find those things.
I need them.
I can't leave.
- Why are you such a...
- I'm sorry...
ask somebody else.
- Ask Livingston.
- You're such a wowser.
Look, read this to Reuben.
I've done research. Positive
messages get through.
I can't say this.
No, no I'm saying it.
You're just a vessel.
Come on Basher, look,
why don't you take a break?
I'll watch all the equipment.
You'll go read it to him.
Shit.
You know we never digging
the tunnel...
they had teams of guys
monitoring this.
Yeah?
How many?
Teams.
That's a 5.6.
If you don't think a 5.6
is possible or even likely.
Then quit frankly you don't know
much about Byllups senior report...
specifically the Saxon
and the Mohabi block.
I know what you're hoping
then it'll be just a blind trust...
See that, that's Rusty.
He's doing an Irwin Allen.
See that?
He's not deaf, Linus.
- Why am I here?
- Close your hotel.
Permanently.
What?
We haven't even opened yet.
- What are all those people downstairs?
- Well, it's a soft open.
It's like an out of town preview...
What do you think? You just come in
here to tell me to close my hotel.
I'm not gonna close my hotel.
Sir, if you just let me come in with
my team and our gear here for a few days.
- No.
- I can proof what I'm saying.
No hey, there is no way we are exposing
our exclusive clientele to a bunch of...
Scientists?
We wouldn't want that, would we?
Let's just hope for the best, shall we.
That should be enough.
Take this.
It's a standard torsion seismograph.
If there is a foreshock
it will register...
and you just might have
time te evacuate.
I don't want this thing on my desk.
No sir, let me tell you what you don't want.
Your hotel on the cover of Time magazine...
in a twisted heap of steel and glass.
You and your customers are
underneath it. Headline reads:
Who's to blame?
That's what you don't want.
Okay...
Put an evacuation plan on paper.
Will do, sir.
Consider it done.
I do thank you for your time.
If you really wanna put yourself to
good use... Why don't you hit the tables?
I don't gamble, sir...
neither should you
not with people's lives.
I'll screen the meetings more careful
the next time. I'm sorry, Mr. Bank.
And now we have a camera
in Bank's office.
I see you, Reuben.
A letter from Basher.
Dear Reuben...
as the band said: two hearts
beat as one.
When men have been
in battle together...
they are bonded like the flower
and the soil and the sun...
and like the moon catches the light...
Reuben, I'll go ahead and leave this...
here.
I see you, pall.
So she says:
What did I do? What did I do?
I said:
What do I look like, a pancake eater?
- So you just left her down on the floor?
- Right on the floor.
- For how long?
- The next morning.
Good.
Yeah.
Thanks Debbie.
Pack your swimsuit.
I don't wanna see any slack
faces in front of the house.
- Only happy faces, no slack faces.
- Right.
Go!
- Go! Go!
- Right.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Mr. Shields, where are you going?
We got you proof grand opening.
A friend of mine, a very serious man...
told me very seriously...
that'll be a good idea
if I left the hotel.
I'm taking his suggestion.
He can't be too serious...
if he knew what I got in store for you now.
Willie, I'm outta here.
Thank you.
- See you Willie.
- I really hate to see you go, man.
Let's go.
Bank here.
Confirmed?
Bine.
- Where?
- The gentleman in the Trilby, sir.
The what?
The Doctor Dolittle hat.
Why don't you just say that?
Okay.
- Excuse me... Mr.?
- Chubb.
Kensington Chubb.
How do you do, Mr. Chubb?
Would you like to follow me, I think
I might be able to move things along.
How very nice of you.
No, no, no, no, no!
Her Highness is a very
delicate animal.
It upsets her so everyone
but papa carries her about.
All's well, dear.
- Why don't you just follow me?
- How very considerate.
I do appreciate what
youre doing for me.
Oh, sorry.
- Why does he get to go...
- He's a V.I.P.
So what's that make me?
A V.U.P.?
A Very Unimportant Person?
I have a reservation.
De ce nu iei o pauză?
Mă ocup eu de oaspete.
Hello sir, I'm sorry for the wait.
Welcome to the Bank.
Hello.
Kensington Chubb here.
Saul, it's me.
He's in his room. Blast him.
Got it.
Gloves and mask
don't take any chances.
Got it.
Hello, front desk.
Yeah, I'm in room 1706...
and there's some sort of
terrible smell in here.
It smells like...
Well but... I need, I need to move!
Certainly, sir.
I'll just see if we have anything available.
I'm sorry, sir. We are fully booked
for the grand opening gala...
but I'll let you know if anything ends up.
Enjoy your stay at the Bank.
- But...
- Goodbye.
- That I'm ready to see all available rooms.
- My way, mister. - Thank you.
Her highness is so very
sensitive to smells.
Get away.
If you keep on complaining...
they'll fire us, just for listening...
I just say that the working
conditions are bad.
Nobody can deny that.
Payment... little.
Working hours... long.
That's the way it is in Mexico.
Did you all forget about...
general Emiliano Zapata?
When they took the land
from the poor...
they believed it was
forever stolen.
But Zapata said to them:
it's better to die on your feet...
than to live on your knees.
And they fought.
Hello.
I'd like a table for one.
I hear your risotto is tremendous.
It is tremendous.
- The name on the reservation?
- Hanna Walking.
I'm sorry, sir. I can't
accommodate you.
Those are reserved.
May I recommend one of
our other restaurants?
Ling Su, Cantonesian cuisine.
Great.
Okay it's not a prop, for prop's sake.
No, the Brody can work.
What? Just you got the
greatest cover known to men?
Right? So you don't even have to
think about these things anymore.
Congratulations!
No, maybe you're getting soft.
No, I'm not gonna put Danny on...
or Rusty.
Just... Goodbye dad.
Okay.
I rerouted all the impulses
going to the main randomizer.
In Black Jack the best is 21.
It's called Black Jack.
So the results should be 20's
and Black Jack...
to all the players...
with the dealer "bust".
Your call.
Do over. A do over.
Okay... I'll keep working.
- Good.
- Great.
Yes, I'll have the dumplings and
the Shataki mushroom...
and a sparkling water.
Staff...
casino...
food...
room cleanliness.
At this point...
there's nothing I can do to help.
He said that he'd be...
Cum îi zice?
Ambulatory by now.
- Are you keeping his spirits.
- We're working on it.
Thanks Stan.
Oh no, that's way too much.
- No.
- It's not like I removed a bullet.
This side.
- Dr. Stan! - Hey Linus, how's it going?
- Great.
- We're dead.
- What are you talking about?
- The factory in Mexico is offline.
- Offline?
- What does that mean exactly?
- I couldn't get details.
It just shut down.
- You don't think that...
- Yeah, I do. - Oh boy.
So he says that they want their bread
and they want their roses too.
We better get down there
and straighten this out.
- He doesn't listen to me.
- You're going.
If we don't get this factory
back online...
we have to dock this showboat.
What do you mean?
Just the whole operation...
Dude, I got the showboat metaphor.
Thank you, Linus.
I gotta get back.
What?
What do you mean "what"?
Little something for the effort, maybe.
We pull tips.
The other guys are gonna think I'm kiting.
- Come on. - You want it
to come out of my pocket, or something?
Yeah.
Take it easy.
What's the problem?
The Tricode Optimizers that be into
into the nipple sleeve receivers...
pulverated their lubricating
blides...
up against tension against the sidewalls.
Aha...
Picture a knee but without any
cartilage, bone on bone.
Where does that put us?
Cattled.
Okay. The good news is
there's another B600 available.
The one that dug the Chunnel.
- I thought we had that one.
- We did.
This one dug from
the French side.
The bad news is with timing this short
we're gonna have to buy this one.
- And it's expensive.
- How much do we have left?
If I tap the whole contingency
just over 10 million.
- How close does that get us?
- No.
How much is it?
- 30.
- 30?
- 6.
- 6?
36.
- Isn't there anyway without the drill?
- The drill is the exit strategy.
Well...
is there a way for us to raise money?
- I got everything I have in this already.
- So do I.
- Me too.
- We all do.
If anyone of us was lying up
on that bed Reuben wouldn't rest...
until he made it right.
I gotta go up there and tell him
that we failed...
and there's nothing we can do about it?
- So we're stopping?
- I'm not saying that. - So what then?
Scuzi, signori.
Mr. Reuben is talking.
He asks for Mr. Danny.
I hear cars pulling in...
I hear whispering conversations,
Linus crying.
Why don't you tell me what
everyone else seems to know?
Well the thing is...
Wait!
Hi.
Good to see you smiling again.
Can I talk to you guys for a second?
That's your idea?
Well, we've shaken all the trees,
we've looked under every rock...
we've searched every...
We talked to everybody
we can trust.
I know it's not a great idea,
but it is an idea...
and I think as long as we have one idea
we shouldn't give up.
I was really hoping to avoid
that this time.
Number one.
If any of you is trying to screw me...
he'll be dead.
And I'm gonna be looking in
on the operation...
just to make sure.
Number two.
I'll lend you this money
I am your senior partner.
Last money in, first money out.
And you will double my investment.
Double?
- Is that a "yes"?
- Double.
That monstrosity that Bank
calls a hotel...
casts a shadow over my pool.
Break him.
Break him in half.
The man has no taste...
and yet every time
he opens a hotel...
he wins a Royal Review Board...
Five Diamond Award.
Every time he wins the Five
Diamond Award, he celebrates by...
We know.
- By buying one for his wife.
- You mean five.
- One is five.
- Number three.
I want you to steal the diamonds.
- No, that's... - Can't be done.
- We don't have the manpower or time.
- Or a way.
- We get caught we go away for life.
We're not gonna risk that
so you can get his diamonds.
They're not for me.
I just want him to lose
what matters most to him.
Do what you want with them.
But you need to steal the diamonds...
or you find somebody else
to finance your drill.
The B600 drill.
So what's the deal with
these diamonds then?
They're out of Tiffany
they're 30 karat each.
Matches the award plaques...
On today's market they'd be worth...
250 million dollars.
Bank's already purchased the next one
in anticipation of winning the award.
The rest are kept in a secure glass
viewing boot at the top of the tower.
- And Benedict said we can keep?
- That's what he said.
Then why want these diamonds
on the agenda to begin with?
Because it can't be done.
This is why revenge jobs
don't work, Daniel.
You put yourself in a position, you know
you should walk away, but you can't.
This is how guys die
or go to jail.
Alright.
Does anybody wanna walk away?
- Saul?
- I say I was walking away.
Let's cut the son of a bitch.
Okay. Bank fired Gerry Guapi Maior
and 4 others, just so he could say
he designed the hotel himself.
What this means to us?
There's no set of unified plans.
- Routes?
- According to March 05 plans...
there's interior shafts with potential
access to diamond viewing room.
But the May 05 plans only show
shafts: here and here.
September 05 shows no shafts...
and December 06 plans are
the same as...
- How many sets of plans are there?
- That's ten.
Since we can't trust the accuracy
of these drawings...
based on my walking around...
these are the shafts we have to
clap an eyeball on.
Now there's no knowledge of floor
thickness underneath the diamonds.
Anything thicker than 5 inches
we have a problem.
Right.
This here is the elevator shaft...
which can be accessed through
a super high roller villa.
- Got it?
- Alright.
So who's gonna be our super high roller?
I'm so sorry to been
a little tardy mister..?
Pepperidge, Lenny Pepperidge.
I'm Mr. Weng's communicator.
He'd like you to know that
he was waiting for 7 minutes.
We've received your 10 million
dollar cash deposit...
and I would like you to know
that what we normally do...
Mr. Weng won't take a line.
He's a man of extraordinary
discipline.
He's willing to risk 10 million,
not a dollar more.
Did you say Mr. Weng was in
real estate, Mr. Pepperidge?
That's right.
I only ask because his name...
doesn't come up on our
standard file database.
And Mr. Weng and I have worked
very hard to keep it that way.
Exactly what kind of real estate did
you say that Mr. Weng was involved?
Look he owns all the air
south of Beijing.
- The air?
- Put it to you this way...
try building something larger
than 3 stories...
in the Tianjin province...
see if his name comes up
in your database then.
How quickly can you transfer his money
from your cage to the cage at the Bellagio?
Now I don't think that's necessary...
at all Mr. Pepperidge, we've
reserved our largest villa for Mr. Weng.
Extension 765.
Hello Robert.
This is Abigail Sponder.
Your bureau introduced
us not too long ago...
at the gaming fraud seminar.
I remember you.
What can I do for you, Miss Sponder?
Well, you know... We're about
to open a new property...
and there are a couple of
characters here...
I'm not to sure about.
Why don't you give me their names
and I'll check them out.
Up you go.
- What do you mean you're not going?
- You gotta go.
Too fast?
You did the bullet train stunt
with all of Asia watching...
elevators aren't faster than that.
That was C.G.I.?
Wait, so this one got legs?
Jesus.
- Okay then.
- We're down again.
Well what about Rouben?
- Well
- It's just a living.
I mean, if we paid somebody
to read to him.
Maybe he'll see his
next birthday.
- January?
- I don't think so.
Shit.
Shit. Shit. Shit.
And then what happened?
She said she liked surprises.
I don't think that's what she meant.
You think?
- So she put down the remote.
- And I put the towel back on.
Now, those are the waters.
- Relationships can be...
- Sure.
- But they're also...
- That's right.
I've gone through so many
blueprints...
I can taste the ink
on my fingers.
Yeah...
The only other access point is through
the main air-conditioning duct.
- We gotta move that guard.
- We don't have anything on him.
Let's find something.
I can get to the helipad from there too
this used to be the dunes.
Reuben thought me to shoot craps
here when I was a kid.
We'd play hardware and
double sixes.
He straightened me out.
I was 20... 2.
First time I met Reuben...
he looked me off getting cheated
at an old dealer's game at the old rancher.
and he bought me breakfast.
Sands was there... Desert Inn.
They built them a lot smaller back then.
They seemed pretty big.
The town has changed.
You know if I read
one more puff
piece about Vegas legend,
Terry Benedict...
I'm gonna have to buy
a magazine of my own.
And I haven't forgotten about that phone.
Ah, the gold model, the one
that retails for 10.000.
The double light Samsung.
Okay, that would be... Ungettable.
No, no... You call Teddy Sanders
of promotion.
I did that and he promised you...
the very first one as soon as
it comes of the line in September.
That's July for me.
What did you say about Samsung?
He said he used to bowl with
the owner of Samsung.
Well call Danny.
Oh and tell Danny I know the perfect guy
we can use for the role-play at the Expo.
We're worried dress up this.
We were!
We are.
Randall is.
- I must have put...
- Don't blame yourself...
I should have fired you
a week ago.
Bye.
Are you having a nice stay?
And you, sir
How's your Bank experience?
Can I be of any personal
assistance to you?
This is quit unorthodox.
I have never found myself talking
directly to a hotel owner.
I understand, you're just a customer.
And I am just an engaged
innkeeper.
- Spot on.
Well, so far,
in my book...
this establishment is: aces.
Aces? That's good.
The ace of diamonds, I hope.
I see what you...
Diamonds, indeed, yes.
- Hey.
Okay the guard by the main elevator
shaft has a full Hitler for a son.
- Yeah.
- You okay?
- Yeah, no, I just bit into a pepper.
- Anyway...
Is that... Are you...
Are you watching Oprah?
With a bottle of wine?
Did you TIVO this.
- I was reading the paper.
- With the sound of her volume?
Not one, not two, not three
but twelve new beds...
It's not just about the kids,
I mean I'm happy for the kids.
So I think we've come up with
the answer to your prayers...
This is what I think we gonna do:
we are buying you a house!
How's it going in Mexico?
Turk's there.
Are they really gonna built her a new home?
Yeah, the whole family.
- What could I say?
- That's what I said.
Hey.
You guys been talking to my father?
Why would we do that?
That's not to know.
Well, look...
we just wanted to know
how the nose was working.
I knew it, man. He just
can't leave it alone.
What did he say?
Oh I told him...
The nose plays.
- The nose does play.
- It's great. Great stuff.
Thanks.
Turk?
Hey, are you gonna get
the factory open?
Oh yes, we just got a great management.
They can't be treating us like this.
Well, I gotta go.
- Yeah, Ortega here.
- Mr. Ortega, this is...
- vice principal Meckler.
- Oh no...
I'm afraid so, we've had another
incident with Manny and Miss Kelso.
It was the leg this time.
I need somebody to come down
and pick him up.
My wife can't...
I'm sorry sir, your wife we haven't been
able to get a hold off. We left messages.
Yo-yo-yo-yo buddy-buddy-buddy,
do me a favor.
Cover my post
for half an hour.
Oh man, I just gotta go...
Come on man, help me out...
my kid just his leg again.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Alright man, I owe you one, alright.
- Yeah, you do.
Alright...
according to this...
the room where the diamonds
are held...
is directly above here.
$250,000,000 worth of diamonds,
18" of floor concrete in the way.
Man, we can't drill through that.
It's just one thing too many.
Look, we're talking about
a secure room, Terry.
This isn't just a glass box
these diamonds are housed in.
This is 2" thick concussion proof glass...
wired with pressure sensitive
7 digit coded alarms.
Kill the power to the hotel.
It's worked for you before.
No-no-no. See the case and the alarm
both have independent power supply.
And besides you don't run
the same gag twice...
you do the next gag.
How big a deal is it
if we don't get the diamonds?
You have all your fares in order?
Alright, so what we'll have to do...
is get inside that glass case
and switching the replicas.
How are we supposed to get in the room?
Bank is the only one with access, right?
- Sponder has too.
- Sponder has access?
Then we're in.
Sponder is a...
believe the term is "cougar".
It's not my term.
I read about it in Maxim magazine.
Okay, well let's get Rusty
in position.
No-no-no not Rusty... Me.
I'm in. I'm already in there.
I put this whole thing in motion
before I even realized it.
I'm so deep into Pepperidge...
I don't even think, I just react
I am him.
You know it. Great. Great.
Would you just tell them.
Now you don't understand English?
He's not trying not to laugh. You know what?
I can do it.
He says he can do it.
- Alright Linus, go get her.
- Alright.
- Give him the accelerator.
- Natural? Chemical?
- I don't need an accelerator.
- Make it powerful.
Thanks a lot.
I'll play it at Gilroy.
- You don't need a...
- Just one Gilroy, last time you did...
News from Mexico.
From a journalist I used to...
She's an ally of the workers.
What she tells me is that the strike...
hinges on working conditions...
and the fact that labor
are underpaid by 50%.
I'm sure you all agree
is always about the money.
- Ho much are we talking about?
- 36.000.
- How many workers?
- 200. Give or take.
- Alright, that's..
- Just over 7 million dollars.
No-no-no not 36k per person...
36 total.
Turk, you virtually got him
holding out for $3.50 a week?
It is a 5% increase.
We ran him a check.
We'll postdate it.
Say to my brother to keep
his ears shut.
This is Roman Nagel...
If your feel consciousness
absolutely has to intrude upon mine...
leave me a message.
Roman? It's Livingston.
I heard you were out here
taking some meetings...
and I was wondering if you
could help me out.
The technical problem I've been
having...
with one of my assignments.
Oh and I was hoping we could,
you know, keep it on a down low...
from Danny and the other guys...
that I'm coming you for help.
So, call me when you get this.
Okay? Okay.
Bye.
Is Sponder with him?
A whole new segment...
- Which car?
- That's a lot to sober...
Which rolls?
Exclusive rights...
What's the ETA? Okay.
He's on his way.
- Think he's gonna fall for this?
- You did.
You're ready?
I was born ready.
Who advances?
- how are you?
- Good to see you.
I caught your show that kid is great.
Thank you for that. Congratulations on the
enormity of your success.
- Back at you.
- Love and respect. Peace.
Good seeing you, Bernie.
Allow me to introduce to you
the greatest advance in gaming.
Get beyond boring cards and tired dice.
It's electrifying!
It's exciting!
It's 'Nuff Said.
Yes sir.
Oh my god, Mr. Bank.
It's an honor, sir.
May I please give you
a demonstration of casino dominos?
House says 40%.
- Is it documented?
- Of course.
All the action makes the player
feel like they have a fighting chance...
if you understand my meaning.
Check it out, ladies and gentlemen
Mr. Bank...
is gonna give a young and upcoming
gamer a chance. Give him a warm applause.
Come on now.
Alright. Make it quick.
Thank you, sir.
Mr. Bank, first round
a betting next... Dominos.
Second round a betting
upcoming community dominos.
Mr. Bank if a player win
a multiple five...
on the first spin. He or she
is a winner.
Pay off five to one.
Or guess what?
They're already laying 11 to 1,
so when they win
Mr. Bank...
we win.
'Nuff Said.
That is good.
I tell you what, why don't
you send me some of your literature...
and we'll see what we can do.
Literature, literature, Mr. Bank.
Come on now. You don't need
to read no literature.
All you need to do is feel it.
Well, I feel it, it's just that
I don't know if it's Bankable.
- Right?
- Bank.
I'd like to place this game
in one of my casinos.
Now that's what I'm talkin about.
That's progressive thinking right there.
And I embrace the fact that 'Nuff Said
might grow a whole new segment in my hotel.
- Hello!
- And I like a lot this, so right now.
Exclusive rights on a place
this beautiful domino table...
at our Tulico location.
Mississippi, that's where, games
gonna die, ain't it.
Stay out of this, Bank.
You've already passed.
Really?
And do for him what I'm prepared to.
Prime placement centre room Vegas
tonight.
Now Mr. Bank has 3 minutes.
You got one. Go!
Okay well,
- When is the jump?
- The motorcycle?
Mr. Roads will jump his motorcycle
through the fireworks and over the Bank...
You guys gotta get together...
fireworks and stunts.
Are you gonna be on the same pay
because of all eyes in Vegas...
gonna be on me.
It's gotta be perfect.
- I'll take you from the top.
- Yes, sir.
- At round about 12 o'clock.
- Not around about, at 12.
The stroke of midnight.
Go off to navy master clock.
Oh, don't make a maniac out of me.
Where the hell are they go?
I don't really know what's
happening, sir...
we just lost two dozen of our
biggest players without an explanation.
Well, get an explanation.
Miss Sponder, this just came in:
Rush Express Hand Deliver.
Oh, thank you... Thank you. Thanks.
My pleasure.
Guys, let's go.
My dear Mr. Bank
this is a thank you...
for all that you've given me...
the opportunity,
the kindness, the warmth...
The one you couldn't get, huh?
The one you couldn't get...
The grand opening.
How did Ocean get
on my big plans?
Would you like me to have more notes, sir?
Don't go with him.
- Hey.
- How are the matches?
Why don't you come to see for yourself?
Why don't you give me one reason
not to bounce your ass out of my place?
You know the reason and already
decided before you came here.
They were all booked here.
You took them.
What did you do?
Bribe them?
Buy them?
Check them?
Yes.
You brought them here to rub it in my face.
You know?
You're half smart, Ocean.
Why don't you get real smart?
Let them play here.
And I'll give you 10% of their losses.
Now you give it to Reuben
if that makes you feel...
I'm not that easy.
You almost killed him.
20% whenever they gamble here.
20?
So it's done.
How do I know?
They cash out every night
settling cash.
Otherwise take him back again.
They'll need villas.
Villas?
Okay.
Let's go boys. Here we go. Alright.
Let's hit the tables.
But I say: why not feel it?
Why not feel the rush?
Come on, take a trip.
Shake my hand.
Who knows?
Maybe you have what it takes
to break the Bank. Whoops.
Long pass check out time, sir.
What? I'm in no condition to check out.
You've overstayed your reservation, sir.
We need the room.
But Nevada Inn keep
un regulament în privinţa...
Except in case of public
health and safety, sir.
An occupant of instance is flagrant and
disregard for expectable standards.
I've not been disregarding my hygiene.
Sir, I'm trying to say is...
- you've gone nose deaf.
- What?
You're oblivious to your fact
on other guests.
I really don't see what effect, I've had...
15 minutes, 15 minutes, 15 minutes...
15... Hey... 15 Minutes.
Pack your things or we will do
that for you. Get the picture?
- Do you get the picture, sir?
- Pack your things.
- Pack your things!
- Okay.
Okay.
The Gilroy
- Well hello there.
- There are no tomorrows, Mr. Pepperidge.
Call me Lenny.
I need this room.
I gave Mr. Cheng...
Mr. Weng a chance.
I need the Asian villas
all the Asian villas.
Perhaps you'd like to tell...
Mr. Weng yourself.
In fact, I would, I would because...
uh you know the last time we spoke...
he was quit rude to me.
Well in that case you'll...
find him somewhere...
between the cashier's cage
and the high stakes room.
He was about to eat...
when the mood to play suddenly hit him.
It just hit him, just like that?
Well I might have said something
to encourage him.
Why would you do that?
When you work for a powerful man...
sometimes the collar
can get a little tight.
Excuse me.
- Is it on?
- Yeah.
Thanks, homes.
Lester says: hang tough.
Mr. Bank,
I just wanna thank you...
for throwing me
out of your hotel.
- And who are you?
- Nobody.
- Alright, fellows...
- See ya later
Careful!
Vorbesc serios...
We're gonna need you standing by
on the support capacitor.
Bad news just walked in.
Alright, the Bureau is in the house.
They move towards Black Jack
somebody tip Livingston.
Well, let me welcome you to the Bank...
with our finest Kabota sake.
And good to have you back, Denny...
got some great on ice.
Enjoy!
Livingston Dell...
Federal Bureau of Investigation.
We got all the exits covered.
You got nowhere to go.
Don't be stupid.
Ho, hey!
What is going on here?
You've been breached.
We've had this man
under surveillance.
He rigs the sheets.
- He rigs them?
- We've been in contact with his company.
His background information was bogus.
- How many machines he's done?
- I'm not sure.
Ah well, just change him out.
We won't have enough.
The company is sending over new machines.
Well if he raged machines
he's working with players.
We know he's involved with confederates.
We just don't know who they are.
If you see anything that looks unusual...
you contact us.
You bet.
You think this is over?
This isn't over.
I'm pressing charges.
State and Federal charges.
Got it?
Now, get him off my floor.
Come on!
- His fingerprints were all over.
- Yes, sir.
I need a name and
all known criminal associates.
Bank's gonna run the prints of
the Shuffle machine.
Dell, he's good. He gets
Livingston's ID.
and known associates.
That's us.
What do we have in place for this?
Nothing. They'll scoop us all up
and Bank will have...
the best night of his life.
We can't let it get to Bank.
I know what to do.
We'll set up a Cartwheel
Back at the house... 15 Minutes.
Who's gonna hack this?
Well the ideal person is in
the back of a car in handcuffs.
I can handle it.
Is anyone else available?
This is Virgil.
I'll give it a shot.
I can handle it.
Virgil it is.
Get it done, Virgil.
Switch these out first
and do the main floor.
Excellent.
Alright, time for the starters now
Rusty, what's your 20?
Anybody got eyes on Rusty?
It's a two men play...
Back in range. Just had to make
the last minute pick up.
Hi boys.
- Hey, there he is!
- Hey, Reuben! - There my man!
- Reuben, welcome back.
- Missed you buddy.
Let's raise the minimum.
I'd like to play all the suits.
- Really, pineapple?
- Yeah...
No-what-what-no-no not here, not here...
I could lose my job.
Oh doesn't the forbidden make it seem
so much more pleasurable to you?
No-no-no-no...
I can't be free with myself...
in Mr. Weng's villa.
Is there another room?
No, we're overbooked...
Somewhere we can go or
we can be alone.
Please... Have me, take me...
Okay...
Come with me.
Kill the slots.
This is why we have soft openings...
so things like this
don't happen.
- Get them fixed.
- Yes, sir!
Wow! Stunning.
What is? Me or the diamonds?
Both.
I think you're the most
honest man in this town.
And I don't think we're gonna need
the security cameras...
for this next part.
Well... Not unless you wanna watch
the playback.
Now...
I thought we agree with the turn off
of our phones.
I know, but that's Bank.
He's the only one that has that number.
I can make you give that back to me.
I could try.
Do you have any wine
back there?
I got everything you need
back there.
Chateau du Camp?
As long as it's not '73.
Send that to Bank's office.
Yeah?
Cue the Cartwheel.
You got it.
At least I was still happy, when
I saw her like on the magazine.
She's actually one person
like I really kill.
Hello?
Oh hey Saul.
I came out here originally for
a hotel manager at first school.
But... like...
I don't know.
Bună...
I'm so sorry, sir.
I tried to stop him...
It's not your fault.
You can't stop a man that's jumping.
It's alright.
Yes.
Mr. Bank...
do you know what Chuck Berry...
said every night
before counting 1, 2, 3, 4?
What did he say?
Pay me my money.
Well, I'm sure my people...
In cash!
Cash?
You've already been wired the money.
Mr. Bank, this is, this is, this-this...
this is a Fender Roads moment.
You're in yet?
I hate that.
Mr. Bank, Mr. Bank, listen...
All do respect, all do respect, sir.
You got a job tomorrow.
Running this place.
You go to work
every day.
Yawn... Yawn...
I make one phone call, I get
Sean Wright, Travis Pestrana...
five of their buddies here
before midnight...
doing Heel Clickers and
Lazy Boys up a back...
Ye-ye-ye... Yes.
If your audience wants to see
a bunch of longhairs...
riding Rice Rides...
but I'm talking about
heavy bikes, sir.
This is heavy bike!
I'm a goddamn American icon!
Don't change it that much.
Keep a little... Keep a structure.
You're a legend in 34 states.
And an animal
on the other 34.
24, 22.
This is a night people will talk
about as long as it's in Las Vegas.
And when we're talking about it...
we'll either be talking
about you or you won't.
Now, that's your choice.
Mr. Bank, can I just say
one more thing?
Are you gonna jump?
Jumping, baby!
Thank you.
Yeah, I'm looking.
Alright, Rusty's out.
I gotta say I'm very at you.
Very nice job.
Yeah, I know I did. That's why
they asked me to do it, not you.
Well see, that is me offering you
an olive basket
and that's you spitting in my face.
Well is that your face?
Okay, where's Eugene's
trapdoor?
Under the Dragon, first machine
on the left.
Got it. What's the secret?
Coin, 3 counts.
Coin, 6 counts.
3 Coins, 5 counts.
2 Coins half count.
Could you make it anymore complicated?
That's just the first sequence.
Then there's two bular.
Right.
I think...
I think I've may have...
I got all three...
I got all three.
Oh my god...
Oh my god!
I'm a winner!
Progressive slots win on
opening night?
Genuine shock,
genuine surprise...
pupil dilation,
elevated heartbeat...
it's legitimate.
- New dice.
- Coming in.
New dice.
New dice, coming in.
Ooh, what was that?
You felt it too?
You!
What a thrill.
it's still up.
Let's hit for playing.
Alright, ladies and gentlemen,
let's place your bets.
There can only be one winner.
Everything alright?
Are we okay?
Did that tremor throw off the system?
No, sir.
It would take more than that to knock her.
- Sir?
- Yeah.
I have a pit boss asking for an approval.
He can't reach Miss Sponder.
- What's the action?
- 10 million. Roulette.
- It's good.
- Okay.
Alright, gentleman's down at
three number combination: 11, 12 and 13.
You get reception here,
that's impossible.
Not with this phone.
Yes, sir.
Hello? Bank here.
We're getting interference
on server 1.
- Hello? - What kind?
- I don't know.
Hello?
Server 1 is gong down.
Oh, no.
Sir,
That's the only explanation.
Some kind of magnetron.
Server 3's starting to wobble.
A magnetron?
Who's got a magnetron?
Alright, everyone...
everyone in this room.
Everyone in this room,
empty your pockets!
Now!
What's all going?
What does that mean?
Oh, no.
What the hell is this?
Security measures.
When the system sensors
a threat, it shuts down and reboots.
- Well, for how long?
- 3 minutes and 20 seconds.
Snake eyes.
All of them.
Oh, that son of a bitch.
We can't take anymore bets.
to a backup.
My system's in lockdown.
All calls in and out of
this room are secure...
unfortunately, it's the system
that's secure.
Again, sir.
It's in lockdown.
- Rebooting.
- And back up.
Three minutes and counting.
Come on 11!
Boys, I think our lucky streak
just ended.
Better cash them in boys.
Yes.
Alright, guys, shut her down.
Shut her down!
She is shut down.
- No time for jokes, fellows.
- Does it sounds like I'm laughing?
Down the street safely. Safely.
Right this way everybody.
Down the street safely, please.
Safely. Right this way.
Right this way everybody.
- Right this way.
- Jones!
Jones!
What are you doing?
The earthquake's over!
They gotta get back! They gotta get back in.
Sir, it's the evacuation plan... I...
Well, it's all over now.
We can get back to us.
Feel my heart.
Let me feel it.
No.
Oh, no.
That's gonna stain.
Why don't we take these off.
- Off?
- Off.
- It's wet...
- Come on get them off.
- It's wet.
- Jos.
Oh, boy.
OK.
Hold it right there.
FBI!
Oh, dear god!
Robert?
This man, Lenny Pepperidge,
AKA Lenny the Pep...
AKA Shelden Wells,
AKA Little Timmy Hardwell...
is a confidence man.
Okay, that's-that's not the whole...
Help her up.
Oh, my god.
He infiltrates high establishments
through legitimate business contacts.
He was gonna drug you
and replace the real diamonds...
with these.
My god.
Oh, my god!
And that's not all...
Oh, my god.
Oh, Abi, Abi okay...
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry.
I...
- Oh, my...
- No, I really like you.
- Shut up.
- I really...
Oh, I am so finished.
Don't let it bother you.
I'm finished.
He's a professional at
a laying suspicion.
And seducing women
of a certain age.
You know, if Bank hears about this.
I am...
I'll be delicate in my report.
Get her statement.
Thank you, agent Caldwell.
I'll need your full name.
Thank you.
I'm just glad your mother
didn't have to see that.
You just don't wanna admit
that the Brody played.
It's a little early for
a victory lap.
Linus, I hate to break this up
but did you make the switch?
Yeah, yeah, everything went according to
plan, we're heading to the roof.
- Did you hear that?
- I'm ready.
No, it's not that I'm just so desperate
to celebrate...
I need you to acknowledge that
it wasn't just a prop for prop's sake...
that the nose clay it worked.
That in a way it was kinda
perversly dignified...
Look, let's just finish the job.
There he is.
Oh, what the hell? What the hell?
Come on.
Give me the diamonds!
- Come on.
- Give him the diamonds.
A gun?
Come on! Let's go!
Rough night. Half a billion
running out the door.
You gonna roll over and die?
Do you think you hit me?
You aren't gonna know
where my soft targets are.
I'm still at a two handicap
on a golf course, you know.
I got the hottest new hotel on the Strip.
And I'm sure I've won a
Five Diamond Award.
- Yet again.
- Sure about that? - Sure.
- I got that baby...
- Soon enough.
Oh, whoops...
This town might have changed,
but not me.
I'm gonna let you down.
I know people.
Highly invested in my
survival...
and they are people who
really know how to hurt...
in ways you can't
even imagine.
Well...
First I know all the guys
that you'd hired...
to come after me...
they like me better
than you.
Second, we're not gonna
go to the cops.
Let's face it, you're not
gonna go to the cops.
Third...
you've shook Sinatra's hand.
You should know better, Willie.
My diamonds.
No, no, no!
Shit!
This town...
is a lonely town
Not the only town...
like a this town
This town...
is a make-you town
Or a break-you town...
and bring you downtown
What's this?
That's just the deed to
4,6 acres of prime...
real estate in the north end
of the Strip.
The moment you become embarrassed
if who you are, you lose yourself.
I changed my house, the way I dress,
what I ate.
For what?
For nothing.
There he is.
Thanks for those letters.
They brought me back.
You're more than welcome.
- Hi.
- Looking for Terry. It's Daniel.
- Danny.
- Terry.
That's what I do when
I see a blitz coming.
A blitz?
I guess Toulour just happened
to be on the roof.
at the exact moment that we were
coming out with the diamonds.
How did you know I'd go for them?
Because you're you
and I am me.
We were watching Toulour
while you had him watching us.
This is your in.
Which you donated
to charity.
Charity?
Camp to Belong.
The kids are very greatful
they're gonna have you up to visit...
next month.
Now you know that wasn't
our deal.
Well if you feel that strongly
about it...
then we'll send the kids
back to their foster homes.
All 200 of them.
- You think this is funny?
- Terry, it sure is shit ain't sad.
Why these children?
Well, I'm just very moved by
the kinda work they're doing there...
and you gotta start somewhere
and luckily you know...
the casino business is doing well...
and I hope there's more millions
to come for other organizations.
But, like I said... I was really
moved by that place...
You know, you gotta do
is look inside a child's eyes...
and... that's all it needs...
all the motivation
that one needs.
- Well, thank you for being an angel.
- No, thank you.
- I'm just following her lead...
- Thank you, Terry Benedict.
We'll be right back.
Well, I gotta jump. My dad's working
a frame he's got a part for me in it.
- Congratulations.
- Nice goin'.
See you when I see you.
Sorry, I guess this is just
a Susan B. Anthony event again.
So...
See you when I see you.
Next time...
try keeping the weight off
in between.
Gotta settle down
have a couple of kids.
We'll be calling standbys
in a few minutes soon.
Please... please...
I gotta get out of here.
Maybe you'll get lucky
this time.
You dropped these.
Go ahead. I got a plane
to catch.
Actually, try this one.
It's been paying out.
I won! Look at this!
I won $11 million!
Can you believe it?
Look at that!
I won $11 million.
I can't believe it!