NARRATOR: There are
many places we could begin
the next chapter of
the legend of Ron Burgundy.
This is one such place.
(SCREAMING)
However, we won't
begin our tale here.
No, our story begins in a
place all newsmen dream of.
In New York City.
(UPBEAT RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
Ron Burgundy!
That lady's got an ass
like the Loch Ness Monster.
Thing is mysterious
and ever sought after.
Ron, aren't you going to
say something to him?
Hey, when you've got an
ass like the North Star,
wise men are going to want
to follow it. (SCOFFS)
NARRATOR: It was a time before
cell phones and steroids.
And for Ron and his
now-wife Veronica,
life was good.
RON: The Tooth Fairy's
exposed breast
made the child uncomfortable.
(CLEARS THROAT)
The Bishop wore
buttless chaps to the bat mitzvah.
Bat mitzvah.
The garden gnome
had a normal-size penis.
(VERONICA WHOOPING)
Corningstone.
(DOING VOCAL EXERCISES)
(IN SHRILL VOICE)
Oh! Oh, no! Oh, no!
They're coming in through
the back door! Oh, no!
(WBC NEWS THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, no!
(SINGING)
Grab the children!
Save the children!
Five, four...
Have a great broadcast.
You, too, darling.
(MOUTHING)
Good evening.
This is the weekend edition
of WBC News at 6:30.
I'm Ron Burgundy.
And I'm Veronica Corningstone.
Our top story tonight.
The U.N. today announced
sanctions against...
When the broadcast is over,
send these two up to my office.
Time to make a change.
(DINGING)
Rumor has it that after 35
years of manning the helm,
Mack Tannen is thinking
about stepping down.
That's right.
(EXHALES)
Do you...
Do you think we could be...
We could be getting
the Nightly News, Ron?
I think that's exactly
what's about to happen.
Oh, my God.
That's what's happening, isn't it?
I'm hyperventilating.
Yes, I see that.
(HYPERVENTILATING)
Look at me.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, you... Well.
I'm laughing like
a ventriloquist's dummy.
You are.
(LAUGHING)
Let's stop that before
we get in there.
Don't do that in there, darling.
VERONICA: Mr. Tannen,
you are an inspiration, sir.
I've been doing the evening
news now for over 35 years.
Done a hell of a job.
Yes, sir.
A hell of a job!
I've gone through four wives.
I have six or seven kids
that I haven't got the time
to tell I love them.
To be honest, they
sound a little needy.
And I killed four men in Okinawa.
W.W. Two.
And that was two weeks ago.
The point is,
this is a very demanding job.
Yes.
But I'm close to thinking that
you may have what it takes.
Now, let me look at you.
Oh, my God.
Would it be wrong to say
you smell terrific?
Ron, please!
Okay.
What are you?
Finnish?
Oddly enough, I'm 100%
full-blown Mexican.
From the state of Oaxaca.
VERONICA: No, you're not, honey.
Hello, sir.
Oh, my heart is racing.
MACK: Hmm.
I just have to say, this is
super creepy and unorthodox.
You like-a da merchandise, huh?
Sorry.
All right.
We're about to make
network news history.
Veronica.
Yes?
You're going to be
the first female full-time
network news anchor.
Oh, my goodness!
Oh! I knew it.
And you, Mr. Burgundy...
I'm going to be the first
lactose intolerant anchor.
Mr. Burgundy.
Yes?
You're fired.
Come again?
Fired.
You are the worst anchorman
I have ever seen.
But what did I do wrong?
Name one thing.
(YELLING) Korean soldiers
were fired upon in the DMZ!
Oh. Jeez, I am so sorry.
Someone put the story
in all capital letters,
and I... I thought
I was supposed to yell it.
President Parter...
Ah, shit! (SIGHS)
I mean, President Carter
will speak at the summit Tuesday.
Tony, did I just curse?
Are you kidding me? Shit!
I mean... Shit. Shoot!
The slain Civil Rights leader
was eulogized... (SNEEZES)
VERONICA: Oh!
Oh, wow! Did you see that?
Right on the lens!
Folks, I'm sorry.
I hold myself to
a high professional standard
and you shouldn't hear
that language, okay?
I'm having a shitty day.
Oh, fuck-stick!
Now, I know this is tricky,
given your relationship,
so I'm going to give you the
evening to think about it.
I forbid it!
You forbid it?
What? Who are you? Julius Caesar?
Who the hell is Julius Caesar?
You know I don't follow the N.B.A.
Look, I am so sorry
that this happened, Ron,
but you and I, we're
partners, sweetheart.
And when something good
happens to me,
it also happens to you.
That's ridiculous!
It clearly just happened to you!
You... Oh! Be quiet.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
WALTER: Mom?
LUPITA: I'm sorry,
Mr. and Mrs. Burgundy.
He no go to sleep.
Damn it, Lupita, what have
you been doing up there?
Eating nachos?
Mommy? Daddy?
Why are you yelling at each other?
Did Mom touch Dad's hair again?
Walter, honey, why don't you
just go to bed, all right?
Mommy and Daddy are just
having a discussion.
No! He needs to hear this.
He's six years old.
He's a man.
Walter, listen to me.
Life isn't a fairy tale.
It's not a bunch of
jumping rope and grabbing ass.
It's complicated.
(SIGHS)
What do you want to
do with your life?
What do you want to be
when you grow up?
I want to be an
astronaut or a cowboy!
You're never going to
be any of those, okay?
Ron!
You've got to set
the bar a lot lower.
Service industry.
Fry cook. Prison guard.
Maybe you're a lighting
guy at a porn shoot.
Which basically means
you hold up a flashlight
while adults do things.
He is a child, Ron!
Nah, nah, nah!
He's got hair on his nugs.
He's old enough to hear this.
Your father is a wise man.
I will lock you in a closet!
Veronica, here's the bottom line.
It's a very simple decision.
It's either me or the job.
It doesn't have
to be a choice, Ron.
Don't do this.
Don't throw away everything
that we've worked so hard for.
Me...
...or the job.
SEAWORLD ANNOUNCER: Hello,
and welcome to the 3:10
Dolphin Show at SeaWorld.
Sponsored by British Petroleum.
B.P. Oil,
nature's best friend.
And now, here's your host,
Ron Burgundy.
Good afternoon, everyone.
And welcome
to world-famous SeaWorld,
here in San Diago, California.
Here's a fun fact, dolphins aren't fish.
They're mammals.
Here's another fun fact,
I haven't felt the loving
embrace of a human being
in over three months.
(SOBBING)
I'm so lonely I paid a
hobo to spoon with me.
Let's bring out our
world-class trainers here,
Jesse and Paula.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Thank you.
Thank you, Ron.
Sometimes I try to kiss 'em.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh, Ron Burgundy, everyone.
I want to kiss you.
No.
Or I'll kiss your friend.
How about the two
trainers kiss each other?
What do you say, huh?
So, let's say hello
to the stars of the show,
Chippy and Roo-roo!
RON: For your information,
Chippy was rehabilitated
and Roo-roo
is an asshole.
Ooh!
Look, they're swimming
and doing tricks!
Folks, what do you expect?
They're dolphins.
(CLEARING THROAT)
(DOLPHIN CLICKING)
What did you say?
Look at you,
with that permanent smile.
You think you're so smart,
with your secret language.
You just fart out
of the top of your head.
(IMITATES FARTING)
(AUDIENCE BOOING)
You're a punk, Ron Burgundy!
Boo!
Children and animals
hate you, Ron Burgundy!
I would eat dolphins
if it was legal!
Unhand me, you buffoons!
(GRUNTS)
All right, first, you threw
up in the shark tank.
Then you fed the seals
a chicken gyro?
And now this?
You're fired, you washed-up drunk!
Guess what, Trevor?
Every morning I get
here a half hour early
and I sexually assault a starfish!
(GRUNTS)
This is the end of the road.
I'm not turning back.
(BARKING)
Well, I know it's not
a pretty sight.
And you're gonna be
the sole witness.
If you can't handle it,
you leave the room.
(SIGHS) It's too late, Baxter.
(BARKING)
I'm going the way
of the ancient samurai
who, when dishonored,
would hang themselves
from a fluorescent light.
(BARKING)
Goodbye, my sweet hairy prince.
Oh!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(GROANS)
Oh!
Sweet cream on nipples!
Uh, Mr. Burgundy?
Hello, I...
Oh, my God!
What the hell happened?
Um... Um...
I tried to hang myself?
Because my life's a mess?
And I saw no other option?
I think you're telling the truth,
but why are you saying
it like you're lying?
It was a call for help?
But it didn't work because
I'm too heavy and the
ceiling lamp broke?
Something like that?
Yeah, I... I think you're
telling the truth.
I am.
That's what happened.
RON: Mmm. These are
first-rate flapjacks.
I'm telling you, suicide
makes you hungry,
I don't care what anyone says.
My name is Freddie Shapp,
and I'm a producer
of a new kind of news.
We're starting
a 24-hour news channel.
First of its kind!
GNN. The Global News Network.
(LAUGHING)
That is without a doubt
the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
You mean news going 24
hours around the clock?
A channel that's never
off, in other words?
Yeah. Yeah.
Just 24 hours. It's, uh...
(LAUGHING)
No offense, but you
are a stupid asshole.
Mr. Burgundy, I assure you
we are 100% for real.
We've got state-of-the-art
facilities in Manhattan.
And Kench Allenby,
multi-millionaire
and owner of Koala Airlines.
So glad he was acquitted of murder.
I'm a big Kench Allenby guy.
He's funding the whole network.
He believes in it.
I don't think you
understand, Freddie.
My hero, Mack Tannen, told me
I was the worst journalist
he'd ever seen.
I'm not good enough.
Here.
This is your first week's salary.
By the hymen of Olivia Newton-John!
What do you say, Ron?
I'll take the job.
And I swear I'll be
number one again.
I'll take back my son,
restore my reputation,
and make everything
right with Veronica.
But more importantly,
I'm going to do
what God put Ron Burgundy
on this Earth to do.
Have salon-quality hair
and read the news.
Ron... You've made my day.
I've got the best damn
news team in the world.
Your call.
I just have to find them.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
San Diago. Looks like we begin
our search right here at home.
Last I heard, Champ Kind was fired
for being drunk
on the air and saying,
"The only Olympic sport
Filipinos are good at
"is eating cats and dogs."
(BAXTER BARKING)
(LAUGHS)
Who loves chicken?
You do!
WOMEN: We do!
♪ Delicious chicken
Swing on through
♪ Meet the crew, hoo-hoo!
I'm local San Diego
legend Champ Kind,
and I believe in two things.
Good chicken, and that the census
is a way for the U.N. to
make your children gay.
So come on by and grab a wing.
'Cause when you do,
you'll say, "Whammy!"
No Catholics or Jews admitted.
All right, there you go.
One Whammy Special,
with Whammy Slaw.
There's a used Band-Aid
in my coleslaw.
My gosh, let me take care of that.
Get out of here before
I smash your head in,
you Commie bastard!
If you're from the census,
you take me off your list!
You never did have much
of a bedside manner, Champ.
Ron? Ron Burgundy?
Get over here!
How are you, friend?
God, I have longed for you.
It's good to see you, too.
Oh, this feels like home.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Better now.
Okay, let's break
the huddle here, huh?
Okay. All right.
All right.
You get back here! Oh!
Don't be weird!
CHAMP: So, anyway,
Harken sat me down, he said,
"Champ, you're a dangerous
alcoholic, a racist,
"and I don't think you
know a lick about sports."
And I said, "Ed, you dirty Polack,
"it's 10:00 in the morning.
"Let's go have some drinks
and go to a baseball game
"where the Mexicans hit some touchdowns."
Then he fires me!
Fortunately,
on the way out the door,
I fake a work injury.
With the settlement,
I bought this place.
Well, I'm glad to see you
landed on your feet, Champ.
Listen, can I ask you a question?
Sure. Anything.
Is... Is this chicken?
Oh, hell, no.
It's really impossible
to turn a profit
if you serve real chicken.
Yeah. We use mainly bats.
What?
Yeah. But the good quality kind.
That's the most horrible
thing I've ever heard.
Yeah? You got to do
what you got to do, right?
So what you got to do
is serve fried bats?
Yep. Do you know
what they call bats?
Bats.
"Chicken of the cave."
No one calls them
"chicken of the cave."
Who's "they," by the way?
There's a guy I met named Paco,
sells bikers speed at the pier.
So that guy calls them
"chicken of the cave."
Yeah.
That's not "they."
Why don't you have a bite
and stop judging it?
I'm not going to bite
into a fried bat.
It's delicious.
It's all tendon.
Look at it.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Was that a bat?
Chicken of the cave.
What brings you here, Ron?
My friend, we've got a job.
In New York City.
Whammy! I'm in!
You've got yourself a sportscaster.
Oh, great.
Denny!
Lock up!
Any idea where Brian Fantana is?
You haven't heard?
Fantana hit the big time.
Aw, baby.
Yeah, that's it, play for me.
Just play around.
Roll around and lift
those legs up. Mmm!
You are a hairy little thing,
aren't you?
(BRIAN GROWLS)
(CAMERA CLICKING)
Yeah. Oh, I like
what's happening!
Oh, that's it.
Yeah. Yeah.
Oh, you little fuzzball,
that's... Oh!
I got it.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
It's not getting
any better than that.
That's brilliant!
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, Brian, you have any
time for the little people?
Well, I'll be a son of a bitch.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hey, Brian.
Champ! How you doing?
Hey!
Wow. This is a...
Cool it!
Oh, I can't believe...
Oh, wow.
It's great to see you!
Welcome.
Welcome to my doj'.
This place is spectacular!
It's amazing.
A bit chaotic today.
We got the Cat Fancy
cover coming out.
You know how that can be. Ooh.
I've been living in a tent
for the last two years.
Oh, yeah, this is not that.
We got a sauna in the kitchen.
A lot of people think that's weird,
but I keep wine in it.
I'm not a wine guy, but I
know you got to keep it hot.
Oh, and check this out.
This...
This was fun.
We shot this over
two weeks in Prague.
RON: Wow.
You know what they call cats?
Chicken of the rail yard.
No.
What?
Don't indulge him.
Yeah.
CHAMP: There's a lot of meat.
But I love it. (CHUCKLES)
And what's so great about
it is it's so damn true.
I hate Mondays!
I'm not a Monday guy.
Ron hates Mondays.
Hell, I'm not crazy
about them, either.
I also don't like Tuesdays,
Wednesdays or Thursdays.
(ALL LAUGHING)
So why are you guys here, anyway?
Well, Brian,
we're getting the news team
back together again.
Really?
And, of course, we want to
know if you'll join us.
Jeez, I don't know.
I kind of got the world
by the tail here. I...
I don't know if I can.
Christ, I get it.
I mean, you're the Quincy
Jones of cat photographers.
Why would you leave all this?
RON: Hey, Brian,
I don't know if you heard,
but New York has
all-nude strip clubs.
The question still remains...
Where's Brick Tamland?
Oh.
You guys didn't hear?
No, what happened?
Brick's...
Dead.
BRIAN: Brick was lost at sea
about a year ago.
RON: Oh.
Thought he saw a bird and
he swam out to pet it.
He never came back.
(PEOPLE SOBBING)
We all loved Brick,
even though he never
had a phone number,
or address or
Social Security number.
In six years of
working at the station,
he never cashed a paycheck.
That sweet Brick.
ED: He was a
sensitive man, though.
He told me he wanted
to donate his organs
to science before he died,
so he could see
where they ended up.
He'll long be remembered
and he'll be sorely missed.
(SIGHS)
Thank you, Reverend.
Oh.
Oh, come on!
BRICK: Brick was a great man.
(SCOFFS) Really?
And I will miss him so much.
And I will not rest
until I find his killer.
What?
His killer?
It is hard for me to believe
that he is gone. (SOBS)
BRIAN: He's not gone.
(SOBBING) I feel that
I just saw him yesterday.
You were probably talking
to yourself in a mirror.
When I got the news...
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
I didn't even know
how to make sense out of it!
None of us understand!
(SHOUTS) Why? Why?
Why did you take him from us?
You're clearly standing
in front of us, Brick.
God damn you!
Brick!
Brick is dead!
RON: No, Brick's alive.
Look at him!
He's not dead.
He's not dead, Brick.
You're not dead.
You're Brick!
Brick, it's you!
He's dead!
No! You are Brick!
Touch yourself.
I am Brick?
ALL: Yes!
I'm alive?
(LAUGHING JOYFULLY)
ED: Of course.
Of course you are.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
You kind of want to slug him.
You want to slug him.
(ANCHORMEN LAUGHING)
RON: Do you remember our
Easter trip to San Francisco?
We got so drunk, we put
Brick in a refrigerator box
and threw him off
the Golden Gate Bridge.
I broke my back!
(ALL LAUGHING)
What about the time
that you dared Champ
to drink that beer stein
full of Woolite?
He drained it faster than you
could say, "No, don't do it.
"That's the equivalent
of drinking poison."
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, Lord, I was in
a six-month coma.
And they say from the
neurological damage,
there's no way I live past 55!
(LAUGHING)
You got three
years left, my friend.
You're gonna die!
Hey, hey, remember?
I was by myself
and I had that dream
about the orange tree.
But instead of oranges,
it had babies on it.
It was a baby tree!
(LAUGHING)
Brick, how could we remember?
It's your dream.
(LAUGHING) I don't know.
It's all the same thing.
It's an interesting dream,
but we're telling stories
involving the entire
news team from the past.
(BRICK LAUGHS)
Or how about the time when I was
born and I came out of the vagina?
(LAUGHING)
I was screaming, "Here I come! Oh!
Here I come, Mom!"
First off, Brick, I highly doubt
you remember your own birth.
And, once again,
we weren't there.
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
Ron, I can't...
I can't stop laughing, Ron!
Put a pencil in his mouth.
RON: It's okay.
CHAMP: There you go.
I'm okay now.
Man, this just feels right!
The news team is back!
Ron,
Brian, Brick, me, even Baxter!
(BARKING)
(LAUGHING)
That old man
is so little and hairy!
Hey, Ron, who's driving?
Oh, it's okay,
it's on cruise control.
Who wants some chimichangas, huh?
Best thing I ever did was install
this deep fryer in the 'bago.
Ron, why do you have
this bag of bowling balls
and this terrarium filled
with scorpions?
Oh, it's a long, crazy story!
BRIAN: Hey, Ron.
Cruise control just regulates
speed, it doesn't steer.
Come again?
CHAMP: Oh!
(HONKING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
(RON WHIMPERING)
(GROANING)
RON: Well, that is gonna
make one hell of a story.
(ALL LAUGHING)
The Big Apple.
Ron Burgundy is back.
CHAMP: Why do they call it
the Big Apple, Ron?
RON: Because New York has
an apple tree on every street.
Here we are.
Welcome to GNN.
I don't know, Ron.
You sure about this place?
Guys, I know it's a bit
of a mess, but trust me,
everything will be ready
for the launch tomorrow.
And we've culled the whole
country for the best newsmen.
There's Curtis Knightfish
from Houston.
Oh, Curtis Knightfish.
They don't get
any better than that.
FREDDIE: And there's Diane
Yahwea from Carson City.
Diane Yahwea.
You know what they call her, right?
"All the Way Yahwea."
She's my aunt.
And the best in the biz.
Jack Lime, out of Chicago.
Rumor is Allenby is giving
him one mil a year.
That's crazy.
Who's worth that kind of money?
RON: Oh, my God!
He's absolutely magnificent!
I bet his poop
smells like sandalwood.
Can I help you, guy?
(STAMMERS) What was that?
I said,
"Can I help you, guy?"
Uh... (CLEARS THROAT)
What do you mean?
Well, you're staring
at me, hotshot.
Do you want my autograph?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
No, he was just explaining
who you were and I
was looking at you.
And then he said something
and I was still looking at you.
(MUMBLES MOCKINGLY)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE)
Jack Lime is a great man!
(LAUGHING)
Is that what I sound
like when I talk?
(MUMBLES MOCKINGLY)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Is there a problem?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No problem.
Well, you're making a face
like you got a problem.
Um, I'm sorry that
I'm making that face.
I don't mean to make a face
that seems like I have a problem.
I don't like that face!
You need to change it,
and change it quick.
Stop making that face.
Is this face better?
JACK: Oh, I don't like...
Oh, that new face is driving me crazy!
Change it, now!
You're getting him mad.
I only have so many faces.
I'm just grinding your
gears, man. (LAUGHS)
Welcome to the station!
We're going to have
a good time together.
Oh, my God.
That's vintage Jack Lime.
Come on, guys.
Let's go meet the boss.
FREDDIE: We'll have
separate cameras
for you, and then sports
and then weather.
Let me ask you this, Freddie,
how's the new head honcho?
Well, Linda Jackson has
a shelf full of Emmys.
She's as tough as nails.
And Linda loves to win.
Oh, hey, Linda!
I want to introduce you
to Ron Burgundy.
Linda Jackson.
How are you, my friend?
FREDDIE: Ron.
This is Linda Jackson.
Hello, Mr. Burgundy.
Oh. Uh...
Black.
Jesus, just stop, Ron.
I'm terribly sorry.
I don't know why
I can't stop saying...
Black. The word "black."
Hello, Mr. Burgundy.
Black.
Stop.
Stop saying "black."
Black. If I don't say it, I'll pass out.
Stop saying it!
Uh, Donna, can you please
get me a cup of coffee?
Right away, Ms. Jackson.
Thank you.
Please be seated.
Everyone.
Sure.
LINDA: Please be seated.
Great. So I know that
all of you are aware
that the news community is laughing
at what we're trying to do
here at 24-hour news.
But that is why they brought me in.
She's the best!
You see, gentlemen, I don't lose.
Listen, I feel like
I need to clear the air.
Oh, please don't.
I want to say, on behalf
of the entire news team,
we are huge supporters of all
African and Americans.
Veronica got so tan!
I remember the first African
and American I ever saw.
It's African-American.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Absolutely 100% positive?
It isn't like...
Ron... (CHUCKLES)
Fish and chips?
Hey, we're all the
same on the inside,
stinky and pink.
When I was in high school,
me and my buddies
used to sneak in
the girls' locker room.
We'd peek at the girls
in the shower,
and I'd look at all of them,
no matter what color they were.
So...
Jesus, this is the worst
meeting I've ever been in.
A black man follows me
everywhere when it's sunny.
Actually, I think that's
your shadow, Brick.
I call him Leon.
And if it's a cloudy day,
what happens to Leon?
He goes home.
It's your shadow.
He's talking about his shadow.
Shut your damn mouths!
Sit down!
What's he doing?
I think you scared him.
You can't shout at Brick.
Is he all right?
Can you sing him
a soothing siren song?
Just a high melodic...
(VOCALIZING)
I'm not singing along with you.
Oh, come on,
Brick. Brick!
Linda has a balloon.
You better get him a balloon.
Is this for real, Freddie?
Linda, I'm sorry.
No, it's okay!
It's okay.
So you have a black boss,
and it's freaking you out.
Is it freaking you out?
A little bit, to be honest.
You freaked out?
Is it freaking you out?
Oh, she's got a knife!
I don't give a shit!
We're not all here to hold
hands and sing Kumbaya.
Black.
So as long as you guys get numbers,
we are gonna get along just fine.
Now, if you don't,
I am gonna be icy.
And unpleasant, you dig?
I dig. We all dig.
I like to dig.
One time I went digging
for treasure and I
found a half a body.
Get out of my office!
I'm telling you, you can't give
an inch in those situations,
and I think we held our
ground pretty firmly.
Guys. Guys, we got
you an apartment
on the Upper East Side
and a whole new wardrobe.
That's wonderful!
When do we begin our broadcast?
Well, the big launch is tomorrow
at 12:00 noon.
Okay.
You guys are slotted for the
2:00 a.m. to 5:00 a.m. slot.
What? That's the graveyard shift!
"I ain't afraid of no ghost."
Oh, come on, it's
going to be great.
Let's get your keys.
Come on!
(PHONE RINGING)
RON: Is there booze
in the apartment?
FREDDIE: Of course
there's gonna be booze.
Of course.
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
BRICK: It won't stop.
Sometimes it stops,
but then it starts again.
What are you doing,
Chani? Answer it!
Hi. Yes, let me transfer you.
Your job is to answer the phones.
I'm getting ready for Secret Santa.
When is that again?
It's at Christmastime.
When else would it be?
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm Brick.
I was dead last week.
I'm Chani.
I like the place between
your head and your body.
I like your hair.
It looks like wet popcorn.
Thank you.
Would you like to see
the smile that I use
when I pose for photographs?
Yes, please.
Do you want to see the face I make
when I see a snake
made out of candy?
Yes.
That's good.
What's your favorite time of day?
Now.
A minute ago.
Um...
(CHUCKLES)
Surprise!
Big daddy's back.
Ron.
What are you doing here?
I'm over at GNN.
I'm living in the city again.
I really wish that you
would have called first.
Look, it doesn't matter whose
fault the break-up was, okay?
I was stubborn.
You were like a mentally ill whore
having PMS from the 1800s.
What's your point, Ron?
The point is
(SIGHS) I'm back home.
And I want to spend
the rest of my life...
MAN: Honey, who is it?
Hi, Ron. I'm Gary,
Veronica's lover.
So, is that a gift for me, Ron?
No, it's not.
It's for Walter.
Okay.
So when were you going
to tell me about Gary?
Ron. You walked
out on me.
What did you expect me to do?
Ron. This is awkward,
I know.
I'm sitting here with your wife.
We make love.
I'm this close to shooting
a flare gun at your dick.
Oh, Ron!
So what does this Gary
do for a living, huh?
Have you done a
background check on him?
Gary is actually one
of the most successful
psychologists in
all of Manhattan, Ron.
Really sweet.
Are you reading my mind right now?
Ron, do you even know
what a psychologist is?
(QUIETLY) Fuck you.
(GASPS) Ron!
GARY: It's okay.
VERONICA: You stop that!
He's externalizing.
That's okay.
No, it's not okay.
He's mad.
You knew I was going
to throw that punch
'cause you're reading my mind!
(DOOR OPENS)
Mom! I'm home!
Hey, little guy.
Hey, darling.
Hi, Walter.
Hey, Dad.
I missed you!
Walter, your father
has a gift for you.
I have a gift specifically
for you, Walter.
There you go.
Yes, Gary.
Okay, that's actually
for me, Walter.
No, it's not.
It's for Walter.
It's a superhero costume.
What is it?
It's "Lace Man."
It's a brand new superhero.
I'm going to be Lace Man!
Look, Ron.
Joint custody isn't easy.
But what we need to do is
rally around this little
guy right now, okay?
That's never gonna happen.
Oh...
Excuse me?
RON: Because you, Veronica,
are unfit to be a mother!
VERONICA: Need I remind you
that you took that
child to a cock fight?
I'm Lace Man!
The game of champions!
He had the time of his life!
He came home splattered in blood!
He picked eight winning cocks.
It's never been done!
You have never tried
to connect with Walter.
(IMITATES GUN FIRING)
All right, let's keep it
civil in front of the boy.
It's bad enough his mother
likes to go down on rodeo clowns.
Okay, you know what, out!
All right.
Get your things! Let's go.
Fine. I'm out of here.
Don't have to tell me twice.
Get your things.
We'll see you guys later.
Yes, you will.
Goodbye, Dad!
Thanks for the present.
Goodbye, Walter, my little man.
You promise to do
good in school, okay?
Okay.
And stay away from the he-shes
Ron!
Down in the Bowery.
Ron, I don't think
that's appropriate.
I'll tell you, those fellas,
they got the looks,
they got the curves,
they got the chi-chi's,
and then at some point
during the evening,
you reach down below the belt
looking to get
a little muffellita,
and you get a handful
of the Battle of the Bulge.
You hear what I'm saying, Walter?
Yes, I do.
Ron, it was nice meeting you.
I think it's time for you to go.
Oh, Ron!
You knew!
You anticipated that because
you're reading my mind!
That confirms it!
(SIGHS)
There's Lime!
Look at him.
He's a goddamn prince!
Man, there's just something
about him, you know?
I'd give anything
to be friends with him.
I don't see what the
big deal is, you know.
He's not that great.
What did you say?
What's that?
I heard you say something.
Oh.
Oh, what did I say?
Oh, nothing.
Oh, no. I heard
you say something.
He said you're not that great!
Brick!
Is that what you said about me?
He's coming over here.
I know!
I'm gonna rip this guy in half.
No, no, no!
Just give me a little piece of him.
Uh, Jack, look, it's just...
The guys look up to
you so much, and
I just was a little jealous.
I just said some junk.
That's funny.
Aren't you the guy who
lost his job to his wife?
ALL: Ooh!
Shouldn't you be
doing her makeup?
(SCREAMING)
All right, guys, that's enough.
No, shut up, Freddie!
And you can shut your
mouth, okay, Jack "Lame!"
Ooh.
ALL: Ooh!
Yeah. Mr. Butt-Vagina's
got some fight in him.
You listen to this one,
big fella.
Yeah.
I bet you that we beat
your ratings tonight.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I'm sorry. I'm trying
to keep it together.
No, no, no.
Don't do this. Don't do this.
You're on at 2:00 a.m.
Jack has prime time!
Maybe... No.
Hey, Freddie, no, no. Hey.
I'll take that bet.
What are the stakes?
If we lose, I'll leave New York.
And I'll never
read the news again.
And if by some snowball's
chance in hell
Mr. Mustache here
pulls a miracle out of his ass?
(SCOFFS)
You change your name
to Jack Lame! Legally.
(CHUCKLES) I like this!
You're on, Stretch.
Everyone heard him?
Freddie, you heard him?
Yeah. I heard him.
This is on like Pong.
RON: Okay. Good.
(CROWD WHOOPING)
Why? Why did you
make that bet, Ron?
We've got the graveyard shift!
We don't have a chance!
Hey, guy!
Ah!
This ain't local news anymore.
We shit standing up here.
What?
It's a huge mess,
but damn, is it cool!
LINDA: All right, everyone!
Ladies and gentlemen,
today wouldn't be possible
without the visionary behind GNN.
Mr. Kench Allenby!
Yeah, yeah!
Thank you.
All right, cheer.
(SPEAKS INCOHERENTLY)
I am jabbered, just jabbered,
full of beans, no doubt.
Does anyone else
speak Australian?
I thought they talked like us.
Can I get you to say
with me, haw-ba-ya-ya!
(SCREAMING INDISTINCTLY)
We can't quite understand you.
How's this?
I'm Kench Allenby.
Oh, yes. That's good.
There we go!
Thank you so much.
I'm Kench Allenby
and you all know my story.
I'm a self-made man.
My late, great father,
Vadge Allenby,
gave me 300 million dollars,
and I toiled my whole bloody life
to turn that into
305 million dollars.
True story. True story.
Wow.
But this is 24-hour
news station...
This is history.
This is like Columbus
discovering the New World.
And the captain
of this fantastic voyage is
the best newsman in America,
Mr. Jack Lime!
Go get 'em, Jack!
Go get 'em!
Thank you. And good luck
to Ron Burgundy, too.
Ooh. (CHUCKLES)
Getting nervous there, compadre?
Let's do this.
Did you see that? How he spun
on that desk? So great.
All right. Quiet on
the floor, please.
All right.
All right. We're up.
Here we go, here we go.
In five, four,
three, two...
JACK: Good day,
and welcome to GNN.
Thank you for joining us
on what we believe to be
a whole new era of news.
I'm Jack Lime, your guide
for this journey of events
we humbly call
24-hour news.
Today's top story,
Mount St. Helens.
Oh, this is just a gimmick.
It's a flash in the pan.
We better hope so.
Residents are being asked
to evacuate the area...
Twenty-four hours
of news.
How are they gonna keep
coming up with this stuff?
My guess is they'll
probably be scraping
the bottom of the barrel.
No, I have a feeling they'll
stick with their integrity
and only report the news
that needs to be reported.
Let's see here.
"Global temperatures
rise half a degree,
"alarm climate
scientists." Boring.
"China could dominate the world
economy in the next decade."
♪ Dun-dun-dun-dun-
dun-dun, dun-dun ♪
Nope.
Anyone else?
What if we show a porno
instead of the news?
Freddie?
No. Absolutely not.
I know. What if we get one
of those wildlife handlers?
We have him bring in,
oh, big game cats.
You know, wild, dangerous tigers and
lions and leopards and the such.
We let them loose inside the studio
with about a dozen chickens.
We play rock music.
And we just call it Let Her Rip.
I'd watch that.
Let Her Rip?
You're describing the end of civilization.
That's not news!
If that's the end
of times, I'm...
I got a front-row seat with a
big tub of buttered popcorn
and a greasy
half-live chicken leg.
Okay, so obviously this is
a waste of time. I'm done.
Freddie! Come on!
We're just brainstorming here.
We're trying to figure out how
to make the news less boring,
and you act like we peed
in your milkshake.
The news is supposed
to be boring, Ron!
This is serious stuff.
You're the one that
made this stupid bet!
I just don't know why we
have to tell the people
what they need to hear.
Why can't we just tell them
what they want to hear?
Wait, wait, wait.
Say that again.
I said, why do we have
to tell the people
what they need to hear?
Why can't we just tell them
what they want to hear?
And what do they
want to hear, Ron?
That we live in the greatest
country God ever created.
Damn straight!
Made him happy.
And we should
do stories on patriots.
Cute, funny little
animals, huh? Or diets.
Why blondes have more fun.
And serious investigative pieces,
about how much ejaculate
is on hotel duvets.
And only the best
sports highlights.
Home runs, slam dunks,
touchdowns and no soccer.
I like the wind!
Brick's right.
People love hurricanes.
Tornadoes, earthquakes, floods,
we'll throw Brick
right in the middle of it.
You'd do that?
People'll go nuts.
I'd watch that!
No, this goes against every rule
of broadcast journalism I know.
Freddie, as the
wise man once said,
"So?"
We got 10 hours till we go on.
We'll only need eight!
♪ Lady
♪ I'm your knight
in shining armor
♪ And I love you
♪ You have made me what I am
♪ And I am yours
(IMITATES SLURPING COFFEE)
♪ My love...
Is that candy?
I don't know.
(COUGHS)
It is candy.
I like you.
Tell me something about you.
Well, I'm 19 years old.
My middle name is Courtney.
I can always guess
how many jelly beans
are in a jelly bean jar,
even if it's not right.
What about you?
My name is Chani Lastname.
I'm a real go-getter
and a person people.
I can type 50 words a minute
with only 300 errors.
I'm trained and certified...
BOTH: To fire a military-grade
missile launcher.
Me, too.
Chani, I just got these phone
messages from last week.
You mailed them to me?
How else was I gonna
get them to you?
You hand them to me.
Oh.
You are the dumbest person
I've met in my entire life,
and that's not an exaggeration.
That makes me feel bad.
Well, it's the truth, Chani.
(GROWLING) You!
Leave her alone!
BOSS: Excuse me, sir.
Get your filthy hands off of her!
(SCREAMS)
Help, help!
Excuse me, sir!
Leave me alone, lady!
Excuse me!
She is a goddess among women!
(SHOUTING INCOHERENTLY)
Glen!
(ROARS)
My phone messages!
Leave him alone!
Not today!
She has butterflies in her heart!
Chani! I can see you behind
that desk, and you're fired!
Why?
(HISSES)
Are you okay?
You saved my life.
She was trying to set me on fire.
I didn't ask for these powers.
I was given them.
Last night
a bird chased me,
and I wished it was you.
Can we go to a date?
(CLEARS THROAT) Yes.
(BOTH WHIMPER)
Dear God, please help
me pull this off.
I swear, if you help me, I will...
I will become a monk.
I will shave my head
and become a monk...
Ah, who are we kidding?
I'm not going to do that.
Oh, did you hear?
Evan said there's some strange
copy in the prompter.
(SIGHS)
It's 2:00 a.m.
It's Freddie Shapp's ass,
not mine. Let's go.
NARRATOR: People who change history
are rarely aware of it
while doing so.
Ron and his news team
simply thought
they were making
the news more fun.
Little did they know
they were changing
the course of broadcast
history forever.
Hello, America.
It's 2:00 a.m. Eastern time.
I'm Ron Burgundy,
and tonight's top story is
America.
She's the greatest
country in the world.
Heck, the history of the world!
You're damn right!
(ALL WHOOPING)
Too much of the news is about
what's wrong with America.
Amen, brother!
Well, tonight, our top story
is what's right with America.
Someone's finally
talking sense on the TV.
For starters, we kick butt.
Nazi butt.
Russian butt.
What the hell is he doing?
He's talking about America.
Why, do you have
a problem with that?
Tonight I begin part one
of my 11-part series
on the power and mystery
of the human vagina.
This series will be
a tasteful look
at just what makes a vagina tick,
as well as a look
at the 50 greatest vaginas
of the 20th century.
Son of a bitch!
(GLASS SHATTERS)
RON: One final question,
and I'll let you go.
Who tops the list of the
top 50 greatest vaginas?
Well, I don't want
to give anything away.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I thought I had you.
I will give you number two.
Please.
Madame Curie.
Of course. Of course.
Whammy! Whammy!
Whammy! Whammy! Whammy!
(REPEATING) Whammy!
Whammy!
Back to you, Ron.
The wind is really windy.
Brick? Brick,
can you hear me?
I can't hear you, Ron!
Okay, but you're
answering the question,
so I think you can hear me.
No, I can!
Brick, do you think
there is any danger
to the average person out there?
I'm afraid for the animals
of New York, Ron.
I saw a woman, and her dog
never touched the ground.
You're saying wind gusts as
fast as a supersonic jet?
It looked like she was
walking a dog balloon.
And go... Switch.
And for our eighth and final
animal story of the night,
it looks like residents
of North Yulk, Montana,
have found the
cutest little patriot
on God's green earth.
(RON LAUGHING)
Look at that little guy!
Oh, wow, he was having some fun.
Well, for all of us here at GNN,
I'm Ron Burgundy.
And don't just
have a great night,
have an American night.
FREDDIE: And we're out!
Wow! (LAUGHS)
I couldn't take my eyes
off the screen!
Yes.
You were electric,
Ron! Whammy!
That just felt right!
That felt right!
I was outside!
You sure were, Brick.
Wonderful job.
BRIAN: Amazing. Great job.
What the hell was that?
Hey, hey, hey.
Take it easy, Linda.
We were just
trying something new.
You changed the format
of the entire show
without consulting me?
That's unacceptable!
Damn straight, sister.
We just done went and brought it!
And here's the truth.
You can't handle it, little mama!
Get out! You are all
terminated immediately.
If you were a man,
I'd knock you out.
Oh. Oh, really?
Well, go ahead!
Take a swing!
Take your best shot!
I have five brothers,
and two of them are defensive
backs in the NFL, so come on!
You want me to do it?
Yeah.
This thing's not gonna feel good.
Do it, Ron.
Just do it.
Are you scared?
What's the problem?
Is he a chicken?
Are you a chicken?
(LINDA CLUCKING)
(LAUGHING)
I'm not a chicken at all.
I'm going to make that
mustache of yours all bloody.
(CHUCKLES)
Well...
Seems like you're
buying time, Ron.
I'm not buying time.
Ron! Just do what men
have been doing
for thousands of years,
and punch the woman.
Punch her!
You're stalling.
Punch the woman!
Here comes the Toledo Express.
All aboard!
(GRUNTING)
Ron! No!
I didn't do it!
(SQUEALING)
Mama, your baby's hurt.
Your baby.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIMPERING)
What is that sound
you're making? Good Lord!
(CONTINUES WHIMPERING)
BRIAN: You sound
like a balloon.
Pull yourself together, man.
Security!
They saw my pee-pee.
The eighth grade boys
saw my pee-pee!
Did you say they
saw your pee-pee?
RON: In the locker room,
they saw my pee-pee.
You just knocked him
back into fifth grade.
Get him out of here!
KENCH: Bugger me
with a didgeridoo.
We knew we'd struggle to start,
but these ratings are lower
than I'd even imagined.
AD SALES GUY: Thank God
for the 2:00 a.m. spike.
It really saved our whole launch.
Spike? What are
you talking about?
What spike?
Burgundy.
Who's Ron Burgundy?
No, no, no, this can't be right.
His team start at a .2,
and then they
finish at a 5.6?
That's unbelievable!
They tripled Jack Lime's numbers!
How is that even possible?
(LAUGHS) Who are these guys?
They're a local team
out of San Diego.
You little beauty!
Well, they no longer work for us.
I fired them.
Well, guys,
it goes without saying
I owe you gentlemen an apology.
I dragged you out here
and this thing
was a disaster
from the word "go."
No, Ron, don't you
beat yourself up.
Yeah, it's all right, Ron.
Gin.
Brian, any idea
what you might do next?
BRIAN: Gonna head back to L.A.
I got a good group
of buddies out there.
O.J. Simpson.
Phil Spector.
Robert Blake.
Sounds like a fun crew.
We go out cruising chicks.
Call ourselves
the "Ladykillers."
I love that name.
You should get it on the
back of matching jackets.
(LAUGHS) That's not a bad idea.
(BARKING)
Uh, guys?
Hey.
I got some news.
Freddie, we don't
exactly want to hear
the word "news" right now.
(SCOFFS) Yeah.
You're right. Forget it.
Forget I was even here.
Forget that GNN wants you back.
For a prime time slot
and a raise in pay.
Quit yanking our penises,
Freddie! What's the deal?
Yeah! Quit yanking
our anuses.
No. I'm not yanking your...
Your ratings went
through the roof.
People love what you did.
You're a success!
Get it? You're a great,
big, fat success!
By the bed pan of Gene Rayburn!
It's total crap
and they can't stop watching!
(ALL CHEERING)
NARRATOR: The news team
had been famous in San Diego,
but that was small time
compared to New York.
This fame was a rocket ship.
A rocket ship
that had free drinks
and topless stewardesses.
That'll do it for all
of us here at GNN.
Thank God for the events,
thank me for the news.
I'm Jack...
...Lame.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
More graphics, all right?
But there's already a lot.
Hey, you heard the man.
More graphics.
Let a citizen ask a question
here, for God's sake!
Can Father Ron please shut
his mouth for half a second?
(ALL ARGUING)
This is against everything
that I have worked
for my entire life.
Oh, honey, come on.
(DISCO MUSIC PLAYING)
If you're like me,
you need an underwear
that fits your active lifestyle.
ANNOUNCER: At finer specialty
and department stores.
I'm weatherman Brick
Tamland, and I like butter.
Butter is nutritious
and it tastes great.
(YELLING) Butter!
There's something new
on the New York social scene.
It's fun, relatively benign
and costs about as much
as a soda pop
at the local drugstore.
Here's Brian Fantana
on why everyone who is someone
is lighting up to smoke crack.
Now, Brian, I understand
we have some crack
and we're going to smoke it
right here in the studio.
I don't know if we can
get a shot of that.
What is that?
Did you know they were gonna have that?
No.
Now, what you're gonna do is, you're
gonna put your rock in the pipe.
Is that where the phrase "Put it in
your pipe and smoke it" comes from?
I don't care.
I love it when you do
cooking segments.
Oh! Oh, whoa!
You feel that right away.
Wow, that's good. That's good. That's
an immediate state of euphoria.
You'll be surprised.
The effect, it happens very... Ohh!
It's just refreshing.
They're actually enjoying it.
Of course they're
enjoying it. It's crack.
RON: Well,
now we know, guys,
you can't smoke crack
on live television.
(ALL CHEERING)
Hey, gang.
You know what would make
this great day even better?
What?
Perms for everyone!
ALL: Yay!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Please come in and shut the door.
If this is about sweeps, um,
I think Brian Fantana
found an outstanding story.
It's about airplane parts
that are falling off of
airplanes out of the sky
and hitting the ground, people.
We're calling it "Death From Above."
We might do some...
You. Come here.
I've been watching you.
You have?
(CHUCKLES)
I've been watching you a lot.
And you just do
whatever you want.
(CHUCKLES) Well, I'm a bit
of a maverick, I guess.
You don't follow the format.
You pretty much
walk around like...
Like you're king of the world.
I'm just a worker bee.
That's all I am.
You know what?
What?
Oh!
I find it hot as shit!
Are you going to hurt me?
Here's the thing,
Mr. Burgundy.
You're a shooting star and
I want to go for a ride.
God, I'm so afraid right now.
Now, I want to hear
you meow like a cat.
(MEOWS)
(SNARLING)
(MEOWS WEAKLY)
Now, I want you
to bark like a dog.
Bark. Bark. Bark!
(BARKING)
Like a puppy.
(BARKS SOFTLY)
(BARKING)
(MEOWING)
(BOTH GROWLING)
Yeah. Come on! Do it!
(SOBBING) Mmm.
Aw.
Don't cry.
(BARKING)
It's sexual and yet frightening.
It's an odd mixture.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Um, come in.
Uh, Linda.
Excuse me, Linda.
Ron, Jack wants to know
if he can go back to
calling himself Jack Lime
instead of Jack Lame.
He's really struggling with it.
No. Can't.
It's a bet.
Oh, Jesus!
If you want to
change it, you can.
Like what?
Art Areola.
No! No, that's worse!
You know it's worse!
How about this one?
You can call yourself Dick Fuck.
Spell it P-H-U-C.
You'll be huge
in the Vietnamese community.
Freddie, I can't.
Listen to me, Burgundy. This is
far from over, do you hear me?
I'll see you on the playground.
Well.
This, uh,
meeting has been
very productive.
You can pick
me up at 8:00.
Okay, I'm very confused
by what's going on here.
Get out!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, Ron. Ron, you are missing
some real high-quality
Garfield laughs over here!
I think our boss just raped me.
What?
I don't know what happened.
All a bit of a blur.
There was hands
and hair, and breath, and lips.
There might have been other
people, I don't know.
Sounds like she wants you.
Hey, man. Women have
been all over me
since we got crazy famous.
Not to brag or anything,
but I just gave
Florence Henderson crabs.
That is in no way a brag,
Brian. That's horrible.
Hey, it's just doing something
beautiful, that two people do.
Except one of them has
microscopic dust mites
all over his penis and testicles.
RON: I'm just saying,
the mom of The Brady Bunch
had a fun time with you,
and then woke up the next day
and realized she had crabs.
I gave her a whole
Brady Bunch of crabs.
(LAUGHS) Sounds to me
like it's her fault
for being a randy gal.
I have a date!
Brick has a date?
Good for Brick!
What's a date?
A date is simply when two
people get together,
do something social,
have a few drinks,
yadda-yadda-yadda...
Take their shirts off...
(GROWLS)
Oh, it's okay.
RON: No, it's a fun thing.
It's fun.
It's all right.
Look. Don't worry, Brick,
we got your back, okay?
First things first, we need to
get you a little protection.
RON: Oh!
There it is.
Brian Fantana's glorious
cabinet of condoms.
Oh, Brian, I know.
How about The Hooded Guest?
I like the cut of your jib.
RON: That one
is ultra-ribbed.
It's like you're wearing an
armadillo shell on your privates.
It takes two hours to get on.
It's hooded.
She'll never see you coming.
Oh, oh. Wait, wait, wait.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
"Lou Dobin's
Good Time Weiner Pouch."
That's a good one.
Dobin. Just a drifter who loves
to watch people have sex.
They're made of denim,
so they look better
after each washing.
Talk about a great ride.
BRIAN: I think I have it.
Po' Boy Condom.
It's a terrific condom.
Although it does burn a bit because
it's covered in Cajun spices.
It'll put a blister
on your po' boy.
Brian, what's the nickname for your
penis whenever you wear a Po' Boy?
Fat Tuesday.
Wait a minute.
I've got it.
"The Rigid Ghost."
RON: Mmm.
Ah, it's the best damn
rubber on the market.
Hah, I got four of my seven illegitimate
children using this condom.
Uh, but, Brian, isn't that the
whole point of wearing a condom?
To not impregnate the woman?
Well, you know the old
expression. "Nope."
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Thank you, Ron,
and happy St. Patrick's Day
to all of our
Native American friends.
On the big map...
Where's my map?
There's no map, it's just green.
No, there's a map there.
Look at the monitor.
Right. Oh.
(WHIMPERS)
Ron, where's my legs?
Where are my legs?
Your legs are there.
I don't have any legs, Ron.
I don't even know
how I'm standing up.
Brick, your legs are fine.
The color of your pants
just matches...
Ron, I don't have any legs!
(SOBBING)
The Chroma-Key behind you.
Ninety-three?
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
Relax.
(SCREAMING)
And after I received my Masters
in Journalism from Columbia,
I got a job with the London
bureau for ABC News.
Wow, London.
You're so impressive, and I've...
I've only been out of
the United States twice.
A handful of times
in Mexico, and then
the second time
I left the country,
we went to Salem, Oregon.
Mr. Burgundy,
are you nervous?
God, yes.
Did I scare you
by coming on so strong?
A little bit, sure.
Look, it's not that
you're not attractive...
It's just I'm a little
old-fashioned.
Well, I am a modern woman.
Mmm.
And let me tell you,
when I see something
that I want, I go for it.
Can I ask you a question?
Mmm-hmm.
Is that your foot
between my legs?
No.
Oh. I'm sorry.
It was my hand.
So...
We're going to do this,
aren't we?
We most definitely
are gonna do this.
I feel a little awkward,
because I'm...
(LOUDLY) I'm about to have
sex with a black lady!
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
I'm sorry! I'm sorry.
That's not the way I like
to handle my business.
When I get nervous,
I sometimes lose control
of the volume of my voice.
Well, I don't mind,
because I am going
to have you tonight.
Then let's leave
(LOUDLY)
and go have interracial sex!
(WHISPERING) Sorry.
(R&B MUSIC PLAYING)
This is the nicest soda machine
anyone's ever taken me to.
The beauty of this
soda machine pales
in comparison to your beauty.
Can I ask you
a personal question?
I'm not sure
what that is, but yes.
Have you ever kissed anyone?
Do faces on the TV screen
and Planet of the Apes
action figures count?
Of course.
Then, yes. I have kissed
Angie Dickinson and Dr. Zaius.
I've only kissed people
in my dreams.
So, I've only kissed
a tiny dragon
and a woman
with her hair on fire.
I don't have a lot
of experience with kissing,
but I do know one thing...
Always get your teeth involved.
I think I'm ready to maybe
try that kiss thing now.
Hello, Ms. Jackson.
I didn't mean to scare you.
Mr. Allenby, I wasn't
expecting you to...
Yeah, no, I know.
Neither was I.
But then I heard
about this little story
that Ron Burgundy and
Brian Fantana are running.
You see, some of the
planes from my airline
have had parts
falling off them lately.
Is it a problem? Yeah.
Is it being fixed?
I don't know, probably.
But if that story runs,
then Koala stock will plummet.
We can't just pull the story.
That would be unethical.
We own the news.
We can do whatever we want.
That's one of the perks.
It's called "synergy."
One company working with another.
To synergy.
You seem a little quiet,
I must say.
Just so you know,
I'm absolutely fine
with going to this family dinner.
They're going to love you.
Mmm. This is delicious!
So...
How long have you
and Linda been dating?
Mother.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh.
No, it's all right.
It's a logical question.
Um...
Ours is a new love,
but it burns very brightly.
And it gets hot
and sweaty and stanky.
There's some stank on that love.
What... What are you
talking about?
Let's put it this way, I be
busting nuts like a squirrel.
Oh, now, we don't have conversations
like that over dinner.
(WHISPERING) What are you doing?
I'm addressing the white
elephant in the room.
I'm breaking down the barriers
of race by assimilation.
That's all I'm doing.
Well, you're coming off like a jerk.
I think it's going well.
LINDA'S FATHER: (CLEARS THROAT)
If you haven't noticed,
we don't converse like that.
Okay, okay.
Look at big papa down here.
He's saying to himself,
"Shit! Look at this honky.
"Sittin' at my table, eatin' my food.
In my house? Touching my daughter?"
I have.
I have touched your daughter.
LINDA: Honey!
We have done things, Papa.
You ain't gonna like.
You ain't gonna like it none!
Oh, my goodness!
I mean, I'm just a guy
from Terre Haute, Indiana
with a big ol' dick and a fat wallet
and a spleef the size of a baby arm.
Just looking for someone
who wants to smoke it.
Let's get some smoke
going in this place, right?
This ain't no Super Fly.
What is your problem, man?
Linda, I don't understand
what you are doing with him.
Oh, you know what
I'm comin' at you with,
you big black mother of Linda.
Mix it up in a pot!
Makin' it spicy!
Oh, my Lord.
Hey.
In the back, cooking up chitlins.
Big ol' titties.
Excuse me?
That's my mama, man.
RON: Hey.
Wave your hands in the air.
Wave your hands in the air
like you just don't care.
Please, don't do this.
Now, which one of you
pipe-hittin' bitches
can pass me the mashed potatoes?
(ALL GASPING)
RON: Oh, I don't think that
dinner could've gone any better.
LINDA: (YELLING)
Are you nuts?
No, I'm not!
I had a wonderful evening!
My dad was kicking you
in the head!
I thought it was like
being jumped into a gang.
Only with dinner guests!
You called my family
"pipe-hittin' bitches!"
I hate to pin it on you, but
you did invite me to dinner.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
I just...
I'm just under
a lot of stress because...
Because Allenby, he
doesn't want you to do
the story that
you're doing for sweeps.
"Death From Above."
It's an excellent story.
Wonderful expose.
Listen, Ron.
Have you ever heard of synergy?
So your mom thought
we should get together,
spend a little time.
She doesn't think I connect
with you as a child.
Can you believe that bullshit?
(SCOFFS)
Oh! This is hard.
Things you say
to a 6-year-old...
Oh! Guess what?
I slept with a black woman.
What?
Nothing.
Dad, do you like Spider-Man?
Nope. Don't care for him.
Never have.
Don't like the mask, the costume,
the get-up, the webs.
He comes off like a real dickhead.
Real poser.
What's a poser?
A poser is Gary.
That's what a poser is.
By the way, how is that shitheel?
What's a shitheel?
A shitheel is a real fun term
that you should call Gary
every time you see him.
When he wakes you up for breakfast,
say, "Good morning, shitheel."
He'll probably give you
$5 or some candy.
Does that sound good?
Yeah.
You're a shitheel, Dad.
(LAUGHS) Good.
You should just call Gary that.
'Cause it makes him really happy.
It makes me sort of happy,
but it makes him really happy.
Dad.
Huh?
Sometimes I hear sounds at night
and I get scared.
I think there's
a ghost in my closet.
Now, you listen to me, son.
There is no such thing
as ghosts. Case closed.
So what's real that's scary?
You really want to know
the one thing
you should be afraid of?
Yes, I really do.
Voodoo.
Voodoo?
Yes, voodoo.
That shit will mess you up.
And it is 100% real.
Promise me
that you'll never go to Haiti.
I promise, Dad.
This was good. I enjoyed
spending time with you.
Me, too, Dad.
Oh, and hey. Do you want
to go to Haiti sometime?
No.
Good. Good.
(YELLING) What did you tell him?
I didn't tell him anything.
He hasn't slept
for four days, Ron!
Everywhere we go, he asks
me if we're going to Haiti!
What does that even mean?
I am so sick and tired
that you've sheltered him
from the evils of voodoo.
You need to learn to connect
with him in a healthy way!
Let me ask you something, and I'm
not trying to be funny here.
Are you sure he's not a midget
with a learning disability?
He is seven years old, Ron.
All right.
Now listen to me.
He has a science fair
tomorrow, at 8:00,
and he wants you to be there.
I will be there.
All right?
Now, who do you have
for sweeps week?
I'm not discussing
work with you, Ron, okay?
Just be there
at the science fair tomorrow.
Fine!
Well, they're calling it
the interview of the decade.
Veronica Corningstone will
sit down with Yasser Arafat.
Yasser who?
The head of the PLO and some say
the key to peace
in the Middle East.
Of course, Ms. Corningstone is
the ex-wife of Ron Burgundy,
so you know that's got to be
a little stinger for Ronny.
Tony Danza's scrotum!
Well, that'll do it
for all of us here at GNN.
Thank God for the events,
thank me for the news.
I'm Dick Phuc.
We're going to get crushed
in ratings. Just crushed.
I really thought we had
a chance this time.
What about my
"Death From Above" story?
You better ask Ron about that.
We're pulling that story, Brian.
What? Why?
I worked hard on that story.
It was my call, all right, Brian?
Just let it go.
It's synergy.
What does that mean?
Take it easy, Ron.
We got further than anybody
thought we would.
We'll get 'em next time.
You take it easy!
I'm not in this to finish second!
I think Champ is just saying...
I know what he was trying
to say, Brian, okay?
And it doesn't surprise me
that you guys don't care.
Let's face it, I'm the one
who gets the ratings.
I'm starting to wonder
what you clowns actually do.
Chani likes clowns.
Except for the scary ones.
Shut up, Brick!
Just shut up for once!
(VOICE BREAKING) Ron
yelled at me.
You're damn right
I yelled at you!
You don't yell at Brick.
Are you still smoking crack?
No.
I only smoked crack
that one time.
That's a lie.
I've done it six more times.
You made Brick cry.
(SOBBING)
You've gone ratings crazy, Ron.
But seriously, do you have
any more of that crack left?
You know what, Ron?
We're a news team,
and that's a bond for life.
But I don't like
the man you've become.
You know, we were happy
when you found us.
Right?
I was taking pictures of pussies,
Champ was serving bats to
people, and Brick was dead.
We took a gamble.
Took a gamble to follow you here.
But I'm starting to realize,
this was all about you,
and beating Veronica
at all costs.
Had nothing to do with the news,
nothing to do with the team.
Brian, don't.
You know, I might not
be the smartest guy,
but I know a thing or two
about a thing or two.
I know that if you're
pleasuring a woman down south,
you use your tongue
to spell out the alphabet.
Around the bubble.
Around her bubble.
The vulva!
The Volvo.
I know that "synergy" is a
completely made-up word.
I know that washing
your hands is for nerds.
Especially if you
don't mind pinkeye.
And I know that, no matter what,
you always stand by your friends.
You'll have to excuse me, Brian.
I've got a sore back
from carrying your ass around
for the last 15 years.
You know what, Burgundy?
I think your mouth is writing
checks that your body isn't...
Can't even...
Do anything with.
(GROANS)
Fine, go!
I don't need you!
I'll do the news by myself!
Tonight I interview
Yasser Arafat,
This is terrible.
the secretive head
of the PLO.
We're on in 20, Ron. 20.
All right.
You ready?
What's that?
Huh?
Oh, that's nothing.
It's just a car chase
on the satellite feed
from Milwaukee.
You know what?
Give it to me live
to start the broadcast.
No. That's not news, Ron.
Give it to me live, okay?
And don't question me again.
Bill!
NARRATOR: Now to you,
the modern viewer,
MAN: Here we go.
reporting on a car chase
may seem commonplace,
3, 2...
but in 1980,
it was unheard of.
Good evening.
I'm Ron Burgundy,
reporting live from New York.
We have breaking news developing
in our nation's heartland.
A high-speed car chase
is in progress...
Keep the "Breaking News" logo.
Keep up the graphics.
Reaching speeds
of 100 miles per hour.
And for the first time
in news history,
we will stay with it live
until it resolves
in either a huge accident
or a massive shootout.
WOMAN: Richard!
Hurry. Get in here!
There's a car chase on the news!
WALTER: When is Dad
gonna be here?
GARY: He'll be here.
Are you a little upset?
Do you want to
do that thing where we
sort of talk about our feelings?
Oh, God, no.
Okay.
RON: This is the pulse
of what's going on
in our country right now.
Freddie, what's going on?
Why is there a local
car chase on the TV?
It's Burgundy. He insisted!
Can't you see what
the son of a bitch is doing?
We didn't have a story,
so he made one.
You can't do that!
Tell Ron to speculate
who's driving the car.
Ron, speculate
on who's driving the car.
Uh, we believe the driver
may be on drugs.
He's probably 6'7", 6'8".
But a skinny 6'7", 6'8".
About 160.
He may have a hostage or two.
Uh, we don't know.
He could have...
The phone lines are lighting up.
It's about the chase!
I've never seen anything like it!
Mr. Arafat,
is there any
scenario by which peace
could be reached with Israel?
ARAFAT: Peace is what burns in my heart.
I am committed to...
What was... Excuse me.
What happened to the...
The network cut to
another developing story.
Some kind of crazy car chase.
Who covers a car chase?
I am sitting here with the most important
interview of my entire career,
and they're cutting
to a car chase?
I would like to watch
the car chase.
You need to shut your mouth.
RON: This is
extremely gripping.
Oh! Oh! He just hit a car!
He just hit a car!
He hit a car!
Did you see that?
RON: Wow!
He hit the car!
When did the news get awesome?
(ALL WHOOPING)
RON: And he just
loses it! Wow!
That's exactly what we needed.
It was getting a little boring...
Hey. You did
a great job.
Thanks, Gary.
I don't think your dad's coming.
I'm sorry, honey,
but I think we need to go.
Stop reading my mind!
All right.
(SIGHS)
I mean, this is
what I worry about.
WALTER: Did you do that
with your mind?
GARY: No.
WALTER: Liar.
We're just getting word that police
have finally apprehended the suspect.
It turns out that
he is an elderly gentleman,
he's 80 years old,
and he was simply confused.
Unbelievable.
I'm Ron Burgundy.
Don't just have a great night,
have an American night.
And we are clear!
Yes!
Great!
All right!
I don't believe it!
You did it, Ron!
Oh, my goodness.
Thanks, Freddie.
I don't deserve this.
It was a team effort.
It really was.
KENCH: Now,
ladies and gentlemen,
we all know there's one reason
that GNN has gotten to the top.
And that reason is the greatest
bloody newsman in the world.
Long may he reign!
Mr. Ron Burgundy!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Yeah, Ron! Yeah!
(PLAYING LIVELY TUNE)
LINDA: Fire it up, Ronny!
(BAND PLAYING DISCO MUSIC)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Let's blaze.
Yeah. To hell
with Ron Burgundy.
We did it, my onyx hellion.
You're magic!
Ron, you should see
what you're doing!
(CONTINUE PLAYING DISCO MUSIC)
NARRATOR:
In the myth of Icarus,
Icarus, full of the folly
that comes with pride,
flew too high
and the sun melted his wings.
Burgundy's fame was bigger
than he ever imagined.
And the fall was dizzying.
(ALL GASPING)
(SCREAMS)
LINDA: Oh, my God, Ronny!
Ron!
Open the bloody gate.
WOMAN: Will somebody call an ambulance?
Do not die in front of us!
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Stay classy, Ron Burgundy.
MAN: Somebody
call an ambulance!
Damn it, Milton, what is it?
BRANGLEY: Well, Ron...
I, um...
It looks as if both optic nerves
are separated from
their respective corneas.
What?
No other way
to put this, but...
You're blind.
Milton, I'm an anchorman.
I read the news off the teleprompter.
It's what I do!
How will I live?
I'm no career counselor,
but there are
many things you can do.
Be an oracle, or a mystic.
Clearly, there must be something
in this new-fangled office
of yours that can help me!
Settle down.
There's got to be
something in here!
Settle down!
(SHOUTING)
Zombies! Zombies!
Ahh!
If you get my hands
on me, I'll kill you.
NARRATOR:
The world of the blind.
Ron Burgundy, a man who had
flourished in a visual medium,
had forever entered
this realm of darkness.
♪ Always lonely
♪ Always looking
♪ To get even with the men
who did him wrong
♪ That was Billy
(BARKING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Who is it?
Ron, it's us!
RON: I'm sure you gentlemen
are famished from your travels.
I hope you like Triscuits
and some pimento loaf.
Still hot off the griddle!
There we go.
Well, everyone at the station
really misses you, Ron.
Jack Lime's been filling in for
you since you've been gone.
You know, he's really not
such a bad guy after all.
Ha-ha.
He goes by Jack Lame now.
Well, he shouldn't be doing that.
He should be going by Jack Lame.
Brick!
Brick.
That's checkers and caulk.
Don't eat that.
What about Linda?
She hasn't called.
Linda's pretty busy.
Ron, I'm going
to need your recipe.
So, Ron, what do you do
with yourself all day?
You're just out here pretty
much away from everything.
Well, every day begins
about the same.
I wake up screaming in terror
because of the blackness
and I think I'm dead.
Every day?
Yes! Every day!
And then I begin what's called
The Great Adventure.
Making breakfast.
I've eaten everything
from nails to drink coasters.
One time I bit hard
into a marble ashtray,
thinking it was a savory waffle.
I wanted that waffle so bad!
Completely shattered my teeth.
Couldn't you tell the ashtray
wasn't hot like a waffle?
No! I couldn't!
Because I'm blind!
I'm not blind 23 hours a
day or 22 hours a day,
I'm blind the whole goddamn time!
Do you have any idea
what it's like
to drink a half a bottle
of ketchup
thinking it was a bottle of
1946 Chateauneuf-Du-Pape?
I even decanted it!
If you drank half a bottle
of that, that's like...
That's like nine or ten gulps.
I mean, you couldn't tell
that was ketchup?
Did I stutter?
I'm ba-lind!
You're having a tough
time, Ron, I know.
You know what
the biggest indignity is?
I can't even masturbate!
Why?
Heck, one morning,
I spent 20 minutes
aggressively rubbing my shin,
wondering, "Where's the sensation?
"Where's the pleasure coming?"
You rubbed your shin
thinking it was a penis?
I know you think
I'm stupid, don't you?
No!
RON: The weirdo
who lives in the weird lighthouse
in the middle of nowhere.
Ron, it was your choice to
live in a "weird lighthouse."
RON: You know why
I live here?
Let me say it
real slow and real loud.
I'm
bl-i-i-i-i-nd!
I guess we should
get out of here.
Maybe you should go. Yes.
Why don't you guys get out of here!
Despite my complete
and utter isolation,
your gentlemen's visit
has actually made it worse!
Goodbye, Ron.
What?
No, don't go!
(DOOR CLOSES)
Please! Wait!
I'm all alone! Come back!
Wait! Come back!
Come back!
(SOBBING)
I'm alone!
Why have you done this to me, God?
Why?
Couldn't you have cured a sick
child or created a new animal?
But, no, you had to
make Ron Burgundy blind!
(SOBBING)
VERONICA: Well, I never
thought that I would see
the Ron Burgundy full
of so much self-pity.
Who is it? What is that noise?
Take my hand.
I can't see it!
Reach for it, Ron!
You have to learn
to do for yourself now.
All right. This...
Okay. Here we go.
Get up. There we go.
Cher, is that you?
You can't recognize me
by my voice?
Jan-Michael Vincent?
Really?
Every news station is
copying what you did, Ron.
All the stories are about animals,
or car chases or strip clubs.
The genie has been
let out of the bottle,
and old Ron Burgundy
popped the cork.
That's why I quit WBC News.
What?
There's no real news
being reported out there.
It's just all about ratings.
Veronica.
Why are you here?
I'm here for our son, Ron.
Walter needs you.
I need you to start
taking responsibility
for him and for yourself.
Do you realize
you're talking to a man
who just this morning
tried to brush his teeth
with a live lobster?
What?
You would've known the second
that you touched it...
I'm just saying it's not
going to be a cakewalk.
Well, then we best get to it.
Now, drink your tea.
Oh!
(CUP SHATTERS)
Let me get a sponge.
I'll get it.
All right.
No, no, just stay there.
I'll have it
cleaned up in a jiffy.
Let's try this again.
Did you throw it?
Yes, I threw it.
Just remember the curves.
The curves.
The green eyes.
Green eyes.
You have to use
your other senses now!
I can't do it!
(BAXTER BARKING)
Baxter found something on the beach!
Ron, be careful!
(BARKING)
RON: It's okay!
Walter, what is it?
It's some kind of fish!
Oh, my goodness!
If he stays tangled in this net,
he's not going to survive.
Walter, sweetheart, it's a shark.
Son,
don't you worry, we won't
let this fellow die.
We'll do it together, Dad.
RON: That should keep him in
there until he's strong enough
to swim out to the deep ocean.
Can I name him?
Of course you can, son.
What about Crackers?
Give me a goddamned break.
Seriously, you've got one of the
most vicious predators in the ocean,
you're gonna name him "Crackers"?
In the future when you say I can name
something, don't be a dick about it.
Why don't we do this?
Let's name him Doby.
You talk all that smack and that's
the best name you come up with?
Well, we're not gonna get
any better than that.
I mean, you obviously can't name
him anything that sounds good.
How about we forget about this whole
name thing and you go straight to hell?
Well, I don't know what to do.
We might as well poison the
water and let him die.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Let's just go with Doby.
Fine, then it's settled.
It's Doby.
We'll call him Doby
even though no one likes it.
All right, I can live with that.
(BARKING)
(RON LAUGHS)
Don't worry, Baxter.
We won't feed him your dog food.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
NARRATOR: Even though Ron
Burgundy had lost his sight,
he had never seen so clearly.
(GASPS) You did it!
NARRATOR: And with every inch
Doby grew, so did Ron's heart.
It's just a bunch
of crazy lines, isn't it?
No. It's beautiful.
It's beautiful.
What about Gary?
We split up two weeks ago.
He was too emotionally stable.
It was so annoying!
NARRATOR: And so, just like
the passing of the seasons,
it came time for Doby to return
to the deep waters
he was meant to call home.
I hear his tail splashing!
He's actually swimming away!
Is he looking back for us
over his shoulder?
Sharks don't have shoulders, Ron.
No, he just swam away,
and he's instantly looking
for fish to eat.
He was my best friend.
♪ You
♪ Swam with strength
♪ Loved with grace
♪ You touched us all
♪ With your expressionless
♪ Face
♪ Doby, oh, Doby
♪ May you find many treasures
♪ Both emotional and monetary
♪ You were wise and loving
♪ and never contrary
♪ Doby
♪ Oh, Doby
♪ I'll never forget thee
CHORUS:
♪ Doby
♪ Oh, Doby
♪ I'll never forget thee
Promise you'll always
be there for me, Dad?
I promise.
If I say I'll be there for you,
there's nothing on God's earth
that will stop me.
I love you, Dad.
Let's get back up to
the lighthouse, all right?
Come on.
Okay.
Let's go.
I hope you eat lots of fish
and people, Doby.
Oh, there you are.
I found the most beautiful
clams down by the estuary.
I thought we could steam
them up tonight
with a nice butter sauce
and some wine.
(SIGHS)
Veronica.
Yes, Ron?
Can you explain this?
(BEEPS)
Ron, this is Dr. Brangley.
I've left dozens of messages.
Somehow, they must be
getting erased.
But there is a procedure
that can possibly
return your sight.
Please get back to me
if you're interested.
(BEEPS)
Well? Have you been
erasing these messages?
Yes. Ron,
just let me explain.
How could you?
We've never been this happy
and I just thought that...
Thought that
if I could see again,
that somehow I couldn't
love you and Walter anymore?
Yes!
(GROWLS)
Damn you, woman!
(YELLING)
(SCREAMS) You lied to me!
I gave you everything!
I gave you my heart,
my smile,
my seed.
And you lied to me.
WALTER: Dad!
Sweetheart.
No! Dad!
Don't leave, Dad!
Dad!
Walter, just...
Sweetheart, we have to let him go.
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
He needs to go free.
Just like Doby.
He'll be back.
He promised.
(CAR CRASHING)
RON: Could you please
call me a damn cab? I'm blind!
Of course!
BRANGLEY: Ron,
the operation was a success.
But we won't know for sure
until we remove the bandages.
Well?
Yes.
I can see.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, God, oh, God.
It's Ron Burgundy, everyone!
You are my inspiration.
Oh, well, thank you.
Welcome back, Ron.
Thanks. Thanks, Bri-man.
Good luck in Vietnam.
Brick.
Brick and I are having a baby!
We're gonna name him
Tortilla Jackson.
All right.
I'm 22 months pregnant.
KENCH: Well,
get over here, you bastard.
Got you a drink,
Ron. Come on.
Uh, hold on to that drink.
I just want to grab some air.
(SIGHS)
(DOOR OPENING)
(EXHALES)
How you doing there?
Oh.
I'm fine. Just, uh...
(CHUCKLES)
Just a lot of people in there.
Listen, Ron, I'm sorry that
I never called or visited.
There's no need to explain.
But, listen, I mean, you're back.
VERONICA: Hello, Ron.
What are you doing here?
I had to come tell you
something very important.
You must be Linda Jackson.
You must be Veronica.
Yes, I am.
It's a pleasure.
This is a touching moment for me.
Please, don't take this
the wrong way,
but if you touch Ron again,
I will shoot you in the
cooch with a B.B. gun.
Oh! Well, you can
talk big all you want,
but guess what, this
kitten's got claws, bitch.
(RON CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Don't mess with me, Linda,
because this "White Thunder"
rolls deep and it rolls nasty.
I was feeling a little bit down,
but this is definitely
picking up my mood.
Well, I guess I'll
leave you two alone.
And it's been an absolute
pleasure, Ms. Corningstone.
This has been great.
Do you guys want
to kiss real quick?
Ron. Read the room.
I'll take that as a no.
Bye, Linda.
I know why you haven't
been returning my messages.
I wasn't calling for me, I was calling
because Walter has a piano recital
in half an hour at the Tishman
School on 65th Street.
And he wrote
a piece for you, Ron.
Aw, Walter.
It would mean the absolute world
to him to have you there.
Ron, I just got a call
from the control room!
Oh, big fan.
Actress Sheila Blackledge,
the mom from the hit sitcom
Four's a Family, Five's a Crowd,
she just found out
her husband cheated on her
and she severed his penis
while he slept!
Oh, my goodness.
The police arrived.
She fled in her white Bronco,
and now they're engaged
in a high-speed car chase!
We've got an exclusive
on the live feed,
but we've got to go, right now!
Ron, this can be your comeback.
Veronica, I...
No, Ron. No.
That will get
sky-high ratings.
Walter will understand.
Go.
FREDDIE: Come on, Ron.
Priorities!
RON: Veronica!
Come on!
LINDA: Can you hear me?
Yes, yes, you're coming in loud and clear.
You're back
and you get this story.
This is gonna be huge.
Right.
So, is it good to be back home?
Um, yeah, I feel good.
God, look at him.
Like a beacon in the night!
(LAUGHING)
My golden goose.
LINDA: All right, baby.
So I'm just gonna be
giving you the details.
RON: Mmm-hmm.
Five, four,
three, two...
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Good evening, America.
After some time off,
it's good to be back with you.
I'm Ron Burgundy.
We have a story tonight
involving an affair,
a cut-off penis,
a TV star and a car chase.
And throw it to the feed.
The only problem is...
What's he doing?
Ron, are you okay?
It's not news.
What?
Turn off the prompter.
Ron, this is Kench.
What the hell do you think
you're doing, mate?
Just read what's in front of you,
or I will ruin you! Don't!
Don't! You leave
Kench inside your head!
God damn it!
He took out his earpiece.
You see, folks, I've read
a lot of news in my day,
but it's...
It's taken me until now
to realize what real news is.
Real news is supposed
to let people know
what the powerful are up to, so that,
that power doesn't become corrupt.
But what happens when
the powerful own the news?
Ugh! You piece of shit!
Shit. He's blowing
the whole thing up.
Recently, I've been on a
bit of a personal journey.
I made love to a proud,
intelligent black woman.
I became blind.
I bottle-fed
and raised a shark.
And I smoked
a fair amount of crack.
But the most important thing
I've learned is that
there was an emptiness left
after turning my back on three of the
best friends anyone could ever ask for.
Hi, Ron!
So, if you'll excuse me,
I'm going to see
my child's recital
and tell the woman I love
that I still love her.
Good night, America,
and never forget,
you deserve the truth.
Good. He's dead, done. Linda,
get the skirt in,
the blonde. Anyone!
He's coming back!
Oh, also, one other thing.
Koala Airlines
is a really shitty airline.
You son of a bitch!
Guys, I'm sorry.
For a while there, I don't know
what became of Ron Burgundy.
Brick, I'm sorry I yelled at you.
Brian, I...
No reason why I killed
that story of yours.
It was excellent reporting.
And, Champ, I'm sorry
I said no to all those
offers for late-night
deep-tissue rubdowns.
BRICK: Ron, you're a good man.
But you have fallen victim to
your own ego and your own hubris.
And before others
can forgive you,
you must learn
to forgive yourself.
What was that, Brick?
I'm wearing two pairs of pants.
Thank you.
So that's it, huh?
You're sorry?
You know what, Burgundy?
Apologies are like assholes.
Everyone's got one
and everyone's got a shoebox full
of Polaroids of them under the bed.
CHAMP: Ron, we're a team.
We need you.
Let him go, Champ.
(SOBBING)
Ron!
Long live Ron Burgundy!
I'm Brick Tamland for GNN News.
The itsy bitsy spider
went up the water spout.
You little hack!
Huh? Who the hell
do you think you are?
After everything
I've done for you,
this is how you repay me?
Well, I will crush you!
(GRUNTS)
Once again, Mr. Burgundy,
you are the ballsiest
white man I've ever known.
What the hell?
One more for old times' sake.
Thank you.
Is Dad going to come?
No, sweetheart,
Daddy has to work.
He's going to come.
I know it.
Taxi!
Taxi! Taxi!
Damn it!
It's so hard for a proud Mexican
to get a taxi in this city!
I need to see my son!
And now, to play an original composition
that he wrote for his father,
here is seven-year-old
Walter Burgundy.
(APPLAUSE)
I made a promise!
I made a promise to my son!
What the hell?
Well, hello, Ron.
You out for a jog?
Jack Lime!
Where's everyone going?
Please. I don't have
time to talk, okay?
I have to be somewhere.
Well, that's funny.
'Cause I got nowhere to be
because you pretty much
destroyed my career.
Do you realize what it did to me,
by making me
call myself Jack Lame?
It was a living hell!
(PANTING)
I'm telling you,
you have to let me go!
Oh, don't worry.
Four against one.
This will be over fast.
Maybe not so fast!
My news team. Thank God!
Ain't a day that will be
or has been
that we don't have
Ron Burgundy's back.
Not a problem.
When I'm done with these mutts,
I'm gonna wipe my shoes
on the curb.
Oh, yeah, Jack Lime?
When I'm done with you,
my mom's going to pick
me up and take me home.
BBC NEWS ANCHOR: Wait!
Here's a headline for you.
"Moronic Yank Wankerman
"Gets a Bloody Good Hiding
From News Reader
"From a Superior Country."
For we are the BBC News Service.
(ALL YELLING)
No. Not now.
Fall back, fall back.
If y'all are gonna get down,
then Wesley Jackson and
the MTV News crew want in.
What's MTV?
I think it's a venereal disease.
The most requested
video of the day?
A new band called Burgundy's
Sucking Chest Wound.
(ALL YELLING)
It wouldn't be a battle
without Jill Janson.
And Wendy Van Peele
from Entertainment News.
Entertainment news
is an abomination!
Who are you wearing today?
Oh, look, it's your own blood!
Today's celebrity birthdays...
None.
Today's celebrity deaths...
All you dick-licks.
I like the way
they're put together.
I like fighting girls.
I like to cunt punt cowboys.
You eat pussy?
You're gonna.
Hey!
There's not gonna be any
fight without Scott Riles
and the incredibly polite
Canadian News team.
(ALL YELLING)
What about the
French-speaking Quebec News?
The real voice of Canada!
Give it a rest, eh?
Give me a break!
They can't have news.
Nothing happens in Canada!
We're gonna mop
the floor with you!
We're gonna put the boots
to you! Sorry.
Sorry.
We're gonna gouge your eyes
out! And kick your head in!
BOTH: Sorry!
I like your ginger ale!
Jeff Bullington, ESPN,
all sports.
Tonight's play of the day is me,
extracting your spine
from your dead body.
Holy shit, there's a lot of news!
It's true, the market
is becoming saturated.
Hey. The History Network
wants in on this.
We're news, too.
Only news told much, much later.
(ALL YELLING)
Wait a minute. Is that the ghost
of Stonewall Jackson with you?
Yes, it is.
And the mighty Minotaur.
(GROWLS)
I don't know about this, man.
The Minotaur isn't even history!
He's mythology!
(ROARING)
Let's not downplay the fact
that that's the ghost
of Stonewall Jackson!
(ECHOING) May the Lord anoint
this hallowed field of battle.
You guys got room in this
battle for an old war horse?
Mack Tannen!
What are you doing here?
You're too old for this.
Well, you see, there's the thing.
When there's an early moon,
I almost feel
like a stallion again!
He's on our side, right, Ron?
(GROWLING)
He's a were-hyena!
I'm-a call Michael Jackson.
I got a video idea.
All right, everyone, listen up!
By virtue of being
on this battlefield,
there is no return.
People will die.
I'm so horny right now.
RON: Some will be disfigured.
In some cases, lasting
friendships will be made.
And as usual,
no touching of the hair and face.
Come on.
What do we look like, rookies?
BOTH: Sorry.
When El Trousias,
maiden of the clouds,
blows the battle horn,
let the battle begin!
I am El Trousias!
Hear my siren song!
(PLAYING)
El Trousias...
The Juicies'. Hmm.
That means you can start.
Brick, what the hell is that?
It's a gun from the future.
No fair! He's got
a gun from the future!
Where did you get it from?
(LAUGHING)
(PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC)
In the name of the King,
the Queen and St. George.
Huzzah!
(ALL YELLING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
Guess you didn't see that coming.
Twenty degrees right.
Fill that gap!
Fall upon your swords!
Life has no meaning!
(LAUGHS)
There will be a mint julep
waiting on the other side, son.
Release your soul to me.
(CONTINUES PLAYING
CLASSICAL MUSIC)
(CANNON FIRING)
(ROARING)
Sorry!
CANADIAN ANCHORS:
Sorry! Sorry!
BRIAN: Sex Panther
powers activate.
(GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
(ALL COUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
It's the ghost of
Stonewall Jackson!
Everyone, it's the ghost
of Stonewall Jackson!
Why do we have to fight?
There's so much
I could learn from you.
(GRUNTING)
In the name
of Margaret Thatcher...
No!
I sentence you to death!
RON: Please, no!
Oh!
What in the name of Dan Issel?
Gary!
Yes, Ron.
You and I never got along.
But using the power of my mind,
I was able to see in the future
that you would do good.
Now, go.
RON: I knew it!
Go to your son's recital.
I knew you had mind powers!
And make it the greatest
day of your life!
Almighty, Almighty,
light the fuse on my call.
Thirty-niner-niner-14,
cook these fools.
I repeat, cook these fools.
We've got to get out of here.
There's too much news!
Man, what a rush!
The monster's my friend!
Ron, we can still
make your kid's recital!
(LAUGHS) Hey, Ronny.
Jack Lime, please, I just want
to get to my son's recital.
No! That is
out of the question!
We're outnumbered, Ron.
Foam the runway,
I'm coming in hot!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
♪ Old MacDonald had a farm
And then four guys
on bikes showed up.
Wes Mantooth and the
Channel Nine news team!
Hey, what the hell
are you guys doing here?
This is a national news fight.
You made one mistake today.
You messed with somebody
from San Diego.
It's actually
pronounced San Diago.
Hell, Ron and I
may not agree on everything,
but we share the bond of being
from the greatest city
in the history of this Earth.
(LAUGHING)
Well, ain't that cute?
But you're outnumbered
three-to-one.
Why don't you
go back to your mama?
Don't you use
my mom's name in vain.
Dorothy Mantooth was
a hard-working single woman
who raised
seven children on her own
and she remained sexually
active till the day she died.
She brought pole dancing
into the mainstream.
Now here's the thing.
While I've been talking,
my news team has emptied
their gas tanks at your feet.
I drop this smoke and
every one of you goes "poof."
Well, you forgot
one thing, leatherman.
You drop that smoke,
you die, too.
(LAUGHING)
With the things
I've done in my life,
oh, I know I'm going
to burn in hell.
So I sure as shit ain't
afraid to burn here on Earth.
Oh, my goodness!
That's the most badass
thing I have ever heard.
All right!
Looks like this fight's over.
(SIGHS)
Let's go, boys.
Yay! We won!
Let's celebrate!
Sparklers!
No, no, no, no, Brick!
ALL: No!
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC ENDS)
(ALL APPLAUDING)
Bravo! Bravo.
Yeah. Whoo!
Dad!
Son, I fought
a Minotaur to be here.
And I'd do it again.
Dad! Together
we can defeat voodoo!
NARRATOR: Ron had finally
learned how to love his son
and his wife
more than his career.
And as it turned out,
his walking off the news
was the highest-rated
TV event of the year.
He and his news team,
along with Veronica,
could have any job they wanted.
But before that, they had one
little thing to take care of.
And now, before I join this
couple in holy matrimony,
Brick and Chani
ask us to join them
as they exchange their vows.
My dearest Brick.
Everything I have is yours.
My four lawnmowers.
My sister.
My 35 ferrets.
My massive student loan
and real estate debt.
It's all yours.
Oh, Chani.
I will never forget
the exact moment I saw you.
My pee-pee got all uncomfortable
in my pants, and I thought,
"Here comes the warm milkshake out
of the tip of my belly stick."
Wait! Look!
Walter, Walter, honey, shh!
Look in the water!
It's Doby!
Oh, my God.
It's Doby! Doby!
VERONICA: Ron, what are you doing?
He's not your friend!
Doby!
CHAMP: Ron! That's a shark!
VERONICA: He will eat you!
♪ Old friends
Doby!
♪ Sat on their park bench
like bookends ♪
Oh, my God!
The shark actually
recognizes him!
(SCREAMING)
BRIAN: Nope. He's
viciously attacking him.
Doby! Doby, it's me! Ron!
NARRATOR: If a man dies
with love in his heart,
does he truly die?
Absolutely!
But on this day,
Ron Burgundy's grapple
with this denizen from the deep
was halted by 28 pounds
of furry providence.
(BARKING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
RON: I bottle-fed you!
(SCREAMS)
Baxter!
(GASPING)
(BARKING)
Baxter!
Baxter! Ah, yes!
(LAUGHING)
(BARKING)
I know, I know, I love you, too.
(PANTING)
Oh. Come on.
(CROWD APPLAUDS)
(CROWD CHEERING)
All right, let's do it.
You guys think...
I don't know
how to use a computer.
Hey, fellas. I just saw
Jack Lime out there.
He's a goddamn iceman.
Scared the crap out of me.