Translation by mattrew
mod_forumcity@hotmail.com
Let's some, its not have many people come in,
I would like to do ... is anybody like to do it in here.
Could everybody split?
As I like to be here. Thanks
- Maybe we can keep ...
- And close the door
- Keep people away from the door ...
- lock it is no good?
Yep Thank you
"And Never Have I Felt so Deeply
at One And the Same Time"
(Next page)
"So Detached From Myself and so Present in The World"
"-  Albert Camus."
(Albert Camus)
French philosopher and writer
"For Henry"
I wasn't good in school
I didn't care for school
Um ... It was an nice socially
Based on my own experience
But I can't just went along ...
I started over in Music Major
I'll be Rock-n-road Star
But that didn't quite worked out.
In 1985
The journey of hurricane during the Gloria
I was taking an train into the city to work
I was ... I gone to work and I was on
the phone with my brother-in-law
who ... he had just started teaching
He said that he was off from school
Now, wait a second,
You off from school for hurricane,
I am going to the city ....
To work in the Office building?
Its an pretty good game, right.
My mother was an teacher
I knew it without an shadow of a doubt
From my early childhood
By the one job, I would never
do as become an teacher
Ever never I would take the
top-cards on a "turn plate"
I'll be seperated anything
Rather than become an teacher
And I decided to be a teacher because I
wanted to do something with my life besides
what I was doing which I was driving a truck
For a company and,
And decided that I want to the better for myself,
so I started teaching a little bit, at the acting school
I was at age of 37
A friend of mine from the College
His aunt was the ...
Principle of the "all-girls" in
the city school in New York
In New Jersey
They were desperate for teachers
So I thought "Great",  I can do this for a year
It will keep my father for
making me an job for prudential.
And I figured it out what I wanted to do
Well they called up for enter an interview
And I have to get an job, and
In a Junior High school in Queens
And I ended up ...
I started it - my... what
was now reached 30 years
Most of the teachers here at one point
They believe
They could make the difference
I know how important it is
After guidance and to have ...
Someone help you to understand
the complexities of the
world that we living, they didn't really
have that ... growing up
I am money
I change hands like a dollar bill
its been robbed by the lab
I am geneis premium and cry for love
with volume
But the tears were offer myself
And that's all went wrong
* Phone ringing *
* Beep *
Hello, Robe, its Dead Mathias here
I'm sick and won't be coming today
alright.
* Beep *
Get to the point, Dr. Harward
I have to school today, alright.
Day school gone down at the
state for last three years
Don't pretend you know the game,
You "ink-mark" my school and the chance
be done the worst kids in the region
Children deserve an education
Don't you agree?
I agree, you joking of it
and wasting my time
Get to the point, Dr. Harward ...
We need an concense builders
A new methodology
You corruptize the system
No, we're cleaning house
Supervisor-attendence feel
that its time your step down.
Babe, you got some fucking nerve come
to my yard with the heart your fucking self.
Carol, it was a time you were an educator
You were well respected.
Why don't you go out and talk?
Everybody to sit down and shut up,
alright stop pulling out the referrals
Sit
Sit down.
I am starting the DVD
- Barth or Barthes
- Barth
- Mr. Barth
- Yes madam
Mr. Barth Henry
So you've been taking an
long term assignments at the ...
"Mark & Arthur"
The French
Ah thats what it worked out.
This an month-long assignment
Until I can fill it permanently
I was asked to meet with you because you come the
highly recommended the best suburb of the hall city.
This is someone who to be the hall-man.
I agree, Mr. Barth
You'll find many of your students
functionally well below the grade level
That is your task is trying to
get them not bother others
Teach curriculum
is most importantly
Understood?
- Good morning
I'm Mr. Barth
Most of you didn't heard this
is English 11 A
- Yes
- Yeah
Listen up,  I have one rule
Just one.
If you don't want to be here
Don't come
Dude, what does that mean?
Its not dude, its Mr. Barth
The letter S for silent
- You are fucking gay
- Marcus, Shut up!
No, you shut up!
A diet Bitch
Hey Marcus
Guess what
What?
You are free to leave
- Right now?
- yah right now.
- hiya ...
- See you later, man
- What's the fuck, you want me to go to the Dean's Office?
- I don't care where you go.
Everyone pull it out of your shit paper
I would like to assess each of you
individual writing skills you have ...
What do you think if I got no paper?
Okay here is the situation
You dead.
- Alright, write an brief but detailed essay about ...
- Hey jerk, ...
- I have a fucking question
... about what a friend or your parents
May say about you during your funeral
- Okay, you have 30 minutes
- Bullshit ...
(class laughing...)
I asked your motherfucking question, didn't I?
Anything else?
You had better fucking up before
I am fucking up your rat shit
That bag ...
It doesn't have any feelings ...
Its empty
I don't have any feeling
that you can hurt either
Okay? I understand you're angry
I used to be very angry too, okay.
I get it. You have no reason to
be angry with me, because ...
I am only the few people that to see
trying to give you an opportunity.
Now I am going to ask you
you just sit down
And do your best
And I will give you a piece of paper
How's that?
Can I get a fucking pen too?
Kids don't have any attention spend
They're bored
So how you supposed to view the man with
class attitude they don't ... if they don't believe ...
that you
Have something meaningful for share
Thank you
Why you fell Marcus out of
the class but not Jerry?
Well I got to make an example for someday
you know Marcus has been expelled from this unit,
and this would not be allowed in my classroom
What they were saying to me is just "material"
What's your name?
Meredith
Nice to meet you, Meredith
So you don't really care
what the kid say to you?
Perhaps I used to it
I wish to be that strong
It doesn't take that strength, Meredith
You must understand that unfortunetly most
of people are act on their self-awareness
You should keep that in mind and you will
have that chance at your second period
You will meet them again at every age
I want to see the Principle!
That's her, mom
You're bitch who expelled my baby?
and for what?
- Excuse me, maybe you would like to ...
- Because you can't handle it? ...
Bitch why don't you be here?  You want to be at home
everyday like that??!  I don't have time for this bullshit!
- Keep your voice down!
- Why don't you be here?
Hey Madam, clam down
We will talk about this in the Dead's Office
I wouldn't go anywhere with you
Look, I know you're angry, but
But they won't listen to you,
you need to talk with me.
- Races come on, I will sue your ass ...
- Come on, ladies ...
This way
- Ladies
- What happened?
Bitch, Aamlteni she can fucking shame in class to
making (Hernández) fucking game, kick your ass!
Excuse me
Are you new here?
Yes, first day
Welcome
That was quite a scene back there.
I was a little shocked
But its actually safe here
Sorry I am Miss Madison
I am Henry, Henry Barth
Whenever on my mind, I
say there was a feeling
I am truthful to myself
I am young
I am old and I am bored up to my soul
So many times
I am out of faces and I am gone
I am just like you
Patricia
* knocking the door*
(Phone ringing)
- Hello
- Henry, its me (Rita), from the hospital
He's done it again, you
need to get down here
Bastard, leave me alone!
Why don't you handle this?
I can't get him out!
- You come and get him ...
- Patricia
Thanks
Grandpa, come on
Its Henry, open the door
Patricia
No, its Henry, its Henry
- Who?
- Its Henry
Grandpa, please, open ...
open the door ...
Wow, sweetheart
I thought that you were with mom
Your dress okay, there ...
Were you going somewhere?
Now I go to work
You are retired
You are retired, okay?
Its very very late so I need
you to go to sleep, okay?
Lets come to bed
How you doing, huh?
Some people they sleep
a lot before they died.
Is that ridiculous?
Fuck.
Herny, everything okay?
Shut up
You listen
I know you're just under-educated drank who
Passing your time with these old dying people
But I paying you to assist him for living
You're not assisting him!
I told you that take the lock
off of his bathroom door!
you know how he get up
at night and he forget
So you have to be there for him
Make him feel safe
Let me be very clear here
You stop neglecting his needs
And I would stop fucking with yours!
I would have you fired!
There is going to be your family
Your children
how can he be in risk!
You got it?!
I got it.
Don't make me come down here
again to sort this out, okay?
Okay?
Give me the fucking money!
Did you heard me?
Give me the fucking money now!
You think I love you?
Give me the fucking money!
- You want the money?
- Now!
* Slap face*
Why you follow me?
I am not, its late, you should
be home, just go school
What? Are you crazy now?
- What the fucking of your deal, huh?
- Keep away from me
Why you let the guy beat shit on me?
- Huh, you selfish like a fucking lemon or something
- Excuse me, I don't wanna talk with you
Don't you think there're something wrong with that?
Listen
Little kid, I don't know how old you
were, you are old and went wrong.
But this is the fucking answer, okay.
Figure it out, you gonna
be really old really quick.
- You should know that
- Why are you mean to me? huh
You don't think that I have feelings?
Do you? Do you have feelings?
Listen, pa
In between you and me
You look like even have more problems than me
Oh really?
- Yes really, so come on, I mean I will make you better
- What are you doing, get off from me please, u alcoholic?
Nothing, I just want to hang out
with you if you want me, and I...
- I don't wanna hang out with you
- I don't know you seem how lonely
Maybe we can get back
to your place just relax ...
You fear to like it?
I'm afraid I fuck the way you done
so many times, I get used to it.
Fuck you, man!
Fuck off, weird.
Have a good night, yeah
Yeah, yeah, just walk away? hey?
Where are you going?
"He just fuck their shit up and the ..."
"The ladies cried for me ..."
"At the funeral"
"Because I ate around no more to,"
"Dig that splited up ..."
"Raw and shit ..."
"And my boys or get faded ..."
"Leave that gun shit and fuck."
Toni
You know it's funny that
I spend a lot of time
Trying not to have an deal
Not really committed
I am a substitute teacher
There are no real responsibility to teach
The responsibility to maintain the order
Make sure that nobody has killed
anybody in the classroom
And then make that into next period
"She used to be an sweet girl"
"She never seems to be
satisfied with her life..."
"And why should she have been"
"An mother of mine gave her
everything she needed ... "
"So why she become so angry?"
"So miserable, so mean for all of a sudden"
"We don't know."
"Frankly, it doesn't reflected on us."
"We were good parents"
"But still, she will repay us for all we've done"
"Like killing herself"
"Stupid and selfish Child"
"Now she will never get into Princeton"
(Princeton is an U.S. well-known university)
No name.
"Hello, its this Mathias Dead"
"I can't do it anymore"
" I ...um I quit! "
Oh, if it isn't ... good
afternoon Dr. Parker
Do you like a happy pill or happy babe?
- They're yummy.
- I need you to fill out the Dead Mathias in the second period.
I am worried about you, Charlie
Just the ... maybe I like to
watch you leave the room
Haha Mr. Seaboldt,  he
maintain an sense of humor
I think the sense of humor is the key,
But I don't make processive ... haha
I mean, I do ...
in a tragic sort of way
What are you doing here Mr Sea?
Um I am coming in fill for
the Dean of Mathias
Mathias is a Bitch
Talked shit.
You can be slapped like a bitch
You are not gonna to give
me the attention either
I am gonna off this shit of type
Motherfucker
Oh shit, I am fucking your
shit type of Motherfucker
Wow...that is I mean really great.
I mean that its truly un-literical
You should take that on the stage
I mean that should serve itself
Umm, hey who could talk
some of my thought says
I am going to un-fuck your
shit, of type Motherfucker.
I'll tell you now, your little naughty
I'm not the fucking shit of your type
I'm not the fucking shit
of type of your ass
You motherfucker!
I am going to on fucking shit
of type your motherfucker
I'll tell what, um...
Why don't you have an seat?
Okay and
I will back shortly and then
to discuss your great future
Okay, my man?
I mean, your motherfucker.
Okay, Miss what?
Ellen, can I see your nipples?
What? No!
It will be wrong.
Actually I can
See there is the whole point, you
have to wearing bra to go to school
Well  Mr. Seaboldt, I'm just want to be me
I don't want you tell me how
to dress, you don't tell me.
Understand?
Ellen you know what's that is?
It's a beautiful picture
of the sunset in Hawaii
Its really pretty, isn't it?
Now
you know what's that is?
It vagina infected with gonorrhea;
Its fucking disgusting
Yes very, as you see
When you come to school
dress like that, you give ...
The wrong signal, don't you
want the people to respect you?
Yah I get respected, I don't have
to give everyone "dick" in my face
Every "dick" in your face.
That respectful.
Put it on, wear this for the rest ...
Hey I said that, wear that
for the rest of the day.
Okay?
Can I go now?
I supposed you can, I mean
If we were done, I'll be done?
- We were done
Another student was saved
* knocking the door*
Come out of the bathroom, Grandma!
Come on, laundry open the door
Hello Grandpa
* knock the door*
Grandpa
You okay?
What is it, Grandpa?
Its Henry, Grandpa
Grandpa, its Henry.
- Who?
- Do you feel pain?
I ... I pissed myself
* Knock the door*
Come on, grandma open the door!
Excuse me
- Can you come in here please?
- There has an accident?
- Yes
-  you should ... haa..
- Do you want to?
- You see, we've been taking care of him, see.
You see? you okay
- You right?
- Have you done any writing, Grandpa?
Any writing, in journals?
No, my life ...
My life is not worth mentioning
Its ok, its okay.
I didn't want to both odd like this
I hate being a burden
You aren't a burden
Okay?
Sure, do you like for coming here
Your mother came by today
Have you spoken to her anything?
No
I would told her I am fine?
You always say you were fine, but
I know you hide things from me
You always been closed off.
Ever since you were an kid.
Why is that?
Why?
Ah .. you upset, I didn't mean
to say these things to you ...
- I didn't mean to make you ...
- yah you didn't upset me
Grandpa
So I don't wanna talk about the past.
You and I remember it very differently
Get some rest, close your eyes, I'm here
- I am here with you
- When you stop coming, Henry?
I would die
Fuck.
You got an cigarette?
No, I don't have a cigarette
Where you go huh?
- What gotta do now?
- What would you gonna do, little kid?
I don't know
Can you lend me ten dollars?
Come on, man I'm hungry
I may have some you need in my place.
Come in, wash your hands.
There are soap over there.
Sit down
Really nice place you got.
Thanks
You've got anything stronger?
Here is your sandwiches.
Hey, hold on man!
Its cost you $100
Relax ...
What?
Have you been raped recently?
What do you care?
I'm not sure what I am doing
to take care of it
I would put something on
Look, I think I got to get back
Back?
Back to where?
Listen, buddy
If you don't got the
money its cool, i mean...
I like you
How about I can do it with you for 50?
Listen to me
Not off the bullsit, okay?
Coming to the bathroom
This stain wound ...
Why you doing this?
Take a shower
- This is freash towel
- Thanks
Go to sleep
Hello, this is Dr. Parker
My son has  ELD - "learning disabilities",
I was an operator, this what he got ...
Now you got to do is get
him an free laptop
Mr. Kevin, your son offensively
hitting another student
His problems are behavioral
Hey he has to do it because my son
is disable to learning anything
And this is your fault!
Hey hey ... what are you doing?
What is the matter with you?
As it is, our research has been made that we have
an real ELD kids here may need your attention.
He is always mad all the time because
he is not getting the services he needed
No Charter Hypathesis that protecting our
right, you will be hear from my lawyer!
Mr. ...
Hey, what are you doing?
What is this?
What is this? Funny? Get the
class, get the class right now
What's the joke? I didn't got the joke, huh.
Is this funny? Was this little goodies?
You like hurting animals? Huh?!
Is that what you like to do? Listen to me,
you like hurting Animals? You like this?!
Come here, go, lets go, come on.
Go walk
Mr. Raymond, the studies shown that the kid
approach hurting the animals at their early age
Eventually they fall into the
highly percentage of adults
Who may fail to develop even
the most basic feelings for people.
Raven
How do you feel about this?
I feel ...
Trapped.
Like the cat.
* Man's moaning"
* Key sound*
Fuck.
Who are you? Why?
Did you paid?
Did you paid for her?
- Yeah alright, yeah yeah alright, here ...
-  Pay her
- alright, here, take ...
- Why are you pay me for, huh?!
Wasn't my mouth!
Get fuck out of here, get out of here!
Fuck!
It wasn't me!
Here ...
Change your sheets!
How you do it again?
Please don't be mad at me.
I am not mad at you
Don't think about relinquish me
I won't do it anymore
I promise
You don't need to promise me
Okay don't promise to me
Whatever it is, you feel
you need to do, you do it.
But don't do it here!
Okay?
What are you doing there?
Don't you knock the door?
What these sculpture all supposed to be?
You tortune Soul?
Why don't you paint something cheerful?
Like happy with colors.
What do you want me dad? Besides of me
before having me born like a peanuts.
I don't work all day
To have my night ruining by your teen ants
Mostly your age, I get my full right of sample at
Stanford University like that some minority can ...
I am not going to support you
And your little creative hobbies!
Okay? I have already tired
of all your art projects
They will going nowhere!
You always know what got to say, Dad
No people grow hair like yours
And lost some weight
You gonna to attract some boys, who knows.
There should be
Prerequisite
Curriculum from being an parent,
before the people attempt to
Don't try this at home
Take this
What those?
You supposed to ask me
before you taken them
They're Vitamins
And Aspirin
At some point
You should get an HIV test.
Why are you crying on the bus?
Go to sleep
A friend of yours?
A friend
Oh...No no
Of course a friend, he was ....
Totally asshole
What was his problem?
He chosen an vocation that
he did not chosen to have ...
That man has spent his whole career
Casting curses before swear,
he talked like that ...
The child hate his face
He was trying to purchase Stanford back and
Ford nerve of quiet willingness
There will be sad for this safety years about bible
You can do no more harm
How did he died?
Who knows, and who cares.
(glauas)
*Phone ringing*
"Hello"
"Its tragedy this life"
"and retention"
"Friendship and exposion"
"Death meetings"
"The Papers cuts"
"The vacant parents"
"The wishes kids"
"The draftful pigs"
"They spilt on my soul"
"This humanition will stuck"
"Disciplines must be restored,
these kids having fun of their run."
" Wow ... run, our Child! "
" It's fucking rabbit! "
" Is every child have value? "
"Where is your worthy of education?
" Fucking kids who has lot of his fire "
" Lot of fire ..."
" No mind to be taught "
* (Section of the speech of Adolf Hitler) *
" Assimilate "
What's that mean?
To take something in
Well excellent, to absorb
" Ubiquitous "
Anyone?
Everywhere all the time
So what is the meaning ...
" ubiquitous and absorption "
Always absorbing everything
everywhere all the time
Well done, George.
How were you to imagine anything?
If the image is always
provided for you
Who here had read "1984" last year?
"American novel turned into a movie"
Good
Anyone?
Meredith
Having two opposing belief at once
Believes that both are true.
Excellent
Why you always suck as a dick, fuck?
To deliberately believes lies
While knowning their false
An example of this in your everyday life
or I ...
I need to be pretty
To be happy
I need surgery
To be pretty
I need to be thin
Famous
Fashionable
Our young men
Today
They being told that women
are prostitutes
Bitches are things to be scroll
Beaten
Shit on
Ashame
This is a marketing holocaust
24 hours a day
For the rest of our lives
The power to be
A harder work
Dumbing us
To death
So, to defend ourselves
And fighting against the similarities of
this dumbs into our thought processors.
We must learn to read
To stimulate our imagination
To quantivate
Our own conscious
Our own belief system
We all need these skills
To defend
To preserve
Our minds
Just carefully, yes perfect
Great
Let me have a look
You just make your destination
- Wow
- I don't care what they say how you doing great.
I was having hard time in
mathematics too, it takes time.
Wow, that was damn cool
Hi guys
Thank you for staying late
15 to 20 of you
Today it will be presented an new course system, Engineering
Bruce of State Examinations preformance as mandiated by
No child had left behind
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen,
it is my pleasure to be here
I have come today with some editify materials help
your maturicuation and non-maturicuation students
Better for prepare upcoming State of Exams in May
Let me start by stating
I love teachers
I love what you do
What you stand for
You guys are the real heroes
Now one thing I've learned all
my years on private sector
Is that
Real estate generate revenue
And emeraging the value of the property
will be this school for saving grades
But your school lower test scores
I will bringing down the whole real
estate value in this neighborhood
During the market which already decline
We gotta to get the score up
New families in our districts
And the motivated kids in this schools
And I am not asking any blame
Excuse me, are you here
to sell some tests material?
Or show your concern the area
of your property owners ?
Listen, umm ... I am curious
Can you giving me pop-corns or we grab
some pop-corns for listening your bullshit?
This faulty has been spent their lives
on the board, and now you tell us
Our careers were about
to re-sell and evaluated
- Bullshit !
- Give him hell lady ...
- Storm the game
- Don't let the things simply, man
That is not the thing that you can't afford
This sound like an threat.
- I mean that's enough, please sit down?
- No I would not ...
That's enough, could you please sit down?
We have some order here, please
Dr. Harward was right
- This school was crying for this district
- Yeah you bad Pal
Could you finish your bad
tricks and go home?
Why you hurry, huh?
I heard you and Richard bastard ...
So enjoy running this relevance
place for fewl more months
Your bastard order will be fucking done!
You urge going home?  Like I don't know what
to do myself like I'm not in the classroom
Some Friday afternoon, I am afraid to go home
I spend all the time on my own
Yeah
- My mother hated my father passionately
- Are they for there not permanently ...
Just watched a lot of TV
- For the only time that I don't feel naked
- Not a temporary one
- I teached for selfish reasons
- My mother was Smith Madison
... I need an good control
- I need ... to get those kids
- It does great similar things ...
- Thats moments in school ...
- Is all she has ...
It must be like an shit end up there
That situation you ever have.
So what is your story?
My story?
I just ... umm I just taking one thing at a time
Why waste your life, you know
something worth to adore?
I teach every day i mean, when we
you are not really know me
So what happened to you?
You don't want something more permanent?
- Hi
- Where have you been?
Why? I was out.
- With a colleague?
- The boy or girl?
A woman
Made me feel like so stupid
Why treat me like a child?
- Because you're a kid, I am sorry I wasn't expecting this
- All you have to do is ...
Tell me that you will be home later
Back up, alright?
I am not obliged to you, okay?  I mean
you welcome to stay here, but you know?
You don't have to get expectation of me, alright?
This is an temporary thing, you ...
you able to stay here, but ...
Eventually you have to go,
you understand that?
- I think it is important you to ...
- Its clear.
I get it, you want me to go now?
I got better considering
than clean up the stuffs
I can't believe you made dinner
From what?
Goceries, from the Goceries store
Wow, it's really nice kid
Its been long time since
somebody cooked me out at home
Thank you Erica.
We all have problems, we all have things dealing with
And we all ...
Take them home with us at night,
take them to work in the morning
I think that is helpness, that
realization for both parties
Being ex-drafting that in the Sea
No bowies and safety, when
you thought you will be the one
Falling the bowie,
Hello
- Anything for dinner?
- Tell me all about it from the beginning -
- You don't care
- Oh no ...
- I am so much in care, love
- relax
You are so self-containing
Give me a kiss
Come on, come with me, I
will sort thing out with you
- Come on
- Stop it
Do you remember when
I bought this for you?
The beautiful summer in "Vennz" before I travel
to Arizona to brought you an ring with passionate
" You're suck! "
- Bloody?
- Yeah
- Grandpa, you doing any writing of your journal?
- No ...
I don't remember much
When you were there,
you can't think in this place
Cannot make new memories
Thank you
- You alright?
- What?
- You see me?
- You see me standing here?
Yes, I see you here
Oh God, its so re-linkness, thank you.
" Carol, there is no way for us to do this, I spoke with the
Super-attendant, its agree to let you out for the rest of year "
" It is where it is, take your pension
and fill out your flabulous ... "
" Send greetings to Bastards ..."
I am Chairman before. If I am Chairman,
I just want to tell someone to fuck off.
I think I am sick
- Why?
-  I crossed the line today
I mean the whole thing is fuck
Whole thing is fuck, is not?
What's up, Dr.Parker?
Can we get over It? I have
got other things to do.
Well, what are your plan for after High School
ever since you will not go to University?
I don't know
Hanging out with my boyfriend,
designing an modelling shit ...
- Be my friends' band (music)
- I have your ten year scores report
Do you know what they said?
Fail, Fail, Fail
- F, F, F
- F, F, F yah
You know what that means?
Its mean you don't care
You're brilliant.
Can I go now?
Oh god, you are an shallow disgusting creature.
You want to know the truth?
One, you not gonna be in an Band,
Or an Model Missy, because you have no ambition.
With no skills, you will gonna be the 80% of
the U.S. workforce for minimum wages job
Which mean the way you living
for the rest of your life
Until they replaced by computers.
- I don't care
- Two, ....
The only talent you ever have
is getting men to fuck you.
Your life will be become an part of pain
Now, can you won't say it again
Not for one more day,
not one more hour!
It will get worse, much worse!
Everyday I came in this office and I
listened your kids to shit-off yourself!
Its so easy to be careless, it takes
curse and courage to take cares
None of you have any of these qualities.
- Get out!  Just get out! Get out!
- Fuck You!!
* Bang - shut the door *
- I am totally burn out
- No you were not.
- I am.
- I mean I don't know how you make it through the day.
Listen, seriously what do you
think you can take these pills right?
I mean, there are lot of rumors there.
Oh come on, I don't dig these things,
I can be an Master of these parents
I will be help them out to throw
the fucking kids out of the window
Come on, you're the best.
I'll tell you my opinion, the
worst thing about this job
Is that nobody say thank you
- No
I'm here to say thank you
Your doing the job, none of us could do
None of us.
- Grace
- Have I ever I told you that you're the only person
That I have to talk to
- Hi Henry
- What happened?
They called to your house
- Your grandfather felt his chest pain
- Then?
Doctors said his condition is stable
He doesn't have a lot of time
- I am so sorry Henry
- How long ...
Have you been here?
Since this morning, I didn't
know how to get an hold of you?
I don't know where you work
You are having a whole day with him?
Hello, grandpa
I am still hanging in there, as I see
Hey sweetheart, your mother
has visited me today
Did you seen her?
- No
- I told her I was afraid  to leave you
... But she promised
- That she would look after you
- Sure, she means that all the time
Patricia tell me that
You've forgiven me, haven't you?
- What do you need to forgiven me, daddy?
- Those things
You know, the things I did
All you have to do is
- Always take care of me
- Why did you afraid of me?
No, daddy, not
I know how you get sometimes
you get little mixed up
You feel responsible for the
things that you didn't do
So I was the one who hurted you?
No Sir, that wasn't you
I wish this wasn't true
Patricia, I always love you
Daddy, you can feel free to
leave, when are you be ready
Do you know that?
Thats okay.
There is nothing to fear
Come on
Let's leave from here
Is Patricia be your mom?
What happened to her?
She left a while ago
You mean she died?
How did she dead?
My father left when I was a kid,
I don't really remember him
Its always the three of us,
Mother and Grandpa and I together
In this house
I've found her... on the foor
... She was taking enough pills
And Grandpa at that moment,
seriously kinda of lost ...
* Tape written - For Henry *
I sat with my grandpa's bench and
we watched her to came and go in
How old were you?
Seven, I am kinda not for sure, i think my
mother was young when something happened
- With my grandpa
- Were you afraid of it?
No
Did she ever say anything to you?
But looking back on it, I think she
protected me on her own way
How?
She made me locked my door at night
The park is now empty in bare,
and we feel ... ashamed about it
The jungle jam slide and
swing and roost together
I also terribly alone now
Where did the ... all children gone
Didn't they know the park needed them?
The child's intelligent heart can flatten
the death of many dark places
I cannot find any kinda
delicated moment of attachment
- Hi Mr. Barthe
- Hello Meredith
- How's going?
- Fine, I am alright ...
- I made a picture for you
Come here
- you did?
- Yeah
Wow, it's beautiful and,
you have the great talent
- Thanks
- Are you doing this for an long time?
I've been doing this since I was a kid.
Man with no face, in a empty room
Is this how you see me, Meredith?
I don't know how I see you
This is just how I feel in your situation
Don't you ever think about who is
going to teach you from the outside
- In real life?
- I guess so
- Does this place seem real to you?
- I watched him down the school
You always seem so sad
If you are having an hard times ...
and if you need someone to talk to
- Meredith
- Yes Sir
- Do you need someone to talk to?
- Yes, will you talk to me?
When you talk to me, you give
me is like you really see me
I do see you Meredith
- Would you like to see Dr. Parker?
- Oh come on, I don't want to find any psychological consultor
I am not, I am not ...
What can I do for you?
Its like you said we brought up to the...there is nothing
left, nothing to realize and how fuck up the things are ...
It's not enough, I won't last
Listen to me, just Listen
We are all the same, we all feel pain,
and we all have to pay us for our lifes
Life is very very confusing, I know
I don't have the answer,
but I know if you write it out
It all be okay.
- Mr. Barthes, do you like me?
- Of course I do
- Meredith, please don't
- I want you to help
- Please, please
- No, no
- You don't ...
- You said you like me, please...
Please, please ...
Oh please, don't put me away, please just
hold on to me, and you said everything will be fine
Everything will be fine,
It is okay, please.
- Please... no, no...
- Meredith, wait a second
- What's going on?
- What?  Hey (Meredith)
- Meredith, Meredith
- What were you doing?
Meredith, I am sorry.
- What?
What are you doing?
- Excuse me?!
- You was just touching her
What do you ... what do you insalivating?
It is inappropriate to be in here
alone with that young girl
It is inappropriate, she needed
someone to talk with to
- What do you think I'm doing? lady
- I don't know what I am doing.
"Just make me close."
What do you think I am fucking provert?
Is that what you insalivating?
She needed someone to talk to her
- Why would you touching her?
- I wasn't touching her
"Its alright my dear"
"Patricia"
I'm not ... not a sick old man!
Is that the way you thinking of me?
Is that what you think?
I just wanted to help her!
- Get out! Excuse me! Excuse me!
- What am I supposed to think?
Fucking to your fucking judgement!
Hello, no he's not home.
Hello Mr. Barthes
Whenever you feel like you are ready
to have some papers downstairs
I need you to take care of them
I am sorry.
I wish things would be different
I tried, you know, fuck
the things it is ... we all
We all have problems with all
the things we dealing with
Somedays would better than others, Some days
we're not so great, somedays we have limited spaces
For others.
Good day, sit down, have a breakfast.
Want some milk?
These kids need something else
They don't need me.
- You don't have it?
- Yeah, I'm not hungry
- You know, you can't keep living on the street.
- No I am not, I mean I here staying with you.
You can not stay here with me.
- Its not good for you
- This not true
You're the only family that I ever have
Well I can't be your family.
I can't give you what you needed
- You have to understand, you should be ...
- You are good ...
And gentle ...
You are the most guy
I love you Henry
- Come in, hi
- Hi
Hello there
- Erica ...
- Don't let them take me ...
Please ...
- Noo ...
- Listen, you should ...
You are all that I have, please...
- Don't let me go
- You should go, sorry
- No, no ...
- No, don't do this ...
- Henry! Henry!
- You should go
- Henry!
- You have to let go
- You have to ...
- Henry!
- You have to leg go now
Henry!
- Thanks, you help me this
- Yes
- Henry! Henry!
- Come on.
- No! No! ...
- Things will be okay
Don't do this
- You gonna be okay
- No! No! No!
No! ...
Well ... I does feel awful for her
- For who?
- For our school
It may sound strange but I always
felt that the school has its spirit
Its not just an budgetful
buildings, bu they're alive.
I just can't understand
where are all the parents?
I don't know
It was in my room for two hours and I saw only
one parent, where are they? Where is everybody?
- We don't know
- Its impossible.
No annoying, its slience, no bombs
Doesn't happen that way
Starting the whisper, then nothing
We had an music once, hadn't we?
Yes, we did
Do you remember that night, where
we have two parents at a time?
And then we have more and the
many more waiting in the waiting list
And halls were filled with joys and
celebrations. Now, its nothing.
I remember the things passed.
I actually felt quite at home
No parents
I thought about how its appropriate,
Its like - A moment of the insight
The reality of the fucking
problem in the first place
Some of us believe that
we can make a difference
And then sometimes when we wake up
And we realize we failed.
* Phone ringing*
* Beep - recording machine *
Hi its Gretchen calling from the free Clinic
Erica Lous has an tests result was back
Please get her to call us as earliest
as possible at your convenience.
Thank you
* Beep - recording machine *
" - You have good parents "
" - Bitch you shut up. "
"A Mother of mine gave her ... "
" A Diet Bitch! "
" What sculpture supposed to be?  This sculpture so bad ..."
" Its has nothing to realize and how fuck up the things are ..."
" - I won't stand that, Dad! "
" - Paint something more cheerful ..."
" We have to pay us our lives ..."
" Grow like your hair, lost some weight"
" We all gonna be okay "
- Good morning
Before we take class
I want to tell you that ...
today will be my last day with you
You will have a permanent teacher on Monday.
- Where will you going, Mr. Barthes?
- I will go to another school
- We will miss you, man. I'll fuck with you.
- Yeah?
All those teachers there in
this place ... they're "dickies"
Don't you get tired of
moving around all the time?
It's my job works, well I was coming
in here for a period of time ...
So you don't have to turn in yourself a lot here ...
and then you will have an permanent teacher come in ...
And I leave
"Attention to all teachers, this is an special
announcement from the Principle's Office. "
" There will be all faulties meeting today
during the nutrients (meal time)"
" Students' nutrients period won't  be extended "
" For ten minutes, thank you."
I invited you here today to
discuss, the status things
I know they wasn't ...
I know that there isn't ...
- I am sorry ...
- We all need something
To extract from the complexity and reality
More or less to think about
where they came from?
More or less to think about the struggle that
it takes to become somebody to get out of ...
... to get out of the ...
The sea of painful,
we all have to get out of it.
- Hello Meredith
- Hello
Haven't seen you in class lately?
Where have you been?
- Baking
- Oh I see
- Yah
- I am happy to see you because it is my last day
How ironic!
Listen, I was thinking,
I bought this for myself
Maybe you could make better use of it.
- I like that, its best
- You can have that one
It's mine
But, can you have this one?
- It's better for you anyway
- Thanks
I am sorry.
If I have hurted you in any way, I um ...
- I know that its tough right now, for you, but its not gonna your wish ...
- Goodbye Mr. Barthes.
Goodbye Meredith.
They say that suicide is a permanent
solution to the temporary problem
How well would you know?
My name is Meredith and
I want to kill myself
Meredith
No
Henry
Things would gonna be fine.
Things would gonna be okay.
We have such a responsibility to guide
a young so that they don't end up ...
Falling apart.
Falling by the way side.
Becoming insignificant.
I realized something today
I'm not a person you are,
you shouldn't be here.
I am not here
You may see me, but I am empty.
Failing, we failing
Failure does have sense of mean,
we left, everyone went down.
Including ourselves.
And I am walking an Hall way to the class.
How many of you have ever felt the
weight of presence down on your chest?
I have.
* Rise hands*
Everyone?  Well, poem wrote about
these things over 100 years ago
So as we read
We can see that the house of
Russia is not nearly an old ...
The crapping castle there be repaired.
It is also an state of existence.
" During the whole whole dark dark soundless day "
" In the autumn of that year, when
the clouds are pressively low in heaven "
" I have been passing alone on the horse's back "
" Through the Singletary nearly track in the country"
" That lane found myself that is
shaved to be evening dawn"
" Was in the view of mountain
Connery House of Russia"
" I know not how it was "
" With the first scream of the building, I
sensibly in suffering gloomy probated in my spirit "
" I looked for poem for some
blank scape for domain "
" Poem for beathe walls, Poem for
white trunks of decayed trees "
" With the other depression souls "
" There wasn't an iceness "
" A sinking."
" Seeking an Heart "
" Detachment "
Translation by mattrew
mod_forumcity@hotmail.com