Sorry, we're closed.
Says who?
Write something. We'll all sign.
On this prank, I'm covering no one.
Let's wait for René!
Move your ass. Do what I said!
Clear out or I'll call the cops!
Cops don't scare us!
Down, everyone!
Noses on the floor! Move it!
Strip!
Kill me instead!
A short poem...
I wrote it, so listen!
"Eddy...
"Loyal friend, goodbye,
"Prince of the B.R.I.!
"You're a man so true,
"We will all miss you.
"Beloved by everyone,
"Without enemies, not a one.
"You're so dear...
Shaddup!
"That we'll all shed a tear,
"A new life you've found,
now you're Riviera-bound,
"Why go away,
leaving Titi this way?"
Great, Titi!
The gift!
We'll see you soon, dear Eddy!
We'll meet again, for sure!
Shit, guys!
A mouse!
Let's split!
Bye, thanks.
- How you getting home?
- A ride with Smao.
- OK, Big Luc.
- Titi!
You forget anything?
It was in the john!
- Shit!
- I'll say!
In case you see a mouse.
Thanks, Leo.
- I take you home?
- No, I'll take you.
- You're taking me?
- Yeah!
Calling all cars.
Look out for a vehicle,
after armed robbery
by three hooded men,
flight direction unknown.
Calling all cars, re a vehicle
a black wagon,
with 3 hooded men...
Hi, Dennis...
Hi, Leo.
You're wrecks!
Eddy's farewell dinner.
What's the score?
One conveyor dead, one mangled,
150,000 Euros gone.
Witnesses?
Only empty offices.
Same guns,
same C4 explosives, same planning.
It's them again.
Look around.
You won't find much,
but go ahead.
The headless man says hi!
Blown away by a mercury bullet.
Eve Verhagen, OCU.
Eddy Valence, BRI.
Yeah, I can read.
Where do you hail from?
Suburban narcotics squad.
Sick of smashing syringes?
You could say that.
Klein is sulking,
stay with him.
Don't chat with the enemy.
We're enemies?
BRl/OCU, it's an old rivalry.
- Aren't we a big family?
- So they say.
She's private property.
Klein's?
Who else?
How could you be pals with him?
He wasn't always like this.
Their names?
Winterstein.
Bruno and Rolf.
The one who did me was Bruno.
Christo warned me:
"Your big mouth
will get you in trouble."
Now it has.
7 vans in 18 months
9 conveyors slaughtered,
and a 2 million Euro booty.
The Ministry of the Interior
sent us a memo.
Asking us, and I quote:
"To tackle the problem head on
"and neutralize the criminals
"who've derided
our forces for too long."
"Too long" is bad!
Means we've been around
for too long, doing nothing!
As of today you're on duty
24 hours a day!
Drop your personal problems,
don't laze on Sundays,
go out and nab that gang of fuckers
before they strike
for the 8th time!
You got that?
Got that,
Capt. Kechichian?
We were up late.
For a good cause.
Sure, loitering in a bar at 2 AM,
after defacing the wall
of a Government building,
how can I fault you
for being so admirable!
- Anything else?
- A lead on the van jobs.
A Serbian arms-dealer:
Victor Dragan.
We got a tip off
from an informant.
A reliable source?
Not at all.
What do you say?
I know the fellow.
A sadistic loner.
Barring a lucky break,
he'll be tough to nail.
Luck can be engineered.
Briefing's over!
Vrinks, you stay.
I've been appointed
Police Commissioner.
As of when?
I take over on Sept 1.
Congratulations.
I hate to leave
before I've cleaned house.
I want that gang, Leo.
As my farewell gift.
You'll get them.
Another thing:
Someone will get my desk.
You're the right man.
Klein wants to be Chief.
He wants power, that's different.
But you both qualify:
Same rank, seniority,
service rating.
So whoever nails that scum,
will be king.
I don't mix with brass.
It's better than mixing
with whores and hoods.
Times have changed.
Get yourself a new style.
You're an anomaly.
Your men, your methods.
In the police,
now you toe the line, you snap to.
If you don't,
no one will cover for you.
All the brass have caved in.
Even you?
Lay off me, shit!
Who the fuck are you?
Shit, what ya doin'?
What have I done?
Don't do that, don't!
Lay off Manou, or I'll stuff you
with your brother's head.
Quite a shiv!
War booty.
Creep's gotta
hitchhike buck-naked,
and cuffed!
We shoulda wasted him!
Gotta be ten grand!
A year's pay for a flatfoot.
Those fuckers!
For our slush fund?
No, it's for Manou.
Leo.
Come in.
Hi, Christo.
Manou's resting in her room.
I'll tell her you're here.
Let her rest.
She OK?
Just OK.
Still after that van gang?
Still am.
I hear they hit again.
Near the beltway, right?
My only advice is:
When you bust 'em, shoot first!
You know anything?
I'm not a snitch.
Ask your questions elsewhere.
Who worked over Manou?
What do you mean?
Leo...
I'm 46,
I spent 18 years in jail.
She's the best thing
that happened to me.
Someone hurt her, I gotta know.
If I tell you, what'll you do?
That's up to me.
You're in trouble
any time you step out of here!
You're a hood, Christo.
With a record for armed robbery.
If you smack your neighbor
over a trifle, you go back to jail!
Manou needs you:
If you go down, so does she.
Screw your cop morality.
Anyway, it's settled.
I dealt with it.
This is to make amends.
Around 7 grand.
I'll see you out.
Thanks, Leo.
I won't forget.
The guy
you're looking for, Dragan.
I know where he is.
At a chick's place on Borrego St.
Don't ask how I know.
Police! Freeze!
Stay there!
Get up!
Let me hug my kid.
Your wrists!
Sign there.
Have a nice leave, Silien.
Your Puch's in the toolbox.
With a 2nd clip, just in case.
This is dumb, Silien.
You got 3 weeks to do.
Watch the road.
Neat vodka.
You kept Dragan to yourself.
Was that wrong?
Don't they say,
it takes two to tango?
We're not dancing anymore.
Anyway, he was a bum lead.
How do you know?
I know. That's all.
Silien here.
How are you, Captain?
Am I intruding?
Sure, it's after midnight.
Where are you?
In a hotel.
I'm out till tomorrow night.
On a leave. Wasn't a jailbreak.
I gotta see you fast.
Tonight, I can't.
You'll regret it.
Meet me in 1 hr at "Swann's".
Same again?
No, thanks.
Camille OK?
She's fine.
When did you buy this?
We'll talk cars later.
What's up?
Nice welcome!
You haven't seen me
in 4 years. Don't I rate a smile?
This is a favor for a pal inside.
You made me cross Paris
for a lousy scam?
I got a hot tip.
You're a piece of shit.
What is it?
Heavy duty stuff. Real hot tip.
Want it or not?
What's the deal?
Just stay with me.
In a half-hour, it's done.
Here he is.
Stay in the car!
Get going!
Stop it!
Why'd you screw me?
Stop, dammit!
I know who the van gang are.
And their next stunt.
They're in the sticks.
It starts from there.
In exchange, you cover me.
Or get nailed with me.
Who did you waste?
Marcus Zerbib,
his driver and his goon.
Marcus Zerbib?
The guy who put you in jail?
You'll get nabbed right away!
Not with a good alibi.
Now...
you can grab
the worst gang around.
Choose.
OK, let's have it.
I know two of 'em:
Francis Horn
and Robert Boulanger.
They're squatting in St Ouen.
On Captain Glarner St.
- Don't you say hi?
- I hadn't seen you.
- Want a drink?
- I'm with friends.
You got friends now?
Your only friend is me.
If I conk out, you're dead.
Here's my direct line,
so you can't forget it.
Give me a lead, fast.
That gang...
I want their names first.
Nobody knows them, I swear!
I want news from you.
Stay in touch.
So I know you're OK.
Good seeing you again.
How'd you get that?
It's nothing. At work.
Why not tell me what you do?
I don't want to lose you.
You get home late, leave early.
Lots of cops live that way.
Many wind up all alone.
What are you after?
Nothing.
I just do my job.
Get up, lazybones!
- Say: "Morning, Dad".
- Morning, Dad.
And give him a kiss.
No school today?
Never on Wednesday.
You know that.
Yeah, if I knew it's Wednesday.
Mom in?
Rushing as usual.
Thanks for the...
coffee!
My ass is spreading,
that's bad.
I don't mind, I love big asses.
Know what my big ass says to you?
That it misses me.
Sunday's my dad's 70th birthday.
He hopes we'll come.
There'll be a crowd.
You don't have to talk.
- What crowd?
- My mom's family.
Uncles, aunts,
cousins coming from Rome.
We'll see.
Lola, hurry!
Bye, daddy-o.
Bye, honey.
6 slugs were fired.
2 hit the driver,
1 the goon, 3 Zerbib.
No one saw much.
The building's all oldies.
By the time they shuffled
to a window, it was all over.
But the concierge saw a girl
get out of the Merc and run away.
Brunette, red coat, a BJ artist.
Zerbib liked cheap whores.
We'll find her.
That's for Homicide, not us.
You knew him well?
Enough to want to nab his killer.
Vrinks, BRI.
The names Horn and Boulanger.
Give me all you've got.
What's with the Zerbib case?
He was getting a BJ in the car.
Had his dong out
and his pants down.
A concierge saw the girl
leave after the shooting.
She see anything else?
Ask Homicide, it's their baby.
Can I see the telex?
Boulanger.
I got several, which do you want?
Robert.
Francis Horn
and Robert Boulanger, aka Bob.
Horn: Armed robbery record.
Wanted for theft,
armed robbery, extortion
and attempted murder.
Weapons freak, ex-mercenary,
trained in Syria, a real psycho.
Boulanger broke from jail
2 years ago, killing a guard
and an officer.
Seems Horn sprung Boulanger
to have him on his team.
I have no other names,
but they operate from here,
a squat beside a warehouse
by the beltway.
First, we find lookouts
and set up surveillance teams.
Smao and Titi will be in the silo
overlooking the squat.
You photograph everyone
coming and going.
You identify all vehicles,
and any lowlifes in the area.
Second, we cordon off the area,
block escape routes,
one team per street in a perimeter
of half a mile within the area.
Third, we advise the local police
we'll be playing
on their turf for a few days,
and to lie low
on the day we make the grab.
No neighborhood investigations
or questioning,
we avoid concierges,
storekeepers, local hangouts.
Klein, OCU.
You don't know me, I know you.
No waves: We settle in, watch and wait.
Know what they'll hit?
No. We can't lose them.
Let's go. Wear bulletproof vests
over your T-shirts.
We have a common friend,
a friend who just died.
Marcus Zerbib, you know him?
He wasn't a friend.
You two were in business.
Some nasty gossips say
he snitched on you 4 years ago.
The guys he snitched on
would fill the phone book.
But only you could gun him down
in cold blood,
during a leave from jail.
Would I waste him
when I have 2 weeks left to do?
What's wrong, Leo?
- Nothing, why?
- Don't kid me.
You're lost, I can tell.
I'm in deep shit,
and I can't discuss it.
Not even with me?
Not even with you.
- Where were you that night?
- With a cop.
HQ's finest cop.
We met at "Swann's"
at 1 AM, we chewed the fat
till 5 AM,
then he dropped me at my hotel. OK?
His name?
Vrinks.
I'll need your boys.
What for?
We located the van gang.
How'd you get the tip?
Know a man called Silien?
Why?
Says he was with you
when Zerbib died.
If he says so, must be true.
Could I have that in writing?
Investigating murders now?
When my snitches get killed.
Those fuckers
give me a giant hard-on.
Some get laid, others freeze!
We're on the wrong team.
No, that's his last fuck.
We'll hump again.
You sure?
Big Luc to Fat Ass.
Mercedes wagon,
local plates, 4 men on board.
It's headed your way.
Long-haired guy is Frank Chenaf.
I nabbed him
for a holdup 10 years ago.
A mean fucker.
I don't know the others.
Sa:i:d and Jamel Attia.
I say it's for tomorrow.
Nabbing 'em in the act's dumb.
They'll fire at us. We may
lose them to avoid bloodshed.
What do you suggest?
We hit 'em at night,
and gun down the lot of them.
What about our ethics code?
I've wiped my ass
with that for years.
They killed 9 men.
9 families
call me every week hoping
I'll have good news at last.
I owe it to them.
It obsesses me.
Stay home,
let Vrinks deal with it.
I've worked 2 years
on this case.
It's my collar
as much as anyone's.
OK, but you'll be back-up.
You only move in on Vrinks's orders.
He and his men are the front line.
He's in charge of this.
Whether you like it or not.
Igor here, they're coming out.
- Headed for the cars.
- Gotcha.
Big Luc here, they're coming out.
Two black SUV's and a Mercedes.
Standby.
I'll advise when they move.
Seurat-Chenaf in the lead car,
the Attia brothers in the second.
And the rest?
- I only see Boulanger.
- The SUV's are off.
They're taking off.
The SUV's are leaving.
Very slowly.
I see them.
They just passed us.
Let 'em leave the area.
Guy and Bernie tail the SUV's.
We tail Horn, Boulanger,
the chick.
We only hit 'em at the warehouse.
I repeat: Don't hit 'em here!
The SUV's are stopped
at the entrance.
- Horn and the chick are out.
- We'll be OK.
Armed to the teeth.
Where's he going?
Eve to Dennis. What's up?
What are the orders?
They're about to leave.
Shit, someone's moving!
Klein's headed for the squat.
- He's alone.
- What's he up to?
He's drawn his gun,
headed for them.
Dennis to Leo.
What is this?
What is this? Answer!
Cops, behind you.
Move in at once!
I said: Move in now!
- Shit, Big Luc!
- They hit me!
Grenade!
Come on, bitch!
Drop your guns!
Drop your gun, pig!
Drop your guns,
hands on your heads!
Hands on your head!
Come along, bitch!
Let go of her!
Fuck you!
Shut up! Drop your gun!
Drop your gun. I'll waste her!
On your knees!
Kneel! That's better!
Hands behind your head, scumbag!
If you tail me,
I'll waste the bitch!
Don't take her, take me.
You're dead! Stay put!
State police found Eve
lying on the freeway.
She jumped out of the moving car.
Fucker's got some nerve!
Big Luc, Smao...
What does this mean?
The Commissioner didn't like
you and your men's stunt
at the funeral.
Screw him!
I know.
But I'm warning you.
Of what?
Top brass are like old maids:
You don't ream them.
Get your men back in line,
drop the petitions,
the strike threats,
the defaming of Klein.
Klein goofed,
he has to be punished.
That's for Internal Affairs, not you.
An investigation's under way.
If Klein was responsible
for this fuck-up,
it'll come out.
Taking on Klein
is taking on the hierarchy,
which is
questioning the system.
You can't do that.
So Eddy died in vain?
He died doing his duty.
Sorry.
I owe him the truth.
What's that?
Requests for transfers.
We all signed.
It's Klein or us,
you decide.
It's Dennis.
I hear you're testifying
against me at the inquiry.
Valence's death was Fate, pal.
Stirring up shit
won't bring him back. You agree?
I'm gonna hang up.
You can't do this to me.
You can't.
This job,
is all I have.
So don't crap on me,
or you'll regret it!
- Where is he?
- Room 24, 2nd floor.
- And the witness?
- He split.
He's married and was with a chick,
didn't want any heat.
Pulling strings
is an insult to Valence.
I can't, Dennis.
Some deaths you can't touch.
- Are you refusing?
- No.
As I said, this isn't any old file.
He was a fine cop,
the union backs Vrinks.
Unless we humor them,
Police HQ will be up in arms.
All I can do is try
to convince the board
not to suspend you.
With your record, it should work.
And if it doesn't?
Police! Freeze!
Know why I didn't kill you, Horn?
Death only happens once.
I won't let it surprise you.
You'll wait for it in a cell,
like an idiot,
until you go nuts
from loneliness.
Know what?
One day
I'll be behind your door!
I'll kill you
and your whole family.
I doubt it.
Can I see you a minute?
Boulanger's dead.
A freeway roadblock.
He tried to run it.
Gift from the Commissioner.
With a letter of congratulations.
To be shared among you.
200 Euros.
Doesn't cover Eddy's wreath.
Klein's in front of the board in 2 days.
I know.
Let the system handle it.
If you mess things up,
they'll make you pay for it.
Where do you stand?
Me...
I've already left.
Evening, Captain.
I hear things are edgy at HQ.
It's a problem for cops.
Not for you.
- That why you wanted to see me?
- No, for my girlfriend.
She got busted.
They claim she's hooking
and gave it to the Aliens Office.
She may be expelled and fined.
What do I care?
The Zerbib affair
interest you?
Go on.
He died in her mouth.
Fix her case, you never heard of me,
she'll tell all.
I'm listening.
There were two men.
One fired,
the other waited in the car.
I saw the one in the car today.
Where did you see him?
At Police HQ.
He's a cop.
What do you want?
Issued by Judge Rousseau,
instructions to search your home
and take you in for questioning.
You crazy?
You'd better let us in.
Go fuck yourself!
You got fucked, Vrinks.
Search the whole place.
Leo,
what's happening?
Who is this?
It's nothing. Stay with Lola.
- Who's Lola?
- My daughter.
Who are you?
Internal Affairs.
Don't worry.
Why are they arresting you?
Later, Camille. Do what I said.
Camille called.
What did she want?
What do you think?
Was Leo's arrest your doing?
It wasn't my doing.
He was arrested for being dumb.
I did my job.
Yourjob is jailing your friends?
When they cross the line, yes.
You won't fulfill yourself that way.
Meaning?
Becoming the fine cop
you'll never be.
Why didn't you tell me?
What for?
We nailed Horn and his gang.
The rest is a detail.
It could jail you for 10 years.
You covered up a murder.
You don't realize.
No.
I got screwed by my informant,
not the same.
I owed him for his tip.
You'd have done the same.
I'm not you.
What should I do?
Come clean:
Don't crap Internal Affairs.
The hooker recognized you and Silien.
Denial makes you an accomplice.
I gotta snitch on Silien?
He put you in deep shit.
Tell us where he is.
- It's your only chance.
- I don't know where he is.
Judge Rousseau
has been assigned to the case.
You know him.
He hates cops, he'll slaughter you.
...Closing a blind eye
on 3 murders to protect an informant
and arrest a vicious gang is one thing.
That this led to a colleague's death,
and the events that ensued,
is another.
What is serious, Vrinks,
is that your silence
meant Silien was freed.
He's a menace to society.
I won't dwell on the ethics
of policemen and informants.
We both know it's open
to personal interpretation,
and rests on fuzzy rules and controls.
But there's a principle
all police officers must obey:
Never to guarantee impunity
to an informant,
or take the place ofjustice,
whatever the goals.
See you soon, boss!
That's why I'm ordering
your incarceration.
Dennis Klein,
badge number 628049.
You appeared
before this board to answer
on your responsibility
in the death of Lt. Eddy Valence
during a police operation
on Glarner St,
in St Ouen, last January 12th.
Seeing the findings
of the Internal Affairs Division,
by Chief Inspector Staneck,
and the statement by Lt. Jenner
confirming
that you acted in self-defense,
as the man Francis Horn had
"spontaneously opened fire,
"while you were
on a reconnaissance mission."
Seeing that Capt. Vrinks's statement
was held to be inadmissible
due to his present situation,
and his closeness to the victim,
this board clears you
of all responsibility
in this tragic matter.
Hence,
all charges are dropped,
nothing will appear
in your file.
Among criminals,
guys like you end up on a vacant lot,
with 3 slugs in their head.
Among criminals, guys like me
don't listen to guys like you.
When'll Dad be back?
Soon.
But he hasn't left us?
Why do you say that?
Because you're sad.
Usually when he's away,
you're not sad.
Usually, he doesn't go so far away.
Your Honor,
I'm Captain Vrinks's wife.
My husband has been
jailed for almost 3 weeks.
I'm still not allowed to see him.
My little girl
asks for news
of her dad every night.
Why do this?
You could issue me
a visiting permit now.
I have a lunch date.
Excuse me.
Who is this?
I want to help you.
Help me do what?
I can't say on the phone.
Can we meet?
I'll call later.
I can't say on the phone.
It's him.
I'll call later.
It's his voice.
Tap her phone day and night.
Don't miss his call.
When you've zeroed in on Silien,
advise me. Only me!
Hello, Camille.
Got time for a coffee?
What do you want?
To say I'm sorry
for what happened.
I didn't want this.
If you need anything...
I don't need you, Dennis.
I haven't for ages.
Is that all?
No...
That won't be necessary.
One question, Mr Vrinks:
The same one.
Where's your friend Hugo Silien?
My answer hasn't changed.
You can take him back.
Why treat me this way?
It's how I treat people here.
I'm not like them.
I'm a cop.
You're nothing now.
Handcuffs! Don't move!
The other one.
Don't worsen things.
Cuff yourselves
to the radiator! Fast!
Don't move, asshole!
Hurry!
Why did you do it?
To see you.
Now what'll they do?
Put me in the corner,
till it blows over.
Then I'll be let back in.
- When?
- Soon.
Hold out!
If you can outside,
I can inside.
They can't keep me for long.
Why didn't you tell me?
So they couldn't question you.
How's Lola?
She misses you.
What did you tell her?
The truth.
Dennis came to see me at work.
What for?
He wanted to know
if I knew a man called Silien.
What did you say?
Nothing.
I said nothing.
- Has he tried to reach you?
- Who?
Silien. Has he?
Answer, Camille.
No one called.
Stay away, he's bad news.
You promise?
I promise.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Kiss Lola.
We can go now.
Let me welcome here
our new Police Chief,
Mr Robert Mancini.
And introduce you
to the man who succeeds him
as the new head of the CID.
Captain Dennis Klein.
Let's wish them both good luck.
To the new head!
What are you after?
Nothing...
I came to watch you, to learn.
Thinking of him?
Should I?
I thought cops were special,
above bad things.
Why should we be?
Give me a good reason.
We're paid to be better.
My respects, Chief.
Throw the fucker out!
Put him in the drunk tank.
Let go!
I know the way out!
He'll resign once he's sober!
Under me, you'd better
lose your bad habits!
This is Captain Klein's number.
Leave a message after the beep.
Boss, it's Jenner. Are you in?
We tapped Silien calling her again.
They're meeting at...
I'm listening.
Subject got in.
They're on Rte 20, freeway bound.
Zebra 4 stay put,
let them come to you.
3 and 5 stay behind.
We'll nab 'em by the freeway.
Think of her, it's risky.
Drive.
There's 20 grand for you.
You and your daughter.
Until Leo's out.
I should say thanks.
My letter explains things.
I can't do more.
If they nab me, I'll get life.
How long's Leo in for?
Those are the rules.
He took a gamble and lost.
Damn that.
What can you do for him?
Nothing.
What's this?
You snitched!
Turn! Stop!
They're headed for you now.
- Don't let her by!
- I must!
Don't let her by! Dammit!
I hear you want a transfer.
Too bad.
I'd put up your name
for promotion to Captain.
Like the others?
They saw it was a smart move.
I'm not made for your clan.
I'm a plain cop,
no dumber than others.
I'm fine as I am.
Then why didn't you speak up?
Vrinks jailed, his wife dead,
you as boss, suits 'em all.
Why should I blab?
One day the ghosts
will come and take you away.
You'll have to answer
for your dirty tricks.
Some day,
we all have to die...
We have to go.
Sorry.
I want to kiss my daughter.
Not cuffed.
I can't. It's the rule.
I'll handle it.
No one knows why Silien shot her.
Bye, darling.
I'll be back soon. Wait for me.
You going back to jail?
Yes, I'll write you every day.
- Don't leave me alone, Dad.
- I'm not.
Granpa's there.
I love you, darling.
I love you, too.
Captain Vrinks released from jail...
Turn it up.
... for complicity
to 2nd degree murder,
the former BRI chief
was freed for good conduct
after serving 7 years.
A reminder, too,
of his wife's tragic death
during the arrest of Hugo Silien,
alleged killer of Marcus Zerbib...
Come in!
He's at the home of
a former hooker, Manou Berliner,
in the 16th district.
Check it out
and stay on his ass.
I want all his moves
and who he sees.
What are you waiting for?
I ran you a bath,
then I'll go shopping.
I'll be off, too.
Don't you move.
Stay here and rest.
It's weird to have you here.
- I won't bother you long.
- You're no bother.
On the contrary.
Christo'll turn in his grave!
A cop in his bathtub!
At the end, he was unrecognizable.
He barely weighed 80 lbs.
His car's still in the garage.
You can use it.
For anything else,
you know this place,
feel at home.
- What's it about?
- I'm here to see Titi Brasseur.
- Who are you?
- Leo Vrinks.
He's OK!
It's not classy, but there's free
booze and lots of ass.
Still see the old bunch?
Not a one.
What'll you do now?
No idea.
Besides Klein,
who saw Camille's death?
No one knows.
No one talked,
it was all hushed up.
Those who didn't blab
got promoted.
Only the Verhagen chick
got left behind.
Where's she now?
Cop shop in the sticks.
On the complaints desk.
In Gennevilliers.
I'll be off.
Too crowded, too noisy.
I'm out of practice.
- I'm sorry.
- You creep!
- Apologize to my wife.
- He didn't.
- Yes, I did.
- No, you didn't!
Who are you shitting?
Lay off him! Asshole!
Don't touch me!
You're a goner!
Sorry.
You know him?
No, why?
We've seen that creep before.
I'm sure of it.
Take good care.
Don't let her by!
No one knows why Silien shot her!
We heard a shot, the car skidded,
he shot at us,
we fired back.
I only want one version.
You knew about Camille?
What could I do?
Leo, wait!
That's him.
- Up already?
- I couldn't sleep.
There's cops parked below.
I saw them.
Why are they there?
They were told to be there.
Policemen's Ball at City Hall
I need a gun.
By when?
By Friday.
Took you long enough.
When did you get out?
2 days ago.
You waited 2 days
before coming to see me?
I waited...
for the right moment.
It's hard to return to the living.
Some day, explain it to me.
Some day...
Why didn't you let me visit you in jail?
I was afraid.
Of what?
Watching you leave each time.
Call me tomorrow?
I promise.
Lola...
That story isn't quite over.
There's a last thing to settle.
Then I'll have to leave.
Where to?
I don't know. Far away.
Don't dump me twice.
Night. See you Saturday.
Who are those assholes?
War booty.
Fuck, that's Bruno's shiv!
Were you on thatjunket?
Answer, who else was along?
Who was with you?
Who's that?
That's a cop...
Your friend is brain-dead.
He'll stay that way
till he's unplugged.
Shit, what ya doin'?
Who the fuck are you?
What have I done?
Lt. Eve Verhagen, please.
It's Vrinks. I'm at Evry hospital.
Titi got beat up, he's in a coma.
For good.
Care to know who did it?
Don't go, Leo.
It's the only thing to do.
Call you when it's done.
What's he up to?
Badges and guns on the dash.
Get out.
In the trunk.
Get in.
This is dumb, Vrinks.
Get in. Hurry!
Good evening.
Thank you for coming so numerous
to this very special event
that honors
all of you, who through
your generosity...
Congratulations, Klein.
Only the dead don't return.
Don't look around.
So you see your face
explode in the mirror.
How could you have shot her?
I could've forgotten everything.
But not that.
Don't let her by!
Don't let her by, dammit!
She was already dead.
No one knows why Silien shot her.
If you miss yourself with the first,
there's 13 more in the clip.
Fuck you!
You hear me, Vrinks!
Go fuck yourself!
You hear? She died
because of you!
Only because of you!
You're the one who fucked up!
If you'd left us alone
it never would've happened!
You hear me,
you dirty fucker!
You hear?
Klein?
- What?
- Remember me?
Who else was there?
Klein.
Top Cop Gunned Down In Central Paris
Want the paper, too?
No, just the candy.
This film is for Capt. Christian Caron
killed on duty Aug. 31, 1989
Subtitles: A. Whitelaw
Processed by VDM - Paris