I'm home
I should've listened to you
and taken my umbrella
I'm soaking wet
So I called him outside on his
lunch break and I told him,
"There's lots of guys waiting
to take your place"
Right at the busiest time
of the lunch hour,
he was just spacing out
in the kitchen
He's totally not helpful
Who does he think runs that place?
What?
I think he's 3 years younger than me
That's right, he's an only child
His parents totally spoiled him
Unbelievable
Well, who cares about him anyway
What do you think?
It's so late already
Skip the bath tonight?
Nozomi...
You're beautiful
Welcome
Yes, just a moment
It's so cold
You're beautiful today, too
I'm off
Beau-ti-ful
AIR DOLL
Moe! Hey, wait!
I forgot
Off you go!
I'm off!
I'm off...
Burnable
Burnable...
Not burnable
Burnable
Burnable, not burnable
Kishida! The stickers!
Thank you
Not burnable
Burnable
Burnable...
Thank you
Do you remember when
that family
was murdered in that
upper-class neighborhood?
It says here it happened
on the 20th of last month
A judge and his wife
and their daughter, a pianist
Each of them murdered in
their sleep, late at night
The murderer was already arrested
He was a failed student
Her parents wouldn't let him
date their daughter
"Don't copy me
"Mr. Echo
"Mr. Copycat"
Cold!
Come here
Rio!
Yuzu! Yuzuki!
Come here
Haruna!
Come!
Yuuki!
Cinema Circus
Video Rental Shop
Are you looking for something?
Help Wanted
Here we are!
This hill!
Pretending to go straight!
It warmed you up
I found myself with a heart...
With a heart I was not
supposed to have
Movies are made with film
Light passes through it
and on to a screen
Film
Right
You never watched a movie?
That's just a substitute. You have to
watch movies in a movie theater
Movie... theater?
Kids these days are unbelievable
What have you seen
at a theater recently?
Me?
You know...
There's this one or...
But you can't beat
"Battles Without Honor
and Humanity"
and Humanity..."
Battles...
Without...
Don't worry, don't worry
It'll be fine. Don't worry
about what your boss told you
I don't see you that way at all
So don't you worry
I can't believe they keep
that useless guy in charge
What are they thinking?
Right, exactly
Thank you very much
Thank you...
What are you looking for?
What?
Wasn't "Battles" great?
"I've still got bullets left,
Yamamori san"
Didn't you watch Part 1?
Part 2 is "Hiroshima"
Want to rent both?
What are you doing
for Christmas, Nozomi?
With your boyfriend?
Your boyfriend,
your favorite guy
You have one, right?
No
Really?
Yes
The first time
I asked my wife out
to a movie "Love Story"
I told a lie
Because I found a heart,
"Planet of the Apes"
"Purple Noon"
Chaplin's "The Great Dictator"
Junichi likes musicals
Musicals are fun movies
with singing and dancing
"There's Something About Mary"
is supposed to be really funny
The water's just right
You've got to get all the way in
Your only flaw is that
your body's so cold
Can you tell?
Smells great
It's a popular shampoo
I spent 100 Yen more than
the usual shampoo
100 Yen makes a big difference
Great...
Lucky you
You don't age
I... found a white hair
down there
What a shock
I wonder how much longer
I can make love with you
So damned pretty
The Winter Triangle
Don't make me repeat myself
Can't you ever remember?
There's Sirius
And Procyon
And Betelgeuse
That's not true
You're beautiful, too
No point being jealous
of the stars
I am an air doll
A substitute for handling
sexual desire
Nozomi...
Always stay beside me
Do you like it?
What is up there?
Up in the sky, there's air
And clouds float there
At night, the moon
and the stars come out
It's invisible so you can't see it
But it's there
You can't see it
Hard to understand
Is that the ocean?
Yes, that's right
Have you never seen the ocean?
No
There's so many boats
What does it mean
"To get old"?
It means aging and getting
closer to death
Death?
Yes
Losing life
Life...
Even here, you can
smell the sea
This smell reminds me
of my childhood
Reminds me, too...
You can eat your broccoli
Aren't you going to eat?
No
Moe, that's not a comb
But Ariel was doing it
Who?
A-ri-el
Ariel...
Right, she was
You don't know, Daddy
I saw it with Mommy
Excuse me
A beer
And also,
what I asked for before
Yes, sir
Hey, you ate your carrot?
Yeah
You can eat the rest then
Hey, what happened?
A blackout?
Is it a blackout?
What?
A birthday
A birthday?
They're celebrating the day
she was born into this world
Look, a present from your mom
Blow them out
Does everybody have one?
A birthday?
What's that?
White clover
White clover...
That's a dandelion
Is this about to be born, now?
No, it's already wilted
Poor thing
But it has to die someday
Otherwise the world
would be overrun
Hard to understand
What else do you
want to know?
I want to know
more about you
"Candy..."
"5,980 Yen"
I'm home
Were you lonely?
Okabe suddenly
took the day off
What's he thinking...
I'm an air doll
A late model, cheap one...
A girl called Ari or Mari
or something,
is combing her hair with a fork,
like this...
You don't know?
No...
That must be "The Little Mermaid"
It's over here
You have it
Thanks
I'm sorry...
A movie with a super-bad cop in it
Like a totally corrupt cop, making
bad drug deals, rotten to the core
Rotten?
Yeah, got anything?
Then, how about,
"Bad Lieutenant", Abel Ferrara
Is it really bad?
It's more than bad
Harvey Keitel is the worst
The worst...
Why don't you rent
"Donnie Brasco", too?
Al Pacino plays a guy in the mafia
- And Johnny Depp is a cop?
- Yeah
- I already saw it
- You did
Excuse me...
You can wipe them off with this
The lines
Lines?
"Dreams?"
"Dream..."
"Dream?"
OK, how about Theo Angelopoulos'
"The Beekeeper"
Gelo?
Angelo...
Across the river there's
a big DVD store
You can't rent "Dream of Light"
You have to buy it
"The Beekeeper" comes in a box set,
so you probably can't rent it,
even there
Thanks
Across the river...
Thank you
I'm sorry...
I am useless...
What's your name?
Look at the flowers
What's the flower called?
Excuse me
I'm sorry
Say, do you know a bug
called the mayfly?
The mayfly...
Dies a day or 2
after it gives birth
So its body is empty
No stomach or intestines
It's filled with eggs instead
It's a creature that's born
only to give birth
Humans aren't so different
Pointless...
I'm empty, too...
A marvelous coincidence
I'm the same...
I'm all empty
I wonder if there are others
These days, everybody is
Everybody?
Yes, especially,
everyone living in this kind of city
You're not the only one
Say, do you know this poem?
Poem?
You don't know poems?
Doesn't matter,
"Life is..."
Life is...
Let's see, "life is..."
Let's see, life is?
It seems life
is constructed in a way
that no one can fulfill it alone
Just as
it's not enough for flowers
to have pistils and stamens
An insect or a breeze
must introduce a pistil to a stamen
Life contains its own absence,
which only an Other can fulfill
It seems the world
is the summation of Others
And yet,
We neither know nor are told
that we will fulfill each other
We lead our scattered lives,
perfectly unaware of each other...
Welcome, would you like
to buy a cake?
The master has come home
Welcome back, Master
Or at times, allowed to find
the Other's presence disagreeable
Why is it,
that the world is constructed
so loosely?
I'm Misato
How old are you, Misato?
I'm 24
24...
Misato, do you know
a good restaurant nearby?
I just started yesterday
I understand
What do you like?
I like pasta
I like pasta, too!
I want Extra Rice
I want Extra Rice, too
Cancel the ham and cheese
hamburg steak
Lunch specials?
More water with lots of ice
Right away
I'll take the lunch special instead
The lunch special?
The suspect, Kume, confessed that
he had bought one gram from a foreigner
for 7,000 Yen when he traveled to Osaka
So expensive...
A horse fly,
bathed in light,
flies in close
to a blooming flower
I, too, might have been
someone's horse fly
Perhaps you, too,
had once been my breeze
No customers...
No...
I hope it'll be OK
I like it here...
This store
What's the name of
the movie adapted
from a Stephen King novel,
starring River Phoenix when he was 15?
"Stand by Me"
Correct
Great!
OK, then,
the Hollywood movie that became
Matsuda Yusaku's last film?
Don't look...
Air...
You need air...
Where's the plug?
Stomach
Sorry
Don't look...
But...
You're...
Fine now
A little... while longer...
I'm off
Going to get old
You see,
I'm going to get old
Were you surprised?
Yeah
But...
But I hear there are plenty of
others like me
Someone said that
Me, too...
Really?
I'm not so different
I see
But...
I guess you're right
When I first met you,
I sort of felt,
that you were just like me
A marv...
I hit the jackpot at Pachinko
A marvelous...
Coincidence
What?
Nothing
So damned pretty
There's Sirius
And Procyon
How did you get
an Osaka accent?
An Osaka accent?
A movie
I saw a movie
What was it called...
The other day...
How did you feel?
The other day?
In the store
When you breathed into me?
No...
When the air left your body
Was it painful?
Yes
It was painful
Having a heart
was heartbreaking
Misato's only virtue
is that she's young
They'll stop spoiling her soon
She's just a part-time employee
That's all
That's right
She's not going to
last long anyway
You don't need to worry
about her
But...
It'll be fine
You know there's no one
that can take your place
Really?
7:18 PM, the 9th
He said, "My pension's gone
You stole it, didn't you"
He just kept accusing me
over and over,
and I just got so mad...
I'm sorry
No, no, that happened in Osaka
The suspect confessed and
has been arrested
Don't worry
It has nothing to do with you
Nothing?
Nothing at all
I've got work
I can't visit until spring
Listen, did you come here
while I was out?
I told you not to clean up my stuff
Did you throw it out?
Well, it's not that important
Why don't you give them
to your neighbors?
How strange
Your sister's having her
second baby next year
You don't have to grow apples with us,
but it's time you come home
Can't you remember how to take orders?
You've worked here for years now
It's fine with me if you want to quit
There's lots of guys waiting
to take your place
What's so funny
It's revolting when you smile
Sorry
Movies for Crying
Excuse me
Hello
How can I help?
This one
Thank you for your business
Did you guys already do it?
You did it with Junichi, right?
You don't have to hide it
You're seeing him, right?
No
Is that your boyfriend?
I saw you in the park
You were with him
I bet Junichi doesn't know
about that guy
You do this with anybody
Girls these days...
Harue...
Hey, touch me
Here
Hey, touch me...
Here...
Harue
I am an air doll
A substitute for handling
sexual desire
I am...
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Nozomi
Nozomi...
How is it?
The white star of the first
magnitude, Procyon
The triangle linking
those 3 stars
is called The Winter Triangle
Got that?
No, I'll get wet
I have to pee
What?
Nozomi?
You bought her a cake
Is it her birthday?
No...
I got one for you, too
On the day I welcomed you here
I don't know...
I don't remember that
I really did
I took a picture
I...
I found a heart
A heart?
Yes, a heart
Why?
I don't know
Tell me,
what do you like about me?
What do I like?
You don't know, do you?
Even the name, Nozomi,
is your old girlfriend's name
You read my blog?
I'm just a substitute for her
But...
I mean...
Sure, at first,
I was lonely without her
But now, it's different
No, what am I saying...
Why me?
Why?
It doesn't have to be me, right?
Right?
The picture...
Listen, will you do me a favor?
Can you go back to being the old doll?
The old doll?
Yeah, the normal, plain old doll
Can't you?
You wish I hadn't found a heart?
Yeah
It's just annoying
This stuff annoys me,
which is why
I chose you in the first place
I'm annoying...
What a mean thing to say
That's not what I mean, it's not
You're not annoying,
it's humans who are
Nozomi!
Thank you
I hate dogs
They get old so fast
and die before you know it
Having a dog just makes you lonely
Is this you?
Yes
I used to be a substitute
high school teacher
A substitute?
That's right
I was always an empty substitute
Were you lonely?
I wonder...
I can't remember anymore
Do you mind,
touching me?
That feels so good
Me, too... See?
They always say,
people with cold hands,
have warm hearts
Maybe it's just a superstition...
Welcome home
I'm home
I made you, but I don't
know the answer
But I doubt even God knows
why the humans
he made have hearts
Do you wish you'd
never found a heart?
I don't know, but...
It hurts
They all started out the same,
but by the time they
come back here,
you can tell from their faces
whether they've been loved
I think that must mean
they all have hearts, too
What will happen to them?
Once a year, in spring,
I throw them all away
Unfortunately, they're
"Not burnable garbage"
Not burnable garbage
After all, once we die,
we're "Burnable garbage"
It's not such a big difference
Burnable garbage
Can you tell me one thing?
Was everything you saw
in this world sad?
Was there something, anything,
that was beautiful?
I'm glad to hear that
Thank you for having me
No, thank you
Off you go
I'm off
I don't mind if I'm a substitute
for someone else
You're not a substitute for anyone
I'll do anything for you
That's what I was born for
Whatever you want
Really?
Yes
I can do whatever I want?
Yes, whatever you want
I couldn't ask anyone else, but...
With you...
Something only I can do?
Yes
What is it?
I want to let your air out
Let my air out?
Yes
But...
Don't worry
I'll breathe into you like before
But...
Why?
Sure, do whatever you want
Where's your plug?
I'll fill you with my breath
Just like you did for me
I couldn't exhale
my breath into Junichi
You alone?
You are alone
What a jerk
I found a heart
Did you see the news?
They found his body
in the trash
Just across the river
Let's trade
Moe, don't touch the garbage
OK
Off you go
I'm off
Subtitles: Arigon
Mommy
Hey!
Moe! Your gym clothes!
Beautiful