Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
India
history is witness this land get a
blood and give against royal.
Since 1011 time to time lots of people
grim this flower in his step.
And then since 1450 mughal is coming here.
Who make him his house.
Give him a love and give a lots of things.
Started with the king babar this mughal's government.
From humayun then it reached to akbar.
Who get a biggest level in
mughals government.
Jalal ud din mohammad akbar.
Mughals alone king.
His care taking place in a rajput house in india.
And second way princess jodha.
She born also in rajput's.
Her father is king bharmal and
mother prince padmawati.
They arrange marriage in child hood with
ratan singh who is king of ajab garh.
Rajput! Who are ready to fight
every time from child hood.
Then he take care his family,
house and his government.
Maan singh.
Sujamal bro.
And he have one fighter.
Jodha's cousin.
Sujamal love jodha like her sister.
And every jodhas voice he reply fast.
You make new...
after the death of sujamal's father.
King bharmal get his position.
That's why sujamal is alone.
Because his luck get him far
from amer place.
Like that prince jodha's story her
luck wrote from rajput's family.
And now year 1555.
That is the year when king humayun's suddenly
death mughal government is shocked.
King hind get this chance and
he get delhi's government.
And again battle started.
Pani pat.
One side is raja hind.
His force more powerful then mughal's
and second side is bharam khan.
The trustful leader of king
humayun force.
Who sharp a nails 13years old
king jalal ud din.
Top the name of in hidustan.
Hands power and is get a more victory.
I am mughals government care taker.
Today again i recognize you.
Mughal's future is in your
hand jalal ud din.
Life last breath your father.
Heaven king hamayun eyes just
one dream.
In whole hidustan mughals flag.
God bless you.
Now you complete his dream.
Hail king jalal ud din akbar.
Ready to attack
attack.
If we catch the hand of king hemu
then disbalance of his force.
See carefully just his eyes have seen.
Our arrow fighterjust only
get his eyes target.
Come our fighter.
Attack
ready to attack.
- Ready...
the biggest king.
Today first time you can't leave
your sword take a breath.
Cut the head of this traitor.
Get the sharpen of ghazi.
He is in a bad condition khan baba
how can we attack him.
If you cant cut his hand the that
like a force gone on wrong turn.
Then our force can't call me
in the name of ghazi.
What i tell you
you do this.
Soldiers.
Mughal's government powerful soldiers.
Like our elders jala ud din akber
have a ghazi place.
Hail the name of king.
And like this bharam khan take
over the delhi goverment...
...jalal ud din mohammad akbar.
Next 6 years behram khan get
the hidustan completely in his hand.
He send a messages to neighbours
government, and country.
We inform to you from mughal king
jalal ud din mohammad akbar.
Since in one month you
take over all your
...government in the hand of
mughal government.
And loyal with mughals government
paid all of taxes.
If you ignore this or you can't accept this
message then you will get difficulties.
And thats non sorry mistake is like a sin.
And with sin and all of the
goverment finished.
From king of hindustan.
Jalal ud din mohammad akbar.
Go and tell to your king.
We cant give you our goverment.
Rajput blood cant listen a messeges.
We want some time.
We have some conditions.
We can't give you ajab garh.
Get back him.
Ready to attack.
All things are ready khan baba.
Jalal
mughal force waiting for you order.
We give him a last chance of comited.
Khan
yes king.
Our last sending messege is back.
My biggest king.
Now cut his head.
No khan baba
after war whose king is alive on our given things.
I can't bare cut his head.
I said sorry king.
But as a loyal servent we do this thing
who is rights in our government.
Enough khan baba not now.
You forget you're a mughals goverment future.
Thats a bhram khan loyal.
My king.
We make a most powerful castle of mughals.
You broke him.
Some time the loyality get
insulting a human being.
I saw rebel in your eyes
since last wars khan baba.
First time i stopped your sword.
Do you know why.
Because now i take my decision my self.
I want now a days win with every
war we polite with him.
Today i annonced we cant
prison war prisioner.
Thats is not right.
In this country we just dont want a royal.
We want also iman flag.
We think you are wrong.
If that is than we cant ignore running
this goverment in your shadow.
Come on...
lets go king
now i want this you leave
all things and go to makkah.
King one more government is in our hand.
What happen with rajput's.
Rajput can't accept our messege.
Rajput
who stomp on the sword.
Brave people.
Why you do this?
Queen finding a princess.
Said to queen i am just coming.
As your order.
Jodha that is now right.
I am still winning and he is coming between us.
But winner is winner brother.
I lose you.
Sujamal bro remember i mistake in
war every thing will be change.
Just you ignore and you lose or die.
You teach me.
Yes i know i tech you.
Ok now my student teach me war subject.
I can't teach you just recognize you.
Just think i like your knowledge.
And well knowledge person is that
who have in knowledge in heart.
You are like that jodha.
Really
- ok i accept i am a good student.
But you are also good princeple brother!
As new principle is like that.
The queen
now you get every style of
princess with your mother.
There is near your wedding ceremony.
So listen brother if father cant
get you king then i can't marry.
Just i said to you.
Jodha there is not good for a girls.
But this is true.
I listen my self papa said this.
He said you are a warrior,
how much wars you win.
And now your training is complete.
Now no worries.
I am right.
In this good celebration now
the time of some informations.
You first information is that.
Now bhagwan das get all responsibilities
of ameer.
And second one is that.
Sujamal doing every work in
the hand of bhagwan das.
Now a final information who you want to know.
This years on final day with the name on jambai mata
princess jodha and prince
ratan singh will get marry.
Take some shy.
What are you doing there is
every one finding you.
Give me you head cloth.
What?
Now go and take my place.
Dada bro i feel bad after listening this.
Maybe this is a felliwo of father.
Dont give the himselfing change
the name of felliwo jodha.
Rajupt is not hungry.
I can't see any thing who is not us.
We want my respect and athourity.
If i can't get this.
Then remember downing sun is also flaming.
Dada brother.
I saw a chance and ask with the king.
And i request talk with raja bharmal
and admit you on ameer royal.
I cant forget your this replying.
What i get against this?
What do you want?
Attack on delhi.
After you get the king royal
then you help me.
For the attack on delhi
but you marriage arrange with king sister.
Yes our marriage is arrange with
jalal ud din's sister bakshi bano.
After that i comitted ajmer,
nagor and vivagh royal.
Do you know sujamal.
Water and needed flavours are same
go up.
Now i want a complete hindustan.
Allright i will help you.
But dont drown a blood on our raj tilak.
What is fear that is done.
In the shadow of shareef ud din
sujamal get my resposibilities.
Yes
now threat is coming on our government.
Lots of womens and childe
are widows and parents less.
I thought and feel shy.
Which one is right thing is sensible person.
Chandar bhan jee.
Releations with the mughals.
Mytri shake hand with jalal ud din.
That is not right?
If you do this then you are irresponsible.
Cometment with mughals.
This is a very big mistake of honesty.
We are also a dishonest person like this.
I have a sorrow.
But i tell you one thing
for saving our government
i consider with mughals.
Allright bhargav jee then i
tell you and ameer's people.
Now your todays decision i tell you
now one marriage cart gone ameer to ajab garh.
Not only ajab garh.
Tell all rajputs raja sahab.
All rajputs.
We appreciate you here raja sahab.
We get a messege from chandar
bhan jee and inform to king.
King is waiting for you in elephant place.
Where is king.
King
there is!
That is a hobbies of our king to ride
a elephant like this.
Now its not a play
the king rajputs king is
waiting for you.
Wellcome.
Greetings king.
I accept your messege.
Really and truely.
I request to you come
inside in my tent.
I glad full after meet with you.
Raja sahab
as you wish.
Be aware
mughal's king of hindustan
jalal ud din akbar is coming.
Wellcome
you are coming here.
I am thank full to you.
I want to know the reason.
By your bless i want to run the
government of ameer.
I am very happy that you want to run
ameer government under our control.
I also want to talk a thing in a privacy.
Tell me
you have to marry with my daughter.
Princess jodha.
This is start of relation between
ameer and mughal.
I understand.
Why are you keep quiet.
Maybe
- no
i appreciate your offer of wedding.
And i thankful to you.
Give me some time.
I'll gve you answer after come back
from tomb of khuwaja mohiuddin chisti.
Whatever you feel.
Help khuwaja help
i am coming to your tomb with a questions.
With a dream of one complete hindustan.
You'll pray to almight god i success in my dream.
Ameen.
Greetings
greetings
everything is alright.
Shareef ud din.
Yes king.
Tell me.
Jalal in the fronmt of ajmer
i saw a some battles.
When some rajput stop some peoples
then they get a problems.
Like this religious issues turn
into big problem.
There is most caring near to ajmer.
King release the order.
Where and where you take the order.
Not only ajmer althought
gujrat violence.
And haji's are coming there.
Who is the king of ajmer
government.
In control of king ameer bharmal.
Khan baba
send my messege to king bharmal.
That i want to marry with his daughter.
And specially said him that for unity of
hindustan i accept the releation.
But king must think he is one of a rajput.
He is non muslim.
How this releation get start.
Please think about your decision.
Shareef ud din i decide this after a deep think.
You know khan baba.
That our elder bharam khan baba
he control long time a mughal's
government by using my name.
In whole this time i always think that why
previous king did'nt control hindustan perfectly.
I am only think that how to
fullfill my dreams.
I know the destination but
i don't know the ways.
Marriage invitation, releation
bined is god help hint.
I am very thankful of my god
he give this idea.
Khan baba send my acceptence.
But father he is mughal.
I have nothing to say before also.
When i engage with ajab garh prince.
I am change.
And i am like him by heart.
Now i get a tick a like his name
they dont know about this.
Jodha i read your heart because
i am your father.
In which prince ratan singh
but he broke this releation by himself.
I did'nt feel good to say.
But not for your father.
But for this nation.
You have to drink this poision.
I heard that there is a messege from
agra about brother wedding.
Yes.
I did'nt understand how
could it done so fast.
Mother is on a tour of the country.
I've to go fast.
How much a things...
please control you passions.
Do you know this wedding is
happening with whom.
With the princess of ameer.
One non muslim
listen carefully.
Nobody will attend this wedding.
Forgive me brother.
No no how can i send this to dada brother.
To know that what he was feel.
Forgive me jodha.
Its is possible prince ratan singh
agree to marry with you.
Only have to send him this message
that you are against this wedding.
Maybe he
- no
i dont want to hurt father
by doing this.
He think that this relation
with mughals is in favour of our nation.
There is a way.
On your wedding we sit a
nanny's on your behalf.
He can't see you.
No mother if mughals knew this then the
nation of ameer have to face a big problem.
They will knew this fraud.
So daughter.
This releation better than insult.
Yes princess
i decided to meet with king
before wedding.
I have some conditions.
And for this she request king to come in her shahi tent.
What are the conditions?
- I dont know
please forgive me.
She even can't tell me.
I wellcome you.
How can i explain my feeling of thanks
that u come here to hear my conditions.
I have two conditions.
After accepting this
i only can marry you.
What are those?
My first condition is that i am allowed to
live as my tradition and relegious way.
No body stop me and force me to change my relegous.
You agreed
and other
i am allowed to take my hidle you give me
place to make a temple in a corner of house.
These are two of my conditions.
King bharma put two conditions
in front of me.
Only after accepting these two
she will say yes for wedding with me.
First is: She will not change
his religion after mairrage.
Second is: She want to make
a hindu temple in mughal tomb
today first time i feel fully
about raj put prestidge.
I appreciate ammeer princes
bravery and simplcity.
I will tell her that i am also
born in same land
where she born
i also have a same feeling
my decision is wedding with
princes ameer is i accepted
her condition is fullfill as she said
congrats congrats
dear king your this wedding will give a
new bless to ajmer peoples and hajis.
Because of this wedding sofis one group want
to give something to khawaja ghareeb nawaz.
The reason of this angerness.
Are you not happy with this wedding
islam give women a complete
rights to broke this relation.
If u didnt like me then the
way of divorce is open.
This is your right you can break
relation ship and get free
divorced used to be there at your side ' but that
relation is used to be seven lives for us
we are thankfull to you for
take caring of our demand
but do'nt know why heart tigles?
With that rive we can't
get our heart together
could be becoz our relegion and
our culture is different!
I said yes but till now my heart
does'nt wishes to gather
we respect you!
Respect your amotions!
And now then we get together
when your heart witness!
May god have sympathy on you.
Where is king?
He is going to marwa for
some micropolo work
is every thing all right jodah?
Yes
you are the mother of king of india
' honorable queen hamida banoo madam!
Welcome!
Come in daugter.
God saves you from bad eyes
let you be happy and ever!
Ameen!
Meet him!
She is maha manga
jalal's foster
but so call mother is the right word!
And also she is priest of mughal temple
take care of your self
maha manga pirde is different!
Jalal respect her most!
Me too!
We used to live out and out
for fifteen years she took care
of jalal during our impresence
till today he can disobey
me but can'nt disobey her
do'nt hesitate princess
that is your greatness
sallema?
Yes!
Take her to 'her residence
yes honorable queen
wait one cermony is remained
plese come in respectfull
king with colourfull feet
come queen here is ladies room
qali haram!
And that is your palace
queen 'divided in five parts!
For meeting meeting
and this is shab and shoom
very quickely learn to talk
and tells our all secrets
and this is sleeping room for sleep
dressing room
for pleasent view moisture
and for prayer sitting room
oh yes you wo'nt need dreb room
could be needed
why not why not now day and night in
mughal ladies room we used to serve
i have heared of your demands
you are really for wobled honorable queen
you keep trust these are mughals
very noble temple of your god!
Not noble very small at our discending
you have to convey that to king!
Yes honorable queen
jallaludin mohammad appearing at common room
mughal king jalaluddin muhammad!
Long live long live!
Long live
king due to war the tax amount increases
and also prices lift up which
effects very much on poor people life
that state problem need special attention
that problem should be dealed in special peel
next problem?
King we are reported that your brother in law sir
shareefuddin hussain has charged on ajmair goverment
and he has done that unforgiveable
offensive due to your and rajput princess marriage
be quiet adam khan!
That time is not for counting our effences
we 'll dicuss it in ioness
no khan baba
let adam khan ask every thing here
bless me sir
sharrifuddin have doubt on adam
balla noble ability and intelligence
till that he used to said
'will put the perons of marrige in to soil
and that he used to say again and again
shareefudin!
King of time!
Don't take it serious
there are limits ofjumping of frog!
But there is some thing in depth
of sharrifuddin sayings madam amanga
king!
To improve the strenth of
goverment you have only that cub
lam sorry for my rudeness
and want to say respectfully that king
heart is getting powerfull against mind
what was a need of having
relationship with hindu princess
that was deciousion of goverment mr. Mullana
which will be in every one favour
and which conatains every commen one favour
'should not be considerd in religious cube
you are saying right
but why hindu place of worship in temple
that is wound on our hearts
sheikh mubbarak 'mr sadir bassi what we
have done is according to time and conditions
growth of kingdom is most convenient to me than you
but!
Now you all respecutfull personalities wants
want to confess king
but!
Queen should be kept out of
temple and palce specialities
and for her ther should not
be any change in islamic law
we want to know why lam not
selected priest except archer khan
we know all
shamusudin khaker is your father
thats why you jeweld him with honor
who is this person whom talking
with sheikh chilli like that
bepachan hindi
we have complete trust on his inteeligence!
But adam khan is elder brother of king
one reason is that makkah wannt to have same
goverment against king wihout crown and fin
with deep cheating 'thousand
makkah died then that could be borned
we want to know what sort of knowledge
you have about juncher and crown
you was nothing only dancing
doll of peram khan fingers
do'nt forget that my mother
pay you time to time ideas
we also have all that ability!
That you have.
On what base we become
him primeminister
what what imorled background he have
every kind of robbery done... insults womens...
defeated people should not be treated
slavery niether chnged thier relegion!
Disobey and refuse to comply
done all what we dislike
done all what we hated most!
All is against pride of mughal kingdom...
and have marriage with
one grimy hindu girl...
...is pride of mugliya kingdom.
Be carefull adam
say princess name with respect...
do; nt forget now she is queen of all india!
I'i will not accept any offenise against her.
King!
It is said' bad time never
comes at door and knocks
after neglecting by shriffudin
sujamal vanished with his rights here and there
he gets stibs first ajabler
prince and then rana udhay singh
to distroy jallaludin muhammad state
with power we should have inner contracts
both becomes ready to help
but only wait of right time
we 'll demolish all rajputs momorandoms'
name of jodah and jalludin
no!
Do'nt say like that rana jee
what she should have to tolerate
i know her very finelly
have too much pain!
Have too much pain!
Great king it is very difficult question
there is answer of that
asked to angels 'what is paradise?
...they answerd that paradise is the heart where love fullfills
subhan allah!
...and then they asked what is hell
they answerd the place where there is no love is known as he
you said right!
Very nice.
Today seating dispersed!
The traitors should be treated more stricktly
and for sharrifuddin you must have to be alert
and he get out of my controll
oh dam luck i again failed
...no problem in that game looser win in love
i and love ' i have also bad luck
tell me one thing did you love some one
why you so plea suddenlly
its all right millakshni
i said true ' even do'nt know what is love
love!
Fellings of lots of colours
you never fell in love how you come to know?
Now listen 'that lots of year spent
in palace we used to clap in vain
honorable queen!
I bring good news!
King have arranged in your pride a royal party.
Royal party? In my pride?
Then not what'in our pride!
Then!
This fore gift is also send for you!
It is beautifull.
Convey king that i liked it too much
very fine queen!
It have only one meaining
he is preparing to take you!
If its like that than i'll not move backward too.
What are u going to do?
We made a ceremony food...
listen that their soft
hands keep taunks...
till then...
you can't do that...
why?
- Why.
Because you are the queen of hindustan...
but i am not queen of that time
but only a wife...
what are you looking at?
First time any queen step on our kitchen...
honoarble queen have
i done any mistkay
he was afraid to be
diped by rocks...
we all at your servce
ready to arranged
le'ts move & listen todays food list...
all dishes are clean dy your oder
queen... respestable queen
what's going here?
Why can't you prepare the food yet?
Today is my off from kitchen...
who give you a day off?
Queen of hindustan...
today she's going to prepared
rajputi food without meat & chicken...
honorable queen is arriving...
atay fatin...
there is difference seing
dream and having them...
do'nt think of that imnobel marraige
that one princess becomes queen
at last what we do...
temple of aagrah, take charged on
noble kictchen i all know this...
take charged on kictchen
every wife have that right
don't forget it you are deal with jalal...
like trade dealing
that is trade for you' for us that
is highly regarded marrige releationships
its break after death, dont
teach me the marrige releations...
what kind of relationship you were
discussing about wich is not fullfilled yet...
relationships fulfilled when childrens born...
till than jalal not lay on hand you...
so princess jodha you were having an enjoyment
of mughal kingdom but don't try to be a part...
what you said?
How you can willing to have a
right of mughal king's mother
i have sheltered him for a
longtime from up and down...
yes i am his mother...
no one can gave him a minor harm...
at childhood once he was
assault with anchor and i faced them...
if any one come between
me and jalal i destroy them...
i have hidden him from everyone
should be remained below your scenes...
my lord today i cooked curry, mix vegetables
for you and my lord sweet dish also ready for you
well done... tell me
pardon us me lord, but todays food
not cooked by us, queen cooked herself...
i gave this party in the honour of honorable queen...
yes, its not her fault...
i told them that i cooked food myself...
why you face trouble for me, its honour for me...
pardon me me lord...
i remind you that by the royal laws meal
should taste by cook first and than serve to the king...
than this meal is suitable for king
but today's chef is jodha queen herself
so she stared to eat food first.
For the safty reasons to act upon the royal laws...
king also himself can't take act upon these royal laws...
eat it respcteble queen...
me lord the meal is safe...
me lord now you start eating...
served me the tasted plate of queen...
i would like to eat by that!
Do'nt eat that!
Why?
It conatins low amount of salt!
On evry bite i would like to say 'subhanallah"
every monday without meat meal
same like that i would like to eat by queen jodah peel
that food could not be purchased or sell
without permission of mughal goverment!
One more idea
some areas are under
brude and dried conclusions
from them not any kind
of tax should be taken
on both ideas due to law
will be proceeded quickely
king!
Oh god what you have done?
When king comes to know with
them i also will be released
from your realease their released is most important
i do, nt want to go but what to do
this state tour is very important!
Queen has seated on brutch
goodbye.
Very fine!
Now ripped
halla!
Mahabee they write that
letter before marriage
how you know?
Minakshi told me!
Memorised it you have'nt
told any thing by any one
if you will to tell it to some
one then you know the result
princess jodah!
Want to become very clever
sooja man!
Jodha sister band is wishing you
you have to go quickely
what? Are you insain ratan singh
going to agra temple means
(prevesh) means calling death by self
paranjii 'i ii go there!
Your mind is dried sojamal
go... go and then in there prison head for walls
i'll go!
Shareefudin now danger is getting more
we could be viewed
we have cheated in taxes and rents
it tip come to shamsudin khan
adam brother!
Only there is one way
before shamsudin ata khan
opened our story goderbal
we have to stop shamsuddin
can we help you!
We are creditor of your
mother to be in royal army!
No what have to be done i'll do by my self
adam brother very carefully
what you do do'nt let it be incomplete
fraud of taxes is show check
these documents all will be cleared
mallap is responsibility of adam khan
you want to say...
in words it was before but today i get proof too
from shamsuddin you are
tracting case very finelly
but about mallma you have
to be eye blind in that
or you can say facility
due to be elder brother checking remains
else'you fullfilled your pockets attempting taxes
it is clear robbery not robbery
said it bitryal primeminister
its good for you khan baba that
do not interfare our matters
otherwise...
...adam khan
threating primeminister is
like accurence against the king
its teribbl eking
...adam dipped in ladies room along with sword
...also he have murderd primeminister
swine... son of basterd... that much dare our
father type of honest person'you murderd him
arrest this blim person
today you cross all limits of my calm adam
that khan baba was not even faithfull
to mugliya stae but also a angel personality person too
like a father to us!
Pick him up and drop him
down from here from head side
no king... no jallal
no jallal
tahir it should be obeyed
no jallal... jallal!
Is he died
...no king still alive
bring him up and throw him again
due to adam inhuminity and
serious crime i'had to kill him
i'know!
Adam urge big mistake
and have its result
and that why lam forgiving you jallal
i know no one come between you and fin
and according to me jodah
would not do such urge
jodah!
Why you are saying her name?
What is zarb-e-hin jalli
the pot of poisen
found from jodah luggage
now my biggest fear
is taking doubt that...
do'nt forget that big amount
of mehndi could black hands
get the knowledge that
whom she write letters
respectable mom what you
want to say in hiddden words
before your wedding her engadgement
was with prince of ajabgar
and then make relationship with you
why?
One beautifull wife face...
she is the killer of rajputs
you want to say that she send
messeges to prince oof ajabger
now you are not a infant
she is your wife
why she prohibbit you to touch
because her all casualties
are with that rajput prince
and very soon some body is comming to meet her
much lusted glass is
always black from back
how's my jodah
...i want to know about you
why you want to meet like that
in your letter it was written that
you are comming to meet but why?
Because i know that
you have passed bad time
thats why after reading
your letter i come soon
which letter?
The one you wrote me!
But i did, nt you any letter
what you are saying jodah?
Here is that letter and your band!
That band!
That letter i have written
before marraige but did not posted
thinking that you would
be in very bad enclusure
how are you brother?
I am fine
without any thing any
land travelling wrongly
leve me every time i worried about you
brother i am fine here
you are happy!?
What do you mean?
I have readed your letter and
come to know how much you are happy
you are thinking wrong brother
king did'not heart my relegious
felling and make on temple too for me
what over comes you i
have great sorrow on that
but i am worried about one thing if you
did'nt write that letter then who did it
king!
So you put that net
you cheated me
no brother
thats why you write that letter
do not take me wrong i
have nothing to do with it
jodah your band always
remain on my wrist
the all of you gave
always remain in memory
brother!
Honorable queen!
Convicting crime against mughal
state stupid nema should be arrested!
No... no... no...
there is not her fault 'what
she had done ' i told her to do
can you tell what kind of work you have with him 'niether
you do'nt feel to have your husband acknowledgement
and politelly at mid night!
And come to meet on unknown man!
Who was he?
Prince of ajabger?
...prince of ajabger?
That was...
...you batrayed me!
Batrayed?
Yes.
Elder respectfull mom told me about that
i did'nt batrayed you maha manga did!
What should elder mother do against me?
She grew me up
that why i always respect her!
Because which maha manga ask me to stay
away from you ' fullfill your heart against me
what you should ask your self king
...shutup
now i'll not hear even one
word against elder mother
just like you can'nt listen about maha manga 'i
too can not hear any thing without my fate and respect
it was mistaken when walking on
love and trust while having happiness
then have to be saperated
i was convicted 'now please sentence me
you go to your mother home!
Because always love depends on trust '
that's why it is right that i should go!
Quickly prepare to send queen
what you did? You accept the son
and now you give him a threat.
I was doing my duty?
I have tollerate many time
but now its enough limit is cross.
He is not a king of ajab garh.
He is a brother ofjodha.
You know what written on that letter?
Jodha writes it before marriage.
But didn't sent
to make your mind disturb
she used that letter in wrong way.
What are you saying?
Is that true?
It's all wrong, they blame me.
I can't do this queen.
Silence...
fall down your voice.
I wantjust answer
is it true or no?
Saleema will give you answer.
Saleema!
Tell him saleema.
Tell me all truth clearly
my lord
i tell her that letter written before marriage,
but she threatened me
and used letter in wrong sences.
Oh god!
In illusion i did big mistake.
What i did!!
I gives you respect as mother.
You have break my trust.
You broke my believeness.
You removed all things.
You give me this reward for
saying you grand mom.
You are whole life with me.
Then i decided i forgive you.
But now i can't see your face.
Take her back jalaal.
How can i face her?
To accept own mistake,
love will increse.
I am sure jodha will accept your apologize.
I was sure that he will definately come.
I can't beleive this.
Welcome.
You come into our house that
we feel proud of us.
That raj tilak is a denity of mughals family.
Whatever he say,
i'll not go back to agra.
There is one tradition here.
When son in law come first time
to take his bride.
So he has to recognize his bride.
If he will success
so he can spend time with her.
Otherwise he will not allow
to meet her.
Welcome!
Son in law.
So finally you find your wife.
Will you come with me or no?
No im not going anywhere
i came here to take you back jodha.
I'll not go back to agra.
With you in this room alone,
feels different.
Yes its differnt.
But i have solution.
Whats that?
I can't see your face,
it's not fair.
Its not fair.
Jodha!
But you don't understand this.
I don't understand.
No you don't know.
You can fight to win.
But not living like king.
What you say?
That you have just win me.
But you don't love me.
Your all demand.
I have always fill as my resposibility
i have always care of your demands.
I have completed all resposibility of
husband.
If you care for me,
you didn't send me back
you can understand that i
was done wrong by situation.
Atleast you tried to know the situation.
The problem is that you are far from the
reality
you dont know how to
acchive peoples heart
to acchive somebody's heart you need
to people in his heart
his minor wishes, problems, trust
everything you need to be feel it
when you realise all this,
you will be king of my heart.
Please forgive me jodha.
Nice
and if i win, then you have to
come back with me.
Take sword
queen of india,
don't forget that im your husband.
I'll not go back
i won
its wrong.
Whatever i won or you lost.
Gira couldn't you stay for a while.
There is a message for king.
Tell him to wait.
Please forgive me jodha.
But remember war carefully.
In a while time
- dead or alive.
I know that
where you teach to run the sword.
Sujamal bro teach me.
He teach you well.
That is my luck i won.
Now you ready to come with me.
I dont want to go.
This is against to your popularity.
I have my own authourity.
I won't go.
Now i did't force you.
Do you know why?
My heart told me you come
with me on your behalf.
You must come.
Because by god i win your heart.
Dont worry no one will recognize me
i am doing this because there is
difference between won and be a king!
But lord why you do this?
To won the peoples trust you
need to pope in there heart
without shahi guard that is
not safe for you.
And one thing more...
- dont call me mylord!
So what should i call you?
Call me jalal!
From which shop we should start
ram ram -
ram ram!
Will you buy it or will just stering it
how much price of this date?
1 gram of 3 coins!
And that seed?
1 gram of 2 coins!
Should i pack it?
No we'll buy flour seed!
Flour seed?
1 gram of 2 coins!
1 gram in 2 coins?
We bought on this price from landlord...
so we have to sell on that price!
He has too high price!
It seems that you came from high place
if you want to buy so buy it
or get lost!
Nonsence
you know whom you talking to?
Talking to... get lost!
Silence! Arrest him.
Whats happening?
Mylord... mylord... forgive me
we have to go back...
no stop... notings happening!
Thats what i want see!
This is unfair of darogas
he ruined us...
but he is loyal servant of royal kingdom!
Ohh man... you are newcomer?
Iook... one more blind in the blind town!
He's not seeing how much
foreigner are punishing us!
Who foreigner? That turkey, irani,
afghani... they all are damn foriegner
the castle of the king is full of foreigner!
But i heard that the king is very kind
and good person!
He is doing too much good activity for local people!
So why dont you go to him for complain about him
leave it dear... there is no one our...
who understand our problems
and we will not belive that the king is indian... and
whether the king or other they all are foreigner
perhaps you dont know that our king borned in
a hindu rajput family and grew up here!
So how can he be a foreigner?
He is indian too how much you are!
Really?
If he's india so what he did
yet for local peoples?
If this king is worried too much about peoples
so why he di'nt stop taking tax on tesri yatra
tax on tesri yatra?
It seems that you came newly in agra and
in this country too...
we hindu always paid tax
on tesri yatra!
Who is not worried who is fullfiled!
Who's local people like us!
Who cant endure that burden.
But no gain...
no one will listen!
Come on!
Is that was right decision
to see the market?
Atleast we understand that what is
thinking our fellow country mens
what kind of tax on tesri yatra is?
The hindu beliver goes to see thier god
on tesri yatra!
In the exchange of they have to pay
tax to royal kingdom!
Is they still paying us?
- Yes mylord!
So why dont you stop it!
This is extremly unfair!
One who pay the money
to see his god!
We had never think about it!
This is receiving from decades.
How can we prepared.
Attention peoples...
i want to annouce something important.
After thinking alot and worry i felt that
to receive tax on tesri yatra is just...
like to judge the greatness of god on
coins!
So therfore i decided to remove the tax on
tesri yatra!
Mylord... you thought very good...
i beg your pardon... i want to say something!
Permission granted.
How unfair is that... you forgot us...
we are also the member of royal castle
in this royal kingdom we participate
to built this kingdom!
We are consultant of yours mylord!
This strange decision of yours
why did'nt you discuss about it
before taking decision!
We did'nt feel to dicuss this!
To take intrest or not is
rights of kingdom...
we are not going against the islam!
This decision is goverment decision!
Not religious!
If this is government decision so
the treasure minister will not say
mylord this decision will
effect on royal treasure.
I wish to know what is royal treasure?
What is this treasure
we are not like others pirates
who steal hindustan money.
Who live in a love of money
this is our country
and we cant see wound on its body
and because of this i love my country fellow mens
without seeing their religion
thier is a noise when coin droped
no noise at the time of pick it up
its a request to you dont take
wrong decision in sentimental mood.
From childhood to till know
someone else taking decision of my life
i always told how to do when to do
now i want to be selfmade
now i will do what every i feel good
khan, announced that the tax should
remove forever on teen yatra have
built the command
queen jodha bai is coming
in dewan e aam.
I feel glad after see you here
i have to come
because you win my heart
lord, first time your nation feel
your love and brotherhood
thats why this nation is sorry for this nonsence.
They want to give you a name
akbar
jalal uddin mohammad akbar
i am very happy with this present
and i accept this present
long livel to jalal udidn akbar
the king got hurted!
Let the king to be rest!
We'll inform the situation about king
we are happy with you... there is no example
about your work!
Delhi is not far
the poision is spreading and fever is
getting high
its hard to control in level
i cant understand... who
attempt to murder the king.
Leave it... rajput family is again
on the way!
Means?
Means... that ifjalaludin could survive
so the revenge of attempting murder...
the government will never spare them.
If he cant survive... so the afghan and
forigener will never spare that chance.
You are absolutely right rana sahib.
Wisdom is that safe yourself.
Surjamal... we can be in this tie
but now the situation is changed
and by the way your this fight is personal.
Now you can make your rules...
we cant say you something about it!
Jodha... he getting sick
oh my god...
the king awaked
your country fellow men are waiting you
now you can rest!
Shareefuddin hussain
jalal knew that the attack on him is by you
his mens are coming to get us
dont be afraid
before win the agra must control ameer
ammer
but after ameer
sujhmal helps you?
Once control ameer then we will see sujhamal
shareefuddin is prepeared to attack on agra
know sujhmal is also supporting him.
For finished this scence give him his part of land
dont be worried
and shareef ud din have to stop him before ameer in amirta.
Sister you
time is very short
my husband kill your brother any time.
Jodha please try to stop this war
otherwise three relatives died in own blood.
It is very dengerous to go in a war
dodhamaal i decide already its very urgent to go
dont be worried.
Dear king there is a army from south
how much distance from us
almost 3 kilometer
2 kilometer
our sworders are ready
only waiting for your order
no
i want peace no war
khan up your flag to send him the signalof negotiation
i am sorry dear king to interupt
shareefudin thinks wrong
he start thinking we are week
thats what i want
sharefudin think us week and did any mistake
thats oke
up the flag
i knew thatjalaludin want to negotiate
manjum khan up the flag as for my acceptnance
and try to settle the army here
he didnt use elephant cuz of less speed
he have lots of food stock
cant effect on him if we stop them here
they fight with us long time
by shareefudin flirt our soldier who are enemy know
i want to get them back in in any case
are you ready appo
dont do any mistake join the akbar force
and after getting right time kill him
jalaluddin send a message to sujhmal that
they are ready to give him the part in goverment.
But this message can not passed to him
once king died then we kill shujamal
dont ask anything
we are not in colebration with sharefudin anymore
go with your army and meet with jalaluddin force
wht is this
why did i amazed you
u send him to inform jalaluddin
yes
because if you are real fighter
then face jalaluddin in battle
dont make a trap for him
trap
when u ask help again raja bharmal that was not trapped
where is your royality at that time
some horseman are coming toward us
sword mens be ready
he is sujhmal
sujhmal
please take out these arrows
yes mylord!
Shekhudin sent the
killer to kill you!
Thorow him!
Father is agreed to talk!
I did mistake to recognize you!
My lord!
Jodha will hurt... dont mension her
she is btrayer!
No shujawal... you considering wrong!
I did'nt belive her and ordered to arrest you!
Jodha is innocent.
What?
Sujamal brother.
Jodha i broke your holy strings
forgive me
dont say that!
I considered you wrong!
I hurted your respect!
Be happy always!
You are great
i was wrong!
I could not recognize you!
What ever you did forjodha
the next generation will remember you always!
Brother!
Bano saifudin is a rebel!
He betryard with us!
To punish the betyar is our religious duty
and ourjudgment
i dont know whatever they did was right or wrong
but now at your decision by mercy let it be!
My god what i do?
Why our peoples ruined by us always!
I was hoping by you...
but your bad luck is that i am safe!
If you had ask to have more province with ajmer!
You'll gain noting by betyer!
Except bloodshed!
You did not think about bloodshed when you
killed brutly adab khan!
That was diffrent metter shariffudin!
Its good that... you make the rule of game...
and broke the rule yourself!
This time i made the rule of game!
I am listening!
If you want so you can stop this bloodshed
how?
You have to fight with me!
Between us by hands!
If i won the india will be mine!
If i lose so i'll leave this country forever!
I am agreed!
What kind of idea to punish the betryer...
what did you agreed?
The bloodshed will stop by running on this way!
I am sorry to say mylord... but you are forgetting that...
shariffudin is very strong by body and he is fighter
i know that!
He is too strong
but i cant let the india
go on the wrong hands!
Shariffuddin!
If you wer'nt husband of bano so
this sword were in your body yet!
Just foresake her i forgive you!
I am taking back all your
province from you!
Now you cant take decision
in matter of kingdom!
Your wish mylord!
And whole life you will
be my loyal slave!
Yes mylord!
Hail the... king of the kingdom
jalaluddin mohammad akbar
respected peoples of kingdom...
the happiness of you life cant be divided by
anybudy!
We being a muslim... a muslim...
always we loved the other religion!
The peoples of our kingdom
are independend...
because they can belive
here religion and respect.
But alas!
That you cant understand me!
And this is my wish that you on the way
of god travel to the macca sharif!
And now i request to the rajput queen of india
that come near to me!
I am telling this last time to the presented
peoples of castle and the whole kingdom!
That queen jodha is hindu
rajput... and my wife!
And also queen of india!
To go against her is like going against kingdom!
Keep remember my words that to respect all religion
and to passion of endure will make next india goldenbird!
Ameen!
Is that enough for today khan?
Just pray for you safety!
This was the story ofjodha akbar!
There is no example of there love!
Or no one remmember there love
perhaps the history did not give it value!
But the truth is that the jodha
akbar made the history silencely
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org