- Gisela, I have to leave
- What are you leaving for?
- Gisela
- Oh, I see
Come on, let's go
- Ok, meet you at the English park tomorrow noon at twelve
- in front the cabin by the lake?
- Yes, Hans really should give me a phone call
- I'll remind him
- Has he calm down now?
- You shouldn't have yelled at him
Everything will be fine
Finally, you should have arrived earlier
Hurry, let's go
- Is this all?
- the rest has not arrived yet
"German people are shocked by soldiers who
fell into the abyss of death at Stalingrad
330,000 fellowmen are forced to
death and extermination step by step
by the great strategies of our strategists
meaninglessly and irresponsibly
Little Sophielein, if you can help Willi
he must be very happy
This is the stamp, and this is the address
Thanks
What to do with the rest?
I'll go deliver them at the college tomorrow
- Are you crazy?
- Willi, did you forget the female college students demonstrating at the Germany Museum a few days ago?
- almost succeed
- Gestapo have been in the first ground alert for this
- Hans...
- Don't forget our slogans are everywhere
Hans, before we have any new envelopes
we can hide the rest under the board
No need. There is nothing left.
Lack of paper
It's already pretty dangerous
to write slogans on walls at night
But compare with giving out flyers at
campus in the day time... Do you want to die?
We have to make our best efforts, cannot
wait anymore Let's bring along the whole city!
It's the most tense moment of the Stalingrad warfare
now. Nazi's secret agents are all over the campus!
If bolshevists come now,
just to kill them all...
- At least we can kill them once for all
- If I were you
I won't hope Soviet Union
comes before Americans
Don't you hate bolshevist the most?
Hans, are you crazy?
Don't go to deliver them in colleges!
I'll go when they are having classes,
nobody will be in the hall...
I'll come out soon, entering from
the front gate and get out from the back one
- It's too dangerous!
- Willi...
I will take all the responsibility
if anything happens.
Won't embroil others
You are going to walk through Schwabing
with a big suitcase?
Let's me take this
Hans, I don't think
we should embroil Sophie in this...
If we were to be checked,
it would be easier for a woman to pass
She is right
Alright, let's go
Alex, meet me in my place at twelve tomorrow
- Starting from tomorrow, no wait?
- We can wait, but Nazis won't
Thanks
Don't work too late
- Goodnight
Dear Lisa,
I'm listening to Schubert's Trout Quintet
I feel Schubert’s inspiration
is flowing in air
I can hear the happy tweedle of birds
and little creatures
The piano constantly repeats the same thematic
rhythm just like a clear, crystal creek
oh, they make me so enchanted
Wish I can hear from you soon
Best wishes, yours Sophie
Not sure if mom still have some jam?
This brand they only sell turnip juice now
Not conspicuous enough, right?
- We bring the light of hope into colleges today
- Yes
Good morning!
- Good morning
- We are going to a neurology hospital, you want to come along?
- Sophie is going to Ulm by bus. I will be there soon
- Hurry up
Hurry, hurry up
- There are some in the case, Hans
- What?
- No one is up there, wait a second
- I'm going with you
Freeze! Stop!
Stop right now!
You... don't run... stop!
- You are under arrested! Stop, damned
- What's wrong?
- You are under arrested!
- Ridiculous, how can you arrest us randomly!
- You are the only people upstairs, come with me
- We were coming out from the Department of Psychology
- You are handing out fly sheets
- Nonsense
Let go of him,
it's me taking off those sheets
Good you admit that. I'm going to report you
You come with me, both of you!
Believe me, even in my college you cannot
get away if you are doing that
"German people are shocked
by soldiers at Stalingrad... "
Come in!
So many? Unbelievable!
- They are all here?
- Yes!
You can go now!
Schmid, write a report
We will catch them all
There... there This college student
seems to have something in his hands...
Quick, give it to me!
Look, there is one more fly sheet
Give it to me!
Or you want me to do it myself?
They should be put together
- I'm Mohr, national police. Long live Hitler
- Long live Hitler
This two, they are under arrested for now...
- These are the documents I took over
- It's me took these two guys...
Do you have any ID?
- Ms. Sophia Magdalena Scholl?
- Yes
- Mr. Hans Fritz Scholl?
- Brother and sister?
- Yes
Female
21 years old...
so, you want to resist Reich that...
has already taken the whole Europe?
when the guy noticed be watched by me
he started ripping the paper in hands
an unacquainted classmate
handed it over to me forcedly
I ripped it 'cause I don't want
to bring any trouble
- Is this your case?
- yes, it's mine
Take it!
I've given the order to close off the college
any teachers and other personnel
shall not leave the school
Sure! certainly I will stay too
- go back and tell Alex to leave me alone
- Quiet!
Scholl, Hanz, get in the room
to Maller for inquest
follow me, madam!
come here please!
unlock cuff!
Thanks
Let's begin
sit down
Sophia Magdalena Scholl, from Ulm
born on May 9, 1992 in Forchtenberg
Christian, and your father?
Robert Scholl, mayor of Forchtenberg
- any professional nursery education before?
- yes, I have
currently live in Munich,
NO 13 Franz-Joseph ST.
- landlord's name is Smith?
- yes
- any criminal record?
- none
you have admitted right in front of the
dorm administrator that it was you...
who spreaded the fly sheets from balustrade
the fly sheets were on the marble handrail
I spreaded them casually
when I was passing by
why?
it's my nature, see anything,
move anything... that's it
I admitted it then and there
and I knew...
I made a stupid mistake
I am very regretted,
but things can not be changed anyhow
Miss Scholl,
you spreaded fly sheets in college
and it has violated
Kriegssonderstrafrechtsverordnung
do you want to know the punishment for
quislism and collaborationism?
- it has nothing to do with me
- imprisonment, labor reform...
- or execution
- it has nothing to do with me, definitely
- cigarettes?
- no, thanks
- but you do smoke, right?
- occasionally
perfect for this situation
just coincidence
why did you bring an empty case to school?
I planed to go to Ulm by car
pick up my clothes in house
- the clothes were taken home for washing by my mother
- back to Ulm?
it's not weekend now
you want to take that long trip back home?
- yes
- just for some clothes?
not only for the clothes, I also want
to visit a friend she just had a baby
- and, my mother was sick
- why didn't you wait till weekend?
so you skipped classes?
why did you go home so hurry?
because my friend suggested going to Hamburg
so I want to get back before weekend
I planed to take 12:48 train
and I already made the appointment with
my sister's friend in Heltz Station
you can ask him
- his name?
- Otto Aicher
he started from Solln
and reached Munich at 12... 11:30
- Aicher, start with an "e"?
- start with "a - i"
you didn't put clothes
in the case to Ulm for washing?
no, I wash my own small clothes
as for the big ones,
no one is needed for washing yet
so, it means you don't need clean clothes yet?
but just now you were saying...
you expressly bring an empty case to home
for washed clothes?
I was thinking that since I went back to Ulm
I should bring next week's clothes too
so you want to go back to Ulm
why did you still come back to school?
I had an appointment with a friend
her name is Gisela Schertling
we planed to have lunch together in the
cabin at British park lakeside at 12 noon
didn't you go to Ulm?
I decided that today temporarily
I came back to school
to cancel the appointment with Gisela
why did your brother accompany you to the school?
didn't you just come to cancel the appointment?
Hanz and I often go to school together
Hanz wants to go to neurosurgery school
dorm administrator said, about 11 o'clock
you two were on aisle of the third floor
- what were you doing?
- we were on the way searching for Gisela
she was in Pro. Huber's philosophy class
- but that was on 2nd floor
- yes, we were there 10 minutes early
so I took my brother
to psychology department for a look
most of my classes are in 3rd floor,
psychology department
where did you see the fly sheets?
you mean the paper? everywhere
- and you did not even take a look and see what it written?
- yes, I did, but only a glance
- my brother told a joke about this
- a political joke?
no, he said it wastes paper, he is
just like me not interested in politics
several days ago, when a district
principal gave speech in Germany Museum
a bunch of female college students made trouble
were you there?
No
- everybody should be there while in the speech
- I don't attend any politics
what do you think of the speech
given by district principal
as he mentioned...
girls should think about
how to give birth for leaders
while not fooling around in college
He said the ugly one
can marry to his adjutant
This is a taste problem
What you did in university
Already make you a suspect,
I seriously advise you
Don't be hesitate any more
to tell the truth
I deny that I have any connection
with this leaflet
Except the joke I made,
I understand that
The suspicion for us
before you finds the real wrongdoers.
- But my brother and I has nothing to do with this
- Do you really think?
You can hide it before me when answer
the question? What do you think?
All I told you are truth
Mrs. Scholl, my co-worker did not
Find anything leaflet in that case, you
brother's Confession also proved what you said
You can relax now
I never worried
Let the recorder come in
I will let her to record my statement
You have to listen carefully
If there is any conflict with your affidavit
You must tell me right away
- Are you clear, Mrs. Scholl?
- Yes
Although this will be kept
in your criminal record
But, we will see
Maybe you still can go to Ulm
according to the plan
It is over
Metternich! Retirement certificate
Hail Hitler
Mr. Sch¨¹rmer, follow me
You students think you can be here
Fool us?
Please hand out your jewellery, watch
We already made up our mind to
Use our lives to resist
Do not consider the world surrounding us
- No matter understand the necessity of this war or not
- Necklace and pendant
The time for a full scale war already comes
Follow me
Let us say farewell to fear
and meaningless hesitation
In this fight with fate
Abide our rule: clean my leather coat
But do not make me wet!
(Means the law deprive citizen's right for consultation in 1935)
- Please take off you cloth and give it to me
It is great danger
We must put into huge effort
If you still have any illegal stuff, give it me
I help you throw them in to toilet
I am also a prisoner
Now, that time is coming
I have nothing
Please take off your gloves
OK, let's continue
Tomorrow will knee down
to thank us our acceptance for him
Ladies, get in, hurry, hurry,
I want to listen to the lecture
Do you know how my brother is now?
Your brother already had it
He is waiting with other men up there
You are the main suspect
Because you have the case
Leaflets are threw down by your too
Do not admit anything!
I admitted nothing
How long have you been here?
One year and five days
They caught one of my letters, I quoted
Words that Ludwig-Thoma criticizes Hitler
- Even though, you still work for those people
- They order me to do this
The reason why I am here
Is to prevent you to commit suicide
- Why are you again Nazi?
- My brother and I are communist
Even my brother has a very
senior position in an insurance company
I admire the selfless help in communist party
People have to do something
Scholl Sophia, go with me!
I hope, we never see each other, good luck!
You too, good luck!
Wait here
OK, Mrs., your release paper
You are lucky this time
Please speak up
Understood
Follow me, follow me
You can take off your coat
Sit down
Your father was put into jail for 6 weeks
Because you call our leader is
God's punishment for human being
He was arrested for the crime of conspiracy
Also his license was revoked too
I want to know. You join Hitler Jugend
What do you dad think about that?
My dad never influence
our political preference
Typical democrat
Why do you join Hitler Jugend?
Because I heard that
Hitler will bring our nation glory
Good luck and fortune,
everyone will have job and bread
Everybody will enjoy freedom and happiness
- You are single?
- I am engaged
With Fritz Hartnagel
He is a commander of eastern front
Stalingrad?
Yes
- When was the last time you see each other?
- Half year ago
Have you seen this gun before?
My brother had a gun like this
He was sergeant in army
Why do you have 190 bullets in your drawer?
9mm bullets?
They are also my brother's
When was the last time you buy stamps?
- About two week ago
- Where did you buy, and how many did you buy?
Leopoldstrasse street, post office 23
Ten 12 cents and five 6 cents
I can't remember exactly
- Only those, you did not buy more?
- No
Have you seen these stamps?
No
- Are you sure you never seen them?
- Never
This was what we found in your brother's room
Why did you never mention...
Your brother has a lot stamps?
Your question is when and where
I bought stamps recently
one hundred and forty?
who needs that many of stamps? for what?
what you need to send out?
compliment to friends and relative,
we are in touch.
- so, your have seen those stamps?
- I am just guessing.
you found those from
my brother's place, not mine
is this your typewriter?
it was in my brother's room,
we borrowed it from landlord.
- she lent to us to type something.
- what thing?
An essay about philosophy and theology
- not for typing those handbills?
- No
An essay about philosophy and theology?
something like...
"Hitler could not win this war,
only keep it going"
or "a criminal cannot give Germany victory"
or "federation is the future of Germany,
freedom of speech, freedom of religion"
Hans didn’t write those
- You wrote those?
- No
- but you believe this kind of world order
- I don't care about politics, and I won't
anyway, we compared all those writing,
and all those bullshit
are done by this typewriter,
then at the beginning of this month,
they are sent to different addresses,
include Munich
I have no idea about this
sit there!
watch it!
all those bullshit were from your
brother's place and your were there
and he was planning to destroy all those bills
Have you seen those paper before?
- No
- keep your lie, but read this for me.
"two hundred thousands German died...
- just for one war opportunist"
- Does this remind you something?
Is it similar to other six handbills?
Take look at the handwriting
- I don’t know
- Listen to me!
this part of evil speaking comes from
a guy named Christoph Probst
He is a friend of your at Innsbruck.
We found his letter.
Exactly same handwriting!
Probst is also a student in astrology
love family and mountains of motherland.
An other do oneself proud bastard
Never understand people are dying at battlefront.
who is in, beside you,
your brother and that Christoph Probst.
- who did those bills?
- please stop slandering me?
You held back all those evidence from your home
Even I asked you to give me the truth
I just admit what I really did
how about listen this,
your brother, was just like you,
how to explain those evidence
"the military plan failed at eastern line...
U.S.A and British military force
increased unpredictability.
I concluded that we could not win this war
after painfully thinking in long time...
I believe that avoiding
the meaningless death...
and keeping the integrality of Europe
the only way is finish the war
as soon as possible, in the other hand,...
I also have deep fear about the way we treat
the occupation area and people in the area"
that is just his political point,
not exculpation to your slander
this is...
...disorganizing army
and betraying our country!
I don’t believe my brother said that!
So you think your brother was lying to us?
Before my brother talk to me personally,
I won't believe that he said those
Eickemayer Studio
you heard about it?
Yes
Eickemayer is at Krakau in recent few months,
he gave the key...
of studio to us, let us take a look
the fingerprint on the copymachine...
they are your brother's
your brother has admitted
he designed,
copyed and handed out
all six kinds of handbills.
He tried to make me believe that, he sent out
five thousand handbills in Munich at one night
you lived with your brother
you were all in the hallway this morning
and you still want me believe
that you have nothing to do with this?
you think all these slander
are meaningless? Just admit it!
You and your brother made
and sent those handbills!
YES! and I am proud of it!
what will happen to me and my brother?
You should think about
this at beginning Miss Scholl
- Our relative will be embroiled?
- I can't decide it
- I have to go to washroom
- Not now!
Who draft out these?
- Me!
- You are lying Miss Scholl! Just few weeks ago...
we did the writing check
from the report,
we are sure they are from a male.
Your brother is the author and the planner!
- who mailed out these handbills?
- my brother and I
excuse me, I have to go to washroom
Locher!
Washroom!
follow me
Hurry!
open the handcuffs, it hurts!
What are you doing with them?
you know, Miss Scholl?
there is no leeway...
you know it, next door to the left
Who wrote these banner “Step out! Hitler!"...
"FREEDOM"...
and a crossed NSDAP badge,
University Ludwig street
Marienplatz Kaufinger street
and Schwabing everywhere
my brother and I
Your brother said after he got arrested
"go back home...
tell Alex don't wait for me"
Schertling was right there
He was telling Schmorell to run away?
Hans had a appointment with Schmid,
he didn’t want him wait for nothing.
- You mentioned about your plan to Schmorell?
- No
- and Graf?
- why are you keep lying?
- I did not
here
this is your confession! Sign it!
Locher!
take her out!
I heard about Mohr told Locher:
this kind of people...
is what Germany needs
but we have to re-educate them
Maybe they will try to
rebuild your world view
but I will tell you, they may just wait
- why?
- even the bosses are impatience
a lot people think allied forces will
get into Germany in eight to ten weeks
after that sooner or later,
Germany will be liberated
If my mother know I am under arrest
She won't stand the shock
She is over 60,
and she is sick all the month
If Gestapo goes to my house...
she my get in jail cause us...
and your father?
He is 10 years younger than my mom,
he always bring us the immaterial power
your mom is not alone.
Thanks
"we are not silence,
we are the forgotten conscience
White roses let you cannot sleep in peace!"
- Who are "us"?
- My brother wrote this.
at the last line of 4th handbill,
"please copy...
and pass around",
and here is about resist movement
- doesn't sound like couple peoples' crime
- We don’t have organization
How much you know about Willi Graf?
Sergeant he has same major as my brother
came to our house sometimes.
we knew he helped you guys
copying the handbills at the studio
Maybe you found his fingerprint
- but he went to studio at other time.
- When?
Middle of January,
We were going to see Eickemayer' painting
that's the reason why
others' fingerprints are in studio
- who were there? Schmorell?
- Maybe, I don’t know
I was just there at beginning,
then I went to concern
- Probst brought handbills to Salzburg and Linz?
- No
Hans didn't tell him anything,
cause he has wife and three children
here, you have to tell me the damn truth,
I am asking you.
Who is in?
Graf Anneliese?
I totally met them about 10 times.
- what did you talk about?
- about lecture and science
- My impression of Graf is that he has no interested in politics
- no interested but knew the inside?
I have to say Graf has nothing
to do with the handbills
- how about Schertling?
- Gisela met me several times.
we studied in same university,
and we knew each other before that.
- she is NSDAP
- as your saying Miss Scholl
The member of resist movement is everywhere in Germany
they all look like have no interested in politics
It is good for your, isn’t it? Mr. Mohr
As our counting,
this so called "white rose"...
bought ten thousand papers in Jan...
and two thousand envelops
- who did that?
- my brother and I
only hundreds of handbills
for the 1st to 4th.
it makes sense.
But you wish I believe you two
copied thousands of handbills
for the 5 and 6th edition?
- then sent them out?
- we worked on them day and night.
I admire you and you take class
at the same time?
yes we were faking
there are lots of members
we knew your brother Graf Schmorell
Furtw?ngler and Wittenstein served
at eastern line before.
all the people got in university in Munich
any political movement between them?
My brother just told me
about innumerable death.
- but never talked about his comrade
- I don't believe you Miss Scholl
At this period, everyone is careful
about their political speech.
Just like what you say in the handbill?
you found these address there?
copy from phonebook of German museum
let's take a look at Stuttgart:
Jan 27th and the morning after, totally...
sent out seven hundred handbills!
same day at Munich...
about two thousands handbills were sent out.
Just you and your brother
cannot done this job!
I took the fast train
to Stuttgart at 27th...
handbills were in a case,
when I arrived...
I threw half of them
into the post-box of station.
all the left I put
into the post-box at country side
your brother couldn’t be
at Munich in Jan 20th...
when we found the addresses from phonebook...
he sent out an other two thousand handbill
in different place? who was helping him?
I wasn't at Munich
who support you money?
my father gave me one fifty each month.
my brother has pay from army
How can you afford your life and
all the handbills and postage?
every time you trip to Ulm,
it took you 15 mark
- we borrowed some money from friends
- from who?
here, up left corner...
"E" must stand for income
- it is the backer's name after amount?
- Yes
your fiancé were in?
- so he knew it!
- No!
every time we borrow,
we give a pretence.
you can ask everyone
my brother and I are the only members
have you thought about
if you and your brother
assume all the crime,
what will happen to you?
We know every name!
Miss Scholl, think about it
and cooperate with us!
we will reconsider your punishment
think about your poor parents
and the shame you brought to them
so, right now you want me...
to sell out your so called partisan
for my own good
exposure criminal is not sellout
my brother's classmate
has nothing to do with this
Launa
take her away
I am very worried about Fritz
how could I write her name in my note?
- he was sold out?
- absolutely not
- he really has not found anything?
- nothing at all
his loyalty is just like a solider
keeps his oath to Hitler
and we had fights for this many times
I am always against supporting the front line
because this will prolong the war
and it makes him angry
- is he in Stalingrad too?
- he used to be there
luckily, he was transferred to Lemberg
as the last group
he lived in Lazaret
Doc cut off two of his fingers
because he and his people had lain in
frozen open air all day and all night
for several weeks in 30¡ãF
I really hope he can survive from the war,
while not become its victim
what will happen
if Fritz knows you were here?
he shall understand me
hope so
what does he look like?
tall, brown hair
a free elf
and he can always make me laugh
love, this unconditional love,
is so amazing
when was the last time you saw him?
last summer,
we were in Karolinensiel of Nordsee
early morning, we sailed out
and went to the beach
by bike together in the evening
singing, chat and talk about peace at night
no solider, no plane and no bomb
only the sea and sky
sea breeze and our dreams
dear God, what can I do besides confiding you
there is nothing I can do
but to leave you my own heart
you create us,
and our hearts are so tense
only to be with you,
I shall find peace inside
Amon
here you are, drink it
it's the coffee
made by authentic coffee bean
for you, Miss Scholl, this also means
the happiness of Deutschland, right?
- yes
- and you are not like Elser
put bomb in B¨¹rgerbrukeller in Munich 1939
although you chose the wrong slogan
you made a peaceful way
so why do you guys want to punish me anyway?
because of the law!
no law, no order!
the law you referring used
to defend people's liberty of speech
before Hitler took power in 1933
but now, under his government
people who deliver free speech are treated by heavy penalty
or death and does order have anything to do with this?
if we don't abide by the law
what else should we abide?
- abide by the law, no matter whose law it is
- that depends on your conscience
what?
this is the law
this is the people
I, as a police officer am amenable to check
whether people's behavior matches the law
and if it doesn't
- I have to figure out where the problem is
- law can be changed
- conscience won't
- what if everyone...
judge right and wrong by his conscience
what result would it become?
and what if the criminals succeed in dropping
the reins of government what will it be?
unavoidably, there will be serious chaos
and those so called freethinking
federation, democracy, we used to have
we know where that will lead us to
everyone will regain his right and order
if there is no Hitler, his party and...
protect to autocratic personal rejection
not just protect people going with the stream
autocratic, main stream
- you are just disdainful
- no, you are
you consider my brother and me as criminals
just because of those sheets
although we've done nothing then
only words tried to convince you
you have privilege,
you and your relatives use this privilege shamefully
you can use our money
for college during wartime
with damn democracy,
all I've learned is slaughter
do you know who made me become a policeman?
French who occupied Pfalz
not German democracy,
if there wasn't this campaign
I was still a policeman
in the countryside of Pirmasens today
shameful Versailles Treaty,
inflation, unemployment
Economic crisis, our leader Adolf Hitler
swept off all of this
and also lead Germany to a doomed war
- it's free of charge for all of the Victims
- in this heroically war
you and us that you disdain and fight against
both feed ourselves
no matter what happens
you live a better life than we do
you absolutely have no need to do so
actually you still said that
our leader and Deutschland are protecting you
among this, in Wittelsbacher Palais
or my family with background
our German soldiers are liberating Europe from
money-supremacy and
Bolschewisten,
and for a wider and free Germany
Germany's territory will not be occupied
you have my words
at the end of the war
foreign troops will garrison
people will point at us
saying we didn't fight against Hitler
if we win out at last
after bleeding and sacrifice German people
will live a richer and free life as your dream
and at that moment, as a member of BDM
what will you say?
German people don't have that belief any more
while under Hitler's rule
If it really come true,
should I say this?
- Are you a prophet?
- Yes
Even the Church is asking
the disciples to follow their lead.
- Even in  despair
- In Church, everyone is free
But Hitler and Nazis
will not give them other choices
Why a young person like you will take
this kind of risks for these wrong ideas
For my own conscience
I don't understand, with your talent
you can't understand and feel right
about National Socialist German
Freedom, Honor, Wealth
A morally responsible country,
this is our faith
Nazi in the name of freedom and honor
Bloodshed the entire Europe
Even this can not wake you up?
If the German youth can not finally relieves Hitler from
his power and help together make a new, better Europe
then Germany will always be a shameful name
New Europe only can
be the national socialism nature
If your leader is a lunatic
Think about national hatred! at Ulm
A Jew teacher was brought before SA-Gruppe
Everyone was ordered to walk
in front of him and spit on his face
At that night, he is gone.
Disappeared like thousands disappeared in 1941
forced to the eastern frontline
You believe these bullshits?
The Jews moved away themselves
Soldiers from eastern frontline were already
talking about slaughters in the concentration camp
Hitler wants to kill all Jews in Europe
He was promoting this absurd idea 20 years ago
How could you believe?
Jew are different from us
This guy will only bring us bad luck
But you
are only a young girl has been misled
by wrong teaching
Probably it's our own fault I feel someone like
you should be a member of our Bund deutsche Maedel
You known, when I learned
Nazis are killing mentally impaired children
with poison gas, how shocked was I?
My mom's friends has described to me
how the children from Church Welfare program were taken from the caretakers
Taken away by trucks
The kids were asking
"Where does the truck go?"
"Going to heaven" Caretakers answers
So the kids got on the truck and singing.
I have the same feelings like them.
You think I am not taught well?
These are invaluable lives
You have heard from the caretakers
They have mental patients.
Yes, I clearly know
under any circumstances,
nobody will be treated
like a person created by God.
Nobody knows, what the soul
of a mental patient is like?
nobody knows, that innate,
incredibly mature existence without body
every life has it's value
You must get used to this coming new age
What you have said is not reality
What I said is related to reality and custom
- Relate to Moral God
- God doesn't exist
You believe what your brother did is right?
You are just an accomplice
It's not like that?
Should we write down like this
No, Mr. Mohr
Because it is not the truth
You known, I have a son.
He is one year younger than you
He sometimes has some weird crazy ideas
But now he is in eastern frontline
Because he knows he must perform his duty.
Mr. Mohr, do you believe out final victory?
Ms. Scholl, if you think about everything
you wouldn't involved in these activities
This is about your life
Here. This is what I wrote
According to our questioning
Below conclusions were drawn
Your brother's and your Behavior
In wartime,
it is a crime again the Nazi Party
Especially in the eyes of
tough fighting army from the eastern frontline
You must face severest punishment.
but in my eyes
confession is not equal to betrayal
Maybe like this,
I rather say. Not mine
but your world view is flawed
Like before, same viewpoint
I have done what is right for my people
I have no regrets I will solely take
all responsibility for all consequences
notekeeper, keep the record.
yes.
like boss know, we are done shortly
If we swear to give up our ideal
Mohr will make a bridge for us with gold
- Really?
- I wouldn't take that risk
Why not?
Sophie, you are so young
you have to live for your ideal and yourself
for your family
For god's sake, take his help
There is no way back
Air Raid Alert
Get down, don't stand beside the windows
get down on the ground is the safest
Get down
Won't take long
we are free
The one just took is not Schmorell
It is Christoph Probst
Same, Treason
I am really sorry
I thought
He has 3 kids
the youngest was just born.
His wife got puerperal fever
Ms. Scholl, you must go see litigant now
Hurry
This is my litigation
your case will be judged at Munich Civil Court
by a senior judge
I have submitted court order
- is it going to be tomorrow?
- no one wants to see it delayed
treason, cause damage to nuclear power station
it will be a public hearing
what a glorious day
I sincerely pray to you
to call upon you
even if you might not know anything about this
I am still hoping to get some comfort from you
I pray to you
My Lord, please don't abundant me
My dear father, please do not abundant me
Amen
My name is Klein, I am your lawyer
appointed by the court
have you seen the court order?
- I have read it
- any questions?
what would happen to my parents
who live in Ulm
Please
it will be considered in a separate case
I just want to know what would happen to them
aren't you my lawyer?
the way you said it as if I was responsible
for the state that you are in
I am entitled to know what would happen
to my family and you know that
do you think you have right to make a request?
whatever comes to my older brother
I don't want a mild sentence
from your angle, I am just guilty
as he is
is there anything more that you
wish to add?
- no
- regarding your brother and you, you are saying
you don't actually want to be a German Citizen
are you sure about that?
the chairman of the people's court will
arrive here from Berlin tomorrow
he will make you forget about this non-sense
you just said, young lady
he will make you and your older brother
feel sorry for what you did
open the door
- any questions?
- no no, see you in court tomorrow
what a coward
Freisler will be suing both of you tomorrow
he used to an USSR police officer
he has to prove his loyalty
our father used to say: I hope you
can live forever in honesty and freedom
however difficult the circumstance it may be
will there be people from the public?
Mmm, there will be
It is a show, to warn others
then Freisler will surely mention leaflets
in front the whole crowd
everyone is going to listen to our view
the students definitely will
maybe a riot, if they know this
was only because of a few leaflets
the result will be an embarrassment for them
the worst scenario would be that
everyone gets shot in 99 days
my older brother once said that
we need to be tough and yet compassionate
I once dreamed that
I was holding a child in my chest
who wore a long white skirt
I could feel her warmth...
suddenly, the earth shook
the ice beneath our feet cracked
I began to slip, then I saw the child
luckily I had enough time to move her
to a safer ground
I felt, but I felt liberated and relaxed
the long white skirted child is our ideal
it survived
- Scholl, stop it
- she should have worn appropriate cloth
thank you
- let God be with you, Sophie
- let God be with you, Elser
thank you so much
- how are you?
- and yourself?
be quiet, you only answer
when are you are asked
- you must fight for yourself
- be quiet please
- heil Hitler
I hereof announce, the No. 1 court of people
opens the case for
Hans Fritz Scholl, Sophie Magdalena Scholl
from Munich
and Christoph Hermann Probst from Aldrans
to cause damage to nuclear power station
and to protect enemies
Probst Christoph
you are married with 3 children?
yes, 2 and a half, 1 and 3 months
and 4 weeks old
regardless your irresponsible behavior
how are you suppose
- to bring your children up to be real Germans
- I am a good father and
and what?
have no Political ambition
he is saying he does not have any Political
ambitions, that almost made me laugh
is this your handwriting
- yes
- it was not because of benefit
from a socialist government
it was a nation's social politics
gave you the chance to have your family
and stopped Scholl's request to write
an article based on
this Stalingrad female hero's story
to portrait our leaders as military exploiters
so that she will surrender
yes, it was just a thought
the word "just" does not exist
when German people have to fight to survive
but I had to admit, I was really
depressed at the time when I wrote this
really? you were depressed at the time?
was that the reason?
the thought went into my head when
I was really depressed
the war, my wife's fever after giving birth
all of these...
Aha, listen everyone
this will not help you to escape from your crime
I had denied it in writing yesterday
plus, I need to clarify that
I did not use finance
or any other way to spread rumors
manipulate anyone
- what my true intention was
- yes, we have heard
you said you were a manipulated idiot
so you can be spared
Mr. Chairman, my children need their father
German children do not need a father like you
you are not worthy, Probst
- defendant, do you have any other questions?
- no, Mr. chairman
bring him down
Scholl, Hans
- You have read medicine since 1939?
- yes
and still thankful for this socialist government
giving you the chance to have
- benefit of 8 terms of study
- it is 8 terms
you spent this nation's money
like a parasite
during the time, you were serving at
a mobile war medical unit
and worked as a medical staff on the
front line between July and November 1942?
it was also true but
I want to say is that
- please be quiet before I ask you
- I want to say that I am not a parasite
shut your mouth or I will have you removed
from this court
to serve as a soldier was a duty
from the medicine school
oh, we will talk about duty
as an university student, you have the
duty to lead an example life
and you were provided with
benefit from the Kingdom
but this did not stop you at the
beginning of summer 1942
giving out 4 "white rose" leaflets
to spread the negative rumor that German
will one day be defeated in the war
and used any possible chances
to change German people's way of life
in a socialist society
- and to destroy their government
- it is outrages
- all lies
- traitors
Scholl
you also have harbored your sister
- it was my decision
- did I ask you, defendant?
- I need to speak out the truth
- your view will not influence our judgment
did you write this leaflet?
did you believe that German people will only
survive through selling out their own country?
- the way will not
- answer yes or no, it is not a difficult question
we do not have a chance to fight against
the US, the UK and the USSR at the same time
look at the map for yourself
Hitler is leading Germans to a sheer hell
he can't win this war, he is only
extending the time of suffering
did you think German's fighting spirit
was no match for theirs
you promote the enemy
will lead more German casualties
the only way to stop more casualties
is to win it quickly
- win the war? how?
- to stop more casualties
you think you alone can decide
the outcome of the war?
what German wants is just a war
German's blood had bled dry, they want
peach, Hitler and his supporters
will be responsible for the genocide
this far excided just a war
every one knows that
- everyone?
- who are you talking about?
you are a mad dog
how dear you trying to bite in a high court
many of audience here as well as myself
went to the war in the east
but you did not
I have seen with my own eyes the bloodshed
in Poland and USSR
staring at the women and children
- killed by German soldiers
- and you naively thank that
people here will believe your non-sense
if Hitler and yourself are not afraid
of our thoughts
- then we will stand here today
- shut your mouth
what a shameless liar
you are an idiot, a traitor
case closed
- any more questions?
- no
- I have no further question, Mr. chairman
- Scholl Hans, get back to your seat
Sophie Scholl
you have giving out leaflets in university
- aren't you ashamed of what you have done
- no, I don't feel so
giving out leaflets in university
is that all?
no, I wanted to have
speak louder, we can not hear you
I wanted to give out the last lot
of leaflets
- so, our ideal can be quickly...
- ideal? you call this filthy your ideal
so dumb, you are not worthy being
a German University student
- we fight with our words
- so you wrote
¡°Nazi will ruin your lives¡±
have a look at yourself
and look at the low class people
where did you get the paper
to make the leaflets?
- bought from university
- oh, from university
you have stolen them while there is
a shortage of paper
this is treason
my brother and I tried to use these leaflets
to awaken German people to stop the blood shed
against the Jews
and not to wait for the other 3 countries
to finish us off
do we want to be expelled from the world
hated by all the nations?
a dominating nation will not care about this
your dominating nation wants peace
to find pride in peach
it wants God, Conscience and compassion
and what is your point?
war will bring German victory
it will become stronger, more pure
after the war
what we said and wrote was also
believed by many
- they just do not dare to say it
- you can shut your mouth then
- do you have more questions to ask me?
- no
session finished, take her away
we will now sum up the
defendant. Statements
- I am
- Please ask them to leave the court
I am Robert Scholl, the father of
two of the defendants
- I want to clarify a few points
- I did not permit you to do so
- get out, take him out
- this is about justice
Silence!
Now for your last statement
defendants, rise please!
- Probst?
- I beg you to spare me, for the sake of my children
I admit and repent everything I have done
And you, Scholl?
I beg you, your honor. Spare this man,
and punish me instead.
If you have nothing to say in your own
behalf, be silent!
Sophia Scholl?
Soon, you shall stand where
we are standing right now.
Every decent human being in this room is
indignant because of what you have said
In name of the German people
The following charges against
Hans Fritz Scholl from Munich
Sophia Magdalena Scholl
from Munich...
And Christoph Hermann Probst
from Aldrans...
are recognized by the 1. senate of the
supreme court...
on February 221943:
The defendants have been sending out flyers
during the war, in order to sabotage
the Arms production and to overthrow the
National Social way of life of our people
To propagandize dangerous ideas and
to disgrace our leader
By doing so helped the enemies
of this country,
and demoralized our troops.
Therefore you are sentenced to death.
You are deprived of any rights as citizen
of this country
You will cover the expense of this trial
Your terror will be over soon
Today you hang us, and tomorrow it
will be your turn
Take them away!
- Heil Hitler!
This way!
If you have anything to say before
your execution...
Please make it short,
Ms. Scholl.
It is today?
I was told, everybody has 99 days...
You should start writing.
Come, somebody is here to see you
See me?
Please don't be afraid
Given the choice, I would still
do the same thing
You did everything well,
I am proud of you
My little girl
Mama...
How you stand here right before me,
brave and steadfast.
Now, you will never again come
in through our door.
We shall meet again in the eternity
Go, Sophie.
Jesus...
Yes, Mother, you too...
Ms. Scholl, please
I have just said farewell to my parents
They will understand
Come with me, please
Ms. Scholl, my name is Alt.
I am the priest in this prison
God, oh almighty father
make this earth fruitful
So the seeds you sow do not fall in vain
Let hope grow, oh my creator,
for those who will only see it for
the last time
- Amen.
I beg you to give me the blessing of God
God the father gives you his blessing,
for you are created by his own image
God the son gives you his blessing,
for his suffering and death have saved you
God the holy spirit gives you his blessing
for he has taken you to his sacred temple
Oh, all mighty God
Have mercy in your judgment
and grant you,
the eternal life
- Amen
No one's love is greater than those who sacrifice
their own life for their friends
God is with you
This is against the regulation, but...
Please hurry
Thanks
It is not in vain.
Ms. Scholl.
The sun is still bright in the sky
Sophia Magdalena Scholl
The national attorney general has decided
on 22.2.1943,
that no pardon will be granted.
So the justice shall run like a river
It is 17:00
The death sentence is to be carried out
Long live the Freedom!
The 6th flyer from the "White Rose"
was brought by Helmuth von Moltke
through Scandinavia to England
Millions of copies were...
air dropped by the allied planes
over Germany in 1943
The title is:
A German flyer,
Manifest of Munich students