The south, 24 stores.
Never tried.
which side?
-east. The Hardest.
Can you do it with your eyes closed?
Questions?
-no.
Meeting at 6 o'clock.
Kamel.
Come on.
Come quickly down.
Do you know how early it is?
-They are doing Les Bleuets.
Yeah right.
-Really. I saw them.
Come.
-I’m coming.
I know it is going to be cool.
Groovy.
Hello, police?
incredible.
I was just going for a drink.
-I don't believe you.
Then you don't believe me.
-You where with that girl.
Which girl?
Pure class.
Cool.
Im not doing this everyday.
There is the police.
-They are always coming to late.
go go.
come on, hurry.
Forward, men.
We get them. come on.
This time they don't escape.
This time I must have them.
Come on, run. Run.
Hurry. Hurry.
Come on. We will nail them.
Go away, boys.
This is a police operation.
Opera, you mean?
-Go, or I will arrest you.
Aren't we to big?
Call for backup.
Do you want a punch, kid?
-Come, we are going.
I want my peace.
Its everyday the same song.
Men, they are here.
Come on, hurry.
Forward, boys.
Come on, hurry, hurry.
We believe in it.
We believe in it, we believe in it.
Good morning, commissaries.
-I’m sick of it.
I can smile,
but don't threat me as a fool.
Briefing.
oke. we re-start.
The Yamakasi's.
Seven neighbourhood kids are making a fool of us.
We are going to change that.
I will introduce them.
ousmane Dadjacan...
...alias zicmu.
The best one to open the ball.
What?
Whats now again?
-Is that your son on the balcony?
Come in.
-our regards, Madame.
Go.
Open the door, this is the police.
On three we will crush the door.
One... two... three.
No.
Don't do it. We are sorry.
You are only making to much noise.
No.
-A mistake.
That was no mistake,
but very stupid.
Who will fall for that,
will get one week street patrol.
The next one.
Jean-Michel Lucas alias Tango.
The second Fred Astaire.
You will see the thunder.
and it is always the same.
What is going on?
-Good morning, miss Boutin.
What do you want?
-Miss...
Miss.... get to work.
There has been slowing down enough already.
When I get him, he will not dance long.
And put yourself together.
This is Abdou n'Goto...
...alias Rocket.
He is not light, but he is a rocket.
Never mind.
Next time better.
You wait and see.
I will get him one day.
And speaking about getting...
This one escapes every time.
Bruno Duris alias the Spider.
The Spider...
Stop it, Your messing up my clothes.
-Sorry.
Can I walk you to work?
-I will look.
hup, hup.
But there is worse.
Malik n'Diaye alias wezel.
he girls, look.
Salto... look.
And this.
Girls, look.
What are you doing, men?
Put that trampoline back.
Terrible.
Just laugh. But with the next one
you will stop laughing.
Baseball.
Real name: oliver Chen.
No. Stop the thief.
Stop the thief.
Stop the thief. Help.
Stop him.
How is it possible?
They think they are hero's.
-They are criminals.
Buildings are no klimtorens.
-They steal nothing.
It's their hobby.
-o, are we their hobby?
We have got enough work already.
Let them play soccer like everybody does.
Chef...
-silence, Asmine.
We are here to life by the law.
The law says: Do not climb on buildings.
Do not take people out of there bed
and don't make fun at the police.
Is that understood?
And at the end, the last one of the group:
ousmane Bana.
Alias Sitting Bull.
Come on, Sitting Bull.
On a nice day he will fall.
And I wanna see that.
Japan has his seven samoerais,
the VS has seven hirelings...
...and we get the seven jerks.
You will arrest them. The city is no zoo.
And before the end of the week...
...otherwise I will call the special force
and Monday it will be... safari.
Get to work.
Hello, cousin. What brings you here?
Good news?
Good and bad.
-You fired?
not yet.
-oke, and now the good news.
I have no shift now.
I come to talk to you as a friend.
I’m scared now.
In the office they have a big file of you.
The chef hates you.
That's a compliment.
-Keep quite for a while.
Why don't you go to the mountains?
Nice chalet, pannkeeks
and all day climbing.
Why? We didn't do nothing?
Some people are mad at you.
And what to think about the parents?
why?
The kids admire you.
they are trying to be you.
Bulling the police, that’s cool.
But you are trained.
One day a boy will fall.
How will you react?
I’m just a little inspector.
My power is small.
Very small.
And with Arabic blood
it will lesser then normal.
If you don't want to work together,
I can do nothing.
Mom is giving a party .
She is making kip-combo. wanna come?
When your mother makes it...
we play Yamakasi.
-come.
Come, Djamel.
-I can't. My hart.
That's not true you don't want to climb.
Are you a sissy?
I can't.
-and pee, may you do that?
Are you going to run forever?
Come, let see that you are
a Yamakasi.
Come, everybody is watching.
You can do it.
Proof that you are a Yamakasi.
Its a little three.
And we yel at you.
Djamel. Djamel.
Come on, Djamel.
-Let see that your a Yamakasi.
Come on, Djamel. Climb.
Your almost there.
don't do stupid, your almost there.
Come.
Djamel.
Djamel, no.
Miss El hadj? with Mme Guerin
from school. I wanna talk about Djamel.
Ala, come quick.
It goes about Djamel.
Good afternoon.
It's all right.
It's all right, It's all right.
This time its worse.
No physical activity.
He has to go to school?
And now? what is going to happen?
He must have a transplant within
24 hours, and...
no.
He is on the list right?
You said so.
Off course,
but this is complicated, Ala.
he has priority,
but there must be a donor.
on a good moment.
And the list changes every hour.
What can we do?
Can we do nothing?
Come on.
Just as I suspected, nothing in France.
What can we do?
-not much. wait.
Sometimes we get donors very
late. we have to keep hoping.
And outside Of France?
That’s something else.
That goes by a firm.
We can look for you.
I got one here.
In Swiss.
Dead in a couple of hours.
And there is no option on it.
-What does that means?
That is not reserved..
its available.
In a couple of hours.
And how are going to work for
that option?
official I can't do anything.
But looking at the fast needs
I could try something.
Try it. we will accept.
Do you know how much it costs?
-no.
Minimum FF 400.000.
We don't have that.
Try the neighbours or friends.
All little things will help.
And the insurance?
The transplantation is covered.
But not the extra things.
I’m willing to help you
to take the risk.
So, now you have an option on it.
Its reserved.
The little Djamel will get his new hart.
You have till tomorrow afternoon.
The ball is on your side now.
Do you want us dead?
-You don't die from music.
put the noise down a little please,
my head begins to pop.
Take an aspirin.
-I already did.
I can cry about you, wezel.
Really cry.
And, are my mates not cool?
Look out.
-Sorry, let me get the spons.
Why not a mob?
Are those diet pills?
no, for asthma.
halfway diner I have to take them.
your halfway?
I had bought two kilo's of citrus.
They can't leave like that.
Who has mine...
Rocket, I was practicing.
Practice with bananas.
The Cooling is full with it.
You run quickly, but you don't
get faster then light.
Aren't you coming in?
-yes I’m coming.
Is there something?
-A boy fell at school.
Djamel, from the other side.
You know him?
Yes, the brother of Ala.
-he is on the intensive care.
he has a change for one out of thousand.
Did you know how it happened?
-no.
He was climbing a tree.
to follow the bigger boys.
Vincent. what nice to see you
at our house.
why aren't you coming in uniform?
-I’m at the office, Miss Bana.
And you don't have to look nice
at the office?
With one part you don't have enough.
We are not that small.
Is it true?
We climbed Les Bleuets
in less than 10 minutes.
And as usual I was the fastest.
Me, Rocket.
-Rasta Rocket.
Fast are you sure.
It was fine, but I can't eat anymore.
-Don't you get food at the police office?
How do you want to catch criminals
when they are not affraid?
Fatima, don't.
I don't wanna lose my son.
Fatima, don't do it.
Come back.
It will not matter.
You there downstairs.
Ala.
Fatima.
Mom.
What? I don't want nothing.
My son needs help.
Fatima, go sit down please...
...we will find a way to solve it
for your son.
be careful. Look at me.
Listen...
we will take care about Djamel.
I swear.
Are you proud of yourself?
You are jerks.
We will save your mother and you will
thank us?
And my little brother?
Who is going to save him?
You with you pirouettes?
Djamel is going to die...
...and it is your fault.
Leave me alone.
We never wanted that.
We do nobody harm.
We only help.
We helped an old woman with her
purse last time.
Yeah. And she couldn't say
thank you.
We like challenges,
but we are not criminals.
wait a sec.
What? we are not leaders.
we never said that we want look a likes.
we are getting up at 6 o'clock
because nobody will see our work.
Don't do that you are blind.
Kids always do bad things.
they see us and try to be us.
-ok, what’s the solution?
You quite with it.
-with what?
Climbing. That’s crap.
-And what must we do then?
Lijm snuiven, destroy cars?
-Don't be a fool.
I’m a fool?
-Are you going to beledigen us more?
Watch out.
-Think on your words.
Shut up.
was tonight not bad enough?
And you would go fight?
what do we do?
-the only thing to do is.
take some responsibility.
who let you in?
we don't want to disturb.
we are coming for Djamel.
Visiting hour is over.
Come back tomorrow.
Its to important.
-It can't.
When the chef sees you,
you will get punishment.
Michelin?
It doesn't take long.
Can we come in?
Great.
Are you coming to visit me?
Did you really climb Les Bleuets
on the east front?
the news is going fast.
The police will be furious.
-they see green and blue.
Greenblue police, cool.
When I’m older,
may I be a Yamakasi too?
You don't become a Yamakasi of yourself.
But when you’re out of here
and you really want it...
...we will teach you.
Promise.
where are you coming from?
I call you back.
we don't have an appointment.
-Its urgent. The little Djamel.
Right, yes.
what can I say...
-the truth.
you are letting him die.
I took the risk
to get an option.
I don't know what I can do more.
what is money problem?
-Simple.
the hospital can't and may not
pay for the bringing.
I hope that you understand that.
And who are those people?
-A contract firm.
the firm hTC.
And when they give us credits
so we can pay in parts?
Impossible. And I would have to ask
the seven directors first.
seven calls.
I can't call them like that.
-where a will is, is a way.
Try it. Its simple.
no, not on this time of the day.
I can't call because...
because a child is dying?
I was not saying that.
-Your children?
Give it.
-they look healthy.
Leave that.
Enough jokes.
In 10 seconds you will leave the room
and in one minute you will leave the hospital.
You get your money.
Tomorrow on 12.00 its on your table.
because of money they let a child die,
and they call us trash.
they deserve a knife in the ribs.
That is not smart.
-you have a better idea?
Everything is better. In this country
we don't leave people die.
Maybe is that in your nice
law books...
...but reality is different.
The city is a jungle.
who has no money can die.
don't become mad. we will
find something. with the banks.
did you look at our faces?
we don't enter a club,
so never mind a bank.
Unless we have a gun.
-You have one, give it to me.
Give me 2 hours. With my workmates
we will find a solution.
But it has to go legal.
You know, you can do it with the law,
we do it with our heart.
The first one that saves Djamel, wins.
-no stupid things.
I will do what I can.
Promise.
How did you get that?
-Stolen from the doctor.
The seven addresses are in it.
We are going to nail them.
-no violence doesn't solve anything.
That’s right, but we are going to
get them.
no, better.
we tell them a story.
Getting money from the rich
for the poor.
Yes, like in the cartoon.
-Robin hood.
Great. The sister of Rachid
has him on video.
Stealing is stealing.
-This is not stealing.
we are giving there own money back.
Great.
I like that.
I like it very much.
Great idea.
Great plan. Nice.
Yes, we get in jail or in the
hospital.
Don't think so low.
Everybody agree?
Yes.
-and what must I do?
I want to help the little djamel too.
Michelin, you are standing stand-by.
When its going bad we will call you.
Good?
-Cool.
Meeting at 5 0'clock.
You can't sleep inspector?
Do you know how late it is?
-Sorry, yes.
Dad kills you.
There is happend something important.
When we never see each other...
nah, we will see each other, but...
Ah, damn.
Love discussions,
is nothing for me.
You will be proud of me.
we have an idea for Djamel.
But it takes time.
And I’m not there today.
I can't prik today.
What if there's no money?
Jewels, credit cards. No big
or heavy things
The last one is for us together, 10 O'clock.
Two hours a piece should be sufficient, don't rush!.
Observe, go in and disappear.
Michelin, you are staying with the cell-phone.
-I've got 2 new batteries.
half past five.
fourth floor.
Late, that's the kitchen.
You shouldn't eat now
We're going to watch there.
shall we?
-no.
we got 4 hours to save Djamel..
You go left, I go right.
Call the cops.
Fine thank you.
-Good morning.
I want to talk to the minister
-he's not coming today.
and his chief?.
I hear he's at the office early usually?
indeed. Do you have an appointment?
It's about a nine-year-old...
-Do you have an appointment?
No, but it's very urgent.
You need an appointment!
U can order it by filling in an application form.
I really have to...
-I'm sorry..
the protocol has is very strict.
there's a life at stake and you
are arguing about a protocol?
Calm down!
And you call the chief
Am I clear now?
What's happening?
-Sir...
inspector Asmine,
sir the chief.
I’m sorry,
but a child is about to die
Only you can do something.
I didn't know I had so much power.
Please, come to my office.
Okay, after you.
Take a seat.
Yuk!. that guy can paint.
That's much too complicated
No big or heavy stuff.
we have to look for something else.
Yech.
That's awful.
You are bound to dislike music.
Five minute, and flee.
How do you know that?
-Mission Impossible.
There should be a key somewhere.
l know where.
Wait a minute.
We're going to teach him in culture.
"Listen to thick, prick.
That's music!"
A unusual story.
Extraordinary I would say.
That's why I pushed so much
My excuses again.
No, u did the right thing.
We should be at service of our people,
It should be the other way around.
Your initiative is admirable
-Thank you.
I there something that can be done against it?
I shall look at the medics.
Otherwise I will call the air force.
They should have a proper plane
-Thank you, in the name of Djamel.
You’re welcome.
Isn't life wonderful?
A big house like this all by ourselves.
We are scared stiff.
You're terrible.
Everywhere those alarms.
-l will kill those electronics.
Easy.
-Too easy if I say.
Too heavy.
-Too vulnerable.
Too beautiful.
Oh no.
-Yikes.
Damn.
They are coming from both sides
-What now?
let them come, distance.
More distance.
Now!
I never ich dowgs again.
I said to stay alert.
-30 million peace loving people my ass.
hopefully the other got more.
we're fine after the other.
I'll stay out of this.
Ala, with Vincent.
-Yes?
Good news I spoke with the chief
personally
He was extremely touched by our cause..
by Djamel
He would take care of it today.
He can call any minute.
Great isn't it?
hij kan elk moment bellen.
yes, but what is he going to do
exactly?
He gets an army plane and people for us.
Ala?
-Hold on...
Are they going to do all this for Djamel?
yes, he seemed very committed.
Truly.
Are u doubting me?
-It's not you, but the rest.
Stay focused, Ala.
djamel will be save in a few hours.
It's will succees, believe me.
Asmine, what are you doing?
-I’ll call you back.
You are a cop,
not a social servant.
You should protect people,
not harass them.
I have talked to an angry chief.
What's wrong with you, insulting
a chief?
I didn't insult him.
You got to a guard and...
...said a lot of bullshit..
That's  not true. I just asked
-I don't care
We don't care about the truth.
Our job is to clean up rubbish.
I don't get it.
Don't be so ignoring, that's hard
-The life of a child is at stake.
And then? we are cops.
Not god, the pope or the doctors without bounds.
We carry out orders.
A child is dieing?
Too bad, but not our cause.
We don't ask you to think.
We are the cement.
And cement doesn't think.
If everybody does his job,
everything goes well. So stay focused.
here, start with this case.
Are u going to operate him?
-No, all good. just routine.
Djamel can't stay in the room
-why?
There are other patients.
He stays here now.
in the lobby?
-It's just for a short time.
We will watch him just as good
-You are pretending if he's already dead.
Diseased are downstairs.
over here they are patients.
We got 5 people for the whole shift.
two heavily wounded are on their way
and we don't have enough space.
is my brother not ill enough?
We can't do anything for him at the moment.
We are helping the ones we can
take care of at the moment.
it's his turn soon.
the best you can do is stay calm and stay
with him.
Good, boys.
Hello, sir. Police
-Come in please.
You are coming for the burglary?
they didn't take much.
My dogs didn't give them the time.
They came in here,
switched off the alarm....
...and went straight to the living room.
How do u know it wasn't one person?
Because of that.
I have eight of them covering the whole house.
You are secured very well.
-After five burglarys I got fed up with it.
What do you do for a living?
-Surgeon. That's why i'm never at home.
Hmm. sluggy boys. real burglars.
-maybe they work in a circus?
May I?
Check if there were similar causes
this morning.
Coffee?
-Please.
For me also.
Can I attach it somewhere?
-Over there.
Thank u.
Great instinct you have.
Hmm.. already four acrobat burglaries
Since six O'clock.
Till now.
check if the victims are related.
Sports club, carbrand or whatever.
Simple, they are all doctors
-That's what I already thought.
And, are you making any progress?
Yes quite .
Do you know Henri Picard?
-That's a colleague.
Pierre Gautier, Jacques Bernier...
-we are in the same council of commissionars
seven in total.
all at the same firm.
Number seven we see never.
He is the boardchief.
Do you have a printerr?
-three.
Warn the others
that they get a visit.
I go to the board chief.
see you.
the minister falls out of our jurisdiction.
Don't worry.
Makes that sense,
seeing the surroundings?
after your conversation this morning...
you are not here too think,
but to obey.
Yes?
Police,madam.
Madam, we are after a burglar.
maybe they will strike here
what? Good God.
-Don't panic.
With us around you don't have to fear
May we?
Yes, go ahead.
Nice.
-Yes, it's a Klimt.
can we look around?
-Yes, sure, go ahead.
Nothing here.
-did they already pass by?
no.
But to protect is better than too cure.
when we do our job...
...we do it thoroughly.
Nobody around it seems.
Everything’s okay it seems.
I’m saying: it seems.
We should be careful, they are fast.
And if you consider their pace..
they aren'dagnerous?
-You never know.
Everything searched?
-you can sleep on both ears.
Madam.
-What if they do come?
The builing is surrounded.
they won't get any further that 10meter.
not even a mouse will slip through.
Thank u.
I feel comfortable.
Just doing our job, madam.
Ten minutes extra
And i get her flat and in extacy.
My Klimt.
They stole my Klimt.
what, which Klimt? where?
My Klimt. Look behind you.
Andre, did you see them?
-no, all fine.
My Klimt.
-easy.
they were here but they got away.
they will come back.
-Easy. Easy.
what's that?
They are on the roof.
request backup.
Go for it.
Don't be an idiot. There. There.
Yikes.
that doesn't look good.
What are you doing damnit?
There they are.
To the stairs..
Quick, in the building..
Stop.
They are here.
Move on.
they don't stop do they?.
there they are.
Freeze.
-Police. Don't move.
Come here.... here, that's what I say.
Easy.
-It is okay, JP. Come on.
You don't happen to have an
emergencyplan do you?
hands on your head.
on your head.
You let me run.
-hands on your head.
I did.
Come here.
One...
-l shoot.
Two...
-Don't be stupid.
Three.
-Stop.
Don't do that...
Bastards.
I'm not doing that.
Ludo? what are you doing?
I know, I do my homework
and then i clean up, promised.
We take the other way.
right, yes. Do that.
Bastards, Bastards, Bastards, .
nice you are here.
he will appreciate that.
Wasn't it hard?
They are here. lk have seen them.
who, Djamel? who is here?
The gosts. they are guarding me.
nobody got hurt?
-not for now.
And, are u almost there?
-Slowly.
Still one and a half hours. just do anything.
-Didn't you do stupid enough already?
And you? did you speak with the minister?
-Yes.
The ball is rolling.
We go.
-l can't let you go
I'm a cop.
cahnge your work.
-For me that means something.
I fight for laws.
And we fight for Djamel, Vincent.
Please let us pass.
-If you cross now, it would't end nice.
They will open fire.
You get in a coffin.
You're not Clint Eastwood.
Shut up, Rasta-Rocket.
or i'll hit you.
what do you say?
you don't get anything do you?
There's friendship, but there's law also.
if I betray my principles,
I have nothing anymore.
Our principles keep us going.
And they give selfrespect.
-Do you get it?
It's they same way with us.
A few rich doktors don't decide
a boys future.
we carry out our idea's...
-Without them we are nothing.
...we regret our whole life.
-there are other solutions than stealing.
Shut up, check your watch.
We see Ala and her mother daily.
Should we notlook next time?
I'm coming... l'm coming.
What do you want?
-Get in.
Wow, what a house...
i can put my half flat in this.
It will cost a day to open all doors.
we spread us.
Meeting outside in 5 minutes.
What, Burglers in my house?
Im comming right on.
lnspector Asmine. I have called u.
orsini. they are still there?
-I think so.
how many? which type?
black, north-Africa?
Can't burglers do something else?
-Give me answer?
It are a few.
Nothing special.
Nice line.
Thats gonna help.
In line, men.
Michel and Philippe, here please.
Three teams with walkie-talkie.
Look out.
-Take cover.
hurry.
-ask for backup.
In the closet.
The police is everywhere.
damn.
-This is not going good.
they are everywhere.
-I ratter have dogs.
we got a emergency plan right?
-we will keep searching for it.
"heavly armed",
isn't that special?
we don't if they shot.
It will be the cleaner then.
Go back to Vitry
and let us do our job.
move.
What happend?
what are you doing here?
-My job.
didn't I have to call that
there were burglers?
Your still here?
I asked you to leave.
How? Everything is blocked.
Commissaris orsini.
I lead this operation.
lnspecteur Asmine caught
the burglers and called u and us.
we have them surrounded.
-so they are still in the house?
Let them first steal everything
before we kick them?
offcourse not. But an interventie
like this needs preparation.
Is there any personel in the hous?
no, only my things.
I want an attack.
I prefer no big attack.
You got five minutes
to get that scum out of my house...
...or i will cal your chef.
-oke if you want, sir.
smokeboms. we can't see nothing.
Everybody upstairs.
where are we waiting for?
they have gone furious.
-Attack.
Attack.
Guys, Think of something.
This is not going good.
-I have an idea maybe.
Michelin... we need you now.
Im comming.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
The frontdoor is broken.
They are attacking back to us. close.
Gard every store.
easy and as plan.
what are we going to do?
-The big cleaning.
gogo.
-Forward.
we have two civilians unarmed
Call the ambulance.
Sir, you said there was nobody in the house.
Thats correct. Only the cleaner and...
I can't know what the personal does.
carefull.
There can still be civilians in the house.
You will get it together...
...but your irrisponsible behaviour
doesn't keep you from my record.
Asmine, Come on.
look for a hole to go to the roof.
nothing. The way is clear.
Guys, we have a problem.
Two even.
What are your names?
Carlos.
-Jean-Pierre.
do you life here?
no, I play here when my mother
cleans here.
Im a friend of Carlos.
-Which klass are you?
the third.
The road is blocked again.
-Continue.
we have two boys here.
leave the building and we let them go.
these two boys are personel
or yours?
or did you forgot to count them?
-I have no childeren.
yeah oke, A son of ten years old,
but he is with his mother.
those your cleaner life with you?
-no. she comes in the afternoons.
Its wednesday,
she brought her childeren.
I prefer you go, with bad information
you are dangerious for us.
I know what I have to do.
leave the zone or i will arrest you.
Understand?
Go, boys.
they will bring you home.
Don't play so much videogames
and go do some sport.
My arm. help.
-Let go.
I have one.
we need to get on the roof.
forward, hurry, hurry.
orsini on Raid 1 ,
no action before they are outside, I said.
We did.
whats the matter today with everybody?
Is it full moon or something?
damn.
here, guys.
-nice.
yes?
-where are you, damn?
Im at 100 meter.
A roadblock.
I will try get threw.
officer, I life there. I wanna go home.
doesn't matter. You must leave, and quick.
And no gsm in the car.
they are worse then by our neighbourhood.
Parc and walk.
Come to the northfront.
-oke, I will call back.
we put everything in a bag.
against the wall, sir.
whats happening?
-A hostige. You can't get threw.
But I life here.
-sorry, to dangerious.
Come back in two hours.
-Two hours? impossible.
without my pills I will be dead.
I will die on your feed,
but you will not get promoted.
Commissaris, I saw two shadows on
the second floor.
They are at the southwing.
Made it. Im there in 10 seconds.
see ya.
Give me a nice homerun.
You know the rest?
No problem.
-Your turn, Baseball.
what are you doing? Stay at the wall.
They are on the roof.
Yankee 0, visiters 1 .
Now im going say something
that you better keep in mind.
hands up.
Situation under control.
no victims.
Finally. I was getting mad.
Thnx, Asmine.
Come with us for the report.
It will be needed,
against the kabinetschef.
forward, men.
Are you comming?
I have my own car.
drive.
I have good news.
the swiss donor died.
we have to answer within 1 hour
otherwise the hart will be unusefull.
How much many do you have now?
The money is underway.
At 12 o'clock its here.
Nice.
That is not looking good.
lndiaan with your plans,
How do we come out of this?
It was jail or hospital.
-I had choose hospital.
after the hospital it went
jail also.
I hope it was not for nothing
and that Djamel is going to make it.
Don't make illusions.
-why?
That fatass will lose the money
before he is in the hospital.
how much do you want?
FF 227.500.
-for everything?
yes, and now penny less.
it's a lot of money,
but it's for a good cause.
If it's for a good cause,
we got a deal.
Deal.
Come with me.
The boss wants to talk to you.
Tell. We listen.
I wanted to go to Paris with a friend
just to get out.
In the suburbs the air is not the best.
We were walking to a good neighbourhood.
We like to come there.
It's like a museum.
-and free.
We passed a beautifull villa.
-Pure luxiory.
Cinderella's castle.
-And then...
we heard screams.
-A yel.
As if they were trying to strangle Cinderella
-we didn't hesitate.
We acted.
-and could call the cops.
But we're not like that.
-Excuse us.
The cops scare our pitbulls.
We climb over the fence
-to save the woman.
A window was open
-There were 2 burglars
Three burglars.
-At least five.
Bold headed guys
-Maybe six even.
They were hitting the poor woman.
-they threw her into the closet.
We attaced.
-and beat the crap out of them.
Hard.
Uou would have done the same thing.
Then we heard sirens.
-cops everywhere.
The two burglars ran away.
We realised that noone
would believe us.
And your collegues started shooting.
Without being able to say anything...
-we pannict.
You are kidding me right?
It's true, I swear.
On my mother
-on my brother.
On my 2 brothers
-On everyone I know.
Not on my father he's dead.
-On my family.
I would spit on the floor
if you wouldn't get angry.
To the jail.
Have you ever read such nonsense?
Sadly, it's the truth.
I'll back that as a witness.
That'll make the case easier.
I hope he has some good insurance.
Let's hope so.
Hey, seven dwarfs. Get out.
Get out i said!
You can go.
The inspector backed your story up.
Hurry before he changes his mind.
Ala, I got it.
I got it Ala.
Here, count it.
I believe you.
-FF 400.000 in cash, before noon.
You can call.
There is no time to waste.
Yeah, but it's 10 past twelve.
Ten minutes late, I'm sorry.
Take the phone and call your friends.
They got a offer for FF 500.000.
The offer got prosponed until 12.05,
but no longer.
I'm sorry.
Are you sure?
You tried everyting
because our patience is running out.
Back up.
I will shoot if I have to.
Get lost or I'll call the cops.
The cops are already here.
I'll come closer so you can read.
Am I close enough? Can you read it?
You see whats on it?
Federal Police.
Put your gun down.
Aim a weapon without this card
is punishable by 1 year of prison.
Buit we'll forget the cops for a while,
to have a man-to-man talk.
How much is is your life worth?
FF 20.000 ?
Let's be generous,
FF 100.000.
And 400.000, that's 500.000.
Exactely the right amount.
If Djamel doesn't have a new heart
in two hours...
...yours will get smashed.
You understand?
Turn it of, we can't hear anything.
I'm proud of you.
-I know.
Be carefull with your jacket.
-Nutcase.
I have some good news.
-You got fired?
Even better. I quit.
I'll make a cassette for Djamel.
you wanted to say something?
can you see us?
-Everything okay?
And leave the nurses alone.
get better fast,
because your training is afterwards.
Yamakasi.