We caught the bitch.
Please, don't hurt me.
Don't be afraid, girl.
Who are you?
Somebody please help me!
Only the evil book can undo
what the evil book has done.
Please...
I just want to go home.
Please. I just want to go home.
Daddy?
Daddy, what are you doing to me?
- Who are these people?
- They're good people.
They're here to help.
What are you talking about?
Where's Mom?
Mommy's dead, baby.
You know that.
You killed her. You did.
No. Why are you saying these things?
Daddy, Please, I just want to go home.
I just want to go home.
Do it!
It's the only way to save her soul!
I'm so sorry, baby.
Daddy, what is that?
No!
Daddy.
Daddy, look. It's me. It's me.
Do it! Give your daughter peace!
I just want you to hold me
and take me home.
Please!
Please, stop.
I will rip your soul out, Daddy.
I'll rip your soul out,
you pathetic fuck!
You motherfucker! I will kill you,
like I killed your whore!
Fuck!
Fuck!...
I love you, baby.
EVIL DEAD
Hey.
How's it going?
Mr. Hot shit city boy.
- Hey, Olivia.
- Come here.
Two arms, please.
Like you missed me.
This is my girl, Natalie.
Oh, the heartbreaker from the carshop.
The doctor?
- Actually, she's...
- I'm a registered nurse.
Nurse? Right, sorry.
You were supposed to be here
two hours ago, man.
And that's our
irresistibly charming, Eric.
So teaching in high school finally
turned you into a bitter old coot, huh?
No, you did.
Kept us waiting here all morning.
Good to see you too, man.
Come here.
You look good.
She's waiting for you at the back.
Great.
Hey, Mia.
I'll be damned.
You actually came.
Come on, I'm your big brother.
Of course I came.
I know I look like roadkill.
No, you look beautiful
as always.
And you're a charming liar.
As always.
Grandpa!
Hey!
Hey there, buddy!
We always loved this place,
didn't we?
He missed you a lot, you know.
- Oh my God.
- What?
- What is that?
Just this, right here.
What...
It's not funny!
This is...
It's made from a buckthorn tree.
It's supposed
to make your will stronger.
But I thought you didn't believe
in that kind of stuff.
I don't. But you do,
so maybe it will work.
Okay.
Well, then, let's do this.
Promise me you'll stay with me
until the end.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- Cross your heart.
Okay.
Hope to die.
May my friends and family,
witness this act.
an irrevocable promise
to my commitment, that...
Fuck it.
I promise not to touch this shit
ever again.
Okay.
Let's play cold turkey.
Hopefully, it still works.
Wait...
Looks like someone broke in.
Be careful.
What's that smell?
Some teenagers probably
just broke in here,
to drink beer,
and bump uglies.
Exactly.
Mom would've hated
seeing the cabin like this.
Okay.
Let's make this place livable.
Hey.
Are you okay?
Do you remember that lullaby
Mommy used to sing to us?
It was something like...
"Baby, you little baby,
it's time to say goodbye."
- "Baby, little baby".
- Mia please...
I don't think you need sad
memories in your head right now.
Mom is not a sad one.
You know what I mean.
You know, during her final days
at the hospital,
Mom sometimes thought
I was you.
She even called me David
for a whole day, once.
And, I played along.
Because...
Mia, look. I wanted to be there.
Okay, I did.
But by the time Mom got bad,
I had just gotten the job
at the garage in Chicago,
I don't know, I had a hard time
finding the right moment to come back.
And then, it was too late,
so...
Maybe you were lucky,
not to see her the way that I did.
Looks like she's doing okay.
David, there's something
you need to know.
Okay.
We already tried this whole thing
back in Flint last summer.
Mia made the same promises,
She took the same
dramatic vow of sobriety,
before chucking her dope
down in the toilet.
She lasted eight hours and quit.
So, we don't like to give her
that chance this time.
What do you mean?
David, when she breaks,
and believe me,
she will,
we don't want to let her leave.
What do you mean?
You want to force her to stay here?
Mia?
This time, the only way,
is the hard way, man.
- She won't survive another O.D.
- What?
Mia O.D'd?
She didn't just O.D.
Legally, your sister died.
They had to defibrillate her.
Oh, Jesus.
Look, we all need to be together on this,
otherwise it won't work.
Good boy.
I came here to make things
better with my sister, not worse.
If she asks me to take her home
at some point,
I'm gonna have to do it.
I can't stand it!
I can't stand it! Fuck!
Oh! I can't stand it!
I don't know what even that smell!
I know. It's Ok.
It's OK, it's OK.
I can't stand
that fucking smell anymore!
Calm down, okay?
We're right here.
I know, I know.
We're all here.
We're not going anywhere.
Withdrawal is kicking in hard enough.
This should be get you
through the night.
I don't know
what is wrong with you people,
but there's something dead
and it reeks.
But there's no smell.
You're just extra sensitive right now.
I just can't stand
that fucking smell anymore!
Wait.
Whoa... Is that blood?
Oh, shit.
What's your medical diagnosis now?
It fucking stinks.
Oh, shit. Careful.
These steps are old and rotten
down here.
- Yeah, like this whole freaking house.
- I know.
Smells like burned hair.
I think it's back there.
Oh, shit.
- Oh, my God!
- Oh, shit!
- What is this?
- I don't know.
Witchcraft?
Who will do this?
Shit, something burned here.
Look.
Shit, man.
What the fuck happened here?
Let's not go crazy over this, okay?
I'll bury those stink cats
out back later.
Yeah, the smell will be gone
in no time.
Yeah, okay.
And what about the voodoo shit
they did down there, huh?
No, no, no.voodoo is more about
dolls, personal artifacts.
- This something different.
- Eric, that's enough.
You shouldn't have touched
anything from that basement.
"Naturom Demonto".
"Kunda"...
"Astratta"...
"Montosse"...
"Can'da".
Please God,
give me a break.
Mia.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry but I have to get out
of here right now.
No, come on.
Slumber party isn't over yet.
Yeah, who will start and play
"Fuck, Marry, Kill." Right?
- Mia, please. Look, Mia...
- I'm going insane here.
Olivia, I feel
like I'm loosing my mind.
Mia, what is it?
I will go through with this, okay?
I just...
I can't do it here.
Mia...
We've decided
we're not gonna take you back.
We can't loose you again.
You're gonna have
to stick it out this time.
David, drive me home.
Come on, David.
Mia...
Mia, maybe they're right.
You're supposed to be here
to support me, not them.
I'm here for you, Mia...
- that's why I came.
- Oh my God.
I'm such an idiot...
to think for once in my life,
I could count on you.
Mia, we're all just trying
to help you!
Yea, well, fuck you very much!
Eric, leave her alone.
Mia.
Mia!
Perfect.
Fuck this! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck!
What the fuck am I doing?
Mia!
Mia.
- Mia!
- Oh, shit.
Oh my God.
Hey, how is she doing?
She's talking about a woman
in the woods.
How the forest attacked her.
I don't know.
It's just crazy withdrawal talk.
Well, don't you think
we should take her to a hospital?
I think we're in over our heads here.
Okay, I'm giving her the exact same
treatment she would get at a hospital.
If we leave now, all of this mess
would've been for nothing.
Ok, what about the wounds
on her arms?
I pulled some thorns out.
Looks like she ran into
a thorn bush out there.
She probably did it on purpose.
What?
David...
From now on, she is gonna do
whatever it takes to get out of here.
Mia.
Listen, you've gotta get out
of those clothes.
- Right? Take a shower.
- David.
Please...
You have to get me...
out of here.
Yeah, but nobody said
this was going to be easy.
No.
You don't understand.
There was something
in the woods, David.
And I think it's in here with us now.
What? Here in the room?
Look, you know
it's all in your head.
Just try to get it together.
You'll feel better tomorrow, Okay?
You'll be glad we were such assholes.
Okay.
Eric, what are you doing in here?
Please, would you just
get rid of that thing?
You should be downstairs
helping your friend clean up that mess.
I don't know
who you're talking about.
Come'on, don't act
like you don't care about him.
I know you do.
Well, I think we can all agree, he hasn't
cared about us for the past freaking century.
Well, he is here now.
Yeah.
Truly amazing.
Grandpa?
Come here, boy.
Fuck!
Grandpa.
No, no, no.
Here, boy.
What did you hit into?
Fuck.
What happened?
- Mia?
- She's in the shower.
What happened? David?
Mia?
Mia, open the door.
- Mia, open the door!
- David, what is wrong?
David, stop
and tell me what's going on.
Mia, open the fucking door!
David!
Mia!
Mia?
Olivia!
Holy, shit!
Mia!
Shit!
This is insane!
Fuck! Where is it?
This can't be happening.
I...um... I...
I gave her sedative,
so she should be up for a couple of hours.
But, fuck. Her burns are serious.
Like, second, third degree.
This is so wrong.
Look, nobody could have known
that she would do something so twisted.
No, you should've known.
We've all been following your way
since we got here.
We should've left
when Mia wanted to.
Baby, please!
Okay, let's not lose our heads. Okay?
With any luck, it'll stop raining
in a couple of hours,
and we'll be able to cross the creek
in the morning,
and we'll take her to a hospital.
Okay?
Everything is gonna be fine.
Everything is gonna be fine?
I don't know if you'd noticed this,
but nothing is been fine.
But everything is been getting worse,
every second.
Mia?
What are you doing?
Mia, put the gun down.
Put the gun down, please.
Mia!
Put the fucking gun!
Oh my God!
You will die, like the others!
One by one, we will take you!
You're all going to die tonight.
The gun! The gun, quickly!
Baby?
Mia?
Let me out!
- Let me out!
- She's totally psychotic.
Oh my God,
What happened to her eyes?
What's she doing?
Sounds like she's flinging herself
against something.
This is impossible.
I just gave her enough sedative
to put a horse to sleep!
So give her another shot!
It could bring her into a coma.
For Christ's sake, Olivia,
she's going to kill herself down there!
Go get the shot!
I gotta get the shrapnel
out of my ram.
What? I have tweezers in my purse.
David. Listen to me.
I don't think a tranquilizer
is gonna do shit.
'Cause I don't think we're dealing
with a freaking panic attack here!
I'm scared that
what's happening to Mia...
has something to do with that
fucking witchcraft in the basement.
Olivia?
Are you okay?
What are you doing in there?
Olivia.
Olivia?
Are you okay?
Oh my God!
Why the fuck did you do that?
Kill him.
No!
She tried to kill me.
Fuck it.
Hold that. You got it?
Hold here, okay? Hold.
Fuck it.
David, I did something terrible.
I'm sure you didn't mean to hurt her.
That thing I killed, was not Olivia.
He's losing too much blood.
Baby, he needs
water and sugar, okay? Go.
- Go!
- Okay, okay.
- Alright.
- David...
I read a passage from that book.
It was some sort of a prayer.
I unleashed something, David.
I unleashed something evil.
Natalie?
Mia?
Natalie.
What am I doing down here?
My leg's hurt.
I can't move.
I'm coming down there, okay?
Why did you lock me down here?
- You were supposed to help me.
- Hey, we're trying to help you. Okay?
You were out of control, you know?
You got violent and we didn't know
what else to do.
Mia, I think something
really terrible was happened,
and we have
to get out of here now, okay?
You don't understand...
He's not gonna let you leave.
And he's not gonna stop
until he has you.
Until he has all of you!
I can smell your filthy soul.
Kiss me, you dirty cunt!
Why don't you come down here
and let me suck your cock, pretty boy?
- Mia...
- Mia is not here, you fucking idiot!
Your little sister is been raped in hell!
I wanna go home.
Eric?
I don't know why,
but I thought that this would end it.
But this book, does not burn.
It does not fucking burn.
Tell me what's going on here.
This book, using some...
ancient alphabet.
Here's some translations,
but it's just a scattered written notes.
They all refer to some...
"evil entity"...
A taker of souls.
A demon.
It says...
Once he feasts on five souls,
the sky will bleed again,
and the abomination...
will rise from hell.
This is insane.
This "thing" is attached
to Mia's soul like a leech.
It's becoming her.
If we wanna stop this,
if we want to help Mia...
I think we gonna have to kill her.
- What did you say?
- If everything said...
Eric!
We're not gonna fucking kill anybody!
Are you listening to yourself?
What about those dead cats
down the basement?
I mean, maybe they had some disease.
I mean, some virus that...
it spread to Mia...
and then she passed it to Olivia,
when she puked all over her face.
But what kind of a virus, makes a person
cutoff their face with a piece of glass?
Oh my God!
Oh God!
I don't know,
what we're dealing with here. Okay?
But it stopped raining,
and in a couple of hours,
the river will be clear,
and we're gonna get out
of this place, all of us.
It doesn't matter where we go.
If we don't do something right now,
we're all gonna be dead by then!
Don't do it, you little bitch!
Don't cut it off!
Fuck you!
No, no, no, no, no!
No, no!
I had to do it.
It feels much better now.
Hold on, baby.
Hold on, please.
Eric and I, we're gonna,
we're gonna put stop to this, okay?
I promise you,
everything's gonna be fine.
Okay? Okay, baby?
She just cut her fucking arm off.
Does this sound fine?
These inscriptions are confusing
and sometimes contradictory.
But they're consistent
about one thing:
In order to stop this,
the possessed must be cleansed.
Purified.
The book describes three specific ways.
A live burial...
bodily dismemberment...
and purification by fire.
Are you sure that this will work?
If we...
If I killed my sister,
she'll be at peace?
Am I sure? Of course not.
This is not a science book.
But look, I'm sure of one thing.
Whatever is inside Mia,
is the cause of all this.
If she dies,
then this thing is gonna die with her.
What if she just lost her mind?
What if she just needs a doctor?
What? A doctor?
My Mom died in a mental hospital,
she was crazy.
She was deranged,
she was a monster.
I've always feared that me and Mia
would end up like her.
You're just a fucking coward.
You know exactly
what we have to do,
but you're too scared
to go through with it.
I'm gonna burn
this fucking place down.
and I'm gonna end this nightmare.
Why don't you just run away?
Go hide beneath some rock
somewhere.
You know, You're great at that.
Oh, shit!
Where the fuck did she go?
David.
Take it before she does.
No!
Stop!
No, no, no, no!
No!
No, no, no!
David.
Why are you hurting me?
My face hurts.
Why?
Why? Why's my face hurt me?
Baby, baby...
Nat, Nat.
Come on. Come on, man.
Here we are.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hold on!
Don't die on me, please.
It wouldn't be so bad right now.
I just don't want to become
the devil's bitch.
I'm gonna do what I gotta do.
I'm gonna do what I gotta do, OK?
I'm sorry, Mia.
I love you.
Baby, little baby,
it's time to say goodbye.
I'll miss you day and night.
Baby, my sweet baby,
I'll write you everyday.
Baby, don't cry baby.
I wish that I can stay.
I can't do this.
This time... the only fucking way...
is the hard way!
David.
Murderer.
Coward.
Eric.
Hey, are you okay?
David.
I missed you, man.
You know that, buddy.
David.
David?
I can't move! I can't breath!
Help me!
Help me, David!
- You're not her.
- David!
Help me!
You're not her!
Why do you hate me David?
I know you do.
You left home.
You left me all alone
with our sick mother.
And I was just a kid.
You made me lie.
Every time she screamed your name,
I told her you where coming to see her.
Like you promise.
But you never did.
Please stop it.
I'm begging you.
I know mother hates you now...
and she waits for you in hell.
Shut up! Shut up!
I'm so sorry, Mia.
I should've been there.
I should've been there for you.
Come on. Please, come back.
Come on, Mia! Come back for me!
Come on, please!
Okay, you're in peace.
You're in peace now.
David?
Mia?
It was so horrible.
It's okay. It's all over now.
Thanks for not leaving me, David.
Wait here.
I'm gonna get the car keys.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
David?
Go! Please, just go!
Go!
I'm not gonna go anywhere!
I'm not going anywhere!
Mia, take the keys.
Look at me, let's go.
Come on. Come on, let's go.
Get out of here.
No! No!
David!
No! No! No!
David! David!
He's coming.
Mia.
Come here, bitch!
Come on!
You're gonna die here,
you pathetic junkie!
I've had enough of this shit!
I will feast on your soul!
Feast on this, motherfucker!
Die!
Go back to hell, bitch!