# Brazil #
# Where hearts were
entertained in June #
# We stood beneath
an amber moon #
# And softly murmured
someday soon #
# -Someday
-We'd kiss #
# -Someday #
...
Central Services
We do the work
You do the pleasure
Hi there. I want to talk
to you about ducts.
Do your ducts seem
old-fashioned, out-of-date?
Central Services's
new duct designs...
are now available in hundreds
of different colors...
to suit your individual taste.
Hurry now, while stocks last, to your
nearest Central Services showroom.
Designer colors to suit
your demanding taste.
Tonight we have with us, from
the Ministry of Information...
Deputy Minister Eugene Helpmann.
Good evening, David.
What do you believe is behind this
recent increase in terrorist bombings?
Bad sportsmanship.
A ruthless minority of people...
seems to have forgotten certain
good old-fashioned virtues.
They just can't stand
seeing the other fella win.
If these people would
just play the game...
they'd get a lot
more out of life.
Nevertheless, Mr. Helpmann,
there are those who maintain...
that the Ministry of Information
has become too large and unwieldy.
David, in a free society,
information's the name of the game.
You can't win the game
if you're a man short.
And the cost of it
all, Deputy Minister.
Seven percent of the
gross national product.
I understand this concern
on behalf of the taxpayer.
People want value for money.
That's why we always
insist on the principle
of information
retrieval charges.
It's absolutely
right and fair...
that those found guilty should pay
for their periods of detention...
and for the information retrieval
procedures used in their interrogation.
Do you believe that the government is
winning the battle against terrorists?
Oh, yes. Our morale is
much higher than theirs.
We're fielding all their strokes,
running a lot of them out...
and pretty consistently
knocking them for six.
I'd say they're nearly
out of the game.
... law-abiding citizens to
have to subsidize criminals?
But, Mr. Helpmann, the bombing
campaign is now in its 13th year.
Beginner's luck.
Thank you very much,
Deputy Minister.
Thank you, David.
And a very merry
Christmas to you all.
"Scrooge was better
than his word.
"He did it all, and
infinitely more.
"And to Tiny Tim,
who did not die...
"he became a second father.
"He became as good a friend
in the good old world.
"And so, as Tiny Tim observed...
God bless us, every one."
-Are you boys giving me the runaround?
-Where are you?
Step right up. This way.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Don't throw that. That's
only for long distance.
All right.
I'm sorry, boys, but we
haven't got any vacancies.
Got no vacancies.
-We got plenty of rooms.
-That's all right. We take a room.
-All right.
-All right. We take a vacancy.
Boy, take the gentlemen's baggage.
...
Who's there?
Who is that?
Father Christmas can't come
if we haven't got a chimney.
You'll see.
No!
What's going on?
I hereby inform you, under
powers entrusted to me...
under section 47, paragraph 7 of
council order number 438476...
That Mr. Buttle, Archibald, residing at
412 North Tower, Shangrila Towers...
has been invited to assist the Ministry
of Information with certain inquiries...
and that he is liable to certain
financial obligations...
as specified in council
order RB/CZ/907/X.
Sign here, please.
Where are you taking him?
There.
Thank you. Same again, please.
Just there. Press
harder his time.
-Good.
-What is this all about?
That is your receipt for your husband.
Thank you.
And this is my receipt
for your receipt.
Mrs. Buttle, are you okay?
-Ho! Ho!
-We're Department of Works!
Department of Works up here!
Careful with those
bloody things.
Don't take any notice
of them, love.
Don't touch me. Why don't you
just get the hell out of here.
Don't you worry, love. We'll have
everything shipshape in a jiffy.
That's it. Nothing
to worry about.
Right. It's Tuttle
downstairs who can worry, eh?
Tuttle? His name's Buttle.
There must be some mistake.
Mistake? We don't make mistakes.
That's bloody typical.
They've gone back to
metric without telling us.
Mrs. Buttle, are you all right?
Yeah.
"Buttle."
Buttle, Archibald.
Ridiculous name.
On the twenty...
Oh, shit.
Mr...
Mr. Lowry, would you
step in here, please?
Ah.
I say, h-has anybody seen Lowry?
Has anybody seen Sam Lowry?
Sam.
-Hello.
-Hello? Sam. Where are you?
-Hello?
-It's 11:00.
-What?
-11:00!
-Mr. Kurtzmann.
-Yes.
You're up late.
-It's 11:00.
-Is it?
Oh. The electrics here
are up the spout.
-I know. Look...
-Oh, yours too?
Yes.
Oh, well, um, I'll be
there as soon as I can.
-Yes. Thanks. Bye.
-Hurry up.
Hello, Sammy.
What have you got to say?
...
Oh, very good, Sammy.
... famous statue pairing
truth and freedom.
This is not the only statue...
Shut up!
What's this gun for?
This one, Sister, is a
nine-millimeter submachine gun...
used for close-quarter
combat fighting.
Very effective weapon.
Would you like to see it?
Sam!
Jack!
-Well...
-Long time no see.
-Hey.
-What are you doing here?
I don't expect to see you
slumming it in Records.
What's the problem?
Problem? No problem. Everything's fine.
Wonderful. Marvelous.
Alison's in great shape.
Kids are fine.
I'm on Security Level 5 now, so
Mr. Helpmann relies on me more and more.
-It's been a great year.
-You sound worried.
Worried? Me? If I'm worried
about anyone, Sam, it's you.
I mean, look at you, Sam.
Whatever happened to you?
Records?
Sam, you were one
of the brightest...
Sam?
Uh, Jack, it's great to see you.
-I'm gonna be late.
-Sam.
Let a friend tell you.
Your life is going wrong.
Records is a dead-end department.
No security level worth a damn.
-It's impossible to get noticed.
-I know.
Wonderful. Marvelous.
Perfect. See you, Jack.
-Give my regards to Alison and the twins.
-Triplets.
Triplets? God. How time flies.
A very clear delineation of picture
this has. Adamant, mobile.
Next.
I want to report a
wrongful arrest.
You want Information Adjustments.
Different department.
I've been to Information
Adjustments.
They sent me here. They said you
have a form I need to fill out.
Have you got an arrest receipt?
Yeah.
-Is it stamped?
-Stamped?
No, no. There's no
stamp on it, you see.
I can't let you have the
form until this is stamped.
-Where do I get it stamped?
-Information Adjustments.
It's nothing. It's nothing.
It keeps picking up old films.
That can't be right, can it?
Perhaps the machine's
on the blink.
No, it's not the machine. There's a
mismatch on the personnel code numbers.
Tuttle should have had Ł31.06 debited
against his account, not Buttle.
-My God! A mistake!
-Well, at least it's not ours.
Isn't it? Whose is it?
-Information Retrieval.
-Oh, good.
Yeah. See, Expediting has put
in for electrical procedures...
in respect of Buttle, Archibald,
shoe repair operative...
but Security has invoiced Admin for
Tuttle, Archibald, heating engineer.
Oh, what a relief.
Finish your tea, Sam.
What? Oh. Thanks.
I don't know what I would do
if you ever got promoted.
-Oh, God, don't worry about that.
-No, but if they did promote you, uh...
I've told you before.
I'd turn it down.
-Would you? Really?
-Really.
You've been promoted.
It's your mother, isn't it?
Pulling strings again.
Sam, it's time for you to grow
up and accept responsibility.
Your poor father would be appalled
at your lack of promotion. Ooh!
Mother, I just wish you
would stop interfering.
I don't want promotion.
I'm happy where I am.
No, you're not. Jack
Lint is a lesson to you.
He doesn't have your brains,
but he's got the ambition.
You haven't got the ambition.
Luckily, you've got me
and the deputy minister.
Mr. Helpmann was very
close to your father.
Now, please, Mrs. Lowry.
Don't get upset.
Mr. Lowry, please wait in reception.
You're giving her wrinkles.
-You see?
-God!
Just try and relax, Mrs. Lowry.
I'll make you 20 years younger.
-Ha!
-Yoo-hoo, Dr. Jaffe. You are a genius.
Would you like to
be surgeon general?
I know simply everybody.
Well, they won't know you
when I've finished with you.
First...
we remove the excess derma.
So.
Now the flaccid tissues under
the eyes and the forehead.
-Zip.
-Oh.
Now, I lift...
the wrinkles and
the worry lines...
right up into the wig,
into the hairline.
Now the template.
-Mercy.
-There. Now a bit of sticky.
Like so.
And already she's twice as beautiful
as she was before. Voilŕ!
Mr. Helpmann was very close
to your poor father.
He was very close to me.
Still is.
He'll take you under his wing when
you get to Information Retrieval.
-Thank you, sir.
-You'll like it there.
You're not listening
to me, Mother.
What the hell is this, lady?
It's a present for my son.
Really!
I hope you like it.
It's very exclusive.
What on earth is it?
Something for an executive.
Ah, Madame Lowry.
You look exquisite today.
Merry Christmas.
Hello, Spiro. Merry Christmas.
-Sorry.
-Uh, you remember my son, Samuel.
-Of course.
-We're joining Mrs. Terrain.
-Yes. The lady's waiting.
-Are we? God.
This way.
Mother. Mother, I thought we
were going to be able to talk.
-We will. We will.
-Ida, Sam.
Oh, God. She's got
what's her name with her.
Yoo-hoo!
Sam!
Well, Alma. How are you?
You look wonderful.
Hello, Shirley.
Thank you, Spiro.
-Salt?
-Not yet.
Sam, happy Christmas.
-So sorry we're late.
-Thanks.
Now, Alma...
what are you going to have?
I can't make up my mind whether to
have the number one or the number two.
-What do you recommend, Spiro?
-Between you and me, madame...
today the number two.
Thank you, Spiro. Shirley. Shirley,
what are you going to have?
Between you and me, mademoiselle,
today the number one.
-Madame Lowry?
-Oh, to hell with the diet.
I'm going to have a
number eight, please.
A most perceptive choice
if I dare say so, madame.
Oh, Ida!
-Monsieur.
-Steak, please. Rare. Mother...
-Monsieur, quel numero?
-I don't know which number.
Mother, please...
-That one. There.
-That's fine. Thanks.
-Mother, will you please listen to me.
-Alma! You wicked girl.
-You've started your treatment.
-Say the number, please.
-You noticed.
-You have to say the number!
Will you please go away!
I'm trying to talk...
I must tell you all about it.
Number three.
Mother, will you listen to me.
I haven't...
Numero huit.
Braised veal in wine sauce.
It's too exciting. I've left
Dr. Jaffe and gone to Dr. Chapman.
-Numero deux. Duck a l'orange.
-Dr. Chapman? Chapman?
Excusez-moi.
The acid man?
Really, Ida! Just because his
techniques are revolutionary...
I don't go around calling
Dr. Jaffe the knife man.
Numero un, crevettes
a la mayonnaise.
I am sorry, Alma. I didn't
mean to sound so...
It's all right, Ida.
It's just...
Steak. Numéro trois.
Mesdames, monsieur...
Bon appetit!
-Merci.
Acid, on the other hand, can be used
for such wonderfully subtle shading.
Such delicate nuances.
Like a Rembrandt etching.
-And it is so much quicker.
-God!
If it wasn't for this complication...
the doctor
says it could have
happened to anybody...
I'd have had this
dressing off yesterday.
Shirley.
Salt?
What were we saying?
-This isn't rare.
-Oh! By the by, Alma...
I saw the most wonderful idea for
Christmas presents at the chemist's.
Gift tokens. Medical
gift tokens.
Oh, that sounds marvelous!
It's good at any doctor's and
most of the major hospitals.
It's also accepted for
gynecological examinations...
including cesarean section.
Spiro.
I'm sorry, madame.
I don't know what to say.
It never really happens to us.
I'm going to do something
about it straightaway.
Really, Sam! Why can't you do
something about these terrorists?
It's my lunch hour.
Besides, it's not my department.
Actually, Alma, that was one of the little
things I've been dying to tell you.
Look. Sam's been promoted
to Information Retrieval.
Oh, that's wonderful!
Congratulations, Sam!
Stop it! I'm not being promoted. I'm
not going to Information Retrieval.
If I want you to stick your oar in,
Mother, I'll tell you where to stick it.
Pepper?
I've gotta go.
-Sam, you haven't had your dessert.
-I don't want dessert.
I don't want promotion.
I don't want anything.
Of course you want something.
You must have hopes,
wishes, dreams!
No, nothing. Not even dreams.
Sam.
Sam!
Oh, God.
Hello. Central Services?
I'm at 579B, Block 19,
Northwestern Section "D."
That's exit one on Green Pastures
Highway at the Orange Blossom Flyover.
And I've got trouble with my
air-conditioning. It's an emergency.
Thank you for calling
Central Services.
I'm sorry. Due to temporary
staff shortage...
Central Services cannot take service calls
centrally between 2300 and 0900 hours.
Have a nice day. This has
not been a recording.
This is an emergency.
Thank you for calling Central Services.
I'm sorry. Due to...
-No. I've got to have a heating engineer.
-Thank you for calling Central Services.
Oh, shit.
Hello.
-Hello.
Hello. Mr. Lowry.
Yes. Who is this?
Put the phone down and
raise your hands.
What? Who is this?
Nice and easy now.
Nice and easy.
Just keep your hands
where I can see them.
What... What are you doing?
Harry Tuttle. Heating
engineer at your service.
Tuttle?
Are you from Central Services?
I called Central Services.
Well, they're a little
overworked these days.
Luckily I intercepted your call.
You did...
Just a minute. What was
that business with the gun?
It's just a precaution, sir.
Just a precaution.
I've had traps set
for me before now.
And there are plenty of
people in Central Services...
who'd love to get their
hands on Harry Tuttle.
Are you telling me
that this is illegal?
Well, yes and no. Officially,
only Central Service
operatives are supposed
to touch this stuff.
-Would you hold this, please?
-Uh...
But nowadays, with all the
new rules and regulations...
they can't get decent
staff anymore.
So they tend to turn a blind
eye as long as I'm careful.
Mind you, if ever they could prove that
I've been working on their equipment...
well, that's a pipe
of a different color.
-Wouldn't it be simpler just to work...
-Would you hold this for me?
Sorry. Yes. I was saying, wouldn't it be
simpler to work with Central Services?
Nah! Nah. Couldn't
stand the pa...
We're getting warm.
You couldn't what?
Couldn't stand the what?
Paperwork. Couldn't
stand the paperwork.
Listen. This whole system of
yours could be on fire...
and I couldn't even turn on a kitchen
tap without filling out a 27 B/6.
Bloody paperwork.
I suppose one has to
expect a certain amount.
Why? I came into this game for
the action, the excitement.
Go anywhere, travel light, get in, get out,
wherever there's trouble, a man alone.
Now they got the whole country sectioned
off. You can't make a move without a form.
Found it.
There's your problem.
-Can you fix it?
-No, I can't.
But I can bypass it
with one of these.
Fine by me.
-Are you expecting anyone?
-No.
-Get down!
-Wait! Wait! Will you wait!
Shh.
The flashlight.
Central Services.
-Central Services.
-Oh, yes.
-You rang, sir?
-Trouble with your air-conditioning?
-Air-conditioning, sir?
No, it's... it's...
it's, uh, all right.
It's, um... It's fixed.
-Fixed.
-Fixed?
Yes, um...
I mean, it, um, fixed itself.
-Oh, it fixed itself!
-Fixed itself?
Yes!
Machines don't fix themselves.
No, they don't fix
themselves, sir.
-He's tampered with it, Dowser.
-I think he's tampered with it, Mr. Spoor.
Sorry you've had a
wasted journey.
Oh, that's all right.
-I think we'll go have a little look.
-No, you can't.
I think we should.
Yes, Mr. Spoor.
Have you got a 27 B/6?
27 B/6?
27...
Now look what
you've done to him!
Well, have you got a 27 B/6?
Not... as such.
But we'll get one.
It's all right. It's all right.
It's all right.
It's all right, then?
Sorry. I'm a bit of a stickler
for paperwork, you see.
I mean, where would we be if we didn't
stick to the correct procedures?
We'll be back.
We'll be back!
It's all right.
Thanks for coming.
We'll be back, you
clever little bastard!
-Thank you.
-We'll show you!
Well...
Thanks, Lowry. You're a
good man in a tight corner.
Thanks.
Listen, um... I, uh...
Well, I...
I just happen to work at the
Ministry of Information.
-What?
-And, uh...
Well, I just happen to know
that Information Retrieval...
are looking for an Archibald
Tuttle, heating engineer.
You, uh...
You wouldn't, by any chance...
Would you?
My good friends call me Harry.
Information Retrieval, huh?
The big boys.
What do they want you for?
-Time to go.
-Sorry.
How's that?
Listen, you, um... you really
must let me give you something.
How much will it be for the, uh...
for the work?
Ah, come on.
You did me a favor. Just
check the corridor.
Oh. Well, thanks.
Listen, kid, we're
all in it together.
-Go on.
-Right.
Okay.
All clear.
I think Kurtzmann is
getting suspicious.
What's playing today?
Casablanca.
Mr. Lowry, will you
step in here, please.
Lowry!
Sam Lowry!
Psst!
Thank God you're here.
We're in terrible trouble.
Shh.
-Look at this. Look at this.
-It's a check.
It's the refund for Tuttle.
-Tuttle?
-Mm-hmm.
No, no. Buttle. I mean Buttle.
It's been confusion
from the word go.
He's been overcharged for
Information Retrieval procedures...
and someone somewhere is trying
to make us carry the can.
Can I have a look? I've never
seen a refund check before.
I'll bet it's Jeffries.
Yes.
He always believes that people should
pay more for their interrogation.
And "B," he loathes me.
We've gotta get rid of it!
Well, send it to somebody else.
Better still, send it to Buttle.
After all, it's his check.
I've tried that. But look.
Look at this.
You see? The population census has
gotten him down as "dormanted."
Uh, the Central Collective Storehouse
computer has got him down as "deleted."
Hang on.
Information Retrieval has got
him down as "inoperative."
There's another one: Security
has got him down as "excised."
-Administration has him
down as "completed."
-He's dead.
Le...
Dead?
Well, that's awful.
We'll never get rid of
the damn thing now.
What we gonna do, Sam?
Could try next of kin.
Next of kin!
Yes!
There we go. Buttle.
Veronica. Mrs.
Veronica?
What's the number on the check?
Uh, 27156789...
/074328K.
Right. Into memory.
Central Banking.
Veronica Buttle.
Mrs.
Deposit.
Thank God for that.
Uh, would you like some tea?
There's a problem. She
doesn't have a bank account.
Well, that's it, then.
I might just as well go
and hang myself now.
This sort of thing could
never have happened
before this stupid
seventh-tier reorganization.
That's Simmons's doing. And he and
Jeffries always sit together at lunch.
Bastards!
Sh... Shh. Shh.
Perhaps we could lose
the thing behind a filing
cabinet or something...
burn it, eat it.
Look, there is one solution.
What?
Drive out to Mrs. Buttle, let
her sign the back of the check.
She can cash it at the
corner sweet shop.
That's brilliant, Sam.
I'll even do it for you.
Here, authorize the check.
What's the address?
Everything's in here.
Uh, w-what should I do next?
Pink and blue receipts. Sign
there, there and there.
-And sign the check there.
-Yes.
I think I've broken a bone.
Look, my wrist is all limp.
What a pathetic creature I am!
Here.
I'll do it for you.
Right.
I'll be on my way.
Sam?
You are good to me, you know.
-Here's looking at you, kid.
-Here's looking at you.
# Brazil #
# Where hearts were
entertained in June #
# We stood
beneath an amber moon... #
We interrupt this program
to bring you news
of a terrorist bombing
at the Blue Lagoon...
# And clung together #
# Then #
# Tomorrow was another day #
# The morning found
me miles away #
# With still a million
things to say #
# Now #
# When twilight dims
the sky above #
# Recalling #
Under Section 972/552.
Hello. I wonder if you
could tell me where the...
Piss off!
Hello.
I'll never confess!
Hey, come on! You
gotta interrogate me!
Mrs. Buttle?
Uh, Mrs. Buttle?
Ah. Um, are you Mrs. Buttle?
Um...
my name's Lowry.
Uh, Sam Lowry.
Um, I'm from the
Ministry of Information.
I've come to give you a check.
Um, it's a refund, actually.
-There was a mistake.
-Mistake?
Yes, yes. Not in my
department, of course.
I'm only Records.
No, it, uh... I'll
tell you what it is.
It seems that Mr. Buttle was
overcharged by Information Retrieval.
Yes, they don't usually
make mistakes, but, uh...
well, I suppose we're all human.
Oh!
What happened to the, um...
Actually, you know, my coming here is rather
unorthodox, bringing you this check...
as any payments are normally made
through Central Computer, but, um...
Well, as there were certain...
difficulties...
we thought, well, rather
than cause delay...
we'd let you have it now.
You know, it being
Christmas and all.
My husband's dead, isn't he?
Um, I do assure you, Mrs. Buttle,
the ministry is very scrupulous...
about following up and
eradicating any error.
But if you do have any
complaints you wish to make...
I'd be, well, only too happy to
send you the appropriate forms.
What have you done
with his body?
Oh! Gosh.
Um, I-I don't know anything
about that, Mrs. Buttle.
I'm really just
delivering the check.
So, if, um... Look, if you wouldn't
mind just signing these two receipts...
I'd be only too happy to, uh...
to leave you in peace.
He hadn't done anything.
He was good!
What have you done
with his body?
It isn't being very
helpful, Mrs. Buttle.
I didn't have to come here,
you know, Mrs. Buttle.
I'll kill you!
I'll kill you, you bastard!
Hey!
Get off!
Are you all right?
Mrs. Buttle, are you all right?
It's you!
Wait! Stop! Don't go! Stop!
Oh, look! He'll
never get that out!
Stop! I had nothing to do with it!
Wait!
Stop!
He's coming back!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus...
-Go away.
-Her name's Jill.
What? Jill?
Jill who? Jill who?
Layton.
Jill Layton.
You're a very good little girl.
What are you doing here?
Waiting for my daddy.
He will be pleased
when he gets home.
Sam, I've just had the
Transport Pool onto me.
You don't anything about a personnel
transporter gone missing, do you?
Personnel transporter? What?
Oh, the prannets. I had
a personal transporter.
Huh.
I'll do the paperwork
in the morning.
Um, is it all right
about Mrs. Tuttl...
Uh, Buttle's check?
-Uh-huh.
-Can I forget it?
-Yeah.
-Oh, what a relief.
I'm gonna have
nightmares, you know.
-Oh, damn and blast!
-What's the matter?
I don't suppose you'd happen to know
how I can get round an I RQ/3, do you?
Ooh, all information on third-level
suspects is classified.
All inquiries
through Information Retrieval,
and that's hopeless. They
never tell you anything.
Come the time they want
something from us, oh, yes.
There is one way I could get round it.
I could accept my mother's promotion.
Yes.
No!
You can't. You've
just turned it down.
I didn't sign the form.
I did it for you.
-You didn't.
-I did.
You didn't!
I did!
What did you do that for?
It's what you wanted, isn't it?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know what I want.
Come on, before they
turn the lights out.
There is one way round it.
I could always accept promotion
to Information Retrieval.
Sam!
Oh, Christ.
What are you doing? What...
My God! What's going on?
-Emergency procedures.
-Emergency procedures!
-I haven't got an emergency!
-Yeah?
This is an emergency!
Have a nice day. This has
not been a recording...
Here. Sign that.
-What is it?
-A 27 B/6.
What do you think it is?
Where's he gone?
Spoor, come here! Look!
I got it! I found it!
Spoor! Spoor! Come here, Spoor!
It's a bypass valve on this...
on the transformer.
Tuttle!
Tuttle. It's Tuttle.
You've had that scab
Tuttle here, ain't ya?
What are you talking about?
-Who fixed your ducts? Huh?
-Fixed your ducts, all right.
I told you before...
they fixed themselves.
Oh, yeah? Then where did
this come from, eh?
Out of your nostril? Eh?
Nostrils, eh?
Central Services.
They don't take
kindly to sabotage.
Sabotage, huh?
Jesus, this place is
in a terrible state.
Just a minute! You're not gonna
leave it like this, are you?
Why not? All you gotta do is blow
your nose and it's fixed, innit?
That's right!
Well...
Oh, my...
Jesus!
What have you done
with his body?
Mrs. Ida Lowry requests the
pleasure of your company
At her apartment tonight
From 8:30
To midnight
To celebrate the completion
Of her recent cosmetic
Surgery
Telegram
Um...
Thanks.
-It's reply paid.
-Is it?
Oh. Um...
Two, three...
Mother, I'm sorry, but I'm
unable to come to your party
-You don't have to sing it.
-I don't?
No.
Oh. Sorry.
Aren't you a bit late? I mean,
the party started an hour ago.
Yeah. It's the backlog.
Everybody complains.
-Oh.
-Was it all right otherwise?
Mr. Helpmann, I'm keen to get
into Information Retrieval.
Mr. Helpmann, I'm dying to get
at this woman. No, no... Ohh!
Oh, God.
-Hold up.
-What? Who are you?
-Hey! What's going on?
-Where's your invitation?
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Mother! Mother!
Sam.
I'm so glad you came.
Come in.
-Mother?
-Come in.
Oh, God, Mother, is that you?
Of course. Isn't it wonderful?
The bandages came off
just this afternoon.
Come on, darling. Join in the fun.
Simply everybody's here.
Is Mr. Helpmann here?
-Would you stop shoving...
-Yes, he is.
Mr. Helpmann is here, and
he wants to talk to you.
Good. I want to talk to him.
He says that you're the first
person ever to refuse a promotion.
-Ah, well...
-He thinks you should see a doctor.
-Actually, Mother, I've decided...
-Oh, Louis! Louis, you know Sam.
Can you believe it?
It's just me and
my little knife.
-Snip, snip, slice, slice.
-It's marvelous.
-Can you believe it?
-Congratulations.
-But this is just the beginning.
-Oh, really?
Oh, Christ, yes. You've seen
her with her clothes off.
Faces are a doddle
compared to tits and ass.
-No hairline.
-Oh, really, Louis!
I've been looking for
you everywhere, Ida.
Mother. Mother, I have to talk to Mr.
Helpmann.
-Oh, you stupid sod.
-Dear boy.
What do you think
of your mother now?
It'll never last.
Excuse me.
Dr. Chapman, did
you say something?
That technique... I've tried it.
Oh, nice effect, but
highly unstable.
In six months she'll
look like Grandma Moses.
Now, see here, Chapman, at least mine don't
end up looking like they've been mugged.
Sam! Sam!
What have you done
with his body?
Sam!
Sam?
-What on earth's happened to you?
-There was a little complication.
Dr. Chapman says it often happens
with a delicate skin like mine.
Nothing to worry about.
He's promised me these bandages
will be off in a jiffy.
-Actually, there's someone I want to meet.
-Oh, I know.
I know.
There we are.
I'm going to leave you
two lovebirds in peace.
Hello, Shirley.
-Oh, God.
-Come on!
Do you want a drink?
Oh. Hello.
Chase those years away!
Listen, Shirley...
your mother and my mother, they
seem to have got the idea that...
Look, I'm very flattered
and, uh, well...
I just don't want you to be
under any false impressions.
It's all right.
I don't like you either.
Sam!
Jack. Excuse me, Shirley.
I'm s... I'm sorry.
-Sam! You remember Alison?
-Evening.
Alison. Sam Lowry. Old friend.
Alison, yes, of course.
-You look different.
-Well, I'm two years older.
-And she's been to Dr. Jaffe.
-Ah.
She doesn't like me telling people,
but, in fact, she's really pleased.
-I knew there was something different.
-Remember how they used to stick out?
What? Oh, yes. Uh, well, rather.
-Always used to wonder if they were real.
-What, my ears?
Sorry?
Dr. Jaffe pinned her ears back.
Yes, that's what I...
Always used to wonder
if she wore falsies.
Ah! Mr. Helpmann.
False ears... Mr. Helpmann!
-Hello, Jack.
-You remember my wife, Alison?
Yes, of course.
Barbara, isn't it?
-How are you?
-Well, actuall...
Barbara's very well, thank you, sir.
Very well indeed. How are you?
-Fine, thanks.
-Good.
Hello, Sam. Ida said you might be here.
Have you got a minute?
-Would you excuse us?
-Oh, no, of course.
Of course. Come on, Alison...
Barbara.
Sam.
I need your help.
Thanks very much, Sam.
Mr. Helpmann, I'm
glad to be of help.
-If I can help you...
-Ah, well, actually...
Oh.
Your father and I
were very close.
Of course, Jeremiah was senior to
me, but we were close friends.
Especially after the bombing.
And I keep his name alive
at the office every day.
It's as though he's there
still speaking to me.
"'Ere I am.
J.H."
The ghost in the machine.
I know he would have
wanted me to help you.
And I promised your mother...
that I'd take you on to the
team at Information Retrieval.
But I gather that, um...
Well, actually, Mr. Helpmann, I've, uh...
I've changed my mind.
I've decided I'd
accept the transfer...
if I'm not too late.
Too late?
That's for me to say.
Well... Well, then, I, uh...
Welcome to Information
Retrieval.
Uh, my name's Lowry.
Sam Lowry.
I've been told to report
to Mr. Warrenn.
Thirtieth floor, sir.
You're expected.
Um, don't you want to search me?
No, sir.
-Want to see my I.D.?
-No need, sir.
-But I could be anybody.
-No, you couldn't, sir.
This is Information Retrieval.
The lift's arrived, sir.
I want that order rescinded!
Half as terrorists,
the rest as victims.
Yes. No.
Definitely no!
-My name's Lowry, Mr. Warrenn. Sam Lowry.
-Ah, Lowry!
Yes. No. Cancel that. Okay.
-Glad to have you aboard. Yes.
-These requisitions...
-Sir, I'd like to point this out...
-No! Don't be ridiculous, Jenkins.
-About these invoices...
-Yes. Yes. Yes.
You'll like it up here.
Send that back.
We've got a crack team of... Are
they kidding? ... decision makers.
No, in triplicate.
I'm expecting big things...
Two copies to Financial!
No. No. Don't let
Progress see those.
Between you and me, Lowry, this... No, no!
Department... Tell Records to get stuffed!
Is about to be upgraded and...
Ah! Here we are.
Your very own number
on your very own door.
And behind that door,
your very own office.
Congratulations, DZ/015.
Welcome to the team.
Yes! No! Cancel that!
Send two copies to Financial!
Well, you can't borrow
any more chairs!
There's only one left in here
now, and I need that to sit on!
What?
Oh.
Sorry.
Who are you?
My name's Lowry. Sam Lowry.
Oh, yes. The new boy
from next door.
My name's Lime. Harvey Lime.
Welcome to Expediting.
I say, look, would you mind if I
borrowed your computer console?
What?
Yes, I'll let you have
it back in 10 minutes.
You want to take my
console into your office?
Yes. Just for a few minutes.
I-I'll tell you what.
You tell me what you want...
and I'll do it for you.
I'm a bit of a whiz
on that thing.
Um...
all right.
Uh, I need some information
on a woman named Layton.
A woman, eh?
-I see.
-Yes.
I know her age and distinguishing marks,
but I need an address or a place of work.
This your dream girl, is it?
What? Um...
Look, let me use your console.
You must be joking.
When there's a woman involved,
there's no stopping me.
Let's have that sheet.
Sod it! It's broken!
You haven't switched it on.
Oh, yes.
Look, you're putting
me off standing there.
Why don't you go back to your office
and I'll give you a knock
when I'm finished.
-Um...
Go on. I'm not going
to elope with her.
All right.
Sam!
Sam.
Don't go.
Please.
Well?
Computers are my forte.
Let me see.
"Jillian Layton. Coloring: White. Hair:
Blonde. Eyes: Blue. Height: 5 foot 4.
Distinguishing marks:
Scar on left"...
Is this all you've got?
Best to take things slowly where
some women are concerned.
Let me see.
Hey! That's mine!
"Layton.
"Truck driver.
All inquiries, reference
office of 412/L, room 5001."
Ah, Lowry, glad I caught you.
No! Send that back!
-Mr. Warrenn!
-Are you settling down?
I want this order rescinded.
There's a query about a personnel
transporter you took out from the pool.
Tell them no. Tell them yes.
Or was it a personnel carrier you
took out from Transportation?
Send that up to Security.
Anyway, tidy it up, Lowry.
There's a good chap.
And get a new suit.
Don't you want the lift?
Can I help you?
No! No! No! Please!
I'm, uh... I'm looking
for Officer 412/L.
He won't be very long now.
I thought so.
You may go in now.
Oh, uh, not that one.
That one. Yes.
Excuse me. Are you
Officer 412/L?
Excuse me!
Jack.
Sam.
Ah! I heard you
were coming aboard.
Congratulations, "DZ/015."
Thanks. Are you Officer 412/L?
Uh-huh. That's me.
Oh, and, Sam, a very
happy Christmas.
-Thanks, Jack.
-Are you settling in all right?
Yes, fine. Jack, I... I
need some information.
Oh, Sam, this is Information
Retrieval, not Information Dispersal.
Hey! Amy!
Don't throw the ball
around in here.
I'm not Amy. I'm Holly.
Did I call you Amy, darling?
I'm sorry.
-A triplet?
-One of them, I think.
Barbara's taken the other
two Christmas shopping.
You're not going to keep
calling her Barbara, are you?
Why ever not? Barbara's a
perfectly good name, isn't it?
Don't you like it?
Yes, it's... fine.
Come on. Let's get
these together.
-Jack.
-Now bring me the blue one over there.
I need to find out
about a woman.
Come on, Chloe, let's show Uncle Sam here
how we can make the word "cat." Shall we?
-I'm Holly.
-Sorry, love. So you are.
-Cat.
-This is her.
Layton.
Oh, shit.
-How much do you know about this?
-Uh, not much.
What does B58/732 mean to you?
-Buttle.
-I knew it.
You always were
bloody quick, Sam.
Who else knows? Warrenn?
Helpmann?
I don't know. I only know
you got the wrong man.
Information Transit
got the wrong man.
I got the right man.
The wrong man was delivered
to me as the right man.
I accepted him on good faith
as the right man. Was I wrong?
You killed Buttle?
Sam, there are very rigid parameters laid
down to prevent such things happening.
It wasn't my fault that Buttle's heart
condition didn't appear on Tuttle's file.
Come and look. How
you getting on?
-Jack.
-A, B, C...
-I really need to know about...
-Tuttle?
Well, we're gonna have to bring
Mr. Tuttle in, aren't we?
And interrogate him at the
same voltage as Mr. Buttle.
And juggle the books
in Electrical Banking.
What has Tuttle done?
We suspect him of, uh,
freelance subversion.
A freelance subversive.
Then all I need to wrap up the
case is the Layton woman.
What has she done?
Well, she witnessed the Tuttle...
Um, the Buttle arrest.
Since then, she's been going
around making wild allegations...
obviously trying to
exploit the situation.
She's working for someone,
and I don't think it's us.
-That's it. Over there, love.
-Terrorist?
Mr. Lint, the next customer
has been delivered.
Thank you, Myrtle.
What are you gonna do
about the Layton woman?
Well, I put her on the detention list.
Security should have her here before 6:00.
What, here? So that she can spill
the beans inside the department?
Don't do that!
Jack, why don't I try
and get to her for you?
I'll, um... I'll deactivate her.
What does that mean, Sam? I don't want
to get involved in anything unsavory.
Trust me, Jack.
Come on, darling. Put these away now.
Mummy'll be here soon.
Let me have her file.
Look, trust me, Jack.
All right. Come on here.
All right, but for Christ's
sake, don't lose it.
All right.
You sit down there, Mary. Sam.
Don't worry. I'll get to her.
You'll never get anywhere
in a suit like that.
Here.
Try this.
-Bye-bye.
-Bye!
Uh, but, Jack, I...
Put it on, big boy. I
won't look at your willy.
Oh, let him go.
Trier, isn't he?
Just... I've been to
the department of...
But you've stamped this form before.
Why won't you stamp it now?
You just said yourself, miss...
we've already stamped it.
No, no! Stop!
Up! Up! Up! Up! Up!
Oh, God.
Come on!
Shit!
Oi! Come out of there.
-What?
-That's the deputy minister's lift.
-I'm sorry. I'm in a hurry.
-Oi, come here.
Come here, sonny. Let's see your I.D.
Card, eh?
My I.D.? Oh, God.
This isn't my suit.
My name is Lowry. Sam Lowry.
Look, really, can't this wait?
No, sir. I'm going to have
to fill in a report on this.
Now, then, uh, what
is the date today?
It's the... Oh, God,
it'll have to wait!
Oi! Oi, you! Stop! Come back here!
Stop!
Aim!
Stop! Don't...
Up!
Well done, men. Quick thinking.
Excellent work.
Um... I'll take
charge of her now.
Good. Good man.
Um, okay.
Uh... It's a...
classified matter...
and, um, I'll, uh...
I'll include your fine handling
of the situation in my report.
Great.
Uh, merry Christmas, Dawson.
Come along with me, please.
Please? Okay. Yes.
Well done, men. Excellent.
Good turnout. Nice. Very good.
Thank you.
No, no, no. This way, please.
Straight ahead.
This way. This way.
This way.
Just keep moving.
-Hey! Stop!
-What?
Come back here!
Pick up all these things!
-Come on! Pick them up!
-Geez... Oh...
Disgraceful!
-Can't you read English?
-Ow! Get your bloody...
You illiterate foreign pig! You
come over here on your own...
...and think you can
mess up our streets!
Oh, God.
Stop!
That's it! Let's go!
Vroom! Vroom!
What are you doing? For
Christ's sake, keep moving!
-Get out of my cab.
-What?
Just drive!
You touched me.
Nobody touches me.
What are you... Oh, God!
Please! Please! Drive on!
Drive on, will you! For... Oh, shit.
Move over. I'll drive.
Don't touch that!
Don't touch anything!
It's okay, Officer. Thank you. It's okay.
Got everything under control. Thank you.
Oh, shit. They're coming.
Listen, please drive. Drive. Trust me.
You are in terrible danger.
You are an embarrassment.
Please.
Please drive. Trust me.
Trust me.
Drive, and I'll
explain everything.
Please...
get out of my cab.
-I'm sorry. I...
-Okay!
Okay, you've asked for it!
I'm Information
Retrieval Officer D...
DZ/105!
And I'm arresting you as a...
Drive on, or I'll blast
your fucking head off!
Go!
Look, I'm, uh... I'm
sorry about that.
I mean, uh, touching you
without permission.
But, um... Hello.
My name is Lowry. Sam Lowry.
I... I'm... I've been, uh...
You won't believe this, and I know
it's going to sound incredible...
but, um... but I've been
dreaming about you.
No, not like that. I
mean, I love you.
In my dreams I love you.
And, uh... I mean...
Extraordinary, isn't it?
Anyway, um...
y-y-you...
You don't believe me, do you?
You, um...
You probably think I-I-I-I'm
bonkers, right? Mad. Raving.
No! No, I think you're
very attractive.
What?
Yeah. Yeah, sit back. Let
me have a look at you.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Good-looking, sexy.
Just my type.
I don't believe you.
Why not?
Well, I-I... I just don't
deserve such terrific luck.
Damn right.
Help!
I love...
You don't trust me, do you?
Oh!
Oh, my God. We shouldn't
have come here.
I got a job to do!
-But they'll be lying in wait.
-Oh, Christ, you're paranoid.
You've got no sense of reality.
Wait, wait, wait! Wait!
We should take the
lorry and get away!
-Yeah? Where to?
-Anywhere, as fast as possible.
-There isn't anywhere!
-Just far away!
That's not far enough!
But... Wait!
Jill!
What's in the, uh, parcel?
-Christmas present.
-Oh.
It's heavy.
Heavy Christmas present.
-You don't trust me, open it.
-No!
No, no, it's, uh... it's fine.
I'd spoil the wrapping.
Anyway, if I want you to trust me, then it's
only fair that I should trust you. Right?
Doesn't it bother you, the sort of
things you do at Information Retrieval?
What?
I suppose you'd rather
have terrorists.
Here's one now.
How many terrorists have you met, Sam?
Actual terrorists?
-Actual terrorists?
-Yeah.
Well... It's only my first day.
-Uh-oh.
-A roadblock.
-What are we gonna do?
-Stay calm.
Don't slow down.
Don't slow down!
Don't stop. Please.
Please do as I say. Go.
Go! Straight ahead! Go!
-Go! Go! Go!
-What are you doing, you stupid asshole?
Whoo!
We did it! We did it!
We broke right through them! We did it!
Whee, whee, whee, whee!
Faster!
-Get off of me!
Don't let them see you!
Just go!
Keep going! Keep going! Faster!
-Get your foot down on it! Move!
-Stay off of it!
No!
Get off!
Shit!
Oh, no.
Go faster! Faster!
-What if we lose the house, yeah?
-Don't touch anything!
Don't touch it!
We did it! We did it! We did it!
We did it!
Oh, no.
And what would you
like for Christmas?
My own credit card.
Hmm.
-Why have we come here?
-Go away!
-Look, why don't we go back to my flat.
-Forget it.
-You don't trust me?
-Trust you? Trust you?
A man who hijacks my
truck, loses me my job...
has every security man
in town looking for me?
-Of course I trust you.
-I was only trying to help.
-Yeah!
-Okay. Okay.
You don't trust me,
I don't trust you.
-What's in that parcel?
-Oh, Jesus.
You saved it from the lorry. It
must be something very special.
I saved you from the lorry. You're
not something "very special."
-How can you... I'm gonna open it.
-Don't touch that!
Sam! It's me!
And Shirley!
Mrs. Terrain.
-That should hold it.
-Sam?
Hello, Shirley.
My God, what on earth's
happened to you now?
My complication had a
little complication.
But Dr. Chapman says
I'll soon be up...
and bounding about
like a young gazelle.
You buying a Christmas
present for your mother?
What?
Oh, um, yes. A little something.
Shirley and I come
here "wegularlarly."
We love romantic lingerie.
Really?
Sam, picture me in these.
-Oh, my God.
-Sam, where are you going?
Sam! Sam!
Jill?
Jill!
Oh, my God. Are you all right?
Well, you don't deserve to be!
What a bloody stupid thing!
How could you? Look at these people!
My God!
It was a bomb. It was a bomb.
I should have opened it. I sat
there with it next... I...
What a stupid thing.
There's your bomb, asshole!
Bribes...
for official monkeys like you.
Oh.
Go on. Make yourself useful.
Here.
Don't touch her! She's hurt!
Damn it!
-Don't touch her!
-No!
Stop!
Sam, no! Sam! Behind you!
These helmets don't half
make your scalp itch.
Oh, don't mention it. And
they make you sweat.
Half the time I can't
ever see where I'm going.
There's a great Niagara of
perspiration coming down.
Well, I'm lucky.
I got these thick eyebrows.
That keeps it up and
channels it out to the ears.
Yeah. Who's he?
Oh, I don't know. Somebody
from Information Retrieval.
They're always hangin'
around in Lingerie.
Where is she? Huh?
Jill, is that you?
Uh... Excuse me, sir. That
is government property.
Oh, Jill.
Jill! Answer me!
I'm looking for a girl
with blonde hair.
She's medium height, green eyes.
I don't know, sir. They check
all that at the depot.
Uh, we can't allow that, sir.
It's more than our job's worth.
Jill! Jill, you must be here!
Jill!
Look, sir, you can fill in an application
form, sir, if you're a relative.
Now, do stop, sir. Please.
Jill? Jill?
Oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear.
Sorry about that, sir.
Regulations.
This is a black eye for
the department, Lowry.
I don't care how you behaved
when you were at Records.
Information Retrieval
is an executive branch.
We're proud of our reputation
and we protect it.
Damn it, Lowry! That convoy of personnel
carriers is still not accounted for!
I thought I told you to deal with it.
And what the hell is this mess?
An empty desk is
an efficient desk.
Good God. Queries from Security.
Searches from Central
Banking about a check?
Clarification notices from Accounting
concerning unreturned receipts?
-Mr. Warrenn, I have to find out about...
-Get up!
I don't know what's
going on here, Lowry.
But don't think you can intimidate us with
your friends and relatives in high places.
Now shape up!
Lime, I have to use
your computer.
Sorry. A bit busy at the moment.
You seem to have rather a lot
to get on with yourself.
Shit.
Come off it, Jack.
Of course you can check to
see if she's been arrested.
I'm sorry, Sam. I'm afraid
this whole case has become
much more complicated since last we...
talked.
But she's innocent, Jack.
She's done nothing wrong.
Tell that to the wives of the security
men she blew up this afternoon.
She's not alone in all this.
We've just had a report in that
Tuttle has wrecked an entire flat...
and sabotaged adjacent
Central Services.
As a matter of fact, it
looks like on your block.
I should keep my eyes open
if I were you, Sam. Bye.
But, Jack, you don't really think Tuttle
and the girl are in league, do you?
I do.
Everything's connected
all along the line.
Cause and effect. That's
the beauty of it.
Our job is to trace the
connections and, uh, reveal them.
This whole Buttle-Tuttle confusion was
obviously planned from the inside.
Bye-bye.
Oh, but, Jack!
She's innocent, Jack.
Sam, we've always been
close, haven't we?
Yes, Jack?
Well, until this all blows
over just stay away from me.
But...
Oh, my God.
You.
It's you. What's happening?
What's happening?
Your thermostat's
gone, and then some.
And then some!
What's happened to my flat?
Hello? What? It's for you.
-But as you don't live here anymore...
-What?
Absolutely. Do you
know what this is?
This is an H2206...
authorizing the compulsory, temporary
requisitioning of this flat...
for our necessary repairs.
-Repairs!
-What?
-No! You...
-Don't forget your receipt.
-Oh! Oh! Oh!
-No, sir. Don't forget your receipt.
I'm sorry, but I'm a bit of
a stickler for paperwork.
He's a stickler for
paperwork, sir!
Bastards!
Tuttle.
-What are you doing?
-Shh.
Phew-ee.
Oh, God.
-Jesus Christ!
-The smell! Stop!
Filling up with...
Oh, God.
Oh, Jesus!
Oh!
Shit!
We're all in it together, kid.
Jill. Jill!
Jill. Oh, God.
Are you all right? What
happened to you after...
Your face. Are you hurt?
Um, no, I-I'm fine.
It's... Well...
I've been worried
sick about you.
-Who was that?
-That's a friend of mine. He...
Oh, God. Holy shit.
We'd better get out of here quick.
Come on. Quietly.
Look out. Here. Take this.
Looks big.
Here.
Quick. Quick.
-Are you sure this is all right?
-Yes. Yes, certain.
My mother's away for Christmas.
She's spending it at
the plastic surgeon's.
The wraps come off tomorrow.
Lock the door after me. Don't
answer the phone to anyone.
I won't be long.
-Where are you going?
-I know a way to save you.
-Trust me. I can do it.
-But you can't go without me.
Excuse me, Dawson. Could you put me
through to Mr. Helpmann's office, please?
I'm afraid I can't, sir.
You have to go through
the proper channels.
And... you can't tell me
what the proper channels are
because that's...
classified information.
I'm glad to see the ministry
is continuing its tradition
of recruiting
the brightest and best, sir.
Thank you, Dawson.
-Good night, Mr. Lime.
-Good night, Dawson.
# The first Noel #
# The angels did say #
# Was to certain
poor shepherds #
# In fields as they lay #
# In fields where they #
No, no, no, Arthur!
You're flat on the "G."
It's your breathing. Now take
a deep breath after "Noel."
Ready? One, two, three.
# The first Noel #
# The angels did say #
'Ere I am, J.H.
The ghost in the machine.
E-R-E-I-A-M-J-H.
Mr. Helpmann.
Mr. Helpmann?
Jill.
Jill?
Who's there?
What do you think?
Is it me?
Well?
You don't exist anymore.
I've killed you.
Jill Layton is dead.
Care for a little necrophilia?
Hmm?
Yee-hah! Yee-hah!
Merry Christmas.
Uh...
Something for an executive?
Sh-She's dead. This is
just a friend of mine.
She's...
-What are you...
-No!
-Oh, my God!
-No! Sam!
"N3/HK/608, you are charged
with the following:
"Giving aid and comfort to
the enemies of society,
"Attempting to conceal a
fugitive from justice;
"passing confidential documents
to unauthorized personnel...
"viz. I.R.
Dossier/Jillian Layton;
"destroying government property viz. an
indeterminate number of personnel carriers;
"taking possession under false
pretenses of said personnel carriers;
"forging the signature of the head
of Records, third department;
"intention to misdirect ministry funds
to the form of a check to A. Buttle...
"through unauthorized channels;
"tampering Central
Services supply ducts;
"obstruction of forces, Law and
Order, in the exercise of their duty;
"bringing into disrepute the
good name of the government...
"and the standing within the community of
the Department of Information Retrieval;
"attempting to disrupt the Ministry
of Information Retrieval's
internal communicating systems;
wasting ministry
time and paper."
Now, either you plead guilty...
to, say, seven or eight
of the charges...
which is going to help keep
costs down within your means...
or you can borrow a sum, to be negotiated
from us, at a very competitive rate.
We can offer you something, let's say
11 and a half percent over 30 years...
but you will have to buy insurance
to qualify for this scheme.
Or, if you prefer something
more specific...
say, against electrical
charges over Ł70...
All you're requested to do at
this stage is to sign this form.
Think carefully
before you decide.
Looking ahead in financial
matters is always a wise course.
Sam, what are we going
to do with you?
Where is Jill?
I've got to find her.
Please. Please, you've got
to get me out of here.
I understand, Sam. I know
exactly how you feel.
So I've brought you a
bottle of barley water.
Oh, please help me.
I assure you, Sam, I'm doing
everything within my power.
But the rules of the
game are laid down.
We all have to play by them.
Even me.
It's all a mistake. You've
got to understand that.
Yes, well,
from the department's point of view,
you're certainly a bit
of an own goal, but...
I'm not a terrorist.
You must know that. Please,
please get me out of here.
Sam, information
retrieval is expensive.
You're running up an enormous
bill by not cooperating.
Please.
Please, Mr. Helpmann.
Help me find Jill.
Jill.
Yes.
Sam, I think I
ought to tell you.
I'm afraid she's upped stumps
and retired to the pavilion.
Thrown in the towel.
Dead?
Yes.
It's all a bit confusing, but
it seems she was killed...
resisting arrest.
No. It's all right.
I did that.
The odd thing is, it appears
to have happened twice.
Bit of a disputed
call, I'm afraid.
Twice?
So, there you are.
All I can say is, don't fall at the last
fence, the finishing post in sight.
See you in the paddock.
Do cooperate. Think
of your mother.
Good luck. Keep your
eye on the ball.
Gotta go. Can't keep
the orphans waiting.
Don't fight it, son.
Confess quickly.
If you hold out too long, you could
jeopardize your credit rating.
695/6.
Thank you.
Jack?
Jack.
Jack. Jack!
Shut up.
Jack. Jack, I'm innocent.
Please.
-Help me.
-Bastard.
Jack.
Jack, this is all a mistake.
Please, Jack.
Take that mask off.
You stupid bastard.
-Jack.
-How could you do this to me?
Jack, I'm frightened.
How do you think I
feel, you shit?
-Jack...
-Shut up!
This is a professional
relationship.
Jack.
Jack, no, you can't.
No, Jack, please.
Jack, no! Don't!
Please, Jack! No!
-You okay?
-Tuttle!
Call me Harry.
Let's go!
Here. Here.
Ah, Mr. Lowry. So pleased
you could make it.
Right this way.
It's a sad loss.
Your mother was with
her at the end.
The gift of eternal life.
Mrs. Terrain has just received
that most wonderful of gifts.
She came to us physically new.
She goes hence from us
not so physically new.
But the spirit never grows old.
Madame Lowry.
Mother.
Oh. Sam.
Mother. Mother!
Stop calling me that.
Mother! Mother, please!
-Is this guy bothering you?
-Oh. Tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk.
Mother!
Go away. This is a
very sacred moment.
He's got away from us, Jack.
Afraid you're
right, Mr. Helpmann.
He's gone.
Well...
# Then #
# Tomorrow was another day #
# The morning found
me miles away #
# With still
a million things to say #
# Now #
# As twilight gleams
the sky above #
# Recalling thrills
of our love #
# There's one thing
I'm certain of #
# Return #
# I will #
# To old #
# Brazil #