[Girl] I remember the first time
I saw someone move
like they were from another planet.
I couldn't keep my eyes away.
When I was little my mom
took me to watch a jam session
in the neighborhood.
It started out small, but word spread.
Soon, some of the best dancers
around were showing up
to compete in something
they eventually called, "The Streets."
It became the hub, and
I got a front row seat to history.
I wanted to glide and spin
and fly like they did.
But it didn't come easy.
My mom would tell me,
"Don't give up, just be you,
'cause life's too short
to be anybody else. "
She was right.
When I was 16 my mom got sick.
Within a couple of months,
she was gone.
And everything changed...
... including The Streets.
[Indistinct chattering over PA]
Shh. Shh.
[# Busta Rhymes and Timbaland:
Get Down]
Suspects jammed it.
- They went up the stairs.
- Sir, are you OK?
[Police radio, indistinct]
[Laughing]
Yo, the Four-one-oh
killed it again, man.
That was sick, son.
Thank you very much.
I'm a genius.
If you do say so yourself.
Girl, get out of here.
Get that mask off.
Yo, we gonna get some
serious YouTube play, son.
Come on, let's go.
We gotta get to the spot
before everybody gets there.
Oh, man, we struck gold
with this. Look at that, D.
This is off the chain.
Boards are gonna go crazy
over this one.
- Yo, let's upload this stat. Not it.
- Not it.
Aye. Why it gotta be me?
- 'Cause you're the youngest.
- And, obviously, the slowest.
[Speaking Spanish]
Girl, stop slinging
that Spanish at me, Telemundo.
- Aquí-quí-quí-quí-quí-quí-quí.
- Aquí-quí-hell!
- Gotcha.
- Oh, Jesus, Tuck!
Oh, man, wish you could see
the look on your faces.
- Can the jokes, son.
- So what did you guys think?
On the real?
- We killed that!
- Oh!
[Laughing] Oh, yes!
Lucky, lucky!
Streets ain't gonna be ready
for us this year.
- [Girl] Finally.
- Let me see that. Let me see that.
- Give us my camera back. Give me here.
- Go, go, go, go.
So what's up?
We going out tonight?
I don't know. It's just...
It's been a crazy time,
at home with Sarah and all.
- Yeah, I heard that before.
- [Man] Yo, Tuck!
Come on, man, we bouncing.
- We gotta go. You're lagging.
- All right.
- I'll see you at rehearsal.
- OK.
[Woman] This video, posted
on the Internet just hours ago
was taken earlier today.
Depicts the most recent in
a wave of public disturbances
plaguing the streets of Baltimore.
The notoriously elusive Four-one-oh
has claimed responsibility
for this morning's attack
that both defaced public property
and shut down
the Charles Center Station
over security concerns.
Police have been tracking
this troubling trend,
and sources
close to the investigation...
- Not so fast, Andie. Get in here.
- Andie!
We've got to talk.
I can't believe you.
- Dinner was an hour ago.
- Sorry, Sarah, bus was late.
I'm here, so just chill out.
Baby, you go on upstairs
and go to bed.
[Boy] OK.
I know where you been.
It's all over the news.
So don't stand here
and lie to my face.
You realize you could
have been arrested?
It wasn't a big deal.
You have no idea.
You've got to take
responsibility for your life.
You can't follow
the Four-one-oh forever.
Those people are criminals.
I'm putting my foot down.
This has got to stop. Now.
No! No, the Four-one-oh
is the only family I have left.
Who are you to tell me
how to live my life?
Your mother was my best friend!
I told her that
I would be your guardian.
I promised her that
I would take care of you
so you wouldn't have
to leave your life here.
But you won't let me.
Instead, you skip school.
You're out all night.
God only knows what you're doing.
I can't do this.
Your Aunt Alice and I
have been talking.
- You can't live here anymore.
- You're sending me to Texas?
Like I haven't lost enough already?
You can't do this to me!
Your mother never would've let you
get away with half the things I have.
No, you have no idea
what my mother would have done.
Felicia, where are you?
I don't know what to do.
I'm going crazy.
I'm done with her.
Please, I need a place to crash.
I'm not staying there anymore.
Call me. I'm heading to the Dragon.
[# Pitbull featuring Casely: Midnight]
What's poppin'?
I'm the man, DJ Sand.
Tonight it's all about
the Benjamins, baby.
We taking it to The Streets for green.
You got money? No, you don't.
We gonna get it started.
Brand new music. Listen to this one.
[Cheering]
Yo, Meazy. What's going on?
- Yo, D. What it is.
- How are ya?
- You out to do some damage tonight?
- You want to take my bag?
Yes, yes, got it, got it.
It's crazy out there.
- I know. It is.
- About to do your thing?
- Oh, I will. You know.
- Go school them fools.
Look who's all grown up now.
Ty, what are you doing?
Oh, my God.
- What's up, little one?
- Oh. I thought you were
- in New York with Nora.
- I am.
I came back to get
the rest of my stuff.
- Guess what.
- What?
- Me and Nora are going on tour.
Oh, that is unreal.
You better remember me
when you get all famous and stuff.
Are you kidding me?
I remember you when you were
running around in diapers.
You were a pain in my ass.
That's really embarrassing.
Seriously, what's going on
with you and Sarah?
- She called you.
- No, she didn't call me.
I came by to see you,
and she told me you took off.
She's flipping out.
Did she tell you
she's sending me away?
She don't know what else
to do with you.
She's trying to look out for you,
like your mom and everyone else
looked out for me.
- So, you're siding with her.
- No, I'm not.
I don't even need to explain this.
I'm out.
Whoa, whoa, come on. Chill out.
Maybe you'll realize there are
some less dramatic options.
Really, like what?
- MSA.
- OK.
- Maryland School of the Arts.
- Yeah, I know what it is.
Are you crazy? Do I look like
some princess prima ballerina?
Andie, what other options
do you have? Hmm?
Let me break it down for you.
Sarah will give you one more shot.
But MSA's no joke.
You gotta go to class, you can't
skip school, you got to study.
No chance, no way.
OK, fine, I'll battle you for it.
Right now.
You win, I never saw you here tonight.
I win, you get your ass back home
and you're at MSA
first thing in the morning.
If you're scared, say you're scared.
I wouldn't want to battle me
if I was a girl.
No smile?
What, you scared? You down?
[DJ Sand] Hold it, hold it.
Hold up, hold it.
We got royalty in the house.
Tyler Gage is in the building.
- [Cheering]
- [DJ Sand] Oh, man.
You know we gotta
do something special, right?
Clear the dance floor. Back up!
[# T-Pain featuring
Teddy Verseti: Church]
Brand new music.
[DJ Sand] Oh, man,
are those trampolines?
Use 'em or lose 'em.
Here we go. Cool, y'all.
Dre, you want to get this?
I'll break my neck.
No, I got it.
[DJ Sand] Is she talking crazy?
You still dance like a little girl?
[DJ Sand] Let her know
what's good, Tyler.
[Tyler]
Come on, I want to show you.
[DJ Sand] Oh, wow! He's killing you!
Whoo!
She punched it on you.
Whatcha gonna do?
Did she stick you?
She stuck it on you.
[DJ Sand]
What you gonna do? He's not...
[DJ Sand] Oh, no!
He's coming out of his clothes!
It's over. It's over.
Come on, y'all. It's all good, Andie.
Next time, baby.
It's all right. You're good, ma.
Oh. Hey.
Don't sweat it. Everybody's
hatin' on you 'cause you're dope.
Are you running off again?
- No.
- No?
- I'm just trying to look out for you.
- Yeah, whatever.
Yeah, whatever.
Don't give me "whatever."
[Rap music plays]
Let's get you out of here.
I've got to get you home,
plus we've got to sell Sarah
on the idea.
- I thought she agreed.
- Just let me do the talking.
[Sarah] No. I'm sending her
to Texas, that's final.
She's already on probation at school.
This is the one shot she needs
to take all that anger she's got
and be able to put it into a structure.
She's not going to school now.
What makes you think
she's gonna go to this school?
- Piece of cake.
- No way.
- That's the thanks for saving your ass?
- She's down?
Believe it or not, she thinks
I set a good example for you.
- What?
- I don't know.
My work here is done.
I'm going home.
Now, all you have to do is get in.
I thought you said
you took care of everything.
I didn't say I'd get you in.
I said I'd get you an audition.
So, go show 'em what you got, all right?
Go hard, make me proud. Promise?
- Promise.
- OK.
Stay out of trouble, all right?
Holy hell. I cannot believe
you're about to do this.
Well, it is this or Texas,
so... take your pick.
Don't blow it.
No pressure or anything, girl.
- Wait a minute.
- [Boy] Check that out.
It can't be that bad, going here.
- [Boy] She's hot.
- Missy, shut up.
- What?
- Just stop talking.
- I guess.
- Look, go in there and kill it.
We'll see you at rehearsal afterwards.
- Come on, Missy.
- Good luck, D. Later.
[Missy] He was cute. You're mad
'cause he wasn't looking at you.
[Felicia] He wasn't looking at you
or your chapped lips.
[Up-tempo piano playing]
Boring. It's a bunch of clones.
Just because they do turns
with their feet and not on their heads?
Very funny. Wake me up
when they're all done.
I think we'd all agree that talent comes
from mastering technique.
I was brought here because
I can turn amateurs into professionals.
- Nailed it.
- [Groans]
Music, please.
- Thank you.
- Do you have your paperwork?
Yep.
- Hi.
[# Cherish featuring Yung Joc: Killa]
[Man] Thank you, Miss, uh... West.
- Mm-hmm.
- Well.
Well, she was different.
Kidding? That was the best dance
today. The girl's amazing.
She's just a street dancer.
Blake, I thought you could
turn anyone into a professional.
[# Plies: Hypnotized]
Hold that.
So what happened?
- You guys, I choked.
- What do you mean?
I tried to get it back
but I just freaked out.
Sarah gonna have her
in Texas before we know it.
- Hello?
- Yo? Who you talking to?
- [Felicia] Oh, here he comes.
- I gotta take this real quick.
Man, what y'all doing? Come on.
- [Missy] How'd she mess up?
- I hope she didn't.
Yo, Rap.
- Looks like I'm staying.
- Oh!
- You are!
- Goodness, girl.
I knew you would.
How were you not gonna make it?
Yo, we need a family meeting.
Yo, we got this gig
at the Dragon coming up,
and we're not even close to being ready.
The Four-one-oh is a unit.
We're only as strong as
our weakest link. With the way
our new members are slacking,
we have to step it up.
Which means,
rehearsal every day, 4:00 p.m.
No excuses, no being late,
and no cell phones.
Are we clear?
- [Missy] Crystal.
- [Felicia] We're clear.
[# Kevin Michael:
We All Want the Same Thing]
[Indistinct chattering]
You're in my seat.
I'm kidding.
This is my seat, but I'll give you
a pass for today.
Nice. Nice. Nice shirt,
Napoleon Dynamite. Nice.
You look fantastic today,
by the way. Nice hair.
What's up?
I'm Robert Alexander, III.
You can call me Moose.
What's up. I'm Andie.
It's like this. Give me your hand.
You got to blow it up.
Blow it up, right. Blow it up.
[Making blowing sounds]
Go by like that. Aye! Yeah?
It's mine, so... Shh.
- You're not eating?
- You call this food?
Tofu dogs are both
nutritious and delicious.
This is good.
Mmm.
# Tastes like candy canes
at Christmas #
- What?
- You've got crap on your face.
Oh. I knew we could
help each other out.
Oh, what makes you think I need help?
[Mocking]
What makes you think I need...
Trust me. I have what you need.
I have the inside on everything.
Who's dating, who's hating.
And who's hooking up.
What's up, Dan? What's up, Gator?
- [Dan] Who's that?
- See you guys later.
That's the music room.
This is the art room
where some of the greatest
Baltimore artists...
[girl] I'm dead serious.
Sorry.
Oh!
You OK?
Hey.
Thank you.
We gotta stop meeting like this,
you know.
It's Andie, right?
I'm Chase. Welcome to MSA.
I'm glad you made it in.
Well, here I am.
You're an amazing little dancer.
- What?
- You're an amazing little dancer.
Little? Really?
Well, you know, I wouldn't call
my dancing "little."
- I definitely was not trying to say...
- [Moose] Andie!
Where have you been?
I've been looking for you.
- Chase.
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- Great. You guys are friends?
- Yeah, we go way back.
- Good.
We're actually late
for a little something, so...
We are?
- Yeah.
- What?
- That thing you told me?
- I didn't tell you anything.
Yes, you did. We're gonna go.
- Remember that thing?
- What?
- That thing you wanted to do?
- What are you talking about?
I can't believe
you know Chase Collins.
That's extremely vital
information to withhold.
- I don't know him.
- He's Mr. Popular.
Like a legacy. His parents,
like, founded this school.
And his brother is legendary.
- Dr. Collins is his brother?
- Yeah.
He used to go here, then moved to
London to dance with the Royal Ballet.
Oh, my God. That's him?
Yeah. It's hard to believe,
right, with all those feathers.
So why'd he come back?
Good question.
Sources say he has some sweet deal
to make MSA the next Juilliard.
Which he's been trying to do.
Maybe he's just burned out.
One thing's for sure.
There's a lot of changes
going down that nobody likes.
Here.
Anyway, the Collins
are like flippin' MSA royalty.
Chase, he's a ladies' man.
- He's a player?
- Like an all-star.
He's only recently taken the jersey
out of retirement. So be warned.
Oh, and that's Cyborg Sophie.
She's an MSA machine
and Collins' crowning achievement.
She's a triple threat.
She acts, sings and dances.
She won every competition out there.
But she just lost
the biggest battle of them all,
the one for Chase's heart.
It's like I've landed
in an episode of The Hills.
He broke up with her a few weeks ago,
but they'll end up together.
Just in time
for the season finale, huh?
See? I knew you'd come around.
Hello, everyone.
I'm Director Collins.
I hope you've all stretched
this morning,
'cause we have
a lot of work to do today.
I'm sure that everyone
has heard of our plans
to move MSA into a new
state-of-the-art facility.
Well, to encourage the donors,
we're throwing a fundraiser,
where you will perform
to demonstrate what
a good investment you are.
It should be a wonderful event.
You are all required to participate
in one way or another.
So, let's begin with some improv,
shall we?
Jimmy, you're up.
[Soft rock piece plays]
[Door opens]
You're late. Not being on time
won't fly in the real world.
Already with that stuff, Blake?
- That's Director Collins.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Chase, show us what you got.
[# Breaking Benjamin: Diary of Jane]
- [Turns music off]
- [Students groan]
Not great. Could do better.
OK. Andie, you're up.
[# Hope: Bring Me Flowers]
Are you serious?
Listen and interpret.
[Laughter]
Andie. Andie!
You're all over the place.
Again, from the top,
listen and interpret.
[Music resumes]
Stop. Stop! Can I have
a word with you in private?
And bring your bags.
You understand you've been
given an opportunity
that others couldn't even dream of?
I put my name on the line for you,
and I'm beginning to wonder
if I made a mistake.
You clearly have
some catching up to do.
Starting tomorrow I'm assigning you
to attend after school sessions with me.
Well, I can't. I gotta be somewhere.
Consider this an opportunity.
What?
[Girls chanting] Made a mistake
and kissed a snake
How many doctors did it take?
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten
Just breathe.
First day's always the worst.
- I was just...
- That's OK.
I come out to the front steps
and meditate, too.
What? It's not meditating.
It's just, you know,
you had some pretty
serious balls today in class.
- I was impressed.
- Oh, gee, thanks.
- You're welcome.
- So what's your deal?
Boy bands making a comeback?
Yeah. They have a course on it here.
I'm getting straight A's.
That wouldn't surprise me.
Look, it's been interesting
bonding with you, but I'm late.
- Late for what?
- Just this rehearsal thing.
- Rehearsal for what?
- Rehearsal with some friends.
- Like a crew?
- What would you know about that?
Knew it. Saw you at the Dragon.
You're with Four-one-oh.
- I don't know what...
- I've always wanted to compete,
I've just never had an in.
Can you hook me up?
Hey, Chase, we're working
on the routine for the fundraiser.
Are you coming?
[Chase] Yeah, I'll be right there.
Sophie, I'll meet you in the rehearsal.
OK.
Look.
The Streets is about where you're from.
It's not some school talent show.
There's no spring floors.
There's no spotlights.
You use what you got and...
What makes you think you got it?
Weren't you late for something, Andie?
[Girls chanting] All dressed in yella
Went upstairs to kiss a fella
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven, eight,
- Bye, Andie West.
- Nine, ten, 11, 12,
13, 14, 15, 16...
...five, six, seven, eight.
Again.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four.
Whoa, wait, oh, wait.
You did that different.
Can you do that from three four?
Let me go figure this out.
Y'all just chill here for a second.
Where have you been?
I been texting you all day.
I know, I'm sorry.
The school thing is crazy.
Will you cover for me with Tuck?
Don't I always cover for you? Yeah.
Yo, D, let me holler at you.
Yo, where you been?
I had to take care of some stuff.
- Yeah, with who?
- Charlie.
Sarah asked me to take care of him
while she was at work.
You still coming over tonight or what?
Yeah, yeah. Gonna take care
of some stuff and I'll be there.
All right.
[Tuck] Yo! Start from the beginning.
OK, now, point your toe.
You see, you're sickling.
There should be no curve
disrupting the line from the knee
all the way down to the tip of your toe.
- Ow! Ow!
- There you go. That's it.
- There. That's it.
- Ow. Pointing hurts.
Yeah, it's supposed to.
[Hip hop music playing]
[Classical music plays]
Pull in your stomach.
Flatten, flatten, flatten.
Now, tuck your butt.
Keep this leg turned out.
Turned out. Turned out!
Oh, my God.
[Hip hop music continues playing]
Balancé, balancé,
chassé, pas de bourrée,
turn, turn, down, finish.
[Hip hop music continues playing]
Turn, turn, spot, spot!
Ready, and feet in front, feet back,
feet front, feet back. Come on.
And back and back
and back and back
and back and back and back
and back and back and back and back.
Good! That's it.
Andie? There's dinner down here.
[Phone vibrating]
- [video game on TV]
- Yo, where D at?
She left me a message.
Sarah got her on lockdown again.
Guess she's missing out... again.
Guess so.
[Moose] And then I was like,
"Damn, your breath stinks."
[Andie] Why would you say that?
- I thought it would be cool.
- Well, it wasn't.
[Hip hop song plays on ringtone]
- It's my mom.
- Oh, my gosh.
- What?
- That is not your ringtone.
Why? It's the coolest thing ever.
OK, fine. Listen.
[# Timbaland: The Way I Are]
Here we go.
Watch me, watch me, watch.
[Andie] I don't even know him.
You were so sick.
I had no idea you could dance.
- Whatever.
- What are you talking about?
Why don't you dance here?
I can freestyle all right. Right?
But I didn't get in here for dance.
I didn't think I could do choreography.
But now I'm all about lighting design.
[Instrumental rock plays]
- [Music turns off]
- The end's not working.
Mixing those moves just feels wrong.
- Come on, man.
- Let me show you something.
If you put this here into a canon,
and then swing through to fifth,
then bring it down. Step, step, stag.
Soutenu, double tour to the knee.
Nice, Jimmy.
[Groans, sighs]
Looks like someone's in a good mood.
Must be hard living in the shadow
of a legend, huh?
Wow, that coming
from the MSA charity case?
I was kidding. You're right,
he's an ass. I'm out of here.
Look, I never called you an ass.
She just said that for dramatic effect.
If you're trying to win her over,
you probably shouldn't
treat her like that.
I'm not trying to win her over.
Then don't lead her on.
Andie.
- Hey.
- What's going on?
I wanted to apologize
for earlier today.
It wasn't anything personal.
I had a really rough day
and I was joking.
Oh, please.
It's not like I sit up at night
and think about what
you do or don't say to me,
but thanks.
- I feel better now.
- Let me give you a ride.
Make it up to you.
I can just take the bus.
No, come on. My car's
gotta smell better than the bus.
[# Scarface: Girl You Know]
- [Missy] There she is.
- [Felicia] She come when we're done.
[Missy] She missed
the whole rehearsal.
Hey, guys.
Miss thing girl. Where you been at?
What's the deal?
Thank you for gracing us
with your presence.
- Rehearsal's done.
- Hey, hey, come on.
I got here as soon as I could.
You know what's been going on.
No, I don't, but I'll tell you
what's been going on.
Everybody's been asking,
"Have you talked to D? Where's D at?"
I'm looking like an ass
making stuff up for you,
so you can go dance around
your fancy new school.
- What is your problem?
- What's going on here?
- Ask her.
- What was that?
I said, "Ask her."
D, you gotta tell me something?
Yeah, the reason I've been late
and haven't been around much
is because...
...l've been going to school at MSA.
So you've been lying to me
and the crew for what?
- Those ballet boys?
- I don't have a choice.
No, that's messed up, D. We're family.
I thought you said
you understood that.
The Four-one-oh
don't come second to nobody.
- You out.
- No, please, Tuck, come on.
It's just been a crazy time.
It's always been a crazy time with you.
Yo, let's go.
- Oh!
- Hey, watch yourself, huh?
God...
Morning, sunshine.
The good times just keep on
coming, don't they?
Ouch.
- What got into you today?
- What?
As opposed to my winning charm
every other day?
Fair enough. Two points to the new girl.
You want to talk about it?
- I got kicked out of my crew.
- What for?
For being here.
I can't believe I messed this up.
They're the ones that messed up.
They lost an amazing dancer.
You should just start your own crew.
No, you can't just start your own crew.
- Why not?
- Because you can't.
- Besides, who would be in it? Me and...
- Me.
- Us.
- OK. We'll just start our own crew.
What else you gonna do?
Nobody here is gonna step out
of their perfect world.
Not the Sophie Donovans, but
there's a lot going on under the radar.
Really?
[Chase] There's this guy we call Hair.
He's this half hippy,
half rhythmic rebel
and he makes the sickest beats.
Teachers don't know
what to do with him.
Can't put him in a class, gets bored,
makes up his own steps.
[# Cupid featuring B.o. B: 3- 6-9]
There's Kido. She's this
foreign exchange student
obsessed with old-school
American hip hop.
And, trust me, she doesn't need
English to speak our language.
Fly's the quiet one,
but not when the music's on.
She's too tall to partner, but when
you're that good, who needs a partner?
[Chase] Which brings us to Monster,
our resident stunt double.
He flips, he slides, he falls.
Whatever you need to make
an action sequence work onstage.
But he never gets the spotlight.
[Chase] Most know my boy, Cable,
as the video yearbook editor.
But little do they know,
he's one of the best freestyle dancers
I've seen in my life.
And, finally, Smiles.
Nicest guy you'll ever meet.
Dopest dancer on the dance floor.
Unfortunately, MSA only sees
what it wants to see.
- [Andie] Don't forget Moose.
- Moose?
- Yeah, trust me on this one.
- [Chase] Come on.
[Andie] But what makes you
think they'll do it?
[Chase] They all have nothing to lose.
No!
You guys, listen up. Check it out.
Now, I know each and every one
of you knows what it's like
to be forced to conform
and become an MSA robot, right?
Yeah, they wanted me to cut my hair.
Yeah, and fix my teeth.
- I like your teeth.
- Thank you.
I like your accent.
What kind of accent?
The accent you have.
You have an accent.
- I have no accent.
- It's really strong.
[Chase] That's my point.
I know that each one of you guys
has an amazing talent
that this school doesn't know
what to do with.
I think it's time we do
something with that talent.
- Like what?
- Like form a crew
and compete at The Streets.
- [All] No, no!
- [Girl] I heard it's dangerous.
Forget about what you heard.
The Streets is about the best dance crew
showing off what they got.
- We don't stand a chance.
- What are you talking about?
I've seen you do stunts
in the school play.
There's a reason
they call you Monster.
Like this?
- [Smiles laughing] That was hot.
- That's crazy.
Kido, you went crazy at the showcase
after-party last year.
Oh, that was fun.
Hey, hey, hey, hey hey, hey.
- Get it, Kido.
- She won't... She won't stop.
She won't stop, she won't.
You need to stop.
- So when is it?
- That's the thing.
Nobody knows when or where
until a text message of the night of.
So we have got to be ready.
Sounds good. Director Collins'd
never let us rehearse here.
- No way.
- Who said Director Collins has to know?
- [Smiles] Wow.
- [Kido] He's got the keys.
Borrowed and copied.
MSA after hours. I like it.
[# Missy Elliot: Shake Your Pom Pom]
Yeah! Oh, man, we did good.
What do you say we go
and check out our competition?
[DJ Sand] All right,
let's get it started right now!
Whoo! Oh, man! Put your hands up.
Put your hands up. I see you, baby!
Want your mama again?
Hey, yo, Leesh.
Leesh, look, look, look, look.
- Andie's here.
- Where?
Right there.
She shouldn't be.
Yo, what you doing here, man?
Oh, please don't tell me
that's your new crew.
- No.
- Yeah, we're her crew.
Getting ready to battle at The Streets.
What street, Sesame Street?
- What do you know about The Streets?
- Why don't you back off?
We're just here
to check a few things out.
This is how you've been wasting
your time, with these losers?
Why don't you do your thing?
We're gonna do ours.
You got a thing that you do?
Why don't you show us now, homeboy?
- All right, let's go.
- Yeah, let's go.
[Speaks Japanese]
Hey, yo, DJ Sand!
Drop that beat, homey.
Looks like we've got new fish in town.
Let's clear the dance floor.
See what they talking about.
Now, you come into my house,
you recognize what's going on.
Don't step in that circle
if you ain't got it.
[# Webbie Feat, Lil' Boosie
and Lil' Phat: Independent]
When do we start?
Five. Start on five when I start.
[DJ Sand] The music's playing already.
Dance to the music.
That's not how we do it here.
This ain't High School Musical.
[Booing]
That's how you dance?
Your mama taught you that?
We don't dance like that.
That's what you learned
at your special school?
Boo! Quit it!
[DJ Sand] That's atrocious.
- [Music stops]
- That's it. No more.
No more.
What in the hell was that?
That's how you dance?
I'll tell you what.
We gonna show you
how we really get down.
Y'all pick up a keychain
on the way out.
Tell your mama not to be late
picking you up from work.
[Man] You guys are garbage!
Lets get it. Four-one-oh,
can we get it started?
Let's get it started. Here we go.
Four-one-oh, forget them.
Let's get it.
[# Missy Elliot: Ching a Ling]
[DJ Sand]
That's what I'm talking about.
See how they entertaining?
- That's how we do it.
- [Cheering]
You can't learn that in school!
Let's just...
Let's just regroup tomorrow.
Come on.
[Chase] Guys, come on.
This is one performance.
You can't let it get you down.
[Andie] We didn't work
this hard to just give up.
[Smiles] Shouldn't have
went there in the first place.
We looked like idiots.
[Cable] Chase, the choreography
wasn't right for this.
- [Voices overlapping]
- [Cable] No, it wasn't.
I'm telling you.
- Hey.
- It's cool. I know her.
What are you doing here?
Things got out of hand last night.
Yeah. Thanks for your support.
Look, I'm sorry.
What they did to you was wrong.
- But you should know that I quit.
- What?
Yeah. They're on such
a power trip. I refuse.
I thought we were supposed
to be about family.
And it just wasn't
the same without you.
But, look, I miss you.
I haven't seen you in that long.
My family's having
a barbeque this Saturday.
Why don't you come through?
- So that's why you came by?
- Yeah.
You know, Felicia is going to
trip if she knows you're here.
Felicia should be the last
of your worries right now.
I swear, we're really not that bad.
Really. Come on.
Hey, you guys,
this is my girl, Missy.
She's here to, uh... help us out.
[Smiles] Help us out?
We bombed last night.
[Cable] Our respect
went out the window.
- [Smiles] Sure did.
- [Overlapping voices]
Hold up, hold up, hold up.
What are y'all talking about,
respect went out the window?
Like respect is going?
You can always get it back.
What are you all thinking
for The Prank?
What's The Prank?
Yo, D, you ain't tell them
about The Prank?
The Prank is what the crews do to show
they're competing for The Streets.
It's a public declaration
saying that you're bringing it.
The crazier it is, the better.
For proof you gotta record it
and post it online.
Then it spreads like wildfire.
And if you guys hit it like I know
you can, y'all get your respect back.
I got an idea.
[Man] Watch this, watch this! Oh-ho!
Been runnin' that ball
on him all day, son.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
- Yo, man.
- Yo!
Why's my crib smell like Funyuns,
broccoli and ball sweat?
It's your boy, Crumbs.
He's been letting it loose all day.
It's the coffee, bro.
[Laughter]
Yo, Tuck, come see this.
You gotta come see this, bro.
[Tape distorts]
[# Digital Underground:
The Humpty Dance]
[Music stops]
Oh, dang!
- Relax, relax.
- That's my computer, man!
[All exclaiming]
Man, clean this fish up!
[Hip hop music plays]
Moose, what are you doing?
Maybe we should put you back
in that grandma suit, huh?
- [Laughter]
- Who's we?
[All chattering indistinctly]
Hey, what are you guys doing?
- Hi, Sophie. What's up?
- Rehearsing for the fundraiser.
Why are you here on a Saturday?
We were gonna do the same thing,
but it's locked.
- We gotta roll, so we'll see y'all.
- Where are we going?
To my house. My family's
having a barbecue, remember?
- Yeah, yeah, barbecue.
- Why you standing there?
Let's be out.
Are you going with them?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
I'd say you should go, but...
But I'm not really sure
it's your scene.
I'd love to.
All right.
Watch your step. Welcome.
- Look at how nice it is.
- Thank you.
Come down, hurry up.
Y'all taking mad long.
- Hey, Mom!
- [Speaking Spanish]
How are you?
We missed you.
Everyone is here. Come in.
- Have some food.
- Whoa, wait.
You're coming with me.
- Where are we going?
- You'll see.
[# Casa de Leones: No Te Veo]
I can't believe I'm doing this.
What's wrong with what I had before?
Latin men like their girls
to look like women, not boys.
A fact you'll appreciate
when you meet my cousin.
You are not setting me up.
Alejandro's nice. Plus he just got here.
You're pimping me out
so that your cousin
can get a green card?
He's from Florida.
Trust me, if he was not my cousin,
you would not be standing there.
- You're sick.
- Hmm.
And I'm hungry,
so are we done here?
I guess.
[Gasps]
Ooh, Miss Thing, you got titties?
[Laughs] Why you trying to look
better than me at my party?
[# Trey Songz: Can't Help but Wait]
- Hey, cuz.
- Hey, mama.
How you doing?
This is my friend, Andie.
Andie, my cousin, Alejandro.
- Nice to meet you.
I'm just gonna sit down
while you guys talk.
- You want to dance a real dance?
- I'd love to.
Come on, mama.
[# Robin Thicke:
Everything I Can't Have]
- May I borrow your boyfriend?
- Oh, he's not my boyfriend.
It doesn't matter. It's just a dance.
It's just a dance.
Andie, come here.
You should really wait your turn.
- Ooh.
- I couldn't.
I didn't know you could salsa.
There's a lot you don't know about me.
Which is surprising, considering
how much you talk about yourself.
Ooh.
What's going on over here?
My goodness, Aunt Maria.
It has been emotional.
- [Laughing]
- I'll hit you up on MySpace sometime.
Thank you. You are charming.
- Thank you so much.
- I had a good time.
Me, too. Don't tell
your husband about us, now.
- Bye.
- [Andie] Hey.
- God?
- [Laughing]
You want to fly up here and give me
a hand with these lights?
Sophie, what's up, girl?
Let me find out.
You got a lot of stuff going.
A lot of sofrito up in you.
Thank you.
You're not so bad yourself.
Gracias, gracias.
Moose, help me with these lights.
Mom's gonna kill me. Hurry up.
- Hurry up!
- Hold this. I'm coming.
Sophie, I'll do it, I'll do it.
I'll do it. You're welcome.
- [Andie] There we go.
- [Chase] This is really high.
No, it's not that bad.
- Yes, it is.
- No, we're good.
- All right. Tree climber.
- [Laughing]
All right, this is gonna
sound cheesy, but...
...for what it's worth,
I'm really glad you're at MSA.
I think you were doing
just fine before I got there.
That's just the thing.
I mean, I've been trained to dance
since I first learned to walk.
But it's always been about
doing it their way and it's just not me.
But, ever since you came,
I feel more like myself.
- Oh, geez.
- [Laughs]
Well, I know what you mean.
My mom always used to tell me,
"Just be yourself."
When I was little
that sounded strange,
'cause I was like,
"How could I be anyone else?"
- I bet you miss her.
- Yeah.
When she got cancer, it was like
the floor fell from underneath.
I've just been running ever since.
But now I can't find my way back.
Well, maybe it's not about going back.
Maybe it's about being
right where you are.
[Car engine starting]
- [Dogs barking]
- [Car approaching]
I heard you was
dancing it up in there.
What, you not joking now?
Come on, guys,
I'm just trying to get home.
You thought it was real funny,
what you did the other day.
- Tuck, it's a joke.
- Look here.
Just 'cause you hang out with D
don't mean you got what it takes.
She don't know where she came from.
You don't know anything about her.
So now you defending her?
Yes, I am.
I'll see you at The Streets.
At The Streets?
You in the streets now.
[Groaning]
Unless you want some more of us,
I suggest you stay away
from The Streets.
And stay farther away from Andie.
Drop this fool.
Come on, get up, fool.
Get up!
Yeah. Ha.
- [Spits]
- You're not so funny now,
are you, clown?
Hey, yo, Tuck.
Hey.
- Chase, what's going on?
- Hey.
- Hi.
How you doing? Is everything OK?
Yes, everything's OK.
Why wouldn't everything be OK?
- Oh, my God. What happened to you?
- Nothing. Nothing.
Don't worry. Listen,
I've got to get to class.
That is not nothing.
Who did this to you?
Just forget about it. Let it go.
Who did this?
Does anybody know
who is responsible for this?
This school will not be associated
with these competitions.
Any future involvement
by our students in The Streets
will lead to expulsion.
And anyone with any information
is expected to come forward.
Get this place cleaned up.
Man, I can't believe
they trashed the studio.
Now we have Director Collins
on our back.
- Glass is all over the floor.
- Somebody broke the stereo.
[Kido] I don't understand.
[Cable] These guys are no joke.
[Smiles] Collins was pissed.
- [Moose] Graffiti was everywhere.
- What are we gonna do?
- We could get expelled.
- My parents would kill me
if I got expelled.
I'd have to go to a regular school
with regular kids.
- Hey, guys.
- [Chatter stops]
This has gotten way out of hand.
I'm really sorry
that I got you all into this.
Andie, don't say that.
I put everything you guys
worked for at risk.
And it's not fair.
- We're all in on this together.
- Yeah, yeah.
No, it's over.
The crew's done. I don't know
what we were thinking.
Andie West, Director Collins
would like to see you.
By being involved in this
you've brought delinquent
behavior into my school
and put my students at risk.
And now the studio
has been vandalized.
It wasn't exactly like that.
I thought I could train you,
turn you into the dancer
that you could be.
But I was wrong.
There's nothing
that we can do for someone
who doesn't appreciate
what's in front of them.
I understand.
You know, I really did try.
I'm not done.
Was there anyone else involved
from this school?
No.
No one else. Just me.
Then I have no choice
but to expel you.
- But I didn't...
- I'm sorry.
That's it. I'm finished. Please leave.
[Chase] Andie.
There you are.
I've been looking all over for you.
- What are we gonna do?
- It's done.
Everything's done.
I think it's pretty clear that
none of this was meant to be.
Whoa, Andie.
Don't do this.
Please just... Just let it go.
- [Sarah] You got that?
- Mm-hmm
You're my big strong boy, huh?
I am your big strong boy.
Your school called.
I know I said things
would be different...
I know what happened.
No more excuses, Andie.
I'm sick and tired of this.
You're going to your aunt's
in Texas, and that's final.
It was my idea.
- Your idea for what?
- To compete in The Streets.
If you're gonna throw someone out
it should have been me.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm not throwing you out.
How would that make me look?
I'm not gonna let her
take the fall for this.
I should never have let her in.
It didn't benefit us in any way.
Not everything we do has to benefit us.
Some people, Andie in particular,
do what they love just because.
Isn't that why we started dancing
in the first place?
Look, I have a lot to do
for the fundraiser.
And so do you.
My decision about Andie is final.
We're done here.
[# Laura lzibor: Mmm]
- [Indistinct chattering]
- [Classical music plays]
Oh, Peggy Beckham.
[Cell phone vibrates]
See, this is our new building.
Made of glass
with state-of-the-art studios.
[Cell phone rings]
Hey. Is Andie here?
Andie?
It's for you.
- What are you guys doing here?
- Andie, we're going.
Eighth and Main, The Streets.
We need you.
No, but what about the fundraiser?
- You could all be expelled.
- Forget the fundraiser.
- We don't want the school to move.
- It's time we took a stand.
- Like you did.
- If MSA doesn't want you...
- Then we don't want you.
- What are you talking about?
We do want Andie.
We want Andie in, yes, right?
- Yes.
- Look, you brought us together
and took the fall for us
when we should have all done more.
[Chase] Andie, that's why we're here.
We've all made a lot of mistakes,
but now's our time.
We can go all the way.
If we don't try, it was all for nothing.
Come on, are you in?
- I can't.
- [All] Why?
I promised Sarah
I'd finish packing tonight.
Andie?
Can we talk a minute?
- Yeah. I'll be right back.
- [All murmuring]
I made a promise to your mom
to take care of you.
I want to keep it.
I know.
I understand that
and I am done fighting.
You know, you remind me
so much of your mother.
You have her passion.
She was a really good friend
to me, Andie.
Just like you are to them.
I just feel like I finally found
this place where I belong.
I found people who believe in me.
I believe in you, too.
I've seen a change in you.
You should go tonight.
Really?
She'd want you to.
- Let's do this.
- [All cheering]
[# Flo-rida featuring T-Pain: Low]
[DJ Sand] Baltimore, y'all ready?
We gonna get down to it,
see who has the hottest skills.
The dopest squad.
You ready to get it started?
It's The Streets, baby.
- [Missy] Take a left.
- [Smiles] And slow down.
[Kido] Faster, faster! I love America!
Whoo!
It's your man, DJ Sand,
and it's the battle of the year.
We're getting ready to get
really banoodles out here.
Can y'all handle that?
[Crowd screaming]
[DJ Sand]
Come on, let's get wild, man.
Yo, man, you see this?
- [Felicia] Are you coming?
- [Man] Good luck. Good luck.
[# Yung Joc: I'm A G]
What part of "You don't belong here"
do you not understand?
Why don't you chill?
We're just trying to perform here
like everyone else.
[Tuck] Yo, homey, this is how it is.
You're not invited.
This is a closed event.
For locals only.
Besides, that jazz funk
that y'all pulled at the Dragon
ain't gonna cut it here.
Neither will those moves
you've been doing the past five years.
And by the way,
I really liked your place,
but I think that fish
made it smell better.
Watch your face.
I'll knock you out, you hear?
- Don't disrespect me in my place.
- You boys fighting in my house now?
You're think you're funny?
You want to tell me
what the hell is going on?
They're at The Streets.
The Streets?
- I have to stop this.
- Wait.
You always tell us that dance
is about having something to say.
I never meant for anyone...
I think that a lot of people
are finally speaking up.
Can't allow my students
to participate in something illegal.
Well, there's a reason
they're there and not here.
You should take a look.
I think you'd be surprised.
- And you are?
- Robert Alexander, III.
But you can call me Moose.
I dance with their crew.
You dance?
Damn right, I dance.
I can take you to where they are.
OK, Goose, let's go.
- No, it's Moose.
- Whatever.
Wait. I'm coming with you.
[DJ Sand] It's the moment
you've all been waiting for.
At this time, let me introduce
the five time reigning champ.
Give it up, make some noise,
for the Four-one-oh!
[# Ludacris: The Potion]
[Woman] Get it, Four-one-oh, let's go!
Let's go!
[DJ Sand] Check it out, baby!
That's what I'm talkin' about!
Give it up to the Four-one-oh!
All right, you've seen 'em all.
Tell me who the hottest crew
in Baltimore is.
That's what you think? I don't know,
the Four-one-oh killed it.
- All right, y'all, let's hit it.
- [DJ Sand] Yo, baby.
No, B, we're from the hood.
Yo, this is a neighborhood battle.
You're out of luck.
Now, go home. Leave.
That's mad wack, B.
[DJ Sand] We're gonna get to it,
figure it out after this.
Andie!
Hey, yo, it's not done yet.
We've got one more for you.
- My crew's back there. We want a shot.
- We're done. Doesn't matter.
Not from around here,
but we want a shot.
Hey!
- Yo!
- [All] Boo!
- [Booing]
- Look.
We're all here because...
All right, all right.
Yo. Some of you guys think...
Some of you guys think
that we don't belong here.
- What is she doing?
- It doesn't matter where we're from.
[Woman]
You are not the valedictorian.
- All right, all right.
- [Booing]
Let me just say something.
The Streets are supposed to be about
different people coming together.
We call this a battle,
but what are we fighting for?
We're all here because we have
this thing we do. We dance.
Right?
Being a part of The Street
used to mean more than turf or power.
It was about bringing
something new to the floor.
And it shouldn't matter what we wear,
what school
or what neighborhood we're from.
Because the best part of The Streets
is, it's not about what you've got.
It's what you make of what you've got.
[Cheering]
So, if the Four-one-oh is too scared
to defend their title against us,
then, hell, we'll be outside doing
our thing where The Streets started.
[Cheering]
We'll accept that.
[Cheering continues]
I'm sure we've got something
that will work.
- La-da!
- Ooh!
Hit it, hit it, hit it.
[Drumming]
[Cheering]
[# Timbaland featuring Dr. Dre, Justin
Timberlake, Missy Elliot: Bounce]
[Cheering]
[# Swizz Beatz: Money in the Bank]
Go, go, go!
[Cheering]
[Crowd screaming]
[Chase] Yeah, we did it, baby.
Whoo-hoo!
All right! Whoo!
Well. That was different.
[Laughs] Yes, sorry about
the whole toe-pointing thing.
Yeah. I guess that
didn't stick too well.
I'll keep working on that.
Yeah, you will, in my class.
At school on Monday.
Oh, my God!
Whoa. Hey, Moose!
Yeah, you.
I think you might be
in the wrong department.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have a little explaining to do
at a fundraiser.
Oh, yeah.
So, see, I told you
we could help each other out.
Yeah, yeah. Whatever.
Whatever.
[Making exploding sound]
Blow it up.
- Moose, hey.
- Hey, Soph.
- How you doing?
- I'm good.
- Did you see us?
- That was great.
Sliding and flipping.
My hat trick was amazing.
I was just doing it,
like it was amazing.
That's what I thought.
Andie! Andie!
Hey!
Happy birthday.
Open your present.
Blow out your candles.
You did so good.
I'm so proud of you.
- Andie, I love you.
- I love you.
I gotta go.
I gotta pump. I gotta pump.
I thought you said we couldn't
start our own crew.
I thought you said
my dancing was little.
Look around. You brought
all these people out here.
[# Flo-rida featuring T-Pain: Low]
[# Missy Elliot:
Shake Your Pom-Pom]
[# Cassie: Is It You]
[# Bayje: Impossible]