Go on. I ain't got nothin'. Psst!
Sweet Jesus!
Oh, God! No! No! No!
Yeah,
this is definitely our campsite.
- So...
- So we're here. Come on.
Can you help me with this?
Here. Over there, by the fire pit.
- Oh, here, here, here, here.
- Oh, yeah. You need that.
Need the hatchet.
- Thank you for doing this.
- I was made for camping.
- This is, like, my thing.
- Hm-hm.
- What? Oh, really?
- You know what?
- What?
- I think I'm gonna like camping.
- Yeah?
- Hm-hm.
- I told you.
Ow! Wait a minute.
- Did you get the bug stuff?
- Come on. Let's get this tent up.
Come on.
Shit, shit, shit.
- The engine's fucking destroyed.
- This ain't how you talked it, D.
Mexico is just around the corner,
sweetheart. Come on.
It's not.
Well, this truck ain't getting us
any closer, alright? Let's go.
- Mine's in.
- It can't be. I... Hold on.
- Well, just hold that. Just trust me.
- OK.
- Hey, got it.
- OK, mine's in.
Ow! Well, now mine's not.
- Are you OK?
- This is...
- Are you sure you got the right hole?
- OK, is this the right pole?
- Look how short that pole is.
- Yeah, it's... Yeah.
I'm starting to think
we're not wilderness people.
Of course we are.
We can't let this tent beat us, OK?
You always say we have to be smarter
than what we're working against.
You know what I'm definitely
smarter than? A motel.
No. You can't see the stars
from a motel. And that wasn't the deal.
The deal was anniversary sex
under the stars.
OK, that part sounds kind of familiar.
Alright, hold your end.
I'll get this in.
- OK.
- You ready? You got it?
OK.
Oh!
Are you kidding me?
Tell me you remembered the spare tent.
No.
Come here. Come here.
Motel. Motel. Motel.
Come on. Come on!
OK.
What are you doing?
Hey, D. That's all our stuff.
We're getting all new stuff, baby.
All new stuff.
Hey, who's the cowgirl, huh?
I fucking hate it when you call me that.
Hey, there's my cowgirl. There she is.
Let's go.
Just gotta hang on a little while
longer. We're almost fucking there.
Who's my lady Lacey, huh?
There you are, baby. Just gotta hang on
a little while fucking longer, alright?
- Do you realise how old this forest is?
- No. Please tell me.
The whole area mostly sucks for logging,
so these trees are completely untouched.
Some of them are 400 years old,
maybe more.
- Really?
- They just grow older and older.
You know, if you spent half as much time
in nature as you do reading about it,
we'd be cuddling
under the stars tonight.
Cuddling.
Hey, come on.
Now we get to spend our anniversary
basking in the glow of free cable TV.
Next year we're camping.
- Alright.
- OK.
See that tree right there? That's a post
oak, a 300-year-old tree at least.
Baby, could we please
just have a moment of silence,
you know, to mourn the loss of our tent?
OK. Look at the positives here
for two seconds. Just go with me.
- OK.
- We get to stay at a ghetto-ass motel.
There's gonna be bugs everywhere.
The AC will probably be broken.
It's gonna be every bit as uncomfortable
as sleeping in the wilderness.
- So why are you complaining?
- Will there be holes in the sheets?
We won't stop
until we find a place that does.
- Or I'll poke holes in them myself.
- I love you.
Oh! Look at that tree. That's gotta be
at least 400 years old, right?
- Look how big that one is.
- That's an old tree.
I'd say closer to 100 or 200.
See it has stumps halfway up?
You're gonna laugh at me?
You're gonna laugh at me when I'm...
I think you're cute.
It's adorable when you talk about trees.
I'm not gonna talk about 'em any more.
What the?
Did you?
- What's she doing out here by herself?
- She looks... not right.
- Well, what do you wanna do?
- Hm.
- She's coming up here.
- I don't know. I think it's weird.
- It's OK. Go.
- Maybe he's with her.
- No, thank you.
- I don't know.
- Oh, my God, Seth.
- Are you fucking deaf?
- Whoa, whoa!
- Out of the fucking car now. Out.
- Baby, no!
- We're good, baby. We're good.
Turn it off. Get out of the car.
Nice and easy, alright?
Get out of the car.
- Just... Just...
- Get out of the fucking car now!
- Oh, God!
- OK, OK.
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah, yeah.
Clear the back seat.
Make room for two more.
No, D, you can't change the plan.
You said no hostages.
I know what I said, baby.
I know what I said. Listen to me.
Plat's 40 miles up the road.
The bank's closed. It don't open
till 8am. Listen to me. Trust me.
We're gonna do this right.
Come here. Come here.
Listen to me. You gotta trust me, OK?
You trust me? You trust me?
OK, give me a kiss.
OK, go get in the front seat.
Let's go, kid.
That's twice.
OK.
- Up.
- Oh, God. God.
- You, around the front. Drive.
- I can drive.
- I wasn't talking to you. Drive.
- What? I can't...
- Drive the fucking car!
- I can't drive stick, OK?
Fuck! Get in the fucking car.
Hands on the wheel,
off the fucking locks.
You, in back, over here.
Lacey's up front.
Go on. Step in there, Lacey.
Get in the fucking car.
Everybody nice and fucking comfy now?
- You OK, baby?
- Yeah. I'm cold.
OK, OK. Just relax, just relax.
Let's go.
- OK, OK.
- What's the problem? Yeah? OK?
OK. Uh-uh.
Wallets and cellphone, give 'em up.
- Same page, friend?
- Seth, just give him the damn thing.
Yeah, just give it to me, Seth.
Jesus. Five bucks?
Don't anybody carry cash any more?
Here, baby. Take that. See if you can
find anything for you in there.
Seth Turner. Polly Watt.
Same address, different names.
Hm. Not married?
- Living together in sin?
- Come on, Dennis.
That ain't your business, now.
Student ID. A little old, ain't you?
- It's a PhD.
- Oh.
- You a doctor?
- Not yet, no.
- But you can do script, huh?
- What?
- Can you write prescriptions?
- No. No, it's a biology PhD.
- Lacey.
- OK. Then you ain't a fucking doctor.
Great.
Not yet.
Where are we going?
Just drive till I say different.
This is a dictatorship from here on out.
If you wanna make life easy,
don't talk no more.
Shit, what was that?
- We hit something.
- What?
Ginger. Ginger.
- Ginger? Ginger's dead, baby.
- We've got a flat tyre.
- What the fuck are you trying to do?
- Relax, Lacey. It's gonna be fine.
- Get the spare. You.
- Er...
- Get the spare!
- I'll get it. It's not his car.
It's not my car.
You know, you suffer from
a severe case of CDS. Can't do shit.
You think Ginger's OK?
She's just a puppy. Huh?
Hurry up.
Here. Hey, if he moves, shoot him.
Hey, let's go.
OK.
Go.
Ginger.
OK. It's OK.
Momma's here now.
It's gonna be OK, Ginger.
OK. You... You gotta help her.
- Please.
- You...
- Come on, Biology. Ginger needs you.
- OK. I'm...
I'm pretty sure it's dead.
Here, make this quick. Fit this tyre.
Grab that.
Ah! Damn.
What the?
You're gonna help her.
- Come on.
- OK. OK.
OK.
It's OK. No, it's OK, lovely.
He's a doctor.
I don't care what Dennis says, OK, baby?
We're gonna take you home, OK?
We're gonna save you.
What is wrong with her?
- I don't know what...
- Hey, fix it.
Alright. Alright.
See these? I don't...
What is that?
Holy shit! Holy motherfucker!
- Seth!
- Get that thing on the ground. Lacey!
- Baby.
- What happened? You OK? Talk to me.
- Shut up!
- Talk to me. Talk to me, Lacey.
- Lacey.
- Get in. Get in!
- Did he mess with you?
- Get in! D, get in.
- Get in the car.
- Seth! Seth!
Ah, fuck!
- What happened?
- We gotta get out of here.
- Drive this fucking car!
- What happened?
- I'm not leaving him.
- Oh, fuck! Drive!
- Fuck! Come on. Go!
Go, go. OK. Go, go! Drive!
Speed up.
I will blow a hole in you
big enough to watch TV through.
- Fucking stop!
- Tell me what's happened, Lace.
What happened back there, hm?
She tried to get me.
- Who?
- Ginger.
- She attacked me with her tail.
- It wasn't Ginger, baby.
- Yeah.
- It was some critter from the woods.
Ginger's dead, sweetheart.
You gotta let her go.
God.
Did you see anything back there?
When was the last time
you took a hit, Lace? Huh?
- It's not that, D.
- Tell me.
D, I swear to God, it's not that.
Hey, I saw some crazy shit.
First two days, I saw shit coming...
Baby, it's not that.
OK? I ain't had a hit
since day before yesterday.
I ain't seeing a goddamn thing.
She tried to get you with her tail, huh?
Fine. I'm gonna straighten you out.
I promise you, if that's the last thing
I do, I'm gonna straighten you out.
I'm gonna get you to Mexico, get you
drinks with fucking umbrellas in 'em.
Motherfuckin' radiator. Fuck!
One sure thing about luck is,
it will change.
Pull over.
- Hey, where are you going?
- Bathroom.
Just hold it.
It's only 30 miles to Platt.
I need to go.
You told me
you were gonna lay off the stuff.
And you told me fuckin' Mexico.
I just don't want you
getting cockeyed on me.
This whole fucking world is cockeyed.
I'm not gonna make a fuckin' difference.
Leave it.
Turn it off.
Tell me you can pump gas.
Let's go. Polly Watt,
we're going to buy coolant and crackers.
Keep a cool hand, Luke.
Hello?
Come on, come on. Fucking... Come on.
Come on.
OK. Come on, you fucking door!
Fuck!
Hello?
They're making this easy, huh?
Fuck!
- Sorry. I didn't...
- Kill me.
Baby? Baby! Baby!
- What's going on?
- There's a man with spikes.
- Spikes?
- No, no, no, no, baby, please.
- Just listen!
- Do you even hear yourself talking?
Baby, in the bathroom, there's a man!
He's fucking...
What the fuck?
Lacey, get back. Lacey, get back!
Lacey!
Run!
Fuck!
Seth! Seth! Seth!
Run! Run! Hurry! Seth!
Get inside!
- Lacey!
- Are you OK? What was that?
- It just tore right through her.
- Oh, shit! Lacey!
- What are you doing?
- Calling for help.
No, no, no, no! What are you doing?
Don't think what's happening out there
changes who we are in here.
- You going to prison bothers me?
- I coulďve killed you. I didn't.
Yeah. We see how well
that worked out for you, don't we?
Stupid fuckin' idiot.
Plans don't change.
Hey, man.
You ain't no hero, kid.
We both know that.
- Let me see.
- I'm OK.
Are you OK?
Fuck!
Are you OK? Let me see.
What are you doing? Hey. Stop it.
She's alive.
Are you nuts?
You can't open that door, OK?
She's alive. Look.
I can't leave her out there.
No. She's...
Alright.
We'll watch the monitor, make sure
that thing on the car doesn't move.
You wanna tell me the rest?
Well, if...
if it goes to get you or whatever,
we're gonna shut that door, we're gonna
lock it and it's gonna stay shut.
You're OK.
- We can lock him out.
- He's got a gun.
- He can shoot through glass.
- Yeah, but he's out of bullets.
- It takes six, right?
- I don't know.
The girl shot two.
How many did he shoot?
What if he has more bullets? No.
Baby? Are you alright here, baby?
Talk to me. Can you hear me?
There you go. There you go.
- Seth, he's gonna kill us.
- Look, OK.
Just statistically speaking,
most people survive hostage situations
if you just stay calm.
Stay calm!
I'm just gonna take you inside,
alright? OK?
Just stay still. Stay still.
Talk to me. Can you hear me?
Jesus. She's dead.
He's completely insane.
OK, alright, I'm just gonna
drag you inside. Here we go.
Oh, my God.
- Come on.
- Polly, here he comes, OK?
Polly, open the door. We're gonna
get through this. Just be calm.
- You don't know that.
- Polly.
- Seth...
- Open the door.
- Open the door!
- Let him in. Polly, let him in.
- She's alive! Open the door!
- It's OK.
Open the door. He's right there!
Open the fucking door.
One!
- Two.
- It's OK. It's OK. No, no, no.
Three.
Don't! It's attacking him!
Don't open it!
No! What is?
Seth, what is? What is that?
Get away from it.
Seth, come on, man.
It's moving.
It's actually moving itself.
It's going for the blood.
- Don't. Come on. Don't.
- Wait.
You see this? It's following me.
It's actually following me.
Look at this.
Do you see that? It's... It's...
It's f...
It's metabolising.
What?
I can't believe this. I think
it's feeding. It's digesting the blood.
See the black stuff right there?
I think that's the waste.
- It was eating her?
- No.
It's absorbing...
the nutrients on a cellular...
It's more like a mould, I think.
What are you saying?
It feeds on people?
No. It probably feeds on any animal.
This is new. I've never seen
anything like this before.
What is it?
I think... I think it's stopping.
What was that?
What the fuck?
Er, it's OK.
- Hey. Hey, man.
- Don't.
- Oh, Jesus.
- Don't. Come on. Don't.
I have to, OK? I have to. Just trust me.
Hey. Hey, man.
Look, you can't help her, OK?
It's not her any more.
Look, come on, man. Please.
You should come with us, OK?
Come with us.
You gotta come with me now, OK?
It's not her any more, alright?
Go, baby. It's OK.
- Seth, come on!
- It's not her. We're coming.
It's not her, OK? It's OK. Go. Go.
Help me get this open.
OK. Alright.
Shit! We need keys.
Go. Go.
Jesus.
Where?
Back door key.
Door key. Where's that door key?
Door key. Door key.
Back door key.
Where's the fucking key,
the back door key?
Shh. OK.
- Gotta pop the hinges.
- What?
- Screwdriver.
Seth! Seth, get me a screwdriver.
- Screwdriver?
- Give me a screwdriver!
OK. Where would I be
if I were a screwdriver?
Where...
OK.
The plan was to get her to Mexico,
get her clean.
We both wanted a baby.
We got a name in our minds.
It was definitely gonna be a baby girl.
We gotta get out of this gas station.
- I can't get it.
- Let me get it.
Hurry, baby. Hurry.
Are you ready? On three.
One, two, three. Stand back.
- OK. OK.
- Over there.
OK.
- OK.
- What?
Wait, wait, wait.
It's gone.
It's on the roof.
We gotta go. Go, go, go, go.
Wait, wait, wait.
It's stopped.
Let's go.
- No, no, no.
- Don't move! Stay there.
OK.
- Shit.
- Look, you gotta help us.
- There's something out there.
- You're under arrest.
Drop the gun.
Put your hands on your head.
Look, you're not listening.
There's something out there!
Got every state trooper
looking for you, Farell.
None of them would mind
taking you out of here feet first.
Ma'am, you really have to
get in your car, OK?
- Go! Go, please!
- Right now.
It's OK. I'm here now. You two are safe.
He's not gonna try anything stupid.
- It's not safe. Get in your car.
- I'll be alright.
Get in your car!
Jesus!
- Jesus! What did you do?
- Just get in your car.
Listen to me. You're gonna get
in your car right now and call this in.
Wake the whole goddamn state
if you have to.
Tell them you've got
a hostage situation on your hands.
- I'm calling it in.
- Yeah.
But I'm not going anywhere.
5-14, come in.
- Please get in your car. Please!
- 5-14, come in.
I'm not letting you out of my sight.
We're gonna get you out of there.
5-14, come in.
- Boyd!
- It's too late.
Boyd! Are you there?
Run! Run! Get out of there right now!
Get away!
It... It took half of her.
It killed her. It killed her!
- Seth!
- It's OK. It's OK.
It killed her. It killed the other girl.
It killed everything.
And it's gonna get in here.
It's gonna kill us.
- No, it's not.
- It's gonna kill us!
It's gonna kill us.
Her car's just right there.
We should make a run for it.
Shit. That thing's way faster
than we are.
- Yeah.
But we got a gun and we got a bat.
A gun and a bat ain't gonna do shit.
You got a firecracker
on your hands here.
Lacey was like that.
I'm nothing like your white-trash,
drugged-out girlfriend.
- Firecracker.
- How is this helping exactly?
- Easy, lady. Help can't even help us.
- We have to do something.
OK. Let's, er... Let's just start
with what we know, OK?
We don't know shit, Seth.
We know it attacks you and you die.
No, we know that that thing infected his
girlfriend, so it's a parasite, right?
It... It uses its host for mobility.
It consumes you.
- It's... It's like a fungus or a mould.
- OK, so what are you saying?
I don't know.
So what you're saying is,
it attacks you and you die.
She called it in, right?
So someone's gonna come.
She called it in.
- Nobody's coming.
- How do you know that?
She said they were looking for you.
There's a manhunt on.
Not here, there ain't.
Down south there will be.
- They think I'm headed to Mexico.
- You are going to Mexico.
Yeah.
I'm going north. Platt first.
Great.
Wonderful.
It's perfect.
- Perfect.
- What? What's perfect?
We're in state forest,
a national treasure, right?
Yeah.
There's ten feet
between the building and the trees.
Oil runs down the steps,
across the dirt, into the trees.
You wanna set the forest on fire?
- Light it up and wait for the sirens.
- It won't work. Motor oil won't burn.
But there is lighter fluid
by the barbecue supplies.
- You...
- Firecracker.
Wait. This is insane. You realise
the fire's gonna come right back at us?
- It won't.
- What?
Here.
Give me one more. Thanks.
Just wait. Just wait. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What if it's outside the door right now?
Can we just stop
and think this through for a second?
This'll work.
Look, any way you slice it,
we're gonna be leaving a trail
of flammable liquid
back into this building.
This is a gas station. We're sitting on
a giant tank of gasoline.
I know. But if we get fire trucks
out here, someone'll kill that thing.
Being trapped in
a burning building, I don't like that.
Your parasitic mould theory
isn't really working right now.
So if you've got another idea,
go ahead.
It's working!
- Wait. Wait.
- What?
All we have to do is grab it.
Take no more than three seconds.
Yeah, three seconds is all it needs.
OK.
What are you thinking?
Here's what we're gonna do.
Tape these together,
snake it outside, hook the receiver,
bring it up, make the call.
No open doors,
no being outside, no fires, OK?
OK.
Right there. Hm-hm.
I don't think it's long enough.
You OK?
Yeah.
I just cut myself.
- Think he's got it.
- There you go.
You got it.
Fuck.
Hm-hm.
You got it right there.
- OK, you got it.
- Grab it. Hold it.
You got it. You got it.
There you go, man.
Keep pulling. There you go.
Pull it up slowly.
There you go.
There you go. Nice and easy.
Come on.
- There you go.
- You got it. Be careful.
Holy fuck! Holy fuck.
You got it. You got it. Hold onto it.
You gotta hold on. Hold on.
Polly!
Polly! Stop! Polly!
Let's go! Come on!
It's breaking in.
It's breaking in. It's breaking in.
It's gone.
It took her legs.
- Jesus Christ.
- Why would it do that?
Where'd he go?
- My God, do you think it got to him?
- I don't see how it would have.
- Hey.
- Seth, I think he made a run for it.
The front door's still locked.
Maybe he's in back.
Seth. Seth.
- He's not back there.
- What is it?
Don't move.
What is it doing?
Run. Run!
Go, go, go, go, go! Go!
Seth!
Watch the splinters.
Don't let it stick you.
- Go, Polly.
- Come on.
Go! Go!
Fuck off!
Move away from the glass.
It'll forget.
- How did you know that?
- There's nothing smart about it.
- I think he's right.
- Yeah, but it chased us in here.
It tracks us somehow,
but it ain't thinking.
I think it moves on instinct.
It's like at a cellular level,
it's like a plant root
trying to find water.
Yeah, but why can't it track us in here?
I don't know.
Oh, shit!
- It's OK.
- Are you OK?
- It's alright.
- What is it? Did it get you?
Goddamn!
Alright, don't let it touch you.
- Whoa. Whoa, whoa.
- Don't touch it!
- Here, let me just see.
- Get away from it!
- Listen...
- You gotta...
- Stay away from it!
Oh, God!
Oh, my God!
- Give me the knife.
- Fuck me.
It's spreading.
I'm gonna have to cut it.
Knife.
- Get the knife, OK?
- OK.
- Give me the knife!
- Oh, God.
- OK.
- What do we do?
- We have to cut it.
- What?
- Get something to hold his arm with.
Grab that thing right there. Get it.
Try to cover his arm.
Don't let any of those touch you, OK?
OK. OK. OK.
- I'm just gonna tie this off.
- Don't let it touch you.
Hurry.
- This is it?
- Yeah.
- Hurry!
- OK.
It's OK. It's OK.
We're cutting your arm off.
- OK.
- Cut faster.
- Fuck!
- Go!
I can't get through the bone
with this knife.
What?
What are we gonna do?
Seth? What are we gonna do?
- Alright, on three. One.
- Do it.
Two.
Three.
It started with that splinter
I got from the flat tyre.
What we ran over was just the same
as that thing out there.
That's all it took.
Looks like I underestimated you.
He can't change a tyre,
but fuck if he can't chop off an arm.
Yeah, he's a keeper.
This one, she locks me out
and leaves me for dead.
Hell, I never dreamed this thing
would turn into a ménage ř trois.
I'd just as soon die with you two
as anybody else.
I'll drink to that.
I wish we'd have made it to Mexico, man.
- I wish we'd never gone camping.
- Shut up. We're not dying in here.
This is not over.
We just gotta get him to a hospital.
- There's one in Platt, right?
- Don't know. Never been there.
That's just the place
Lacey was stashing my nest egg.
You two never read about me?
- You shot a cop?
- No.
They shot me.
I was stealing big rigs.
Then this last time, I was working
on a five-day straight mid-high.
I asked this guy to give up his keys.
He didn't and I shot him.
Didn't kill him straight away,
just shattered his spine.
He died about a year later, and by then,
him and his old lady had gone bankrupt
from all the medical bills
and I was sitting in the penitentiary.
I know how it sounds.
I just figured if I ever got out,
I'd do two things.
I'd get my ass
across the border with Lacey
and make sure his wife
was taken care of.
You were gonna give your nest egg
to that trucker's wife?
I know it sounds foolish, but...
...I figured if I ever got
a second chance, she should too.
Isn't he the strangest one-armed convict
you've ever met?
- Baby?
- Temperature.
- I have to check something.
- What?
We gotta chance it.
Seth.
- I don't see it.
- Stay ready.
Maybe it rejoined the big one.
Do you see it?
Seth.
Now, watch this.
Now, this has been stuck in my head.
Watch out!
Why does it give up on me
and go straight for the car?
- Watch out!
- See, it just hits the car.
It doesn't turn after me.
I don't think it was ever going for me.
It was going for the car cos the car
was hotter. I think it tracks with heat.
It's a simple organism
and it's just looking for food.
It goes for the warmest thing
and kills it.
The engine was overheated, right?
So it was way hotter than me.
It can't track us in the refrigerator.
Exactly. It's too cold.
We're invisible to it.
All I have to do is walk to the
sheriff's car and bring it to the door.
No. That thing would be on you
in three seconds. You said so yourself.
Yeah, but not if my temperature
was below the ambient temperature.
The human body can drop
to 32 degrees Celsius
before medical emergency occurs,
so that's 89.6 degrees Fahrenheit.
Thank God for global warming in July.
All we have to do is keep
my body temperature below 93 degrees.
I'll be like a fucking ghost
to that thing.
What about the medical emergency?
95.
Seth, you're gonna kill yourself.
Not if you keep me above 89.6.
Here, gotta get this hand cold.
You don't have to prove anything to me.
I know.
But if we don't get out of here,
I'm never gonna...
We'll never get to show that tent
who's boss.
Try it again.
94.
You don't wanna do too much of that.
You're gonna warm up my lips.
Shut up.
You're gonna be OK.
Just a couple more degrees.
Almost ready.
We're gonna use these fireworks
to keep that thing off you, OK?
- Got enough?
- Yeah.
Hey, make sure she's ready
when I bring the car around, OK?
She usually takes forever with that.
No, no, no, don't touch me.
You're gonna warm me up.
Come back.
You know I will.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Next year's gonna be better, I promise.
Next year Hawaii.
Alright, go! Go! Go!
Damn it.
Come on, buddy. You gotta go faster.
He's gonna need more time.
- He's almost there.
- There you go.
Hey, fireworks.
I don't see it!
Where'd it go?
Hello.
Polly! I don't see it.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
- Seth!
- Polly!
Seth!
Dennis!
Come on! Get up! Get up!
Polly? Come on.
Where'd it go? Do you see it?
No.
Hold it.
What? Hey!
Hey!
Shit!
Seth! Seth!
The fire.
We gotta get it in the fire!
Fuck. Polly!
Polly!
Here!
- Are you sure?
- Here!
Go.
Go!
- Come on. Come on. Come on.
- Keep going.
Keep running.
Fuck it.
Dennis.
Go. Go.
Let me see him.
- Oh, no.
- What you gonna cut off now, Doc?
Here. Take this.
Take it to the bank in Platt.
Give it all to her.
- Now, you two, make it count.
- OK.
Now, get the fuck out of here.
Come on.
- Let's go.
- Go on.
- Get out of here.
- Come on, Polly.
Polly, come on.
I love you.
Fuck it.
Here I come, baby.
Oh, baby.
Now, we're gonna get you warmed up.
Just tell me
if you see any fire trucks.
Yeah, OK.
Well, I see a post oak.
- It's gotta be 300 years old.
- It's not a post oak.
- No?
- It's just a tree. Keep walking.
OK.