Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
That party we just threw, there were
over a thousand people there, bro.
No way. Oh my God,
I can't wait to get up there.
You know what we hook you up to.
Is move some "candy" I'll put
some serious paper in your pocket man.
Oh, speaking of this is,
I'll bring in about
two boats to begin
the holiday break.
Two boats man?
That's like 2.000 pills.
OK, another Seven G's is what it is.
And some of that could be yours.
No, I'm Good Man.
Look man. you don't
got to do anything.
I just got to ship the box
to your house OK?
I can't fly with this stuff.
I don't know, bro. - Come on, it's for
like a day until I get there.
And you can even have some. And
you said that Amanda are dying to roll
I'll talk to you later, alright?
I'll text you the traffic...
No. Don't.
Hey, why don't you answer the phone?
- I was skyping with Craig.
Hallo?
Hey, Maggy. No, Nick said the layoff
wouldn't affect our division.
Mike I understand, but the bottom line is
I need to buy all four rigs.
Anything less than that, There's no point.
I might as well just keep leasing.
Well that's what they do, those hollers
They get together once a year,..
..and they raise a raid
before the gas prices .
They do, because they know
they can get away with it.
See the contract?
Yeah, it’s real. But I just don't know
when it's going to start.
How much money am I going to have to borrow?
Alright, let's move some equity around.
I've been rolling the dice my whole life,
might as well do it aging.
I got to go.
Solid week boys, thank you.
I figure Analyze would have you
putting on brims and balloon.
I'm still out getting Izzy's cake.
Good luck with that.
- I need it.
Have a good weekend, Wayne.
- See you.
You know there's no OT, unless
it's authorized.
I don't look for OT, sir.
This guy broke a pallet.
I get my bags out of the wheatear
It's going to rain tonight.
Good heads up.
Whoa sir, I got this.
Seriously, I don't want you get dirty.
It's alright.
Let's do it together.
I'm John Matthews.
- Daniel James.
Good to meet you, Daniel.
Don't worry about it.
How long have you
been working here?
Do you mean work for you?
About 3 weeks now.
What do you think
about give me that raise already?
Fat chance, buddy.
You got to try, right?
You got to give it a whirl.
Packages for Jason Collins?
- Yeah, that's me.
Alright, sign right there.
Alright, thanks.
Have a Good one.
- Thanks man.
Department of Justice! This is DEA!
Open the door!
Right there! Back fence!
Down! Get on the ground!
This is central. Reporting in.
Acknowledge.
We have custody.
Cake.
That looks so good .
I love you.
Hi, baby.
You're having fun on your birthday, Izzy ?
Hey, Sylvie. Let me call you back.
What?
They tell you anything?
Just to wait here
until we're called.
They're treating him like he's some
kind of major criminal, John.
We'll straight 'em out.
Is he in with my last name or yours?
You know we changed it to mine.
Why are you even asking?
Hi, my sons Jason Collins..
- Take a seat and wait to be called.
Can you at least tell me where he is?
You notice anything different?
Like what?
With him. Who he's
been hanging with.
Anything out of ordinary.
No, John. I haven't notice anything.
This is such bullshit.
I mean he's a good kid.
Mike's sending a lawyer.
Good, you can afford it.
Didn't you quit?
Mr. and Mrs. Matthews?
- Yeah.
Thanks for coming.
- Where's Jason?
They're moving him from this
holding cell to court room.
He's scheduled for a
hearing this evening.
It's alright. Leave him in jail for
a little bit. Scare the hell out of him.
No one's trying to
scare your son.
This is federal case.
The amount of MDMA or
ecstasy they found
means they've charged Jason for
distribution of narcotics.
Jason said that a friend asks to have
the drugs sent to the house.
What friend?
- Friend with the name Craig Johnson?
That's his best friend.
Christ, I have known Craig
since he was little.
Jason was arrested trying to
mail the pills,..
..and he agreed to work with the government.
What do you mean,
"agreed to work with the government"?
Both Craig and Jason
are being charged under
federal mandatory
minimum sentencing laws.
These laws were design to
ensure high level drug trafficker ..
..get them to snitch on other trafficker
in order to reduce their own sentences
However, most of the conviction over half
have been first time offender
like your son.
So, Craig is implicating Jason?
- Yes, in order to reduce the sentence..
..Craig told the DEA, that Jason agreed
to have the pills sent to the house,..
..and also has agreed to help sell them.
- What?
Now Jason has denied both of these
accusation. Do you believe them?
Of course I believe him. He would never be
involved in anything like this.
Are we talking about
probation here or
could he actually go
to jail for this?
The mandatory minimum laws are very simple.
The amount of jail
time depends upon
the amount of drugs.
There are no mid..
Wait, what is that mean?
Jason is facing a mandatory minimum
sentence of 10 years in prison.
10 years?
- Are you out of your mind!
He just got accepted at collage.
John tell him.
Oh God..
Jason.
United States vs. Jason Collins.
how could they deny him bail?
He's never even been arrested before.
You want to know the truth?
I knew something like
this would happen.
I figure if I just got him off to college.
But no.
Jason has no God damn idea
what real responsibility mean.
Especially while still being baby
all the time.
And when your own
son doesn't want
have anything to do
with you anymore?
Not true.
- Not true?
That's not true at all.
It's just really hard for kids who
go through divorces.
I acted out when my father left.
Yeah well, he's not
a kid anymore.
Not while he's sitting in that cell.
The sprinkler’s on?
Is everything have
to go to shit?
Here's the situation. It's very simple
You help them make traffic drug arrests..
And they will reduce your sentence
from 10 years to 2.
1 suspended.
I told you. I don't know anyone else.
Just Craig.
Bullshit.
Your mom told me she
smelt marijuana of you before .
Where did you get
that from, huh?
Jason, this is serious.
Come on honey,
you got to tell us who sold you the pot.
I didn't have to buy it.
Amanda's dad grows it.
He has medicinal licence.
It's legal.
I just took some. I just wanted to try it.
OK. Are there any of
your friend who do
drugs and might
interested in selling?
What, you mean
setting someone up ?
Like Craig did to me?
No Way.
You better wake up right now.
Because this is
really happening.
You going to take
that plead
and you going to help them make the arrest.
You hear me?
I'll take my chances in court.
No, you won't. If you do not work with
the prosecutor..
..they can raise the minimum limits
to 30 years.
Which means you'll be out in time
for your 50th birthday.
And they are banning over 90%
on convictions.
Jason, baby. Please
listen to him.
We don't have another choice.
I'm not setting anyone up.
- Baby. - I won't do it.
Yes you are.
Listen to me dammit!
You think you know what you're doing?
You have no idea
until you spend the
next 10 years of
your life in prison.
I'm not going to let that
happen to you, son.
You hear me?
You're not the one who have to do it.
Morning, John.
I need to show you something.
This is a..
What a beauty ain't they?
And they say the other 2 will
ready next month.
Great.
I got to make a phone call.
Terry, this is John Matthews.
Good.
We definitely got to get out
we'll hit a few. Very soon.
Let me ask you something?
Do you have a connection
to Joanne Keeghan?
US attorney down town.
Mr. Matthews, you've got a lot of friends
in this city.
I received 4 phone calls
in matters of an hour.
I'm sure you'd do the same for your kids.
I don't have any children.
Alright, well.
18 years old.
You must've had him
when you're quite young.
Sophomore in collage.
Me and his mom were high school sweetheart.
Well, you have my sympathy.
But I believe in
mandatory minimum laws.
We're fighting the world right
now, not just on drugs.
But the violence they bring.
And we are losing badly, so it's time
for all our sake we have to turn this around.
Ms. Keeghan I agree.
I do.
But my son, Jason. He's not a drug dealer.
He's a good kid.
And he just made really dumb naive mistake.
And he's willing to do anything he can
to help out the situation.
The only drug dealer
that he knows is..
Craig Johnson, who you already
have in custody.
I'm really sorry to hear that.
Please, There's got to be
something I could do.
The laws are design to preclude
any special circumstances.
So it's really quite simple. We'll need
your son help us make arrest..
..before we can help them
reduce the sentence.
Which he can't do that, or
isn't willing to do that..
..then there's really nothing we can do.
I'm sorry.
And now I have to be somewhere else.
What if I did it for him?
- What?
What if I help you make arrest?
It's not the way it works.
- Please.
I just want to help my son.
I understand, I really
am sorry, but..
..my hands are tied.
There's nothing I can do
Thank you for stopping by.
Hallo. /
Hi.
You're here to see?
- Jason Collins.
Just sign in.
Proceed to booth 3. /
Thank you.
What happened?
Nothing.
Tell me.
It's OK.
Talk to me son.
it's OK, tell me.
You remember when someone keep tipping
and nagging your house?
That was me.
I would sit around
the corner and laugh
I watch you try to clean it up.
Doesn't matter now, Jason.
The last time I did.
I didn't know you were out of town.
I felt like crap watching
Elize do it herself.
So, I pretended I was stopping by.
I help her.
- She told me.
I hated that you have to live in that
big house and new family.
Me and mom are just stuck in that old one.
I wanted you to live with me.
I wanted you in my life.
It was my fault, not yours.
I was always gone.
I was always on those trucks.
I was always working,
got so caught up.
And I'm failing you as a father.
That's exactly what I did.
I should've never taken that packages,
I know what was in it.
I should've just told the guy got
the wrong address .
But I didn't, because me and Amanda
wanted to try something.
But I swear to you dad, I would
never ever..
.. I wasn't planning in helping
to sell that stuff.
I'm not a drug dealer.
You believe me, right?
Of course I believe you.
And I know
I should be punish..
..for what I did.
But not like this.
Jason, don't cry.
Don't cry, Jason.
Not in here.
Listen to me, Jason.
You got to show me.
You got to stand up for yourself in here.
You have to.
I promise you, I'm going to get you
out of here.
How?
You just got to trust me.
I love you.
What you want?
- Coke.
Crack is whack, man.
Who do you think you are, dude?
I just go to somebody else.
Look man, you really buying it?
Money talks.
Get off me.
Give it back.
Cops are rolling!
What the hell were you thinking?
I'm sorry I threw your name
down at the station.
Your son is not going to be better off
if you're dead.
Clearly what I did last night
didn't work out
Clearly?
- Please, what do I got to do?
You are so stubborn. You're
not going to stop are you?
No. I'm not
Alight. hypothetically,..
..I would need airtight arrest of
someone in possession of narcotics,..
..in the amount of constitute conspiracy
to distribute.
If we're talking
cocaine, that would be
at least 500 gram
or half a kilo.
What?
- I'm in a construction business.
And we have ex-cons who are working
the yard all the time.
Maybe someone knows someone
who knows someone.
You're their boss.
Why would they trust you?
Let me worry about that.
Believe me, I am not worried.
Because the risk is all yours
Come on. I'll give you a lift
No, thank you. But I'm good
I'm the boss.
Get in.
How's the job treating you.
In fact that I got a job.
I guess, I'm just trying
to say thank you.
Me and my family really
appreciate the opportunity.
It's got to be hard for a..
..ex-con.
That's why we're here?
You need to talk to me
about my past?
I was completely honest
on my application.
But if there's anything else..
No. That's it.
That's not it
Couple of years ago I caught
2 of my drivers..
..they were transporting
some stuff
They know that the cops rarely stop semis
And even if they did,..
..sure as hell didn't have time to search.
They were low level small time.
I was hoping that someone with the
connections into that world..
Are you accused me
of something, sir?
You think I've done something?
No.
With all due respect sir.
Why don't you just
go ahead and tell me what it is
that you want from me.
An introduction.
I can't help you with that.
You give me info the right people
I'll give you $ 5,000.
Something good come out of it,
I'll give you another $ 5,000.
That's $ 10,000.
- No, I can count.
Like I said, I can't help you with that.
Why not?
You see I'm on the track of
my life again now
And I'm doing it for my family.
That's why I'm working like I do
I sweat my ass everyday in that yard.
This conversation is just..
This conversation is
a conspiracy alright.
And that can take me 25 to life.
I will act..
I'd appreciate it
maybe we just pretend this never happens.
OK?
I'll see you.
I just need an introduction, OK.
Go home, be happy with what you got.
Thank you for the coffee.
Daniel!
Twenty Grand
I'll double it because of
the risk you're taking.
Anthony, go inside.
- Come on dad.
Go home, now.
Go, Go on.
What are you looking at?
Hold. Hold up.
I don't care you are slang what you slang,
you are smoke what you smoke.
We put holes on each other.
If that's what you want
But I'm going to tell you right now.
You got to stay away from my son.
You hear me?
What are you stupid, Flaco?
This guy is 'Shark Caller'
from the east side esse!
Dad, why'd you...
- Anthony, go play your game.
Alright, what happened?
Nothing happened bee.
It's just father and son stuff.
What are you doing?
- I'm going to work.
What do you mean work?
Larry called. Told me I have to be there
in 1 hour. - Come on bee, he can't do that.
He can't just call you 7:30 at night
telling you to come work ..
He can do whatever he want Daniel.
That is if I want to keep my job.
Look, I'm already late.
There's food for both
of you on the stove.
What are you saying?
Let me ask you something.
What if me and my little
partner over there
before bed time we
cruise to the office?
We charmed your guest.
Fatten up them tips.
Make a world for everybody.
I'd like that.
OK, I have to go.
Don't go to work.
I love you.
- I love you.
Hey Ant get on the couch man.
Sit down bud.
Why do we move here?
We move here so you don't have to hangout
with fools like that.
That's why. Alright?
There ain't nobody else to hang with
around here.
I want to go back to
our old apartment.
You know we can't,
so don't say it.
Look man, I know it's hard.
At some times like this,
I promise you..
One day we got to move somewhere,
And you going to get real friends.
Real friends.
You ain't got to proof nothing,
you got to do nothing for them.
But those punks out there, man..
You're better than that.
Let me tell you something else.
You're better than me, man.
So much better than me.
Hey, what's a 'Shark Caller'?
Where did you hear that?
Don't worry about that.
I love you man.
And I'm proud of you.
You need to be smart.
Go get your homework man.
We going to bang it out.
Just keep going man.
All the way to the end
Don't stop.
Right here?
- OK.
I need to go alone first.
This guy in here, Malik.
If he never see you before.
Shit I'm going to tell you right now.
You never going to leave this block
That's a promise.
What 'up Coz?
What 'up, Malik?
The last I see your ass..
..where was it last?
Stand stone, man.
It's cold as hell up there was it Coz?
That's true.
Me and old boy right here
we used to get it in.
Moving 'product' like we was
the United Nation and shit.
'Coz nobody comes to that paper.
- Colour that matters is grey.
So how long you've been home man?
You just come now and see me.
Come on, Malik you know it.
I can't be associated with no ass
criminals now.
I hear you.
That's why I'd be in here.
Two strikers like us man
we can't walk the striff.
It ain't safe
So I'm saying, you back
in the game right?
How come we don't cross out with your Home?
Just can't have any of your
Home bad ideas man
I'm telling you, them days
they are over for me Malik, that's it.
Right here.
It's a one time.
You're smart Coz.
Real smart.
Keep that pain to yourself.
Yo Home, kill the beat.
I'm John Matthews.
I see that's the way action I was
looking for player.
Ain't never had wine you
grilled before, huh?
Now see, if you with the popo..
..and you be the biggest
pussy pig I'd ever see.
Now let's have a honest conversation
as to why you're in my crib.
I don't have product..
..or distribution.
But I do know business.
If anyone needed a transportation..
..I can provide that.
With no risk.
- There's always risks.
My way, minimizes it.
See what I want to know is why
as a successful..
..businessman man like your self
want to take and risk it all?
I'm in construction business.
The way the economy is
today it's all gone to shit.
And I don't see any chance of
them coming back
And I'm willing to do whatever it takes to
keep my business afloat.
I've worked too hard
for too long.
So how much weight can you move?
My trucks? Half a ton..
..without attacking attention.
Half a ton?
Man if I have a thousand
pounds I wouldn't..
..be sitting in this dump right now.
All I'm saying is,
whatever you want to move.
it won’t matters in my trucks.
You know they weight
the trucks at the state line.
How you going to cover that?
We offset the weight.
Counts off all the time.
If the police get lucky,
they only get the driver.
We won't be there for the holding
or unloading.
Sounded like you're ready for the game.
So, what are you talking player?
- 15% whole sale.
I give nobody over 10%.
You know I got something for you too.
If the first run goes good
I'm willing to re-negotiate.
You're going to drive the first load.
Everybody know what game Malik is.
We have to see are you for real first.
And then, maybe..
Just maybe, we going to back to talking.
Alright.
Why don't you wait
outside for a minute.
Let me and my boy here Cruzz
have a word.
You going to ride shotgun.
No, Malik. Maybe you misunderstood
why I'm here.
Misunderstood?
- I'm here for an Introduction Malik.
Hell no, Cruzzer.
See, we'll be vouching for no fish,
when we was back in the yard.
You know how they work. We ain't talking
no hoe time Home.
We in the streets.
That's three strikes, bro.
And 3rd strike will be
3rd strike for you my man.
You better be convincing me
right now, or he's smoked.
And we can act like none of this
ever happen
It's your call.
For the first round,
I'll be going with you.
We do it my way.
I say how it goes
What do you mean?
- I want to get paid today.
OK, so I don't know if we have to
see your banker.
I don't care man, go rob a store.
But I need to get paid
Don't worry, you'll get your $ 10,000.
No $ 10,000 man.
We said $ 20,000 that what you said.
- And then what? You skip town on me?
Blow the money?
So you come with me
on this first run, that's fine,..
..the moment it's done,
you'll get your other $ 10,000.
My word.
- Your word?
Only reason this is going down because
I went on the line with you.
3 days ago man,
I was working a job.
I was staying clean.
I was doing everything I was
supposed to do. And now here I am.
I'm back in.
You think this is some
kind a thrill for me?
You just please take me my money.
You check them out with
them niggers at sandstone?
They say that Cruzz are solid.
He's on the main line like he said.
Soldering up
Putting word like good word should.
Even had the keys to the yard
for a minute.
That's the Cruzz I had known.
What about other player?
Bong said he live in the suburbs.
Fat crib. With a wife,
little girl.
He ain't  for hollow that for sure.
He better not be.
But he'll know with El Topo.
The new TV spot are testing really
well with the corp.
Then why am I down by five?
Because the liberal think
you're a bitch.
Oh, maybe I should go to
a gay wedding.
Wouldn't hurt.
Oh, please.
You win 900 convictions last year alone
It's a big volume to our core
But to win this pliminary let's keep
our priorities.
Your next meeting is checking in
down at security. - Who is it?
John Matthews.
I'll need a coffee.
Let's go prep our schedule.
Man if I have a thousand pounds
I wouldn't be sitting in this dump right now.
All I'm saying is, whatever you want to move
it won’t matters in my trucks.
So I look at it as
business thing.
What do I have that they want.
I'm impressed. You're a natural.
You're luck he didn't rip you open, man.
He's a heavy hitters.
Runs the entire Adams district now.
What's his jacket?
He earn his stripes on the corner as
a punk ass kid.
Did a nickel for ADW,
3 more for distribution.
Rival rob his bank last year.
So they sending out as a posy
to do a drive by.
He track them each down
and blood them out with a buck knife.
Personally.
Alright, I'm singing off.
Cooper is my witness.
We arrest Mr. Anderson
And I will reduce Jake sentence.
Jason. - Right, sorry.
Jason's sentence.
How much?
I'll cut it to a year.
Come on, I can't let 'em
get off scot free.
And with the time that
he's already served.
Jason will probably be out in
6 months.
That is the best that I can do.
OK.
- Alright.
Rock and roll.
She going to keep her word?
Don't give her reason not to.
Hi, daddy.
Hey, honey.
How long are you going away for?
Just 2 days.
That's it.
You know how much I love you Izzy?
Come here.
Are you sure you have to go now?
You know with everything going on
with Jason? Yeah, we need the contract.
Specially after those new truck bought.
Come on, Iz. Let’s go.
We got to go to school.
You getting ready to go
out on one of those trucks?
How long are you going for?
- I don't even know where we're going to.
It's good thing your boss is giving
you more responsibilities.
It means he believes in you.
I'm proud of you.
Oh yeah?
Yeha.
- It's a good thing.
I love you so much.
Wires sent by your place.
Do the same with your
warehouse when you're gone.
I heard you've done this before.
Undercover.
You have any advices?
Just be yourself, John.
You try to be something you're not,
their bloodhounds will smell it right away.
You're a family man, who's
trying to stay afloat.
You have means they could use.
That's it, you hide in plain sight.
Just keep doing what you doing.
And they'll believe it.
Because it's the truth.
Alright, audio is up.
Here we go.
The trucks GPS already still?
You got it.
In here.
Where're we going?
- El Paso, right by the border.
It's over 1,000 mills.
What do you think?
we should go around the corner?
If you don't mind me asking.
How long were you in prison?
A little over a nickel.
You never told me you have kids.
What are you doing man?
Just don't do that.
You don't need to ask
me about my life alright,
and I won't ask you about yours.
That guy say we're about 150 mill outs.
I got it.
We got get this thing move.
We can't.
Check my right.
Whoa, stop!
What're you doing?
Go. go, go.
John, what are you doing?
Matthews I sup in semi
and heads right towards us.
Is Torres mobile?
- Negative.
We got local PD responding
two shots fired.
Tell Torres to supersede PD.
No one sets foot in that yard.
No one tips off Malik's suppliers.
Torres, talk to me.
Let's go. Let's go.
What the hell was that? - I don't know man.
We got to hide this thing.
No, we got to get back on the interstate.
Public, moving.
Yeah man. I'm sorry for your truck.
Your driver.
He's 42.
He handle the situation
Very well.
We will use that.
- Glad to hear.
I'll you know when he get here.
The eases don't play boy.
Smoked everyone in them buster.
They are back digging ditches right now.
Who's trying to jack?
- I don't even care man.
What I care about, El Topo
loving them trucks.
We take our game to a whole
another level. You hear?
You have one new message.
Hi, honey. I got your message about
your meeting being delayed.
But Izzy is really excited to make
you dinner tomorrow night.
I love you, bye.
Alright everybody, get alive.
Alright we're here.
- Black Yukon on ward no. 4.
Put the work in the back of you bush truck
and follow.
Malik you know that
ain't nothing to do with us.
Man just hand them goodies
and get over here Home.
He's changing up the meet,
says he wants us to put it in your pickup.
Alright, There's a hidden
compartment behind the back seat.
Where are you going?
Take a leak.
Yeah?
Tell me you got a wire on that truck.
- In the dash and the back.
Sims, get that hell on too.
I need Raven 1 over the following location.
Who'd you call, John?
I asked you a question.
Who'd you call?
My wife.
- Your wife.
You expect me to believe that?
Why don't you go ahead
and grape that beam for me.
I said grab that beam.
Turn your ass around and grab that beam.
You playing me man?
John you need to know that this comes down
neither you or me.
I will take your life.
I will shoot you where you stand.
Do you understand me?
I'm going to ask you one last time..
Who did you call?
My wife.
- Don't bullshitting me man.!
It was my wife!
It was my wife Daniel, it was my wife.
Don't you lie to me!
- That's the truth!
You have a cell phone in your truck.
Why didn't you use it?
I wanted her to see the
caller ID from the warehouse.
So she believe that I'm
working my ass off.
To save the company. That's the truth.!
You did this.
Lay back.
Alright, right here.
Just let them be out first, alright.
It makes easy when they got other plans.
Like what?
Shooting our ass and they ain't going to pay.
Alright we good.
Take 'em on our way out.
Welcome to the real
party, player.
Ready to crack off early?
You ain't got cold feet, do you?
I'm here.
Let me see what man.
Taste it.
I'm good.
I didn't ask.
Get up real quick, huh?
Here's $ 10,000 per kilo.
You're welcome.
Alright visual confirm
of the exchange.
Hold to my signal
I got some people they
want to sit down and talk .
a bit of serious baby.
Real serious.
- What?
I'll let you know
And we're back to the yard, ain't it Cruzz?
He's heading towards the exit,
what're you going to do?
Let them go.
- Repeat.
Repeat. Let them go.
Let's go man. we're done,
let's get out of here. Let's go.
What are you looking at man?
- Just make sure they're gone.
They're gone, dude.
What's with you?
That stuff act's out.
Let's go.
It's 11 o'clock. I thought you weren't
coming home for dinner. where were you?
I was at work.
- No there's something going on.
We're supposed to be an open book
remember?
Is this about Jason?
Please talk to me. I have no idea
what's going on.
If I help them make arrest,
They'd reduce Jason's sentence.
OK, how are you supposed to help them?
By doing drug dealing.
Are you out of your mind?
You wanted to know.
People get shot and killed.
This is my son.
- You have more than one child!
I'd do the same thing for her.
You know that.
This is not my rule.
It's their rule.
Which means that every move that I make,
or I don't make..
..Jason will have to live like
10 years of his live.
And what if you don't live?
Baby, have you thought about that?
You have family here too.
And I hope that I have your support
when the time comes.
You're not old enough
to vote though are you?
John, my secretary said
you need to see me?
You said all we need was either
Malik and drug in the same place.
That's exactly what we had last night
We had a deal!
We had it done.
Calm down!
It's not just about you.
- Stop it.
Malik's supplier could be
our next exchange.
Cooper made the call.  It's she right one
we go for the highest target.
You just have to be patient.
Take the next meeting.
Your son will be alright.
You had Malik single handily with tangy
and you let him go?
He would've given up everybody.
- Bullshit..
I had to make a judgement.
TidaNo you didn't.
It's my call. And I will decide
exactly how this comes down.
Do you understand?
It's that clear?
Crystal.
Hey, Sylvie.
They took what?
Manny, lend me your car bro.
I came to visit Jason, but they wouldn't
let me see him.
They said that he's
in the infirmary.
What happened?
- He was assaulted.
They said he had
over 36 stitches.
When they said assaulted...
I don't know, they said they were
going to keep him in at least 2 more days.
And there's no way that
you and can even see him.
I'm trying here, right?
I talked to the lawyers at
'Project Innocent' and they said
that they were going to use his case..
It's not going to last that long.
I don't see you getting anywhere!
Oh, God..
Please don't do this to him.
I should've known he was in trouble.
I should've been able to protect him.
This is nightmare.
It's not your fault.
What's going on?
You followed me here?
Who'd you visit?
It's my son.
Look man. He made a mistake.
His friends set 'em up.
They said if we cooperate,
we help him.
You made a deal?
You got any idea what they're
going to do to us man?
You have any idea?
It's Malik man. It's the cartel man.
You know what they going to do to our family?
It's my son. - Your son?
What about my son man?
I've got a son, John.
You're a dead man, John.
You're dead man.
Where's your mom?
She's sleeping.
Vanessa, what are you doing?
Is this what you've
been doing, huh?
Your work shift, huh?
Can't even take care of
your own God damn son!
Vanessa, he's in the other room.
Look it's not what you think OK.
Listen to me. It's not what you think.
Bullshit!
You made me a promise, Daniel!
I stay cleaning,
you stay away from that life.
Remember? - I understand baby.
But right now what I need you to do is...
..I need you to pack a bag for you
and Anthony. You need to stay with your mama.
You don't tell me what to do.
Not after lie..
Enough OK? just...
Look..
I'm in trouble baby.
I am in trouble baby.
Please don't do that Vanessa.
Sweetheart..
Wait,wait,wait.
I can't do it aging.
I can't watch you go to prison or..
or end up dead.
That's not going to happen.
You hear me?
I'm not going anywhere.
Why do you do this to us?
Why do you keep doing this?
I'm scared...
I'm sorry..
They just came right in.
Where's Isabelle?
She's still at school.
Get her, take her to your sister. Now!
Go!
What are you doing here, Malik?
I like your old lady.
She in a hurry, huh?
What do you want?
You want that paper, right?
What about  Daniel?
- What about 'em?
Come on man, El Topo wait.
Only him.
Arms up.
You have a cell phone?
Yeah.
It no longer works.
Anything else on you electronics.
I understand your business
is in a complicated spot.
Pretty hard to make money now a days.
It doesn't have to be.
When you work for us, you'll be
treated like family.
Of course, includes your wife..
your child.
I hear Isabelle is a beautiful girl.
You and Annalisa are
really lucky to have her.
Thank you.
You will make this next trip alone.
Once you make the pickup,
You will take it to Mexico.
We will unload your construction supply
as well before you
cross back to the border,..
..so everything looks legitimate.
Palacio will pay you $ 250,000.
All goes well, you will receive much more.
Show us your loyalty.
And your future will be bright my friend.
I will call you the day
after tomorrow 10 AM.
With an address.
Be ready to leave.
What about Malik?
You work for us now.
Let's get one thing clear man.
You still works for me.
Got it.
Just handle your bin player.
'Coz I ain't letting nobody
getting me away me and my bread.
John, are you OK?
- You're at Gaby's yet?
I'm in like 30 minutes.
You can't go there now.
Why? - I need you to pull over
so we can talk about this.
No, tell me now.
What is happening.
Is my sister in danger?
Mommy, where are we?
I love you, John. I do.
They knew my wife and kids name. Dammit!
What did they knew about Jason?
- They don't.
How the hell do you know that?
- Because from the moment we started
this operation, we log you
separately into NATIS.
What is NATIS?
Fed data base.
Anyone who logs in to your case file
runs your name or Jason
They notify me.
They ran your name yesterday at noon.
That's why they know about
Annalisa and Isabelle.
And not Jason. - No, because he's listed
under his mother's maiden name.
And you don't have the same address.
He's safe.
Who'd you meet with?
Malik called them El Topo.
Who is he?
He's Juan Carlos Montero.
They call him 'The Mole'.
El Topo. He's ex-Mexican paramilitary
and he runs this region
for the Nuevo León cartel.
That's who he is.
Yeah, and Pintero was seriously
crippling our organisation.
What did he say about the run?
Just that there was another pick up.
And I got to take it to Mexico.
What, in to Mexico?
Why?
Because that means you're
running their money this time.
You see John. One of the ways that we
fighting the cartel..
..is to stop them getting their profit.
Right now it's virtually
impossible for them to wire the money in..
..so they have to physically transport it.
Hundreds of millions of dollars.
This could be an
incredible opportunity for us.
Especially if we got Pintero too.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Yeah sure. John, would you
excuse us for a second?
I'd appreciated it.
Thanks.
What? - You know damn well what.
El Tope’s a game changer, and
he's way out of his depth.
Are you kidding me? We can
still bring in Malik.
No.
- We squeeze him for a 3rd strike..
There's no way El Topo is going to be
at the exchange tomorrow.
I am not missing this opportunity,
even if we don't get him.
You know the way this works.
You follow the drugs, you get players.
You follow the money, you get a 'kingpin'.
You know that if he crosses that border,
he's never coming back.
You good with that?
John?
Sit down. Drink?
- No.
Coffee?
We had a deal. I deliver Malik to you..
..you reduce my sin sentence to a year.
I'm really sorry. But we are
way past Malik now.
If we pick him up,
we're going to tip off the cartel.
And what about go to a judge?
- You can if you want to, but..
..with the mandatory minimum laws.
Judges has no say to reduce sentence.
Only the federal prosecutor does,
and that's me.
Look. This is the last stop.
You've been very patience.
I give you my word.
Your son is coming home soon.
Immediately.
- 'Scuese me?
I go through with this, Jason come home
that instant.
And I'll make sure that
every parents out there..
knows how compassionate
you've been to my son.
OK. You complete this.
And I will have the judge
release your son.
But, I need the money..
..and the arrest of
the cartel player, nothing less.
Hey, John. What time they calling you
with the pickup address?
10.30. Tomorrow morning.
The reason they pick Sunday,
is a high traffic day at the border.
Less inspections.
You don't think this is
a good idea, do you?
Hey man. Don't matter what I think.
You made a deal with
the 'Dragon Lady', not me.
John, you got to know there's a reason..
..they pick you so quick for this run.
Cartels don't use
wrong people to carry loads.
They recruit..
..guys like you.
Favourite target is a..
middle class kid in a school.
Make it sound all exciting to
carry your backpack full of dope
for pockets full of cash.
Then they do it.
These guys threatening
to kill our family..
They use them, they abuse them..
They end up in a pool of acid.
That's it, they're gone. Done.
Easy come, easy go.
Because there's always
be another mule to
take their place.
Brother you got to
know this is one
serious backpack
you're about to carry.
Hello. I'm here to see my son.
He should be out from infirmary.
I see, under Matthews?
Jason Collins.
Just sign in.
Go to window 4.
Thank you.
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
God dammit. I can't keep letting
this happen to you.
They said anything about moving you?
How is everybody?
Bagaimana Izzy?
She doing alright?
I've been wanting to tell you something.
I'd admire you so much
The stand you're taking.
You didn't take the easy way out.
Not setting up one of your friends.
I couldn't do what you did.
So looks like you're the one..
..teaching me.
What real character
and integrity is all about.
I love you son.
I love you too.
Who is it?
- It's John.
What are you doing here man?
I park a few blocks away.
In case somebody's watching.
Daniel, thank you for
not ratting me out.
Believe me man, I've thought about it.
If I don't go through with this.
They not going to release my son.
What you don't understand man..
You play nice with the feds man.
But what happen when Malik and
everyone finds out that you're an informant?
What happens to me that
puts me right with you?
They know I'm a ratt.
They will hunt us down man.
They going to come after the families John.
Daniel, I know I'm the one
who put us all in danger.
And I got to live with that.
There is no way..
..I'm going to let either side..
..dictate our fates.
No way.
The address come through?
Yeah, I know the area. It's going to take
about an hour and a half to get there.
The route is only 52 miles
west of your warehouse.
It's still going to take
90 minutes in the semi.
No longer.
- Leaving now.
Both wire is loud and clear.
Our guys is 20 miles out.
- OK.
He's been sitting there 15 minutes.
What's he doing? Shit.
Alright, let's do a drive by.
Shit. Anybody hear anything?
Voices? Struggle?
Where the hell are you, John?
What took you so long?
Just lost the DEA. We're on.
Hey John. You sure
you pull this off, right?
Not without your part, No.
I need that number.
We counted every dollar.
You'll be responsible for it.
We can't triangulate the cell.
maybe it's turned off.
Why would he just?
What the address in Mexico?
- At El Paso..
The main border crossing.
I will tell you which lane.
Only you are going to be in
that truck to avoid suspicion.
We're going to follow in the cars.
Once you've crossed, Nico Juarez they
going to direct you to..
..the final stop.
- Alright.
I like them your tactics, Home.
Straight boom rush.
That's the Cruzz I know.
I need the number on El Topo bro.
I'm going to leave,..
..and I'm going to call 911 man.
Man, me and you both know
they're already on their way.
Yeah? - You and I know if I cross into
Mexico, I'm a dead man.
So you think you better
off going alone?
Despite what you might think of me, John..
..I am your only protection on this.
yeah, maybe so.
But as many times you guys
change your game on me.
I had to put something in the play first.
Yeah, like what exactly?
You know my deal with Keeghan
was for the money and the boss.
Well, I'm going to make sure that
they happen on this side of the border.
Would you track the
cell phone number that I'm on.
I'm in one my other trucks right now,
and it's filled with their cash.
John, listen to me. I just
got a hit on NATIS.
Somebody connected
you with Jason.
I don't know who it is,
but I'm working on it.
John, can you hear me?
Pull over, now!
- What's happening there?
They know. Get Jason to protective custody.
They have people on the inside.
- Don't you worry about him.
We're on it.
We got units coming to 'em now.
We already got the prison lockdown.
He's in isolation cell.
Locate the second number. It's: 517-555-0199.
It's El Topo cell.
- Get me that number tracked now!
Putta!
Did you get them?
Yeah. We lock his position of his cell.
I've tactical teams en route
I'm shot in the leg.
John, listen to me hang in there.
I've got units responding to you now.
Just get off at Woodworth.
It's the next exit.
I'll have you converge there.
Clear!
- Kitchen clear.
House is all clear.
No one's home.
Just missed them.
- Turn around.
He's heading north by Nichols.
Seal the perimeter.
Show me your hands!
Show the hands, now!
Shut it off!
Keep 'em up!
Ladies and gentlemen. We are here
today to announce..
..the arrest of Juan Carlos Pintera..
..and other key members
of the Nueva Leon cartel.
Rest assured you will be safer tonight.
Thank you.
So you going to vote for her?
John, you did a great thing.
Thank you so much.
I only wish I could tell people about it.
- Nah, it's OK.
As long as I see Jason free in the morning.
Is all I need.
7 AM sharp. He'll be out.
So how is your family dealing with..
..going into witness protection?
I haven't told them yet.
Coop, Daniel James.
How's the arm?
- I'll live.
Heard you refuse in Wait a second?
Yeah, we got a plan.
Just going to disappear on our own.
What you need me to do is statement right?
That's why I'm here.
Start by signing that.
- Wait a second man, What is that?
Listen. You've got nothing
to worry about, Daniel.
We know you're instrumental in this bust.
Hundred G'S? - Yes, reward money
for capture Juan Carlos Pintera.
It's John Matthews's money man.
Well he said something
about having to lay you off.
Let's get started.
Let’s go home.
Thank you.