Alright, fellas. Stand up for
the count. Stand up.
Hayman.
- Here.
Hathford.
-- Here.
Morning ladies, morning.
Ellersby.
Madlock.
McChaughney.
Let's move it.
You asked me about
my worst secret.
My most personal secret.
The secret of all my secrets.
...but first
I'm Vince Rizzo.
I wanna begin by telling you
about where I live.
City Island is a fishing village
located in Le Bronx, New York.
Not City Island is distinct
from the rest of Le Bronx
by virtue of being located
on its own two-lane spit
right in the middle of the South.
Most people don't believe
it until they see it.
And within the one square mile
that comprises all there is of City Island
lies yet another distinction.
That of the mussel sucker
versus the clam digger.
The mussel sucker is an island resident
who moved here from somewhere else.
The clam diggers like myself were
born and bred on City Island.
preferably in the same house which've
been handed down to other generations.
In short, the world can be divided between
Clam diggers and mussel suckers.
Those who stay and
those who wander.
You asked me about my worst secret
my most personal secret
The secret of all my secrets.
Well, like most of us...
I guess I have a few.
Vince, I need the blow dryer.
- Coming.
- Hey Vinnie, are you ready for your test today?
- Totally.
I'm gonna start my car.
Be there in five minutes.
Morning.
Hey, call Vivian, will you?
Find out what bus she's taking.
Is she staying over?
Spring break.
She's here all week.
We'll probably go out
for Mexican tonight.
I can't, I got a poker game.
You're daughter is home from college
and all you can think about...
She's here all week, right?
Just make an early dinner and don't
let it start with me, please.
Somewhat, Vince, you were fixing
the boatshed or tearing it down.
Pick whatever you want,
coz I don't have time, alright.
Hey, Sheryl.
Do you want to do something?
I'm not going to class.
- Like what?
- I don't know.
Feed you some donuts.
Feed me donuts?
Oh nice, just make a
fat joke, freak!
I'm gonna lock it.
Watch the gates.
Alright fellas. Stand up
for the count.
Alright morning ladies, morning.
Is it a meeting?
Would you like his voicemail?
He played a poker
game last night.
Wait.
Nirhof?
Nardela?
Listen, who are the new guys?
Well we got a Bogart, he transferred
from upstate and a Nardela
Yeah, Nardela, who's is she?
It's the same old thing, man.
Grand theft auto, out with
coke with attempt to sell.
Done 3 out 5 at the South Court.
Pile him up on us
due to overcrowding.
It says here, that his parole is provisional.
Be released to a closest living relative.
Yeah, he's gonna do 30 days on the outside...
if he had a family member who
would've claimed his sorry grand theft ass.
He said, he's gotta finish
out the rest of his town.
That was a tough break.
-- He will get out eventually.
And then he can go back
to boosting Ferrari's.
Well, it says it was an Impala.
Who boost Impala's?
Stealing the wrong kind of car.
Hey, sweetheart.
How are you doing?
How's my future college grad?
Fine. Whatever.
Listen. Your mom wants to know
what you wanna do all week.
All week?
Yeah, you know, for your spring break.
Oh, right.
Did you make other plans
or something? You forget?
No, of course not.
I just, have work...
Well, bring your books. Take the
six o'clock and I'll pick you up.
You don't have to do that...
I know I don't have to do that
but I wanna do it because I love you.
I'll pick you up.
I love you too.
Blue shirt, you're on.
I'm losing the whole week full of shifts.
Forgot about spring break.
Why don't you take a vacation
like the other kids?
You don't have to come, dad.
I could've have rented a car service.
Scholarships don't pay for car service.
They pay for your education.
Did you bring your books?
No.
Don't you got to study or nothing?
Fine. Whatever. Dad.
Well, you know, I'm just concerned
that you don't fall behind in your studies.
Stop, dad
- Yeah, I'm concerned about your education, you know
- Stop, dad!
You got yourself like 20 feet in front of
you and you can stop like over there
and you got still 20 feet. Keep this thing out.
Get this piece of junk out of here.
Just get it out of here.
Get in your car.
Well, that's great Vince, beautiful!
A thing of beauty!
Yeah, you like it, huh. I did it on purpose.
I knew you'd like it so much.
We're just having a sale in White Plains.
We should go tomorrow.
Sure.
Maybe we'll go to the Botanical Gardens.
Vinnie said he wanted to go.
I, what?
- To the botanical gardens.
Botanical Gardens?
You're serious about going
to the botanical gardens?
I'm just saying there are much more
interesting things that we could do.
We can tie ourselves to the couch and watch
Cartoon Network for 48 hours straight or something like that.
And maybe afterwards you know,
we could take a tour of the zip lock bag factory.
That will be fun.
Vinnie, shut up.
You shut up Vivian, seriously.
Shut up, man.
My heart, my heart, somebody call an ambulance.
I need help. I need help.
That's enough.
So when's he leaving this
phase of stupid adolescence?
Never, he's never leaving high school.
coz he thinks he's too smart
to go to any of his classes.
To get an "A".
Oh sweet! I got an "A".
I'm having so much fun looking
at this letter on a piece of paper.
5 more of this letter
on this piece of paper...
...and I can get a 4.0 GPA average.
For what? So I can grow up and
become another meaningless...
Prison guard? Like your father
who also does not have a college degree.
Nice.
That's not what I was gonna say but...
Excuse me.
First of all, it's a correctional officer
and you know what happens
if you don't go to college?
You wind up answering phones for a living.
That's nice for you,
if you wanna hear that kind of stuff.
I went to Ianto.
Two years on Ianto which is
not exactly a Harvard degree.
Well, if I hadn't gotten pregnant
I would've gotten my degree.
Great, mom. So I supposed
that ties the game.
Do not spoil my college degree.
I'm just saying if I hadn't gotten pregnant
I would've had a degree.
Yeah, but you wouldn't have hers.
So what? Degree, you daughter?
We all know what you're saying.
Where are you going?
- I got a poker game.
Play hard, pops.
- Shut up, Vinnie.
My life is falling apart.
It's all crumbling.
Louder, I can't hear you.
I need to know
you love me.
I...
Say it.
Jesus Christ.
Yes.
I love you.
Wait a minute, why
did you need to pause here?
What were all those pauses for?
What were they?
What do you mean?
You said 2 lines and I
counted 4 pauses in 2 lines.
Why do you need a pause
before you say, "what"?
Oh, he's stalling for time.
- Why? I mean does he love her or does he not love her?
He does love her.
- So what the hell you need to pause for? Listen.
We have the Collar Moratorium on pauses.
Five years of my life is going out the window...
...listening to pauses in this room.
I can't do it anymore.
So we gotta cut out the pauses.
In 2000 years of theatre history
you'll never find anybody pausing.
The only pause - they either
or they listen.
They did their acting while they were talking.
All of a sudden, Marlon Brando comes
in to the picture about 45, 50 years ago.
And everybody says:
"Oh my God, the man is a genius."
Did you see him thinking?
Did you see Brando in the fugitive kind?
Anybody see that?
Somebody asked Brando
what his name is.
He's gonna think about it.
Why does he have to think about that?
Takes me half an hour
to get back to the guy.
It's not acting and
it's not thinking. It's just...
well, it's just bullshit.
No more pauses!
If you wanna think, think in
the privacy of your own heart.
Otherwise, very nice work.
Very good.
Okay, everybody up. Stretch.
Nice deep stretch.
I can't talk right now.
I don't know maybe Monday.
Just give my shift to Autumn.
Alright bye.
Who was that?
Work.
And you, and you...
Okay.
All the people I've mentioned turn
left and face your new partner.
Go on, say hello.
Hi, I'm Molly Charlsworth.
- Hi, Vince Rizzo.
Nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
Your assignment for next week is...
to find the most embarrassing...
the most unspeakable thing you can think of...
your secret of secrets...
and you're gonna share it
with you new partner.
So what are you gonna do
with your partner's secret?
You're gonna use to find the courage...
to dramatize your own secret
which you've been trying to hide...
within an inch of your lives...
and you're gonna present
it to us next week...
in the form of a monologue
with no pauses. Is that clear?
Good. Any questions?
Very good. Good class!
So then to get her money in her room...
you said your father didn't get
himself, he just tried to kill your mother.
Only, my mother was away
and my father was a drunk.
It's when their wedding
put an end, come to life.
So my brother and I went to stay with
my aunt on her plantation in Hawaii...
And my brother turned to
opium byproducts.
And I got shackled off to so dusty and
best forgotten European boarding schools.
Wow.
What happened to your brother?
Oh God, no, I'm sorry...
It's just not very useful
for these purposes.
You see, the problem is I've told
this secret about a million times.
I've auditioned with it, in fact...
So it's your turn, Vince
and I'm stuck.
I don't know. Is it possible
that I don't have one?
No.
That would make far too healthy
towards being an actor.
Fat Chicks Bronx New York
Come on, think.
Well, for one thing...
I mean, right here...
my wife right now thinks that
I got a poker game tonight.
You mean, instead of telling her
you've enrolled in an acting class...
you told her you're out gambling.
Is that better?
Well, it's kinda hard to
explain, but yeah.
You see, my wife she wouldn't go...
she wouldn't go for the fact
that I wanna be an actor.
How very refreshing!
Yeah, I guess.
Come on, tell it to me.
Like you were confessing it.
I am Vince Rizzo, you asked
me about my worst secret...
my most personal secret.
Well, my wife she thinks I got
a poker game tonight...
...and it's bullshit.
What do you mean?
You could do worse?
Yeah, try me.
I hardly know you.
I know, isn't it lovely?
I just met my son.
Where?
In the facility where I work,
I'm a correctional officer.
You're a prison guard?
Well, sort of...
Yeah.
And how old is he, you're son?
- He's 24.
His name is Tony.
Tony Nardela.
This is brilliant.
How did you recognize him?
Well, his name it just popped
right out from the rap sheet.
You know, Nardela because
that was his mom, mom's name.
and he was born in Campton, New Jersey
which is where she lived.
I wasn't actually there
with them coz I took off.
Have you ever told your
current wife about him?
Or about his mother?
- No.
Or about any of it?
I always meant to, but...
I could never find the right time.
He's really handsome.
FeedingDenise.com
Hi, I'm Denise and
I'm a proud BBW.
That's "Big, Beautiful Woman",
for those new to this.
I'm 5'8", 350 pounds and
I think eating...
and feeding a sexy woman
is the sexiest thing in the world.
If you join my club...
you'll get 24-hour access
to a live view of my kitchen...
where I spend the most of my
time when I'm not working.
Hi, I'm Denise and
I'm a proud BBWW.
That's "Big, Beautiful Woman"
for those new to this.
My wife, she's a fighter,
she's tough...
she has very firm opinions on things.
You just wanna make sure
she's fighting on your side.
Wow, she sounds like the real thing.
Oh yeah, she's the real thing.
And she looks great too.
She's very beautiful.
But you know, lately...
somewhat it's like we're
not friends anymore.
The reappearance of your secret
lovechild might well provide a solution.
- How?
He'll provide a dangerous
symbol of your own virility.
She'll be reminded of all the things
that attracted her to you to begin with...
You see, the Vincent
she never really knew...
Is the Vincent she seeks
or she wants back.
Does that make any sense?
- No, but you know...
women are emotionally incoherent.
It's the most defining characteristic.
I do some of my best work by a cellular.
Call me, Vincent but
only on a win.
Good night.
I was thinking as you know, being a
Saturday night and all and Vivian's here...
Why don't we have a big
home cook dinner tonight?
Big, nice, big.
- Yeah sure, like I do every Saturday night.
Yeah, but like you know,
something special.
Like for a real special occasion
or something special.
You want balloons or something?
No, I don't want balloons or something.
I'm just saying something nice.
When don't I make it nice?
- Make something nicer.
Make it yourself!
The great communicator.
You went outside last night?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I did heroine with a bunch of
prostitutes at the Plaza Hotel.
I'm thinking of becoming a pimp.
Good. I'll see you later.
My name is Vince Rizzo
Correctional Officer 426.
Says here you made provisional parole
but you got no family to be released to.
Yeah, that's life.
You got a mother named Nen.
- Yeah.
5 foot 2, red headed.
Yeah.
How is she doing?
Not so good. She's dead.
About 4 years ago.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Why? You know her?
Yeah, I know her.
Anything else?
- Yeah, there's something else.
I spoke to Warden Amboy.
You're gonna be released to me.
You're gonna be in my personal
care for the next 30 days.
I live in Le Bronx.
Get the prisoner ready.
Can I ask you like why
I'm chained to a Ford?
I'm gonna unchain you, Tony
but first I gotta tell you something.
See this house here?
That's my home.
My grandfather built this home
and I share it with my family.
Well, you got them chained
up in the house too?
You're gonna get real nice food...
and a real nice place to live
for the first time in 3 years.
So you better behave yourself.
And all these, because you
knew my bitch mother.
Well, I got to admit your mom
can be difficult sometimes but...
but she was also...
drunk and a whore.
Why do you call her that?
She used to punish me
when I booze in cases of Vodka
from the liquor store I worked
at by screwing my friends
which makes her
drunk and a whore.
Don't you have any
fun memories of her?
Well, she was always around,
my father left before I was born.
What do you know about him?
- He's dead.
That's too bad.
The only thing that's too
bad is that I didn't get a chance...
to visit his deathbed and
dance in his ugly face
for leaving me with that bitch.
Okay, let's go!
I'll go with a handcuff?
- I'll unchain you in a minute.
I don't want you running away before I show
you what kind of setup I did for you.
Run away, why would I do that?
You said this was a house.
This is it.
I started fixing it a couple of years ago
but I got busy with other things.
Here's the deal: You're gonna
help me put a bathroom in here.
Excuse me?
A bathroom. My wife always wanted
a bathroom and as I figured...
you know, I saw in your sheet
you're a handy man.
30 days you build a bathroom with me.
Once you're through, I'll pay you a fair wage
You can go wherever the hell you want
with a few bucks in your pocket. That's the deal.
How am I supposed to build
a bathroom with handcuffs on me?
Don't go running away from me, Tony.
Coz if you do, I'm gonna personally
come after you. Understand me?
I'll throw your ass back in the cage.
And this time they ain't gonna be kidding.
They're gonna put you away
for a long stretch, you understand me?
Yeah, whatever.
Why don't you try: "Okay, Vince
I promise you that"?
Okay Vince, I promise you that.
Why don't you try...
"Thank you Vince for getting
my ass out of the cage."
Spit it out.
Thanks for getting me out of the cage.
- You're welcome.
And don't be talking shit about your
mother she wasn't perfect but she was...
...she was a good lay.
Yeah, whatever.
Shit, my wife.
Is that what you call her?
I don't smoke.
- Yeah, I can tell.
Whatever you do just don't
mention the prison thing.
Just say we're old friends.
Are we in a bowling team together?
My daughter's back from college
so you better take it easy.
And don't mention that I knew
you mother. It's bad news.
I'll tell you when you can come out.
Anybody home?
- I'm here.
So is dad, he's out back,
handcuffed to some biker dude.
...been back there for quite
some time. Bullshit.
You bring some filthy
biker into my house
without even so much as asking me.
- He's not a biker, he's a nice young man...
he's gonna be working for his board.
- Where did you meet this guy anyway?
He's getting out of jail in a month.
I told them I will take responsibility for him.
Oh my God, Vince.
What? You just pick that con at random
and bring him into my house?
I don't pick no con at random,
I happened to know his mother.
What?
His mother, I happened
to know his mother.
What do you mean?
Who was she?
Mom, now you think he never knew
any woman before you? Calm down.
Are you serious?
- I knew his mother. She was like a...
No! No! No!
...because it's my house!
- He cannot stay here, Vince!
Do you understand me?
Before we go on, I'd like
to thank my beautiful wife, Joycie
for this special dinner
that she prepared.
Yeah, it looks great, Mom!
Thank you.
I like to welcome
Tony to our table.
Good times ahead. Nothing but
good, sweet, breezy times.
Plus the food is gotta be
like at least marginally...
better than that shit
they serve in jail, right?
What's the matter with you?
My peptic ulcer!
You have to watch it!
-- Vinnie, shut up.
No, yo, you shut up, get off my ass.
What're you gonna do?
Vince tells me that he was
friends with your mother.
Yeah, a long time ago, I guess.
I guess so.
Well, I never heard about it.
It was because...it was
before we met, sweetie.
He says she was a very nice
woman, good looking too, I bet.
Here we go.
Mom, Dad's right, why don't
we just be upfront here...
come out with it, just ask him
if he had sex with this woman.
Apologize to me.
That's my brain tumor.
Well, he does have a point.
With all due respect, it is
what you were getting at.
I don't care if you had
sex with her or not.
Why are you two
gaining up on me?
Come on, Joycie...
you know, after 20 years I know
where you're going before even you do.
Well, that must be very
boring for you, Vince. Really.
Who knew that I was failing to keep
you entertained all these years.
Mom, he didn't mean it like that.
- You're taking his side too now?
I'm not taking any sides.
I'm just saying...
You know, dad says some things
in stupid ways sometimes.
In a stupid way? Now your dad is
stupid for some reason all of a sudden?
I meant you said it
in a stupid way.
You just said that I
was sounding stupid.
You might talk to your colleagues,
to your college friends but...
you don't talk to your father like that.
- Well, you blame her for a real education.
I'm not saying anything about it,
I'm just saying she can't talk to me...
Why? Do you have to bring college into it?
- No, you brought college into it!
Stop, guys!
Just stop.
She's telling I'm stupid in the
front of the dining room table.
Dad, stop!
Want some cheese?
- Yeah, sure.
Okay Vivian, I've got
to ask you a question.
What?
Are your breast continuing
to grow? Because...
and this is to my endeavor, way bigger.
- What are you doing?
How dare you talk
to your sister like that?
Get in my room? Pretty lame, mom.
It's a little old school.
Don't talk to your
mother like that.
Go to your room, right now.
- I like this family. This is nice.
My room's got everything.
Everything I need is in my room.
Hey, you want me to get up?
I'm getting up.
It's not my punishment.
I'm done. I'm done. I'm leaving.
Unbelievable.
What?
Vince?
He does have a point there, sweetie.
I mean...
It does seem to be getting
larger in that area.
Jesus, dad!
What's the matter with you?
Where're you going?
That girl buries her head
in her books, 18 hours a day.
She comes home for a little
quality family time...
and you gotta go and screw it up.
What's screwed up? I'm just saying they're
getting larger. 'twas a compliment.
Oh my God!
What's the matter with you guys?
- Inappropriate!
I'm inappropriate? I'm the guy here
who's trying to hold this thing together.
What's the matter with you guys, huh?
The hell with this.
The hell with all of you's.
Dinner was great.
Thank you.
Hey, Molly.
Yeah, it's me. Vince.
I'm calling you on a whim.
Spring break over?
Just out here to watch the show.
Take off early tonight, split a shit with me.
Highly unlikely. Agent
Invasion is out of force.
Shit, I could've cleaned up this week.
Have a drink.
My husband thinks I quit.
One good thing about the joint.
They don't let you smoke anymore so...
I quit inside.
Being in prison and
not being able to smoke?
That's like being in jail.
Join me.
You got to tell them, I mean...
...the longer it goes about not knowing who
you really are, the greater her sense of betrayal.
And she's been betrayed enough.
Yeah, and it all started
when I walked off.
No, don't do that.
Things come to self-flagellation.
I mean, I understand it of course.
It was one of the Catholic of you and
everything but you're beyond it.
You've opened up your
home to a convicted felon.
You'd shown him huge trust...
by leaving him alone
there with your family.
Oh, Jesus, that's all I need.
No, because he's your
flesh and blood.
If you can't trust your own blood
then what the hell can you trust.
Vince, come on, it's time for you to just
take the final step and fill his part right there.
He started that boatshed 3 years ago...
with enough wooden junk
to build a forest.
This is gonna be his new career,
building things.
He gets discouraged when
things take too long.
Like more than an hour.
And him? and his poker games.
Does he really think
I'd buy that crap?
- What is it in "New Screen and Stage"?
The Wall Street Journal
is staging actors.
You prove yours, that's it.
A new open course...
Parts that are never get
and projects that are never made.
For instance...
Here, open call, male, 30-50
working class type,
no agency rep required.
Auditions will be held Monday,
9 AM, Barret St, Armond.
That would be a good one for you.
...Yeah, no kidding.
Does it also say, if you got
no age, you're not qualified?
Does it say no talent?
So what happens, you go to
that street and then what happens?
You've never been to an audition before?
- No.
Oh Vincent, it's dreadful.
What?
Okay, so, you walk in...
you wait in a room crowded with the faces
that look vaguely familiar in an explicit way.
They mark you in, they stare
at you, they hate you.
You sing and dance and throw a
baton, show off all the talents..
that once thrilled your mother and father.
They make faces, sometimes very rarely.
They ask you a question.
Then you're dismissed
and you go home for the night.
Content not peeing there.
Sounds terrifying.
But having said all that...
you really should go for this one.
It sounds perfect for you, come on.
Thank you very much.
You walked me off a cliff.
Welcome my new fat-friendly fan.
You're now officially
a member of my club.
If you see me out at the BBW
Function in the New York Metro area
you can tell me
you're a special member
by saying our secret word:
"Botero"
When you think about it, Vincent,
acting is one of the strangest things
a person can possibly choose to do.
Pretending to be someone else
who was dreamed up by some third party.
It's like agreeing to be a marionette.
Why do you act?
Rarely, what other profession could have
committed my sort of behavior problems.
Yeah, sort of like they pay
you for being a professional schooler.
Perfect.
I grew up with a mother
and no father.
And my mother hated my father so much...
for leaving. Then, she took it
out on me because I reminded her of him.
I didn't even know him.
It's hilarious.
Upstairs, my son's room
has a bunch of sweaters
Second door on your left.
Thank you.
Botero?
Hello, who's there?
So you thought any more
about your secret?
All the time.
For you to have a land of secrets.
Yeah, skies.
That'll be very difficult for you
to decide which one is the best.
Am I ever gonna get a chance to hear it?
I don't mean to press you
or anything, it's just that...
I'm feeling a little nervous
since we have a class in 3 days and...
...I just wanna be helpful.
Where do you live?
Le Bronx.
No thanks.
What?
Forget it, soak it in the ash.
I'm sorry.
I'm sure Le Bronx is lovely.
My part overly is,
the other part not so much.
I lived in a place called City Island.
It's an old fishing village.
Really?
City Island
For two worlds standing
apart really from each other.
City: so short and abrupt and definite.
and Island: it's subtle, unknown.
..and with a silent "S".
I would never...
thought about it in those terms,
but yeah, it's a great spot.
If you live there, you go up there...
you would never think
about moving somewhere else.
Good night, Tony.
Pleasant dreams.
Good night, Mrs. Rizzo.
Joyce.
- Mrs. Rizzo is Vince's mom.
That's it.
What?
It's my secret.
No, not yet.
I needed it to stay mine
just for a little bit longer.
Once you know, it's no
longer treated a secret.
Be at the moment when it's obvious.
Will you keep it with you?
Yeah, of course.
Vince.
-What?
What a wonderful time
to not disappear.
Where were you last night honey?
Friends.
Where are you going?
Beach.
Okay, here's what I'm thinking...
take the pipe and we'll run
it right through here.
We angle it off, we chase the steps up
the hill and tap it to the main line.
Feels good, son, don't you?
You know, my grandfather built this
house way before I was born.
Yeah, you told me.
He came from the old country.
He became a fish scaler.
Yeah?
- Yeah, him and his brother.
Couple of young mussel suckers.
How's that?
City Island has an old custom.
If you come from somewhere else
you're known as a "mussel sucker."
But if you're born and raised here
like myself, you're a "clam digger"
Clam digger.
Mussel sucker.
Hey, you wanna see something?
- No.
Really.
- Are you sure?
Go away.
If could mess with your head like forever.
I'd wanna see it.
Where did you get that?
Dad hides it in the bathroom.
Hey, relax, relax.
It's just me.
You scared the hell out of me.
What's that?
What?
- That.
It's between you and me, okay.
It's an open call for a movie tomorrow.
So?
Ever since I was a little kid
I wanted to become an actor.
I thought it was something I could do.
I've been taking acting classes
over there in the city.
Nobody knows. Joyce don't know.
Nobody knows.
It's kinda stupid.
She thinks I got a poker game.
Well, what you really had
going on is an acting class?
I got an acting class.
Another friend of mine who goes to the classes,
explaining to me what it's like going on auditions.
Doesn't sound like it's for me.
- You should give it a shot if that's what you wanna do.
It's what I wanna do
but I'm no actor.
Not for real anyway.
But anyone can act
if they have to.
What do you mean anybody
can act if they...
you can't act if you have to.
You gotta study that.
A lot like..like when I got to South court.
I figured that acting more psycho
than everyone else when I was younger.
Had to watch out for myself.
So what did you do?
I went at the ugliest guy I could find.
I think I'm pissed off of you.
And I don't know why.
Do I need a reason?
You said that?
- Shut up! I'm talking to you.
Give me top ten reason you're a
piece of shit and I'll let you know...
when something rings a bell,
but don't lie to me.
And don't figure me as one of your
sissy boys, it's gonna pay out for you.
You're sadly a deformed
excuse for humanity
posing as a piece of prison garbage.
And it worked.
That was just...acting.
Think about it, right.
Hey, that was terrific.
Hey, how are you doing?
I come here for the movie audition.
- Back of the line.
Do you know anything
about this movie here?
It's for Scorsese and DeNiro.
Where were you?
Funeral?
Yeah.
Hey yourself.
Yeah what?
Relax.
Botero.
Botero! Botero.
It's Botero.
Dude, it's Botero I wikipediad that.
They got the pronunciation
spelled out like, at a dictionary.
I'm making triple braised
baby back ribs...
mix grilled.
sweltered in steaks.
Do you wanna go shopping with me?
Yes.
Yes, I do actually.
Hey, I'm almost done with the thrash.
What do you want me to do next?
Oh I don't know.
What did Vince want done in there?
A toilet, wall, shower stall,
I mean, he wasn't really specific.
You know, we could go to a
bathroom place or something.
Pick some stuff out.
Well, I got no plans. I took a
day off, you know, "family time".
Maybe we should ask
Vince if he has any...
preferences.
Preferences for what?
Toilets and stuff?
That's funny.
Why is that funny?
You know, toilets...
I just wanna go back to work.
And why does this holiday even exist?
It's sucks, you know, my parents
were so freaking toxic. It's just...
I gotta get out of here.
I better call my husband.
- Sure.
No way, no way,
no way, no way...
No, no, no.
No way, no.
Officer Rizzo, please.
Yeah, I'm holding for
my husband, Officer Rizzo.
He called in sick?
Hey sweetie, how are you doing?
Where are you?
Yeah, I'm a...
I'm at work.
I'm on the yards.
Well, I was just wondering...
if you had a preference for toilets.
Toilets?
No preference.
Take Tony with you
he could help.
Yeah, okay. Good idea.
I'll take Tony.
Oh, Vince...
you know, how every cop
always leaves his house with a gun?
Well, my husband swears...
that every car should have
a good pair of handcuffs.
Like he's Joe Justice.
Orchard Beach.
Have you ever been?
I actually considered killing myself.
I considered, you know,
chop off a sexual organ in defiance.
I just gotta to tell you, though
it's my thing...
I need to feed a girl
like a lot of food.
You're a classic feeder, Vinnie.
You gain pleasure by
giving pleasure.
Who was the girl in the
park you were with yesterday?
Oh, that's Sheryl,
she's just a friend from school.
She's a sweet lady.
Try to love her.
So Tony, you do anything else besides...
Boosting a car?
I also get stuff...
all up at the gas station.
Robbed a pharmacy,
couple of jewelry stores.
Are you scared of me?
Oh, yeah.
Sir, follow us.
Sir, this way.
Can you make a line
in the order I called you?
And you, you join us.
Sir, you too. You.
You in the back. This way.
And him.
And you, back of the line.
Thank you very much.
Go home. Come on.
It's okay Tony, it's not like
I'm doing this forever or nothing.
I don't care.
It doesn't matter to me.
Let me ask you if he
wasn't fooling around...
No, no, you don't worry about that.
I mean, these decisions I make are mine.
But I mean, what if he hadn't?
Hadn't what?
Made what you thought he made.
You're having another feeling.
What other feeling?
Like you don't like me?
Definitely not the case.
Good.
Vince Rizzo.
Follow me.
Relax yourself.
Step on the mark.
State yourself.
Say what?
Look into the camera
and say your name.
Oh yeah, Vincent Rizzo
Correctional Officer 426.
No, Joyce, I can't, I can't.
It's not that I don't wanna, I do.
It's not nothing.
Except your husband...
maybe he's got something going on
in his life, maybe it's not a poker game.
but it's doesn't got to be
with another woman, you know.
Really?
Like what he's taking a class?
Please.
Whenever you're ready.
Excuse me?
Start.
Oh, do the thing.
I'm sorry, are you doing
a Marlon Brando impression?
No.
Okay, let's just try again
in your own voice.
So make no mistake Joey!
From now on out, I'm watching you.
What you do, who you do.
Watch it!
Coz Frankie Gunucci has
eyes in the back of his head.
In the back of his head?
In the back? Should it be like
I have eyes in the back...
Thank you, Mr. Rizzo.
Excuse me?
- Thank you.
That's it?
Hold on one second.
Absolutely.
I'll try.
Are you a professional actor?
No, I'm a correctional officer.
Okay, could you come back?
Come back to the mark.
You're a correctional officer.
Is that a prison guard?
Prison guard?
Yeah, I guess you can call it that.
Okay, and where do you work?
Dalegrove Correctional Facility, Westchester.
Is that like one of those
Country Club prisons?
I'm sorry...
...but I wouldn't call it that.
Not by a long shot.
You want me to talk about this?
- Sure.
We got guys in there that if
you see inside their minds
and see what they're thinking,
you wouldn't be thinking of no golf game.
Okay, well, tell me more about what you do?
What's a typical day?
A typical day is no such animal.
I mean, some days
I walk and talk, you know...
you do the count.
You send the guys out in the yard.
But other days.
Other days are trouble.
The gangs are out of control,
you gotta lock down...
The boys and the girls,
they go in a little dispatch.
Kinda like the real world but
here, they jump your bones.
And sometimes I see a new recruit come in
and I'm looking at him I'm going...
"I got two words for you: Bye, bye."
Coz you're not gonna be the same guy coming in
as you are going out, you know what I'm saying.
Okay so, you know, that scene we just
read just do it again in your own words.
Not using the...
Throw the script away.
- Improvisation, it's like an improvisation.
How would you say it?
This Joey Zambuli character...
he thinks he got the goods
on the Frankie Gunucci...
which is the guy I play, right?
Which makes Zambuli like the worst kind of creep.
Why do you say that?
Well, you know, where I work,
everything is about power.
Zambuli they try to intimidate
the new recruits when they come in.
And if you're a new recruit and
you don't get in their face right away
and hold your ground, they're
gonna have you on all fours...
...sucking cement.
You know what sucking cement means, right?
I know what that means.
What do you do with guys like that?
What I would do is I would pretend that...
Bang!, right up, right from the start
when they come to me...
I pretend I'm more psycho than they are
you know, get them off guard.
Look at this guy, get right in his face
and give him a little intimidation like that.
And you say: "I'm pissed off of you,
and I don't know why. Do I got a reason?"
Something like that.
Look right into the camera
and talk to Joey Zambuli.
Like if Joey Zambuli is in the camera.
- Uh huh, and you are pissed off.
I don't like him
- No.
Yeah, I mean, he's a creep.
Hey Zambuli, I think I'm pissed off of you
and I don't know why. Do I got a reason?
Let me help you out a little bit.
Why don't you give me your
Top Ten Reasons why you're...
why you're a piece of shit.
And I'll tell you when one rings a bell.
Okay, go.
And don't lie to me!
You got it? Don't lie to me.
And don't figure me for
one of your little sissy boys.
That's gonna put out for you.
Whenever you ask.
Because I got eyes in the front of my head
and in the back of my head and in the side of my head.
And they all see 20:20, capiche?
Comprende?
You're a sadly deformed excuse
for humanity...
posing as some sort of prison garbage.
You mess with me...
You mess with Frankie Gunucci!
Frankie Gunucci! You lose!
Thank you.
What?
Yeah, you better thank me,
you piece of shit, get out of my face!
Get out of my face!
Yeah, take your eyes out
of your fucking head.
Thank you, Mr. Rizzo.
- Shove it up your nose you're gonna be looking like this...
Mr. Rizzo, thank you.
- the rest of your life.
Excuse me?
Oh, that's all?
Sorry, I got carried away.
- That's okay.
Thank you, that was crazy.
Pretty wild.
You need this?
No that's fine, you can keep it.
- Thank you very much.
That's nice. I had a good time.
I was walking out I was feeling
like I was gonna throw up.
and then she stopped me,
she brought me back in.
And before I knew it,
she's asking me these questions...
she's got me doing an improvisation
and I lost my mind.
It was crazy.
Wait.
You just did an improve for
Martin Scorsese's casting director.
Vincent, that's not everyday
garden variety audition. That's...
I mean, that's just...
You're in a... elite...
elite core of auditionists.
No, I wouldn't call that elite.
- It's amazing.
It was wild.
I mean, she had me screaming
inside the camera and I lost my mind.
But all to me,
it was all bullshit.
What do you mean?
Well, because I pretended as though I, you know,
that's the way I talk to the guys inside.
but actually that's the way my son,
Tony, talks to the guys inside.
No, that's so much better.
You corrupted someone else's experience
and filtered it in to your own personality...
in order to create a character.
That's not bullshit, Vincent.
That's acting.
You could do that in acting.
Yes.
- It's allowed?
I can't believe this has
happened to you today.
It was real pretty crazy,
I tell you. I kind of...
Yeah, this is me.
You want me to come back?
Did I forget something?
Who's this?
Louise from casting?
The producers would like
to see you reading again...
with some of the other actors
who've already been cast.
This would be, Wednesday at 2.
Can you make it?
Read with other actors?
Yes, yes, I guess yes.
I mean, Wednesday at 2.
I got work on Wednesday.
No, I don't have work on
Wednesday, Wednesday at 2?
It's okay, yeah, that'll be fine.
I can be there, yeah.
Thank you for everything, I guess.
You gotta go back.
Yeah, I guess so.
Vincent...
- Yeah.
First time out, God!
- Yeah, beginner's luck.
What's wrong?
Come on,
what's going on?
What?
No, it's super brilliant.
It's amazing.
You know, well, it's
all meant to be somehow
you know we meet, to have coffee
and tell each other secrets.
And for me to show you
an advert in screen stage...
that launches your career.
Yeah, I know no careers being launched yet.
You know, I'm just going back in
and I haven't even got the part yet.
You can't believe how amazing this is.
Excuse me, everybody.
I'm sorry to bother you but
I just want to tell you for a second...
about my dear friend here, Vincent Rizzo.
Went on his very first audition today.
For a Martin Scorsese film.
And they liked him so much...
that they've called him back on Wednesday.
And he's a prison guard.
Joyce.
I had a great time.
So Vincent, tell me something...
What're you gonna tell your wife?
She doesn't gonna have any idea that you
even have the tiniest little inkling of acting ambition at all.
No, she still knows nothing.
She still thinks a got a poker game, that's it.
And even if I will to tell her.
She would never believe that.
I mean, I have to start like, go so far back
to try to even explain when it happened...
and how it happened and
where are the Brando thing.
And I mean, no matter what I say,
I don't even know where to start.
What about that the truth
is not outside of the question, is it?
It's out of the question.
Can I have some chicken, please.
- Chicken, right.
Mind if my hands...
You okay honey, you need anything else?
- No, I'm good.
Okay, I think I got it.
What if you pretend
to be my manager?
And then you could say
you then discovered me.
Nice. I like it.
- Thank you very much.
Yes, I discovered you
in some sort of a strange way.
Like my brother's an inmate or something.
- Nice.
And I set you up with Martin Scorsese's
casting. It's perfect.
If she has any problems your wife
can come to me about them.
And you're okay with that?
Because, you know, she can be kind of a hurricane.
Wives always hate me Vincent
I'm used to it.
Are you ready?
To go to City Island?
- Now?
So this is it?
- Yeah.
I like it.
- Yeah, it's nice.
It's kinda like New England
by way of Washington Heights.
City Island Yacht and Beach Club?
Well, it's more like a boat yard.
It's got some grass and barbecues and...
...it's got a pier. But the views are great.
Can we see the views for
like just a minute?
Yeah, I don't see why not?
Excellent.
Every busy city needs
an island of peace.
And every busy soul needs
a place to propose.
Tell it to me again.
- What?
Your big secret.
- About Tony?
You already know the whole thing.
You're the only one who does know.
Yeah, I know, but how did it work?
How did you?...His mom and...
When did you know you were leaving?
Well, I met Nen when
I was about 19.
And she was older.
And she was kinda hot for me and
I was hot to get out of the family.
You know, get away from City Island.
We used to drink at the same
bottle of wine in Arthur Avenue.
Pretty soon, I started
living at her place.
And then that's when things
got a little complicated.
Next you know she was pregnant.
I knew by then she
was bad news for me so...
She said: "I knew you're leaving anyway."
"I'm not gonna get stuck
with nothing for myself" so...
That's when I know
she was having a kid.
And I had to do what I have to do.
Or what I thought I had to do.
I was also a kid.
Anyway, I had 7500 bucks
in my pocket and I, you know...
working on my father's boat
here in City Island.
I was gonna use it to
go to City College...
...but I gave it to her instead.
And then you know,
I got into this prison stuff.
I figured I need a steady income,
pension, I met Joyce...
You never told anyone in your family?
I don't wanna bother anybody.
It was my thing.
Plus, I wasn't too proud of taking off.
Leaving is never pretty
no matter how you do it.
Yeah, you can say that again.
Bitch!
There was no one there.
I hate those things.
Won't you hate those things?
I'm always getting a wrong number.
No, it wasn't a wrong number.
It was an announcement.
A ring a bell.
An indication.
For what?
Now, Vincent.
Now is the time.
Have you still got it?
What? Your secret?
Yeah, of course.
Sure?
No.
Yes.
Who are they?
My three secrets.
They're beautiful.
Thank you.
Where are they?
With my husband in Schenectady.
What are they doing up there?
Real question is,
what am I doing down here?
That's where I'm from, Vincent.
Born and raised.
My father was the janitor
at the grade school...
...and my mother left
home when I was 6.
And their mother left
5 months ago.
Why?
To see if it was possible to
pretend the past never existed.
It's not possible.
Please, don't hate me, Vincent.
If anyone might understand,
it would be you.
What's up? Seltzer water?
- Seltzer water, please. Seltzer water.
What the hell are you doing here?
Yeah, well, I guess I can
ask you the same question.
Does my mother know
that you have her car?
Does your mother know
that you're a stripper?
Give me the key.
Listen, I'm not trying to make any...
- Let me have the key.
You don't have it, do you?
You stole my mother's car, didn't you?
You're such a loser.
Hi, yeah, I like to report a stolen car.
Yeah, I'll hold.
Why are you even here, huh?
Yeah, hi, my mother's car was stolen.
Yeah, license plate number, hold on...
Give me that.
- Calm down!
You stole my mother's car.
- And you're a stripper.
Stripping isn't against the law.
- Oh, then it's okay for me to tell your parents of what you do.
No, don't you dare, you loser!
Bitch. Hooker!
Don't call me that!
I'm not a hooker!
Showing your tits for money,
what's that called, librarian?
I got suspended from school, alright
and I lost my scholarship.
It's just so I could
make enough money
so I could go back and have to tell my parents.
And I'm the loser, huh?
Come here. Come here.
- Get off. What are you doing?
I'm bringing your mom's car back
with you in it, you know, I really delivered.
And only you know, I took it.
And only I know you work here.
And that's gonna be the deal with us forever
until one of us blows it. That's how it works for us, Vivian?
That's how it's gonna work for you and me.
Got it, Vivian?
Take these off!
Why did my father
even bring you home?
I have no idea.
Did something happen between you and my mom?
- No.
Are you gonna tell them that...?
Hey, I gave you my word, didn't I?
My word's my word.
Which something you and your jerk off family
probably never even heard off.
That's weird.
- What's wrong?
She's not home.
Maybe she went out for some food.
This is so nice.
Yeah, my grandfather built this house.
He's a builder.
Yeah, so, here's what I'm thinking.
Now, when she comes in.
I'm just gonna say straight up,
I'll just look at her and say:
"Joyce, it's time we gotta talk."
Vincent, darling.
That's the wrong way.
Women, they feel...
challenged by too much honesty.
No, you gotta trust me on this.
After 20 years with her,
I know what I'm talking about.
Vincent.
- Why?
Darling, 30 years I've been
a woman. Let me handle her.
Remain casual and don't mention
about anything unusual going on.
Before she can even think and ask
what I'm doing here...
she'll be thanking me.
For having come into your life.
Hey, how are you doing?
You're home.
Yeah, Vince, I'm home.
Where I live.
Yeah, where you live.
Who's this?
- Who's this?
I'm Molly Charlsworth.
It's such a pleasure.
Yeah, Molly wants, see...
Molly here and I we got some...
we got something we wanna tell you.
Something we want...
Go ahead, tell her.
Well, I have something
I wanna say too, Vince.
Yeah, but, we gotta tell you here
something that's very important.
Really? Coz what I gotta say
is pretty important too.
Yeah. But is it more important or
less important than what I gotta tell you?
Well, I don't know Vince,
I don't know what it is you gotta tell me.
May I just...
- Not a word, bitch.
Hey, Joyce, you don't have to talk...
Freak!
- Freak?
You bring her into my home.
Into my own house...
where I raised your 2 children.
You bring this...
this thing of yours.
Let me tell you something, Vince.
I'm gonna do you a big favor.
- What?
I'm gonna put both of you
out of your misery.
I would not be insulted
in my own home.
I want you gone, Vince.
Out of my life.
No more wandering around behind my back.
No more dirty cheap little lies.
No more lying in bed...
wondering who else has been touching my husband.
No more lying to myself
that it doesn't matter.
I found passion today, Vince.
It felt great.
I was touched and kissed...
...and held.
And I felt like you haven't
made me feel in years.
What are you talking about here?
I'm talking about Tony.
Tony? You did something with Tony?
I did more than something with Tony.
Dear...
...great in script.
Vince, get the key,
the key, I need it now.
Me and you, we're gonna go
for a walk right now.
It's not what you think. Just relax.
Settle down.
A little walk and a long talk.
Put down the knife, alright?
- Stay right there.
What're you wearing over there?
What's that you're wearing?
Vince!
Yeah, you better run,
you son of a bitch, I'm gonna kill you!
Dad?
Where are you going? You piece of shit!
You're a piece of shit...
...who screwed my wife and screwed my daughter.
And who's next? Who's next, my son?
Hey, didn't screw nobody, alright.
He didn't screw nobody.
Vince, you're making a big mistake.
Put down the knife, alright.
He's defending you.
Put down the...
- Just put down the knife!
Oh, dad, totally lame.
There's no more knife, alright.
- Okay, no more knife.
Peace, okay.
I don't know what you think
happened here but peace okay...
and we can talk.
- Okay, I'm sorry.
Leave him alone, Vince.
Rough.
Vince, stop it!
Stop it, Vince!
He didn't do nothing.
Hey, get off. Get out of here.
Do nothing? What about all that passion?
And all that crap you're talking about..
Yeah, what about yours?
Your Molly Ringworth over there.
Who I'm supposed to thank
for being in your life.
You bring your filthy girlfriend
into my house.
She's not my girlfriend!
I'm his manager.
Your what?
My manager for the Scorsese
and DeNiro movie.
What DeNiro movie?
I'm gonna be in a Robert DeNiro
movie with Martin Scorsese.
Your dad's an actor?
No, liar, he's a liar.
Oh, what kind of bullshit is that?
Actually, he hasn't been signed yet...
but he auditioned today and
apparently make quite an impression.
They called him back.
You went on a movie audition today.
That's right. That's what I've
been trying to tell you.
And Molly here she is a friend of mine...
a "friend". "Friend".
And we go to an acting class together.
And she's the one who told
me to go on the audition today.
And that's why I'm  here.
And that's what's happening.
What acting class?
When do you take an acting class?
When I play poker!
It's the truth, you see...
Vincent didn't tell because...
he has feelings of shame
and inferiority about his ambition.
Hey, don't go that far.
Oh, I don't believe you.
What? You know what,
I don't give a shit if you don't believe me.
In fact, I don't give a shit
if you don't believe me...
because you got a few things
to answer for yourself.
Like what's going on over here?
What? What?
Are you leaving me for her?
Oh come on, mom.
Dad couldn't get her.
Hey, little girl, I think you better shut
your mouth and mind your own business.
Anyway, what are you doing handcuffed
to that animal over there in that robe?
Tell him.
Yeah, tell him.
I was back at school...
Oh my God! Just tell him
the truth. You're all so sick.
I stole your car.
- You stole the car?
I boosted your goddamn car so I could
take off and get away from all your crap.
What is that gotta do with her?
The young one over there.
Go ahead.
Yeah, go ahead.
I'm a stripper.
A what?
What about those two things?
I paid for them myself, alright.
You go to college, you're in a school,
you got that scholarship.
They took it away, okay.
I can go back next semester but
I gotta pay for it myself.
And I'm gonna.
Why did they take your scholarship away?
Because I screwed up, okay,
Mom, I screwed up. Me.
And I got caught...
I got caught with pot in my room.
You smoked pot?
Yes, I smoked pot.
God, it's such a stupid word, pot.
They took away your scholarship...
and kicked you out of school
because of a little pot?
Oh sweetie, honey everyone smokes pot.
Okay, wait a second with the lovey dovey
thing here, we got a lot of things to settle.
You've stolen my car, you know I can
have you locked up in 10 minutes for that.
Fine, do it. At least
everyones honest.
You're so scared of your wife you
won't even smoke in front of her.
Vince? You're smoking.
No, no, I quit.
Liar. And you got your wife
thinking you got a girlfriend...
coz you're too scared to tell her
you wanna take an acting class.
This whole time, you got
this weird agenda with me
and you won't even tell me what it is.
Why did you get me out of jail, Vince?
Why did you bring me here?
- I told you I was a friend of your mother.
My mother never had a friend so
good they'd do me a right turn.
Everyone hated her.
She was a drunk and a whore.
And she got you to get me out of jail.
I don't know what the hell I'm gonna think...
Whatever I did, I did on my own.
Nobody puts me up to anything.
Your mother was a
goddamn psycho bitch.
And that's why I walked out of
her before you were born.
You're my father.
I'm your father.
Oh my God.
Wait a second.
Alright, what happened here?
Oh, no, no, sweetie.
Your son was a perfect gentleman.
How long have you known about this guy?
I've been trying to tell you
for years now. I just...
There's so much I wanna tell you.
I just could never...I could never
find which seems to be the right time.
I thought you were just sick of me.
- Sick of you?
No, scared of you maybe a little bit
but never sick of you.
You're like a...
you're the air that I breath.
Will somebody please uncuff me?
I can't believe...
I got your back.
You're my boy now.
Hey, come here, hug your brother.
Right now, let's go, hug your brother.
Well, mom, you were right.
Dad did have sex with Tony's mom.
Kudos to you!
Well, well done.
Molly?
Molly Charlsworth?
She left town, I think.
Isn't she your partner?
- Yeah.
Is she gonna be back?
- I don't think so.
One less actor in New York
for you guys to compete with.
You ready, Vince?
Yeah.
- Go ahead.
You know the day, you asked
me about my worst secret
my most personal secret
the secret of all my secrets.
At that time, I don't understand it.
But now I get it.
First, I wanna begin you why,
where I'm from...
My name is Vincent Rizzo
and I'm from City Island...
Somehow with Tony's appearance...
a lot of good things happened.
You are one lying son of a bitch!
To my husband, the best actor in City Island.
I guessed I should've looked for a musical.
How's that man? It's good?
- Fantastic.
To my father, the only actor on City Island.
- Hey, watch yourself.
And here, we're going again.
But it's not you, you were excellent, Vince.
We're making some adjustments.
- Okay, whatever. I'm here.
Every busy city needs an island of peace.
Just like every busy soul needs a place to propose.
Hey, Vinnie, get over here.
Me, I was lucky..
because God he has a way of busting you...
when you most need it.
And he has a way of giving you a second chance.
To attend for your screw ups.
Now, I got my second chance.
Okay, let's eat!