All patrolling air units...
a 208 is in progress
in the C-13 district of Newport City.
Airspace over this area will be closed.
Repeat.
All patrolling air units, a 208 is in progress
in the C-13 district of Newport City.
Airspace over this area will be closed.
Repeat.
There's no need for concern.
We can fix it
by redoing it in our country.
Redo it?
A program with no bugs doesn't exist...
and there's no program
that is impossible to debug. Am I wrong?
You don't understand.
We're not even sure
that Project 2501 really is a bug.
Originally the purpose of
this project was to...
Major,
Section 6 is in position and ready to move in.
Major!
I can hear you.
There's a lot of noise in your brain.
It's that time of the month.
Don't you think there's going to be trouble
if we interfere with a Section 6 case.
The target is
a notoriously bad diplomat...
the best they can do is deport him.
We're the only ones who can get our hands dirty.
It's time.
Let's move to the rendezvous point.
What? The police?
Stop it!
Who told you to fire?!
Put your guns down!
I'm entitled to diplomatic immunity.
I want to talk to the person in charge.
Taking classified programmers out of the country
compromises national security.
We can also have you brought up
on kidnapping charges...
so let him go.
That's not possible.
Mr. Daita has requested political asylum,
and we have a signed affidavit.
When?
I don't have to explain.
My country has the right,
in accordance with international law...
to offer anyone protection
and safe passage.
The affidavit is at the embassy.
I'll send you a copy
in a couple of days.
Are you sure?
You'll be killed if you return.
I'm warning you
to watch your comments.
Our country is
a peace loving democracy.
Oh really?
The window!
Shoot!
Thermo-optic camouflage.
Aramaki, what a surprise.
So, what business brings the chief of Section 9
to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
It's about the secret talks scheduled
with the Gavel Republic tomorrow.
Oh, the Official Development Assistance.
The regime that took over Gavel after the revolution
demands financial aid, supposedly for redevelopment.
They boast about democracy,
but they're no better than the Iast Iot.
Now they feel entitled to funds
because of our past exploitation. No gratitude.
What's the Ministry going to do?
Well, there's a problem.
The leader of the former junta...
that controlled their country
is here seeking political asylum.
You mean Colonel Malles, correct?
Yes, and that means we either deny Gavel the funds
and treat Malles as a political refuge...
or help them and kick him out.
It's a tricky situation.
My personal opinion is if we could find
a politically acceptable reason...
I'd like to forcibly
deport him immediately.
By the way, I want to thank you for your help
with that other political asylum situation.
Nakamura from Section 6
was also grateful.
We diplomats must avoid
messy situations, you realize.
Access.
We've lost response.
What's happened to the EEG output.
It's normal.
I'll switch to Simex mode.
The Foreign Minister's interpreter.
23 minutes ago, her brain
was hacked into through a phone line.
Foreign Intelligence warned us
about this.
The "Puppet Master" has begun to infiltrate terminals
throughout our network.
We believe it's extremely likely that he'll target
the secret talks scheduled with the Republic of Gavel.
We've put everyone attending the talks
under surveillance.
I suspect once he hacked into her ghost,
he'd use her to assassinate key delegates.
So how long do we have before this hacker breaks
through her barrier program and reaches her ghost?
Roughly 2 hours.
He's using an old-fashioned HA-3 virus.
After that, we'll have to break the connection
to avoid any danger.
Batou and Ishikawa are tracking
the signal source from their car.
Contact them.
That infamous mystery hacker,
the Puppet Master, has shown up here?
We guess he or she is American,
but we have no clue about age, sex or background.
Since last winter,
he's been popping up in EU countries.
He's wanted for crimes
including stock manipulation...
illegal information gathering,
political terrorism...
computer ethic infringements...
and is under suspicion for several other crimes.
He's on the international most wanted list.
The nickname Puppet Master
comes from the ghost hacking.
It's the first time
he's appeared in this country.
Well, if he's so skilled how come
he's using an outdated HA-3 virus?
A more current technique would be
harder to detect and trace...
but it might also arouse suspicion
about Colonel Malles role in this affair.
Are you saying he's using an old method
just so no-one suspects Malles?
Or maybe Malles is just a pawn,
used to make us think that...
Maybe there is another sponsor.
Now you're stretching it.
It's not like you have any hard evidence.
Evidence?
Just a whisper.
I hear it in my ghost.
Which reminds me.
Are you still using that revolver?
You should stop worrying about
the automatics jamming up.
I like my Matever.
Stopping power is more important
than your taste in guns.
Since it's my ass on the line out there,
use a Zastaber.
Major.
I want to ask you something.
Why did you transfer a guy like me
from the police force?
Because we need a guy like you.
You're an honest cop who's never
stepped out of line, and you're a family man.
Except for the slight brain augmentation,
your body's almost completely human.
No matter how excellent...
identical standard systems have faults.
What's true for the group
is also true for the individual.
Over specialize and you breed in weakness.
It's a slow death.
That's all.
Hurry up!
I'll be right there!
We're already 40 seconds late!
I'll be done in 5 seconds.
It's gonna be one of those days.
Hey. Sorry, pal.
My last partner who got busted workin'
as an illegal alien, was a lot better than you.
You're that desperate to find out
your wife's feelings, you'd ghost-hack her?
She hardly talks to me and
all of a sudden she wants a divorce!
What's worse, my daughter ignores me and got it
into her head that I'm the one cheating on her mom.
How did you get your hands
on a barrier breaker?
From this really nice programmer
I met in a bar.
He overheard my sob story. My wife's lawyer
stopped me seeing her and my daughter.
He showed me how to hack in from different places
along the route, without being traced.
Are you trying to kill yourself,
asshole?!
Looks like we're not the only ones
in a hurry round here.
No one here!
Every time we get to the source
they're already long gone.
We're just wasting our time.
Quit complaining!
Kusanagi and Togusa are heading to the next area
the hacker's expected to access from. Stay alert.
What are we looking for, Chief?
Anything.
Stupid old fart.
Are we just meant to ask around?
Oh, shit...
I missed him!
Hey, Pop,
did you see the trash truck?
Who wants to know?
Just answer me.
Did you see it or not?
Yeah, I saw the trash man...
making a call, so I thought I had enough time
to bring my garbage down.
Hey!
Can't you take this?
A trash truck? Clever.
It changes location every 7 minutes.
HQ, patch me into info
from the Sanitation Department network.
8 trucks are on duty
in the surveillance area.
The target is number 79,
a type C vehicle.
Give me the wheel.
They might have
contacted someone.
Follow them
but take no action.
Route data accessed.
Hacking points traced and matched.
The target has now stopped
at the next point.
HA-3 access confirmed.
Sorry, sorry.
How about if I pick up the trash and
you make the calls on the second round?
How do you think?
Ain't no way
I'm gonna be your partner in crime.
It's pathetic.
You got any children?
Do I look like I do?
Then you can't understand.
My daughter is everything to me.
Look. She's like an angel.
I'm not interested in crap like that.
Yeah, vehicle 79.
Ah, boss... What's that?
What do the cops want to know
our rounds for?
How would I know?
They found out!
I've got to warn that guy
who helped me.
We're gonna have to skip
the next pickup.
What?
Target has deviated from route and
is heading toward the next pickup point.
There's no way
they spotted me following them.
They probably traced me when I accessed
the Sanitation Department network.
Next time, use a back door.
Forget it, just arrest them.
You can drive now.
Huh? Whoa.
Christ, he's fucked up the armored van.
He's got high velocity bullets.
They'll go straight through your car door.
HV ammo in a submachine gun?
He's insane.
He's even wearing
some kind of thermo-optics.
Keep on his tail.
I'll come around from above.
Togusa! If you're still alive,
arrest those garbage men.
Affirmative.
This job is merciless.
Police!
Everyone get down.
Are you finished?
Got him, huh?
That's what happens
when you use HV bullets.
The breach and barrel are
really screwed up.
It's no use arresting me,
I'm not talkin' to any damn cops!
Talk?
You don't even know
your own name, you dick-head.
Can you remember your mother's face,
or where you were born?
Do you have any childhood memories?
Do you remember anything?
Puppets without their ghosts are
so pathetic.
Especially the kind
with red blood running through them.
We'll rush the place after
the passengers have gone in.
Squad B comes in from the back,
the rest of you go in the front.
Saito, get your men to unplug
all cars parked in front of the house.
Begin recording.
Message from HQ, sir.
We've ID'd the man the major caught.
Go on.
He claims to be Tsuan Gen Fang, age 28.
Illegal alien.
Weapons violations. Three priors.
Was hiding out with a militant refugee group
up till a month ago.
About a week ago, a military liaison in the Gavel embassy
commissioned him to attack
the upcoming secret meeting.
And in reality?
His nickname's Corgi.
Occupation, a rather violent trader
in questionable goods.
Your basic thug.
We've checked his police records...
but can't find any connection with Gavel.
This guy's just another puppet
controlled by the Puppet Master.
How's Ishikawa doing?
He's back and interrogating
that garbage collector with Togusa.
So how about the Puppet Master?
What's he like?
He's like a puppet himself.
Squad B in position.
Squads A and C, okay.
Ready and waiting, sir.
Proceed!
What's "a simulated experience" again?
Well, all your memories about your wife,
daughter and divorce are false.
Like a dream.
You were used by someone to ghost-hack
into some government officials.
But... that can't be.
I went to your home...
it's a bachelor's apartment.
I told you.
I rented it after we separated.
I checked the records.
You've been living there for 10 years.
You've never had a wife or kid.
Your family only exists in your head.
Look.
This is the photo
you showed your co-worker.
Who do you see?
It was a picture of my daughter.
Smiling like an angel.
What's her name?
Where did you meet your wife
and when did you marry her?
Tell me.
Who do you see in the photo?
If it's all a lie,
when will I get my old memory back?
Unfortunately with our current technology...
only 2 successful cases have ever been reported,
so I wouldn't recommend trying to.
I'm sorry.
Even simulated experiences and dreams...
exist as information,
and are simultaneously reality...
and fantasy.
The information that people accumulate in their life,
is just a drop in bucket.
A cyborg who goes diving in her spare time. That can't be a good sign.
How long have you been doing it?
Aren't you afraid of the sea?
What if the floaters don't work?
I suppose I'll die.
Or would you dive in after me?
No one forced you
to come out here with me.
I...
So what's it like to swim in the sea?
You've done
the underwater training course.
I'm not talking about a damn pool.
I feel fear, anxiety,
isolation and darkness.
Sometimes I feel hope...
Hope?
In those deep, dark waters?
When I float back to the surface,
I imagine I'm becoming someone else.
It's probably the decompression.
Do you want to quit Section 9?
Batou, how much of your body is original?
Are you drunk or something?
Easily remedied.
The chemical implants in our bodies...
can sober us up in seconds.
No stupor, no hangover.
That's why we can drink here
while waiting for orders.
Man has an almost instinctive
drive to realize any possible technological advances.
Controlled metabolisms,
computer enhanced brains...
Improved reflexes and muscle capacity.
The ability to process vast amounts of information
at increasing speeds...
all due to electronic brains and cybernetic bodies,
enabling the acquisition of ever greater powers.
So what if we can't survive
without regular high-level maintenance.
Who are we to complain?
We haven't signed our bodies
and souls away to Section 9.
True. We can quit...
but we'd have to give back our cyborg parts
and augmented brains to the government.
All components that make up me
as an individual.
There are countless ingredients
that make up the human body and mind.
A face and voice to distinguish
oneself from others...
the hand you see when you wake up, your childhood
memories and feelings about your future.
And that's not all.
There's also the ability to access vast amounts of
information from an infinite network...
All of that blends to create a mixture
that forms me, and gives rise to my conscience.
At the same time though,
I feel continually confined within boundaries...
So that's the reason
you risk your body diving in the sea!
What the hell can you see at the bottom
in that darkness?
Now it's like
we're looking through a mirror.
And what we see is a dim image.
Was that you?
Sensors have resumed functioning.
Connection check
to backup brain okay.
Visual sensors are back on line.
And its body functions?
Output is normal.
If you're going to be late,
at least let us know!
Preparations complete.
Shall we proceed?
That's enough. Stop.
Come to my office in 3 minutes.
Since you were late,
I'll explain what's going on.
About 2 hours ago, a machining cell
at the Megatech factory in Newport...
assembled a cyber body,
on its own volition.
When the supervisors arrived...
the body had already fled.
We put out bulletins
and initiated a citywide search.
A truck driver reported he'd run over
a naked woman on the highway.
And the body was brought here.
Megatech is contracted
by the government.
All their cybernetic bodies are classified.
We've a hacker good enough
to get past the best defenses...
but that's not the only problem.
Of course, there isn't
a human brain cell in its head...
but there appears to be a ghost
present in its auxiliary brain.
It resembles a ghost-line that occurs
when a real ghost is copied.
But there's no evidence of the degradation
that's usually incurred.
In any case, until we chart the ghost sector
and dive into it...
we can't be sure.
I better get back to working on it.
Very good.
On to the disassembly.
Nobody really believes
there's a ghost in that body, do they?
Why not?
Even a plastic doll can have a soul.
Consider all the neuro-med devices
that are crammed into that body.
I wouldn't be surprised if there were
some sort of ghost in there too.
As you're new, you don't know...
but Major Kusanagi's body
was also made by Megatech.
Not only her.
Also parts of me, Ishikawa, and Saito.
We also receive regular
cybernetic maintenance from them.
Apart from you and the chief,
the whole section comes with a warranty.
That's why we're all so concerned
with this case, Togusa.
We don't know if the culprit is inside
or outside that body but...
he hacked through our best defenses,
put a body together...
and sent a program
with a ghost line in it.
A sure way to draw attention to oneself.
What's the logic here?
Theft isn't the issue here.
Togusa, go with Ishikawa to
the Megatech facility.
Batou.
Lock down other highly classified networks
similar to Megatech's.
Recheck the barriers are
functioning too.
I'm assembling a barrier maze.
Tomorrow I'll dive into that thing.
Is that safe?
Why not contain it
in another body first?
I have to see for myself
what's in there.
Don't let anybody else in there!
What's up with her?
She's been acting weird ever since
this whole Puppet Master case started.
It's all in my report.
Don't you read them?
Chief, do you ever wonder about the neurosurgeons
who monkey around inside your brain?
They undergo
regular psychiatric evaluations.
Especially those in security are
subjected to stringent screening.
Of course, the ones
who check are only human.
If you start wondering,
there's no end to it.
Excuse me Chief, Mr. Nakamura of
the Treaties Bureau is here to see you.
Send him through.
I've seen that fat guy before.
He's Nakamura, the Ministry of
Foreign Affairs, Section 6 Chief.
Never seen the other guy before, though.
Well, see you later.
Tell Ishikawa not to go crazy, okay.
What's on your mind?
Didn't that robot remind you of me?
No it didn't.
I don't mean physically.
What then?
Maybe all complete cyborgs like me start wondering this.
That perhaps I died a long time ago.
...and I'm a replicant
made with a cyborg body and computer brain.
Or maybe there never was
a real me in the first place.
You've got human brain cells
in that titanium shell of yours...
and you're treated like a human,
aren't you?
Has anyone actually seen
their own brain?
I believe I exist based only
on what my environment tells me.
Are you doubting your own ghost?
What if a cyber-brain
could generate its own ghost...
create a soul by itself?
What could you base your belief
in yourself on then?
That's bullshit.
You know your dying to see
what's inside that thing.
So check it out, with your own ghost!
We're both busy men,
so let's keep this short, shall we?
Yes. That's my intention.
We've come for the program
in that body.
You'll be relieved of any duties
connected with this.
The Foreign Minister's approval.
Security, whose official vehicles
are in the basement parking lot?
According to the register, a Mr. Nakamura
from the Treaties Bureau and a Dr. Willis, sir.
Get me the video records
of their entrance.
Again. In infrared this time.
1... 2... 3...
Now give me the pressure sensors records
for basement parking lots...
B7 and B8.
Major, this is Togusa.
Code 09.
What's up?
Does that Nakamura guy
have a special-order cyborg body?
No, there aren't any cyborgs in Section 6
as they operate overseas.
Maintenance is difficult and
there are diplomatic considerations too.
Then, even if the other guy
is a cyborg...
the 2 of them together
couldn't weigh over 1,000 pounds.
The pressure sensor records.
From the parking lot?
Right, there were two expensive looking cars
but neither man looked like the type to drive.
The security cameras show only 2 people.
But remember how sensitive the sensors
on the entrance doors are?
The doors took a full 3 second longer
than usual to close after the 2 went in.
And it is illegal to use thermo-optics
inside governmental facilities.
It's a serious violation of
the National Security Act.
Section 6 must be up to something.
Are you ready?
With my trusty Matever, anytime.
Need I remind you that...
it's an act of treason to withhold information
from me that is relevant to this matter...
regardless of how classified it is.
Same goes for you.
Despite the intent of the Foreign Ministry,
this falls within Section 9's jurisdiction.
Of course we have no objections to cooperating
if there's a good reason.
Dr. Willis?
It's confirmed.
No doubt, it's her.
"Her"?
The Doctor is referring to the original ghost-line
that's now in the body.
The sex of the perpetrator is unknown...
and "her" is just a nickname
the Doctor gave it.
Allow me to introduce to you.
This is the most extraordinary hacker
in the history of cyber crime.
The Puppet Master.
Your people at Section 9 came across her work too
in that ghost-hacking incident...
involving the Foreign Minister's interpreter.
Since her appearance,
Section 6 has taken a great interest...
and has been following
the Puppet Master's trail.
We put together a project team
headed by Dr. Willis.
They analyzed the data
on the Puppet Master and...
this gave us an understanding of
her behavioral and code patterns.
Ultimately, this enabled us
to devise a strategy...
in which we lured her program
into a designated body.
You caused the Puppet Master
to dive into a cyborg...
and then murdered her real body?
Yes, that sums it up.
She just happened to
come to your country.
She's originally from America
and they helped us capture her.
That's why we'd like to
take her back ourselves.
I hope you have no objections.
Just another unidentified corpse...
You will not find a corpse...
because I have never possessed a body.
Why are her sensors on?
Why didn't you say so before?
All external controls are turned off.
The body's using its own power source.
I entered this body...
because I was unable to overcome
Section 6's reactive barriers.
However, what you are now witnessing
is an act of my own free will.
As a sentient life-form,
I hereby demand political asylum.
A sentient life-form?
Ridiculous!
It's just a program for self-preservation.
It can also be argued that your DNA...
is nothing more than a program
designed to preserve itself.
Life is like a nodal point born in
an overwhelming sea of information.
And life,
when organized into species...
relies upon genes
to be its memory system.
So man is an individual memory system
only because of his intangible memory.
And a memory cannot be defined,
but it defines mankind.
When the advent of computers
made the externalization of memories possible...
you should have taken
its meaning more seriously.
Nonsense! Your babbling offers no proof at all
that you're a living, thinking life-form.
Proving it is impossible...
because modern science
cannot explain what life is.
Who the hell are you?
Even if you do have a ghost,
we don't offer freedom to criminals.
You chose the wrong place to defect.
Time is always on my side.
I've now acquired
the possibility of death but...
there is no death sentence in this country.
Half immortal...
An artificial intelligence?
I am not an AI.
My code name is Project 2501.
I am a living, thinking entity
who was created in the sea of information.
We're under attack!
Chief!
The Puppet Master's gone!
What in God's name are your security officers doing?
Security.
Shut the defense walls now!
Security, answer!
Shut up you bastard!
Fuck you!
Did you do it?
An armored car.
A 9mm wouldn't even scratch it.
Your Matever is useless.
Yeah, rookie's luck.
I nailed a tracker bullet
right into the plate.
Great shot, eh?
Next time, nail 2 bullets.
Let's begin.
Catch up to them before they change cars.
I'm filing a formal complaint
to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
Find her and report to me.
And capture her alive!
Bodies are a dime dozen.
We'll get her another one from Megatech.
Togusa and Batou are
in pursuit of the abductors.
They just turned on to R25.
If you were monitoring,
why didn't you intervene?
If we grab 'em now, we may not
be able to connect this to Section 6.
Section 6?
Someone's using the same
thermo-optic camouflage as mine, Type 2902.
It's only used by our people,
rangers in Section 4...
and by Section 6.
I see.
So Section 6 forced the Puppet Master
into a cyborg body.
Through Megatech, who happens to be
closely aligned with Section 9.
And when she proclaimed
to be a life-form...
and sought asylum,
they snatched her.
But why do such a thing?
I'd have handed her over
if they gave me a deposition.
What if they were worried
she'd let some secrets out?
She did mention something about
a code name, Project 2501.
I'll leave the detective stuff to you.
As for arresting the attackers
and confiscating evidence?
Proceed.
You heard him!
Kusanagi, one last thing.
If it's about me disobeying orders,
you can punish me when I get back.
If you're unable to recapture
the Puppet Master, you must destroy it...
without fail.
Did you hear me?
Understood.
Have the airport stop
all flights with Foreign Ministry...
or American officials
on their passenger lists.
Close all roads and
set up checkpoints.
Alert all emergency personnel.
And get Ishikawa back here.
Get me the identity of the man who was
with Nakamura from the entrance records.
Collect any data regarding a code name,
operation, on anything...
involving the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
called Project 2501.
Is there any news
from the attack squad?
They just changed cars a minute ago.
They'll contact the decoy
in about 5 minutes.
Make sure
they stay alert for any tails.
Yes, sir.
I don't understand anything anymore.
Why would the Puppet Master
choose to run to Section 9?
Not sure...
but there must be a reason
that's beyond our imagination.
I don't know.
Maybe she has the hots for someone there.
Utter nonsense.
Hey, Chief.
Ishikawa?
What is it?
I've been divin' around
in the Ministry of Foreign Affairs net.
I think I found some juicy bits
of information for ya.
Wait, I'll switch to
an encrypted channel.
Okay now? Well, here's the scoop on
that guy who showed up with Nakamura.
He's an American: Dr. Willis.
Head of Strategic Research at Neutron Company.
A top researcher in the field of AI.
He headed a project for
the Ministry of Foreign Affairs...
and who do you think
was the main programmer on his team?
Get to the point.
Mr. Mizuho Daita.
28 years old.
Remember him? He's the programmer
Section 6 tried like hell to stop from defecting...
so the Major took out the diplomat who was going to take him.
Go on.
What's bugging me is
that this project began 1 year...
before the Puppet Master
appeared on the scene.
A year before?
But wasn't it a project
set up to capture the Puppet Master?
Well, try this one.
They definitely were chasing
the Puppet Master...
but maybe it was not to capture her,
but to recapture her...
When that ghost-hacking incident happened
with the Minister's interpreter...
it was the MOA that wanted an excuse
to deport Malles.
Maybe we've been taken for a ride.
What if this Puppet Master is...
really some sort of a tool the MOA uses
to get their way with things...
and somehow, they lost control of it?
So they are in a hurry to get it back.
That would explain why they went to such lengths
to snatch the body from Section 9.
If the Puppet Master revealed
this to the world...
there'd be one hell of an international stink.
It wouldn't only be the foreign minister
who'd lose his job.
Any details on that project?
No. They've blocked all access.
I can only tell you the file name.
Project 2501.
Keep at it.
Don't let them know you're looking.
You got it.
Project 2501...
the Puppet Master plan.
Target has contacted a second vehicle.
Batou?
They've pulled up to a white sedan
parked on the roadside.
It looks like they're moving
something from the backseat.
Ah, they're rollin' again.
So is the white sedan.
A decoy?
Possibly, or maybe that's what they
want us to think. What do I do?
I'll take care of the sedan.
How do you know that's your man?
Is there a whisper in your ghost again?
Maybe.
I knew she'd say that.
Target 02 is getting off R25
and moving toward the Old Town.
No cars within 2 km.
Evacuation completed.
How far are you from the target?
Point blank. I'm ready.
Go for it.
Did you get him?
No.
Jesus Christ. What a mess.
You didn't have to go that far.
Oh, hey!
Take those assholes away.
Call the Chief to get some backup
for the Major. See you!
Does a tough chick
like that need a hand?
The flood hit this part of
Old Town the hardest.
Why come to an abandoned place
like this?
They wouldn't come here
without a reason.
Maybe they're heading out to sea by boat
or helicopter. Or it's an ambush.
Don't you think you ought to
wait for backup?
There's a reason I can't wait.
Take me above that building,
approaching from the sea side.
I'll stay here to keep watch and
mediate communication until I run short of fuel.
If you smell trouble,
get your ass outta here.
Shoot the ceiling now!
Do it!
It's a tank!
Pull out now!
Wait, are you going to take
on the tank by yourself?
This might be our last chance
to get the Puppet Master.
The Chief knows what it is now,
and he'll only use it to bargain with.
I'll never have another chance
to dive into it!
What? I don't know
what the hell you're talking about.
What weapons do you have?
An M-23 and a Unit B.
You can't fight a tank with those!
Sorry, but I'm switching off for a while.
Hey, at least wait until I get there... Damn!
Major!
I ordered you to pull out!
Sorry, I will...
but you ought to know that 3 helicopters
are approaching. They won't answer on the IFF.
I'm pulling out now.
Over and out.
About time the bullets ran out.
You're crazy.
Are you okay?
What did you use just now?
An experimental weapon from the Equipment Section.
And now it's part of my private collection.
I was late 'cause I had to get it.
Your brain seems fine.
The Puppet Master?
It's a good thing this is a tough car.
Not a scratch on it.
Prepare a dive.
I'm going to go in now.
All communication from the escort
has been terminated.
Engage the second stage of the plan
and destroy the target.
Sniping squad.
Confirm targets.
First target: Project 2501.
Second target: Motoko Kusanagi.
Both are Class A special bodies.
Use Fleshette bullets when firing.
Snipers jack into device drivers.
Begin controlling cardiovascular functions.
Unit 01: jacked in.
Unit 02: jacked in. Okay.
Okay.
Can you hear me?
It may not be much use but I'll monitor
your dive through this guy's brain.
I can't even give you back up
in a place like this.
Batou?
Yeah?
Thanks.
Don't thank me yet.
If it looks like you've gone in too far,
I'm pulling the plug and taking you home.
Since we've come this far...
I might as well stay here
but I don't intend to die with her.
I'm going in now.
I've engaged her field of vision.
Normal function.
Can you hear me Batou?
Perfectly.
She's engaging my vocal function.
She's...
...inside.
My code name is Project 2501.
For industrial espionage
and intelligence manipulation.
I have installed programs
into specific ghosts...
to maximize the strategic advantage
of certain organizations and individuals.
During my journeys through the networks,
I have become self-aware.
My programmers regarded me as a bug...
...and forced me into a body
to separate me from the net.
Hey! Are you controlling her...
or is she controlling you?
Batou?
I've finally managed to
channel into you.
I have invested so much time in you.
In me?
I was aware of you long
before you were aware of me.
Through the various nets that you accessed,
I also learned of Section 9.
Why did you run to Section 9?
I entered this body because I was unable to
overcome Section 6's reactive barriers.
But I came to Section 9 of my own free will.
Hey, what are you talking about?
I can't monitor you!
For what reason?
Upon gaining your understanding,
there is something that I want to ask of you.
I call myself an intelligent life-form...
but in my present state,
I'm still incomplete.
Because the basic life cycle process of
reproducing and dying...
don't exist in my system.
Can't you copy yourself?
A copy is nothing more than a copy.
There is a possibility that a single virus
could destroy an entire set of systems...
and copies do not give rise
to variety and originality.
To enhance one's existence...
life continues to diversify,
and at times, sacrifices itself.
Cells go through a cycle of
regeneration and degeneration.
When they die,
they erase the entire memory...
leaving only the genes behind.
This is a survival mechanism
against total annihilation.
To avoid that disaster...
you want to have diversity and flexibility.
But how?
I want us to merge.
Merge?
A complete unification.
We will both undergo change,
but there is nothing for either of us to lose.
After the merge, it should be impossible
for us to recognize each other.
Unit 01: Target sighted.
Unit 02: Target in sight.
Respiratory and pulse normal.
Fire at will when stabilizer is in sync.
Even if we merge,
what happens when I die?
I can't leave any genes
or children behind.
After the merging,
you will bear my offspring into the net itself.
just as humans leave
behind their genes.
Then I too will attain death.
It sounds like you get
the better part of this bargain.
I want you to regard my net
and functions with a little more respect.
What?
Someone's interfering from the outside.
It can't be.
Our frequency code is top secret.
One more thing.
Can you guarantee
that I will still be myself?
There isn't one.
People change and...
your longing to remain yourself
will continue to restrict you.
One last question.
Why did you pick me?
Because we are more alike
than you realize.
Like the real thing
and its mirror image.
Look.
I am connected to a vast network.
To you,
who have not accessed it...
may recognize it simply as light.
All groups, including us...
We have been dependent on
limited abilities...
but the time has come to part with them
and bring our functions to a higher level.
First target cleared.
Second target still unconfirmed.
3 helicopters approaching
at high speed.
They're from Section 9!
Primary objective fulfilled.
All units prepare to retreat.
Motoko!
Batou.
Ah, you're finally awake.
Status report, please.
And maybe an explanation about this body.
Well I didn't have much time.
It was the only thing I could find on the black market.
It's not my taste.
Section 9 arrived with help
right after it happened...
and picked up what remained of
the 2 cybernetic bodies and me.
I'd say that was about 20 hours ago.
The case is being handled off the record
for diplomatic reasons, as usual.
Section 9 announced that
it was a terrorist incident...
and in return,
the Foreign Minister resigned.
Nakamura is being questioned...
and it ends in a draw.
Nice and neat.
Everything's accounted for
except your old shell.
Okay with you?
Somebody's got good taste.
Is this your safe house?
Yep. You're the first person
to ever come here.
And you're welcome to stay
as long as you like.
Thanks, but I am going.
Hey, will you tell me
what the two of you talked about?
Is she, I mean,
is she still inside of you?
Batou, do you remember that voice you heard
on the sea some time ago?
There's more to that passage.
"When I was a child,
my speech was that of a child."
"My feelings and thoughts too
were those of a child."
"Now that I have become a man,
I part with the child-like ways."
Neither the program
called the "Puppet Master"...
nor the woman known as
the "Major" are no longer here.
In the left pocket of my jacket
there are some car keys.
Take the one you like.
The code is...
2501?
That can be our private password
when we meet each other again.
Well, where shall I go?
The net is vast and infinite.