You fixed it yet?
Just a couple more minutes.
You said that an hour ago.
I promised
to make you dinner, right?
Yeah.
Well, I'm making you
a gourmet dinner.
Trust me.
It'll be worth the wait.
Surrender.
Hmm?
Surrender to the wonders
of takeout.
Oh.
I knew this was coming.
'Cause when your fingers dial
those seven little numbers,
it really turns me on.
Is that the best
you can come up with?
Yeah.
Wow. You are fast.
Who was it?
I don't know.
It doesn't even say
where it's from.
Well, there's
one way to find out.
Oh, Jamie,
you adopted us a baby.
A baby?
Have you seen this thing?
Well, who would send you
a doll?
I have no idea.
There's no card, no note.
His eyes look so real.
"I don't know about you, but
Lisa's hungry for Chinese. "
I think
my wife's gone crazy.
Oh, my God! This reminds me of
that poem from when we were kids.
What poem?
You remember. Come on.
That old ghost story about the
woman who had all those dolls.
"Beware the stare
of Mary Shaw
"She had no children,
only dolls... "
And something,
something scary.
Something, something... Boo!
I think you're having just a
little too much fun there, Lise.
Oh, baby, I won't let
the scary dummy hurt you.
Thank you. Thank you.
If you get Jamie to scream,
I'll make sure you get seven minutes
in heaven with my old Barbie. Deal?
"Yes, Lisa. "
God, I'm such a loser.
Good boy.
Jamie?
Baby, I'm back.
Lisa! What are you trying
to do? Burn the place down?
Lise?
Oh, Lisa.
I'm in here.
Dinner in bed again.
Lisa!
Yes, Jamie?
What's going on?
I have a surprise for
you, Jamie. For you, Jamie.
Lisa, this is not funny!
The strange is that she's
got no defensive wounds.
Now, if somebody was trying to turn
my face into a jack-o'- lantern,
I'd be fighting back a little.
Yeah, but then you always have
been a little feisty, my girl.
Ligature marks?
Not a one.
What about...
Drugs?
That's a gift. I think the words
here, and they come out there.
Preliminary results say no.
But the final tox results
won't be in for 48 hours.
Personally, I think only someone
high as a kite would kill his wife
and then pose her
as a mannequin.
But the weirdest thing
is her face.
I've never seen
anything like it.
You know what it was?
Your mistake?
It was the rose.
Yep. Boy, I'll tell you,
if I had a dollar for every time
some guy gave his wife a rose
on the day that he,
you know...
Like that's an alibi.
Alibi?
I didn't hear you.
Did you say something?
Why would I need an alibi?
I'm sure your lawyer
would want you to have one.
My lawyer?
Yeah.
I mean, the prosecution, they're
going to have your fingerprints,
no signs of forced entry
on your apartment,
and you as the last person
to see your wife alive.
I mean, that's a lot
to go up against.
You think
I killed my wife?
Excuse me?
Do you think
I killed my wife?
No. No, I don't think you did.
I'm just trying
to help your lawyer out.
I mean, he's going to need
something more concrete.
I mean, at least to shift
the suspicion away from you.
Suspicion? I mean, if you
want to talk suspicion,
why don't you start by looking at the
package that turned up on my doorstep?
Oh, yeah.
That package, right.
Let's see. You received
an unmarked package
just moments
before Lisa was killed.
Yeah. A package containing
a ventriloquist dummy.
Ventriloquist dummy. Yeah.
Well, the mystery toy
department is down the hall.
This is
the homicide department.
So unless you can tell me
how some puppet
ties into your wife's murder,
I don't see the relevance.
In the town where I'm from,
a ventriloquist dummy
is a bad omen.
It's kind of a local legend,
and some people believe that the dummy
brings death to those around them.
Okay.
Well, Jamie,
I've never arrested a dummy
for murder before.
But I have arrested
quite a few husbands.
You don't think it's weird
that this package arrives
right before Lisa is killed?
No, I'll tell you
what I think is weird.
You said that your wife spoke to you
just moments before you found her, right?
Yeah. Yeah. But she didn't have a tongue.
In fact, according to you,
she was already dead.
Now, see, to me, that's weird.
So, what're you going to do?
Arrest me?
Not yet.
Look, you can go, Ashen.
You're a free man for now.
Good.
It'll give me more time
to do your job for you.
Jamie!
I'm so sorry for your loss.
But I'm so glad
to have you home.
Oh!
My Lord, you must think I'm so rude.
We haven't even
been introduced.
I'm Ella.
I'm...
Well, I guess
I'm your stepmother.
Is he in?
Yes, he is.
Please come in.
Thanks.
There are some things that you
need to know about your father.
I know everything I need to.
Ella!
Who's down there with you?
Your father won't
fight you, Jamie.
He doesn't fight anyone,
not anymore.
Well, then you're not
married to my father.
Ella!
I can hear you.
Goddamn chair is stuck.
Here, Edward,
let me help you.
My son.
What a pleasant surprise.
What happened to you?
Your father had a stroke
two months ago.
Why didn't anybody tell me?
You never return my calls.
It's because I never know
what to say to you.
I take it I wasn't the easiest
person to get along with in the past,
but I've changed.
Really?
Yes. A stroke can do that
to a man.
Listen, I'm sorry
about your wife.
I hear you've
brought her home.
Yeah.
Don't worry.
I'll call Henry Walker,
make the arrangements.
No, that's okay,
I can take care of it.
Jamie, please. As your father,
it's the least I can do.
You've done the least
you can do my whole life.
It's too late
for charity now.
Is that why you've come here,
to remind me what a bad
father I've been to you?
In light of what has happened, I was
hoping we could put that in the past.
I didn't come
to talk about that, I...
I came to ask you something.
Do you remember when I was a
kid, Mom used to read me a poem?
Do you remember what it was?
What poem?
"Beware the stare
of Mary Shaw
"She had no children,
only dolls
"And if you see her
in your dreams... "
"Be sure you never,
ever scream"
You know it?
It's just a scary poem parents would
tell their kids to keep them in line.
No. It's more than just a ghost story.
And the adults believed in it, as well.
We live
in a small town, Jamie.
Small minds breed
small-minded superstitions.
That's all.
There's nothing else to tell.
Nothing?
Edward,
your son has been
through a lot.
Why don't we make up
a room for him?
No, that's okay.
I'm not staying long.
I got a funeral to prepare.
Jamie, Jamie!
Jamie! Please wait.
Won't you stay the night here?
It was nice meeting you, Ella.
Your father's changed. He's not
the same man that you remember.
Really?
You see that?
Mom used to be in that picture with
us, until he drove her to kill herself.
Had his second wife
in that one there.
But she was smart enough
to leave.
So, it's a good thing you're
going to outlive him, lady.
There'll be no one
to paint you out.
What more?
What more do you
want from me?
Peck, peck, peck,
peck, peck, peck.
I must say I was deeply
saddened to hear the news.
If you're up to it, I can walk you
through the various casket options we have.
Or we can do it later.
It's okay.
Let's... Let's do it now.
Okay. Now, I don't know
what your preferences are.
Have you spoken
to her family yet?
Only once. We didn't really
talk about casket choices.
When is she arriving?
Tonight.
Once the police have released
her body, then I'll pick her up.
Oh, I'll need you to fill out
these forms, at your convenience.
Jamie.
Jamie!
No, it can't be.
Marion?
Marion, is that you?
Marion, I told you
not to go down there anymore.
The silent time's here.
Now, come out of there
and go to bed.
She's here now.
I know it.
Marion,
I don't have time
to play games.
She won't find me down here.
Marion, I'm not
going to ask you again.
Let's go. Come on, come on.
You just shush now.
The silent time is here.
Go on.
Go on up. I'll be up later.
Did you see her? Did you?
When she killed your wife?
Did you see her do it?
Killed my wife?
What are you talking about?
"Beware the stare
of Mary Shaw
"She had no children,
only dolls
"And if you see her
in your dreams... "
Marion!
She's here. No one's safe.
No one's safe.
Come, Marion.
Marion, you leave him alone.
No one's safe.
This is not the time.
What's she talking about?
I'm sorry, Jamie. She doesn't
know what she's saying.
She's here!
Come. I'm going to take you home
now. Let's go, let's go. Come on.
You must bury the doll!
Bury the doll!
Leave him alone.
Leave him alone. Come on.
Marion, we'll go home now.
Who dug you up?
Thought I asked you
not to leave the city.
I came to bury my wife.
You got a problem with that?
Nope.
Problem is, she's not the
only one that you came to bury.
So, you've been
following me now?
You know, Jamie,
you really are forcing me
to use the word "perplexed"
an awful lot lately.
You mind telling me
what the hell that is?
Okay. Since you don't want
to answer my questions,
maybe you'd like
to answer his.
"Why did you bury me, Jamie?
"Is it because I'm evidence
in a capital crime,
"a crime that you are
the number one suspect in?"
You understand
what I'm saying here?
It's like I told you before.
The night Lisa was murdered,
somebody sent it to me.
It just arrived
on our doorstep.
So, why'd you bury it?
It came from that cemetery.
I was just putting it back.
In the cemetery?
There's an old ghost story around
here about a woman named Mary Shaw.
She was buried
with her doll collection.
Now, the story goes, "If you ever
see her, make sure you never scream. "
Or what?
Oh.
Or you end up
without a tongue.
I guess your wife
didn't listen, then, huh?
You son of a...
Hey! Hey!
Settle down, Jamie.
Let's not add assaulting an officer
to your list of offenses here.
So you're trying to tell me
that a ghost killed your wife?
I don't know,
I don't know.
What do you know?
I do know
whoever sent this to me
either knows who killed my
wife or did it themselves.
Hmm.
That's a theory.
I'm going to go.
And I hope you don't mind me taking
our little friend here with me,
seeing as he's evidence
and all.
Great.
Good night, neighbor.
Neighbor?
Sleep tight.
You know, I noticed
you have very smooth skin.
What's your secret?
Oh.
Well, that never works for me.
Friend of yours?
You said Mary Shaw
killed my wife.
Why would you say that?
Marion.
Marion, please!
Yes, I know, I know...
What do you know
about Mary Shaw?
I didn't say anything! I...
You're... You're not
supposed to have that.
Where did you get that?
Maybe you can tell me.
It's hers!
Who? Mary Shaw's?
We don't say her name
around here.
You don't say her name.
Well, why don't you try, huh?
It might just help me
find out who killed my wife.
There are things you remember, and
there are things you can't forget.
Like the look on that
woman's face when she died.
Her name was Mary Shaw, the
ventriloquist who lost her voice.
Back when I was a boy, those were
the glory days of Ravens Fair,
and the town built itself
a grand old theater,
the Guignol Theater,
out on Lost Lake.
I only ever went there once.
Ladies and gentlemen,
prepare to be astounded.
Prepare to be amazed.
Witness Mary Shaw give life
to the boy made of wood.
Where is Billy?
Billy!
Where are you, Billy?
You won't find me, Mother!
I knew
you were hiding out there!
You, there!
Could you check
under your seat for me?
He's here!
Would you mind
bringing him to me?
Good boy.
Say thank you.
Thank you, Henry.
Is that right, young man?
Is your name Henry?
Well, I guess my boy's
had his eye on you.
Now, why did you
run away, Billy?
Don't I treat you well?
Oh, yes, you're the best
mother I could ever hope for!
It's just that it gets so
dusty inside that little box,
it makes me want to...
Want to what?
Want to...
Oh, Billy!
You sneezed all over my shoe!
I'm sorry, Mother.
I can't help it.
I can see
your lips moving!
What?
Who said that?
I did. I can see it.
Her lips are moving.
What do you say
to that, Billy?
Young Michael here doesn't
think you're a real person!
What do you mean, Mother?
He thinks you're a dummy,
and that I'm doing
your voice for you.
But that can't be true!
There's no way you'd give me
all the good lines!
Forget about him, Billy!
There will always be doubters!
I don't want
to forget, Mother!
I think we should show
this boy just how real I am.
I'm just as real as him!
No.
I'm afraid we must go on with the show.
No! I'm as real as you are,
and I'll show you!
Leave him alone, Billy!
I'll show him
what it's like, Mother!
Listen to me! That's enough!
I'm as real as you!
No more!
Bring him up here!
Now who's the dummy?
Some weeks later, that disbelieving
little boy went missing.
Gone without a trace.
But I always felt that Mary
Shaw played some role in it.
And not long after that,
she was murdered.
Who killed her?
No one ever found out.
In her will, Mary stated that her
dummies were to be buried with her,
her children,
as she called them.
All 101 of them.
Her body was brought
to my father's mortuary,
so he could begin work
on her other final request.
Not only did she ask
to be buried with her dolls,
she asked to become
a doll herself.
Henry, are you all right?
Ever since she was buried, Ravens
Fair has been plagued by death,
families murdered.
They were found
without their tongues.
Posed in family portraits.
Your wife's is the last.
How could you take
these pictures?
No, I have to take pictures.
It's part of my business.
Who would have dug up
the dummy and sent it to me?
I don't know.
No one in this town dares
speak Mary Shaw's name,
let alone go near her grave.
They know she won't stop
killing until the screaming does.
You said she lived out
at that old theater, right?
The one on Lost Lake?
Jamie!
Jamie, please!
Please be careful.
If you go looking for answers,
you just might find them.
That's what I'm counting on.
Morning, Mary.
I'm just going to go
check in on the kids.
Mama! Mama! Mama.
What do you want
with him? What is it?
What do you want?
We did what you wanted.
We put you in there with
your family, all together.
Why can't you
just leave us alone?
Why won't you?
I didn't do anything!
Yes, you did. You talked.
I didn't talk! I didn't!
I didn't say anything!
I didn't!
Hey!
Say something.
Why have you gone so quiet?
I'm putting you back where
you belong, once and for all!
He talked to me!
Stop it!
He did, he talked to me,
he talked to me.
Marion?
Marion, I'm sorry
I yelled at you.
Marion?
You don't have
to hide anymore.
This will all be over soon.
Marion?
Marion, now
you come on out now!
Ma...
Marion?
Marion, open the door.
Marion! Come on,
no games, Marion!
Open the door!
Marion, open this door,
please! Marion!
Hello, Henry!
Oh, my God.
You're voice
is mine now, Henry.
Jamie, you're
just in time for dinner.
I'm not hungry.
It's soup.
Delicious, too,
if I must say so myself.
I'll vouch for that.
I didn't come here to eat,
I came to talk
about Mary Shaw.
You lied to me.
No, I didn't.
Sit down.
No, I want the truth.
What does Michael Ashen and our
family have to do with Mary Shaw?
Fine.
When he was a boy,
your great-uncle, Michael
Ashen, vanished without a trace.
For our family, there
was only ever one suspect,
Mary Shaw.
So, they dealt
their own justice.
They forced her to scream.
Then cut out her tongue.
Our family killed her?
Along with others
from Ravens Fair.
But she didn't stay dead.
She came back
and took her revenge.
One by one, each of the men
involved were killed.
Their tongues ripped out.
And then the same thing
happened to their wives.
And then their children.
And their children's children.
All these years you've resented
me for sending you away,
but I did it to distance you
from this curse.
Distance?
Well, it found Lisa!
Lisa's death made me realize
we can't run from our fate.
Spirits have long memories.
She'll come for us in the end.
Now I'm paying
for the sins of my fathers.
Jamie, I'm sorry.
All I ever meant to do was to protect
you, even if it earned your hatred.
I don't know how,
but one way or another,
I'm going to stop this thing.
Please, Son!
Well, hey, there!
I was wondering if you could help
me with a missing person's case.
Wait.
I'm looking for a male, brown
hair, he's around this tall,
sometimes seen
with a hand up his ass.
Actually, his brothers and sisters
have just gone missing, too.
What are you talking about?
Somebody dug them up.
All 100 of them.
What I want to know is
who did it and why.
So do I!
Don't give me some ghost story about
a woman who kills you if you scream,
because nobody in this town
has ever heard of Mary Shaw
or your little fairy tale.
They're lying!
They're afraid!
Afraid of what?
Afraid of ghosts?
Or are they afraid of talking to the cop
who's investigating your wife's murder?
They have no reason
to protect me.
But they believe in Mary Shaw.
That's why they won't answer
your stupid questions.
No, it's you who won't
answer my questions, Jamie.
That's why I'm going to arrest
you for stealing evidence.
Then I'm going to sit
you down, and you will...
What do you want
me to tell you?
Something less perplexing
than a ghost story. Come on.
Jamie, is everything
all right?
It's for you.
They said it was urgent.
Go ahead.
Hello?
Jamie.
Who is this?
Jamie?
Henry?
I can prove it.
Henry, I can't hear you,
you're breaking up.
I can prove it.
I can... you didn't kill her.
There's a way, at the theater.
Meet me at the theater.
It's on Lost Lake.
Yeah, I know where it is.
Now, Jamie.
Henry, wait!
What have you found?
Henry! Henry!
That was Henry Walker
from the funeral home.
He says he can prove
I didn't kill my wife.
Convenient time for him to call. Let's go.
Wait, wait, wait. I'm going
to meet him at the theater.
That's where I'm going.
No, you're going with me.
Your appointment
with me comes first.
You wanted answers.
I'm giving you answers.
Camp is over. I'm done with
the ghost stories. Let's go.
Listen, we're talking
about my wife here. Come on.
Do us both a favor, Jamie.
Don't make me cuff you
in front of your mom.
Jamie!
Jamie. Jamie!
Hey, you don't want
to make me chase you!
Jamie!
I don't have
a full tank of gas!
Jamie!
Henry?
Hello?
Where are you?
Henry?
Come on, Jamie.
I'm up here.
I'm coming, Jamie.
Jamie?
I know you're here.
I'm in here.
Henry?
Guess again.
He's here.
Nobody's here. Our boats
were the only two out there.
Listen, I'm telling you
he's here!
And I'm telling you
he is not here!
Yes, he is.
If you say I told you so,
I'll shoot you.
Where the hell are you?
Hang on to this for a second.
Where are you going?
Remember, whatever happens,
don't scream.
Jamie. Jamie?
Jamie?
Jamie!
You follow me.
Yes, sir.
All right, Jamie,
where is he?
You know, if I see
one more of these...
They're all here.
Yep.
All home.
Someone brought them
back here.
All but one.
What?
What the hell is that?
Is that a doll?
It's not a doll.
It's a boy.
You mean, it was a boy.
It's me.
All right, I get it.
I think we just solved a
70-year-old missing person's case.
Who was that?
A long-lost relative.
This is how it starts.
What's going on here, Jamie?
Jamie.
What the...
Mary Shaw?
Clever.
Who's there?
Show yourself!
Come out!
What do you want?
To silence all those
who silenced me.
Is that why you killed
Michael Ashen?
So hard to construct
the perfect doll.
Sometimes you have
to use existing parts.
"I love you, Mommy.
I love you, Mommy. "
"I love you.
"I love you, Mommy. "
Why Lisa?
Why did you take her from me?
Come closer and I'll tell you.
Don't go back there. Don't.
Come on, come on. Don't go.
Come closer.
I'll whisper it to you.
You weren't the last Ashen.
The last Ashen was inside her.
Don't scream.
The doll!
What the hell's
going on here, Jamie?
What's going on?
She's living in the dolls!
What?
Destroy the dolls!
I am!
All of the dolls!
Jamie! Run!
Come on!
One left.
Henry!
Please. Please.
Please.
Please say
something.
Shit.
Marion. Marion, listen to me.
Where is the dummy?
He took it.
Who took it?
Mr. Ashen.
Mr...
Marion, my father
is in a wheelchair.
He never leaves the house.
He left this house.
He had the doll.
It was him.
Why did you
bury me, Jamie?
I'm in here!
Dad?
I take it I wasn't the easiest
person to get along with in the past,
but I've changed.
Jamie!
Soup! Delicious, too.
I'll vouch for that.
Jamie, I can prove
you didn't kill her.
Jamie!
So glad to have you home.
Now who's the dummy?
No!
"Beware the stare
of Mary Shaw
"She had no children,
only dolls
"And if you see her
in your dreams
"Be sure you never,
ever, scream"