999, indeed.
I haven't heard of such
a number for a house.
Yes?
Forgive my boldness, sir,
but wooden leg or no wooden leg,
you are this child's
last surviving relative.
Her father named you
as guardian in his will.
Yeah. I don't dispute that.
I merely point out
that this house is a shrine
to paleontology.
There's no corner in it for
a small girl... or her nurse.
We require two rooms.
That is all.
Some of these stones
could go to a museum.
My fossils?
In a public museum?
This has got nothing to do
with fossils.
If you don't want the child,
you should say it straight out.
But she'd be miserable here.
My parents are dead.
I'd be miserable anywhere.
Smilodon Popularis.
Why don't you just stick a knife
in my heart?
They're all magnets for dust,
and that big cat
was plain unpleasant.
It's a saber-toothed tiger,
Nana.
It's lovely.
An armadillo skeleton!
Goodbye!
I keep a pack of women
in this house!
There isn't one of them about
anywhere when they're wanted!
Oh! Darling Gum!
We weren't expecting you.
Oh, ship sank... iceberg.
If you don't mind me asking,
what have you got in the bag?
Ah. A surprise.
Let's hope it's not
another fossil.
The world is full
of entrancements, woman.
Not all of them
are made of stone.
A baby?
Found it...
floating on a lifeboat.
Both parents drowned.
Awful bloody shame.
A baby? A baby just like that?
What will people say?
Have you no regard for
your great-niece's reputation?
Well, I-I'll put
a notice in The Times...
"Professor Matthew Brown adopts
entirely unrelated child."
-But, Gum...
-I thought women liked babies.
They like babies that are in
good order... babies with names.
Ah.
Well, I thought perhaps Pauline.
And surnames.
Fossil.
It's not as though we've got
an empty room to put her in.
You don't mind, do you?
Gum, I came here
with nothing once.
That's the spirit.
Where are you actually going?
Siberia.
I'll bring you back a souvenir.
No. Not another one.
Mm.
Red Cross hospital
outside Vladivostok.
Mother died when it was born.
What about the father?
Salt mines... worked to death.
Awful bloody end.
Yeah, they called it Petrova.
Needs feeding up a bit.
It is to be hoped
this one has brains.
It's easy to see who's going to
be misplaying in my nursery.
"Dearest niece,
another small Fossil
from your Great-Uncle Matthew.
Daughter of a dancer.
Mother has no money
and no time for her offspring.
She sends a pair
of ballet shoes enclosed."
He says, " I regret
not delivering the child myself,
but I ran into a friend about
to leave for the Galápagos.
There's enough money in the bank
to last you for five years.
P. S... Child's name Posy.
Unfortunate but true."
Ballet shoes, indeed.
Change of clothes
would be more useful.
Or a feeding bottle.
"To the little Fossils."
"Turquoise for Pauline.
Pearls for Petrova.
Coral for Posy."
Make the most of it.
That'll be the last we hear
from him for quite some time.
I bet Gum had a car.
Only a man with a car
would've bought a house
at the far end
of the longest road in London.
Garnie said he used to
come and go in taxis.
I wish we could.
I'd be happy
if they let us get the bus.
The professor may have had
his faults, Petrova.
Might I remind you,
he had but the single leg.
You three have got
a full pair each.
So you can save the penny
and walk and be thankful.
The Rockefeller family
we are not.
At least you get to go
to school.
I still have to do lessons
with Garnie
and take an extra walk
at lunchtime every day.
If I have to look
at the dolls' houses
in the museum one more time,
I shall be sick.
That's enough, Miss Madam.
All over my outdoor shoes.
Then I shan't be able
to go anywhere.
We've had more fuss from
Miss Posy about her education.
Cromwell House is out
of the question, isn't it?
It's not just that I can't send
Posy to Cromwell House.
Give it here!
Get off!
I'm having to take
the other two away.
I have to give notice to Clara.
There's no money left.
Nothing in the bank at all.
I'm so sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
It's not news.
Isn't it?
Been looking through
situations vacant in the papers.
I didn't think you'd notice.
I brought you up.
I notice everything.
The trouble is, Nana,
unless somebody advertises for
a paleontologist's assistant,
I'm not qualified for anything.
There's a way 'round everything
if you stop and think.
I finished my fractions.
Already?
They were the hardest
in the book.
She'll have to sit there quietly
with her magazine.
You can't be setting
any more sums.
You've got to go to Selfridges
and get those eiderdowns.
Petrova, darling, would you go?
You're only reading.
-Good afternoon.
-I like your car.
How are you finding
the acceleration?
Terrific. Naught to 40
in about three minutes.
Is your mother at home?
Oh, we haven't got a mother.
And it's all right.
You don't have to say
you're sorry.
How do you do?
I've just come about the room.
Oh, do come in.
Forgive me. I was trying
to clean a fireplace.
I don't know how long I'd stay.
I've only just got back
from Kuala Lumpur.
Petrova! Have you been...
Well, um...
there's no minimum agreement.
Nana,
Petrova's been wearing my...
This is nice.
Put photographs on here.
Good afternoon.
Have you come about the rooms?
With particular regard
to shelves.
And smoking.
I'm Dr. Smith.
This is Dr. Jakes.
Do come in.
Rather smart.
Very nice aesthetic.
Come in.
Nana said you might need this.
Oh! How kind.
Thank you, my dear.
Well, we... we both had
lengthy careers in academia.
It all adds up
to quite a lot of books.
Most of them hers.
I specialized in Shakespeare.
Dr. Smith is a mathematician.
Where do you go to school,
child?
We don't.
Garnie, our guardian,
teaches us from home.
Good God, that must be dull.
Oh, that is quite an adventure,
having relatives by accident.
Such a unique name.
Fossil.
I suppose it is.
I always thought Smith
was such a beast of a moniker.
Try doing anything remarkable
with that.
And heredity is such a burden.
If I made the name Jakes
worthwhile,
people would think it was
because of my grandfather.
Who knows what you three
might achieve?
You ought to try to do something
for your country.
Fossil would look splendid
in the history books.
What do you think
she meant by "history books"?
I'm not sure.
I suppose they meant giving some
sort of service to our country.
We ought to make a vow.
A vow?
To our country?
A promise... to ourselves.
Like this.
Put your hands on mine.
We three Fossils vow to put
our name in the history books
because it is uniquely ours
and ours alone,
and no one can say it's because
of our grandfathers.
We vow.
Posy!
Ow!
What's that?
I shall be out every day
from 8:00 till 7:30.
I bathe three times a week,
and I never eat breakfast.
Oh.
Strong floor.
Was this a ballroom?
Not while I've been living here.
Do you like to dance, too, dear?
Perfect.
Come on.
The more, the merrier.
Tango!
Come here, little one.
Come on.
It's going to be fine.
Whee!
Well, Miss Brown, I will take
this room on one condition.
Oh, please.
Just let them audition.
I've been on the staff
of the academy for years,
and I cannot recommend
the place enough.
I can't afford the fees,
Miss Dane.
Madam Fidolia is a refugee
from Russia.
The Revolution completely did it
for her.
She'd been such a favorite
of the czar.
She has a history of taking on
girls from impoverished homes.
She trains them for nothing
and then takes 10% of
their earnings when they work.
They'd be sent out to work?
As soon as they're old enough
to have a license.
But I don't want the children
going on the stage.
And I'm quite sure
that Nana doesn't either.
Whilst I don't care
for Miss Dane
casting aspersions on this home,
you might say that Posy's
bound to dance anyway
given that she came with
her own little ballet slippers.
Pauline does nothing
but look in mirrors and recite.
And as for Petrova,
all she thinks about
is aeroplanes and engine parts.
Been trying to turn her into
a lady for the past 10 years
and got nowhere.
-So if this Madam Folderoll...
-Fidolia.
...proves willing to try,
I would let her.
Miss Brown,
we request a consultation.
Now?
Um, the fact of the matter is,
my dear, we very much doubt
whether you're qualified
to teach those children.
But I'm very well grounded
in natural science,
and I've got
my school certificate.
I did consider the school
at the top of the road, but...
You can't send them there.
They'll get lice.
My opinion entirely.
Frightful accents.
Which wouldn't help their
chances in the theater at all.
My dear, life can be
a surprising affair,
as Dr. Smith and I found out.
We both felt
that we should retire
but find that we are unsuited
to a life of idleness.
And more to the point,
we miss our teaching.
We should very much like
to coach the girls.
All-'round education,
specializing in mathematics
and literature.
The children will be prepared
to take their school certificate
and matriculation.
No charge. Ours to suit.
What do you think?
I don't know what to think.
Do you want your charges
educated?
And do you want them trained
to earn a living?
I want both.
The world isn't kind to girls
who can't support themselves.
Careful!
Come on!
Tsk.
Bare legs in the street.
Do they look smart, Nana?
No, but they look neat.
Petrova, will you
at least try and smile?
I swear the face on that child
would stop a clock.
And shuffle, shuffle,
hop, step, tap...
There it is.
And up, Muriel!
Should we knock, do you suppose?
Posy.
It's so gloomy.
Ah.
The Fossil sisters.
How do you do?
I'm Pauline.
No.
All my pupils,
morning and night,
before or after class,
whenever we meet,
they say "Madame" and curtsy.
So...
Madame.
Which is Petrova?
-Me.
-You are Russian.
Yes.
You speak Russian?
But you feel Russian?
Actually, she's always said
she couldn't feel more British.
You are the first compatriot
of mine to come to my academy.
I will make wonderful artist
of you.
You must be Posy.
Madame.
5, 6, 7, 8!
And smile!
Smile!
You don't see Shirley Temple
with a gloomy face!
Moment.
-Madame.
To center, if you please.
I think polka, Mrs. Davis.
"Stockinette vests, buff.
Two each.
Royal blue cotton rompers.
White tarlatan ballet dresses.
Two each.
White knickers, all frills.
Two black sateen
elocution overalls per child."
How are we going to
make it all by Monday?
I don't care
if we have to sew all night.
This is the biggest chance
these girls have ever had.
# Life is just
a bowl of cherries #
# So live and laugh at it all #
All the way up
to her darling derriere.
# Laugh at it all #
There's no point making me
into a wonderful artiste.
I already know
what I really want to be.
Racing driver?
I want to fly planes,
like Amy Johnson.
Very laudable ambition.
It's not because
she's fashionable
and in all the magazines.
It's not even
because I love engines.
It's... the idea that
there are roads in the sky,
ways 'round the world
that no one has discovered.
Roads in the sky.
And until I can do that,
I'd like to work with cars.
Well, that's good.
'Cause I've just bought
a garage.
A garage?
It's gonna be tough going
for the first few months.
I might need some help
from time to time.
All right.
When you said
you were going to make a drink,
I thought you meant
a cup of cocoa.
Oh, be a sport.
Look, I've even got a jar
of maraschino cherries.
I absolutely promise
not to get you tight.
This is the way they used to
mix them at the Ritz
when I was in
"Miss Rosebud's Bouncing Babes."
You drank cocktails
when you were a bouncing babe?
Oh, I was practically 19.
Miss Rosebud had to bind
my bosoms flat.
Otherwise they bounced rather
more than was approved of.
Chin-chin.
The girls will be happy,
won't they?
Oh, my darling.
You don't even need to ask.
# It's just the time
for dancing #
# Tomorrow is your day #
# Go where the music's calling #
# And dance the blues away #
# And all you need to ask for
is just one dance more #
Hurry up, Pauline!
You'll have to hang on!
Need a hand?
Oh, you are kind.
But they won't take long.
You know, when I was at school,
shoe-cleaning was a punishment.
Matron would say, "Clean them
till they shine like mirrors.
Give you time to reflect
on your misdeeds."
There was a fire in that room.
I always quite enjoyed it.
Well, Mr. Simpson.
You are a gentleman.
Let's leave that to me.
There's a bit of a knack
with tap shoes.
I'll, uh, I-I'll...
I'll let you get on, then.
Thank you.
Do you know sometimes I think
heaven sent those lodgers
to this house?
Not a moment too soon,
if you ask me.
We really need to get
that wiring mended.
And you're looking very thin.
I've always been thin.
And you're going gray.
I am not.
I just got the odd silver hair.
I'm starting to rehearse
my m'audition in a week.
What is a m'audition, anyway?
It's what you have to have
to show your managers.
It means "my audition."
But over the years,
it's run into one out of habit.
Typical academy.
Always got to be a special word
for everything.
Anyone who goes out
for any audition anywhere
has to sing, dance, and recite.
Doesn't matter
which school you train at.
It's what you have to do.
I'm dreading my next birthday.
I'll have to get a license
and tap-dance on the stage.
I don't want to tap-dance
either.
But I think I'd like to act.
How long will it be
till these fit?
Another hole
in my elocution drawers.
It's massive.
Right.
Today's French acting class
is canceled.
Anyone involved in the choral
speaking championships,
please go and wait
in studio one.
Posy Fossil?
Madame would like a word.
Winifred Bagnall
and Pauline Fossil,
stay here and speak to me.
You better not be in bother.
Petrova?
Haven't you got anywhere to go?
No, not now.
Well, dear, wait outside while
I have a word with these two.
Yes, Miss Jay.
There's an audition tomorrow.
The Princess Theatre.
You are both to be there
punctually at noon, and...
...I want you to style your hair
like this.
Is it for "Alice in Wonderland"?
Mm.
Girls going for Alice
always wear a ribbon.
Wish it wasn't the Princess,
though.
It's such a mean management.
One ought to get six,
but it's more likely four.
They might squeeze five.
Five what... shillings?
Pounds... per week.
Don't you need any money
at home?
You will attend
no further classes
with your sisters and Miss Dane.
You will no longer study
tap dancing.
character dancing.
You will no longer study
singing, musical comedy,
or mime.
In future,
you will receive instruction
only in classical ballet.
And all that instruction
will come from me.
You are the first child
in the history of the academy
to come entirely
under my personal supervision.
You have the potential to be
a truly remarkable dancer.
As remarkable as you?
Oh, my child.
Much, much more remarkable
than me.
But, Sylvia.
She needs an attractive frock
with a full-flared skirt
in order to show off her dancing
to advantage.
Can't she just wear
a practice dress
or go in a jersey and skirt?
Oh, darling, are you mad?
She has to look quite perfectly
turned up.
Otherwise, she simply
will not stand a chance.
Pauline, performance
comes from within.
When I watch you reciting Puck,
I don't see
Pauline Fossil, schoolgirl.
I see a queer, mercurial
woodland creature.
In a jersey and skirt.
Irena, that is unhelpful.
I still don't see what's wrong
with cotton.
From the summer before last!
She's outgrowing them all.
'Round the bust.
-Shut up, Posy!
-Be quiet, Posy.
Less of the bust chat,
thank you.
Oh, I'll be quiet.
But not until I've said
that I think it's very unfair
that in the middle of all
this fuss about Pauline's frock
and Pauline's audition,
not one person has said
they're pleased
about Madame's plans for me!
I can't go looking like this.
Posy, that's an absolutely...
They have a flap on?
It's a flap about money.
And Garnie says we shouldn't
discuss that sort of thing.
Easily done...
...when there's plenty about.
Have you ever been poor?
Dreadfully poor.
Have you ever been in...
in a pawnshop?
More than once
by the time I was your age.
There's one just off
Earl's Court Road.
Nana says people
borrow money there
in exchange for items of value.
She said it's a facility
for the desperate.
Are you desperate?
Are things really so bad?
We do have items of value.
What I propose is this.
I will personally advance you
the sum of £ 4 and 10 shillings
in exchange for custody
of the necklaces.
And Garnie will not be told
of this arrangement.
And if she asks any questions,
I shall say I've had a windfall.
I'll sign.
Pauline will then use
the advance
to purchase
an appropriate audition frock
and will then buy the necklaces
back in small installments,
always provided
she gets the part.
No matter how long
the process takes,
no interest will be charged.
# You can't escape #
# It's in your memory #
# By morning, night, and noon #
# She will leave you #
# And then come back again #
# A pretty girl
is just like a pretty tune #
She's very good.
She's the best all-'round
student the academy's ever had.
I have a hole underneath
the right arm on my frock.
I had to change my position
for the attitude at the end.
Little fair girl in black.
What's your name?
Pauline Fossil.
Come down to center stage.
Would you like to sing first,
or would you like to recite?
I'll recite.
Puck,
"A Midsummer's Night Dream."
I am that merry wanderer
of the night.
I jest to Oberon
and make him smile.
When I a fat
and bean-fed horse beguile,
neighing in likeness
of a filly foal.
Sometimes lurk I
in a gossip's bowl,
in very likeness
of a roasted crab.
And when she drinks,
against her lips I bob,
and on her withered dewlaps
pours the ale.
Will all playing cards, dormice,
and dancing frog footmen
make your way
directly to the stage?
Any mock turtles,
wait in the wings till called.
Well done.
Well done, both of you.
Now, Pauline is to play Alice.
And Winifred will be engaged
as understudy.
When I finished my dance,
people clapped.
Nobody clapped her!
There was just silence!
Dance is important, but Pauline
looks right for Alice.
She looks right for everything!
She always will.
Pretty face.
Blond hair.
It's got nothing whatsoever
to do with talent,
and it's so unfair!
Winifred!
I will not take housekeeping
money from you, Pauline.
What would the authorities
think of me, making a...
Thank you.
Making a profit from an orphan?
Besides, the law states
that a working child must save.
Only one-third of her earnings.
One-third of £ 4
is 26 shillings and 8 pence.
Even after 8 shillings
has gone to the academy,
that would leave £2,
5 shillings, and 4 pence
for the house.
There's no need
to blind me with accountancy.
Garnie, we know we're poor.
I don't know how they found out.
Listening at doors, I don't
doubt... naughty, sneaky habit.
I'm assuming
this is Mr. Simpson's.
And if you'll excuse my saying,
I think you ought to take
what Pauline's offered.
I wanted Pauline to save
for the future.
All kinds of things might happen
in the future.
The professor might come back...
Your health might come back
on its own... in the future.
You inherited that chest
from your father.
Think of what happened to him.
She'll accept
30 shillings a week.
Now, off upstairs,
the lot of you!
Or you'll be feeling
the back of my hairbrush!
Sylvia, what matters most
is the life the girls have now.
And it wouldn't amount to much
if it didn't have you in it.
Now there's money coming in,
there's things you can see to.
You can go see a specialist,
for a start.
Petrova.
Do you think I can do it?
Do what?
Play Alice.
Winifred was better than me
at the audition.
And it's a massive part.
You can't lose your nerve.
We need the money.
Stop!
You're nothing
but a pack of playing cards!
Well done!
Bravo!
We'll see you back at home.
You're wearing the necklaces.
Mr. Simpson brought them down.
He didn't want Garnie
to be suspicious.
Well done.
Very good.
What did you really think?
-You were marvelous.
-Did you see us?
Get that on your way out,
would you, Winifred?
I'll see to it.
Let's button up that gabardine.
I see Pauline left her wrap
in the wings again.
Could you remind her to wear it
over her costume at all times
unless she's actually
on the stage?
Most certainly.
She knows the rules.
Ahem.
Miss Brown?
She's worn out
with all the excitement.
Should we, uh, let her sleep?
Shh.
Well done.
I'm not a complete novice.
What happened
to your wife and child?
There was a...
a typhoid epidemic.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I didn't mean to pry.
No.
I sometimes feel that
I'd like to talk about it.
Then I find it's better
if I don't.
-Good night.
They've announced a month
of extra matinees.
And next week,
Princess Elizabeth
and Princess Margaret Rose
are coming.
And will they be calling for tea
in your dressing room
afterwards?
Oh, I hope not.
I'm always so tired after shows.
Posy, would you run downstairs
and fetch my handkerchief?
No, I will not.
Is something the matter
with your arms and legs?
No.
I just need to save my strength.
It's going to be
awfully difficult
when we're all working,
isn't it, Petrova?
Yes.
All of us
giving out orders at once.
Mm-hmm.
I think you're both being
absolutely vile.
Ooh, door-slamming.
That's a new one.
And where do you think
you're going?
Wretched bills.
-Harley Street, please.
-Okay.
Bravo!
Jolly well done!
Thanks for the good show!
Three curtain calls again.
Compliments of Mr. French,
but would Miss Fossil go back
for her wrap?
You will keep leaving it
in the wings.
Let Winifred get it!
It's the least she can do,
sitting in my dressing room
night after night!
If everybody had their right,
it would be you sitting
in Winifred's dressing room
night after night!
-How can you even say that?!
-I can say that because...
What is this
appalling commotion?
As you know, sir, Pauline left
her wrap in the wings again.
I have reprimanded her,
but she will not fetch it.
Fetch it yourselves
if you want it fetched!
-Pauline!
-That is enough.
Rules are not made
for little girls to break.
What's your name again...
um, Winifred...
Winifred Bagnall, sir.
-I'm Pauline's understudy.
-Yes.
Well, I think it's high time
your positions were reversed.
From tomorrow, Winifred
will pay the part of Alice.
Pauline, will you
please tell me what's happened?
Can't you just mind
your own business?
Garnie's been
to see a specialist.
He asked to see her again.
I found a letter all about it.
I know we shouldn't snoop.
But they never tell us anything!
I-It said... she's got...
inflammation of the lungs,
t-that she should move
to a milder climate.
But you're working now,
and the extra matinees
are just about to start.
We could send her to Bournemouth
or Brighton.
Can't we?
I was so selfish.
All I could think about
was proving myself,
making everyone see
that I was talented.
But you are talented.
I have to be.
You have to be.
Posy has to be.
Posy is.
Don't you ever worry
that all the three of has
is each other...
what we are, what we can do...
our talents?
No.
Don't you think it's true?
I daren't think it's true.
Epaulement, child.
When the right leg
is extended behind,
the left shoulder
must move back.
1, 2, 3, 4.
Pas de bourrée.
Reach, child.
Reach.
Petrova!
Coming.
We three Fossils vow to put
our names in the history books
because it is uniquely ours
and ours alone,
and no one can say it's because
of our grandfathers.
We also vow to earn some money
to help Garnie
and support ourselves
until Gum comes home.
Amen.
Amen?
We aren't in church.
We do the vow every birthday
and every Christmas,
and we've never said
"amen" ever.
I haven't had any work
since "Alice."
We need help, and I don't care
where it comes from.
Well, it looks like amen, then.
Amen.
Yes, amen.
Come on, Petrova!
Give me your worst!
Oh, well done!
Come on, girls.
Mind yourself with that bat.
We don't want any broken teeth.
I was cricket captain.
My sport was lacrosse.
Oh, come on.
Give us another shot.
She'll be thrilled!
Oh, for heaven's sake!
But you've already given her
a sovereign.
And I could have made
a cake myself.
You do more than enough already.
Oh, dear, oh, dear.
How old would he be now...
your son?
He'd be getting on for, uh... 11.
Come on, birthday girl.
Oh, Sylvia!
Thank the Lord I found you!
There's an audition. " Midsummer
Night's Dream, " West End.
Directed by Sir Donald Houghton.
They want to see Pauline
and Petrova
tomorrow morning at 10:00!
Oh!
Shakespeare?
Oh, dear.
Petrova and the iambic
pentameter are not soul mates.
It's no good.
Won't fit either of you.
You've gone the same way
as your sister.
'Round the you-know-what.
That's enough from you.
Your turn will come.
We need a new dress each.
It'll look good
if we're dressed the same.
And Nana can make them both.
Oh, out of what, might I ask...
Scotch mist?
There's no money, Pauline.
How much does a piece
of material cost?
More than we've got.
That's how much.
Then we just can't go.
We have to go.
We have to get these jobs.
I suppose there's always
my birthday sovereign.
We needn't have bothered.
I look awful anyway.
It's only a sty.
When we take the patch off,
the borax will have worked.
There won't even be
a suggestion of a swelling.
Little dark girl
with the red eye.
What's your name?
Petrova Fossil.
What part have you come
to try for?
Mustardseed.
Oh.
Come down to the front
of the stage, please.
Whenever you're ready.
Do you want me to sing
or recite?
There's no need to sing.
This isn't a musical.
"Henry V," Act 3, Scene 2.
The Boy.
Oh.
Isn't that prose?
Yes.
Very well.
Go on.
"As young as I am."
As young as I am,
I-I have observed
these three swashers.
I am but boy to them
all three...
Thank you.
That's enough.
No.
Please.
You must let her finish.
I said that's enough
because I had heard enough.
She has got the part.
She has a decent accent, and we
must cast these parts today.
And, um, there are no other
candidates for Mustardseed.
No, sir.
Pauline?
Mr. French.
I take it she's your sister.
Yes.
We won't bother hearing you.
You can both go.
You're hired.
Run along and fetch your coats
before I change my mind.
Thank you.
We got them!
We got them, we got them!
Are we too late?!
We've been to Eastbourne
to Father's sanatorium.
I didn't get the message
till today.
I was being seen
for Mustardseed.
They cast me.
T-They thought nobody else
was coming.
You could try
for the ballet of the fairies
after lunch.
Couldn't get into a ballet
of goblins
looking the way I do today.
My dress has gone underneath
the other arm.
You can borrow my frock
or Pauline's.
Can't she?
Mm.
The trouble with you, Petrova,
is that you're a martyr
to your conscience.
The trouble with you is
that you haven't got one.
Look. This is Winifred
in the ballet of the fairies.
I'm the best all-'round student
this academy's ever had.
Even though I've got
a, frankly, enormous bottom,
I'm going to spend most of Act 2
behind a tree.
Posy Fossil,
you are a heartless monster.
You noticed.
I brought you up.
I notice everything.
Right,
we'll start with Cue 19-A,
which is Oberon's line,
"I am invisible, and I will
overhear their conference."
Pauline!
Bravo!
Do you still hate
the idea of working?
Well, I always wanted to fly.
And I will purge
thy mortal grossness
so that thou shalt like
an airy spirit go.
Peaseblossom, Cobweb, Moth,
and Mustardseed.
Ready.
And I.
Give me the line again.
Again.
And I?
Oh, please.
Am I asking for the moon?
All I want you to give me
are two sharp,
clearly differentiated notes.
As soon as you would care
to do so.
A-And I.
This is not the moment
to be funny.
I'm afraid I have no further
time to waste on you.
If your work does not improve,
I shall take the part away.
Petrova?
What ever's happened?
I'm going to get the sack.
I'll practice with you.
The doctors will help.
I'll still get the sack.
Darling, there is nothing
in this world
worth getting so upset about.
Yes, there is!
You're ill.
You need a rest
and a holiday and...
You need a rest and a holiday,
and you can't have one
if I get the sack.
I don't know where on earth
you got such a silly idea.
I can assure you,
Petrova Fossil,
that there is nothing whatever
the matter with my health.
Do you hear me?
I'm not having you upset
like this.
I'm going to see Donald
and giving him your notice.
-No!
-Don't.
I just feel so stupid
when I'm on the stage.
What do you mean,
you feel stupid?
I mean I feel like myself.
We have to help her.
So now I actually have to be
in character all the time...
meals and lessons...
and everything.
There's a hole in the exhaust.
The wardrobe mistress would
kill me if I get oil on this.
Has it helped, though?
Well, I don't feel human
anymore.
I don't know how you stand it.
I stand it
because we're saving up.
Garnie isn't well.
She's got trouble
with her lungs.
Pauline and I want her to have
a holiday.
She likes hotels
with tea and orchestras
but will doubtless have to
settle for two weeks in a tent.
You're a very generous girl,
Petrova.
Mustardseed.
You're supposed to call me
So, when do you open...
Mustardseed?
Tuesday.
Still, at least it will
all be over by Christmas.
Thank God that's over.
Sir Donald's doing
"Richard III" next.
He hasn't cast
the Princess in the Tower yet.
Do you think I should write to
him and ask him to audition us?
Don't even think of doing that
to me.
I wouldn't be doing anything
to you.
We'd both be doing something
for poor Garnie.
This has nothing to do
with Garnie.
We've got enough money
for a holiday.
This is all about you...
you and your acting.
Do you think you're the only one
that knows their heart's desire?
You're going to have to forget
your heart's desire.
There aren't
any 14-year-old aviators.
Pauline, you can make me sing,
and you can make me dance.
You can shove me out
onto a stage
and not care that I'm useless
and I'm hating it inside.
I put up with it because
we have to earn our living.
But if you keep pushing me,
then I will break.
Theo, is everything all right?
Just a minute!
Nana can smell
something strange.
Oh. Must be my new perfume,
Coty Chypre.
Isn't it divine?
No, it's another stench
entirely...
something more
like scorching dog.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's me.
I've been giving myself
a permanent wave.
Nana, fetch soft soap and the
brandy from the medicine chest.
It's stopped breaking off now.
It's just a bit... short.
Oh, Lord.
Serves me right for trying
to turn the clock back.
Why do you want to turn
the clock back?
I've got to the point where
chaps have just stopped looking.
You know what it's like.
One enters the room and makes
no more impression than a draft.
I suppose so.
It was all so different
when I was young.
I mean, there weren't many men
because of the beastly war.
Some of them
actually had bits missing.
Those that were intact
were often rather mad.
But they would wait for one
at the stage door
or ask one out for drinks.
And when one appeared,
there'd be such a lightening
of their faces,
as though they had
this surge of possibility and...
I used to feel it, too.
Don't you anymore?
I had to start telling myself
that there was no shame
in being an old maid.
Well, anyway.
The other day I had the first
tiny flicker of hope in an age.
And next thing I knew,
I was in the chemist's
with my hand around a bottle
of Empress Waving Compound.
-Where did it come from?
-It's imported from New York.
No, no.
I meant the hope.
Oh.
It's a chap.
I've known him for ages.
He's awfully quiet, but he has
the most speaking eyes.
And he just looked at me,
and I had this sense
that maybe he was
going to ask me something.
Good luck!
The record-breaking
aviatrix Amy Johnson
finally touched down
on British soil this week
after her triumphant flight
from Cape Town in South Africa.
With clouds and wind adding
to the danger of the journey,
Amy has proven once again
that by sheer skill
and determination,
there's no difficulty
that can't be overcome.
Petrova.
What do you think of Theo?
-Theo Dane?
-Yes.
Would you say
she's a nice sort of person?
Is she kind?
Well, she wears
a lot of perfume.
Coty Chypre.
It rubs off on everything.
I could probably bear that.
Well, goodbye, Amy.
The very best of luck.
Thanks very much.
I sincerely hope I shall, too.
Come on!
You're being really slow.
Come on.
No!
No, no, no!
What are you doing?
We're going to tie Posy
to a tree and scalp her!
No!
Hello?
I, uh, parked in the lane.
Awfully sorry to surprise you,
but there's news from London.
It's all right.
It's good news.
Don't kick!
Help me!
I can't believe
I'm going for a screen test.
I don't know anything about
Charles II's sister Henrietta.
I don't even know
what she looks like.
Well, let's just hope
she had a pimple on her nose.
Rat.
Come on, now.
Take the dishes down to
the water and get them swilled.
Bags I dry.
You always dry.
That's the easy bit.
May I smoke?
Of course.
Mr. Simpson, would you mind
awfully if I had one?
Sorry.
Didn't know you indulged.
Oh, I don't.
At least I never have before.
I suppose,
with the girls and everything,
I don't really get to go
to places where I would.
Thank you.
Nana did wonder
if I ought to have the odd one.
She thinks that it helps
to break up chest congestion.
But honestly,
the thought of sitting alone
in the kitchen in the dark,
dragging away
on my solitary fag...
It's such a tragic picture,
I simply couldn't bear to.
Oh, Lord.
I do feel a fool.
Quick, take it away
before the girls get back.
What time do we need to
leave tomorrow?
9:00 should do it.
We'll be at Shepperton by noon.
We could perhaps
have tea out afterwards
on the way back to London.
I'm afraid I must be home
by 4:00.
I have an appointment
with Theo.
Oh.
Well, we can't let you be late.
This will get you wet.
That's cold!
Pauline Fossil.
Screen test.
Mr. Sholsky.
So, Pauline Fossil.
How old are you?
I'm nearly 16.
Do you want to be in movies?
I don't know.
I don't know much about them.
But you want to be an actress.
No, I need to be an actress.
Hold it.
Theo just asked for tea in her
room for her and Mr. Simpson.
Just leave it outside!
There you are.
You've earned this.
Yes.
Earl's Court, 4-2-8.
That's simply wonderful.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I said, "That's wonderful news."
Don't move, Pauline.
Stick to your marks.
Okay, people.
We are going again.
Clear the set, please.
Clear the set.
Shh, shh, shh.
And...
Scene 84. Take 1.
Action.
Write to me while I am gone.
I will try.
Not "I will try," but "I will."
I will.
Cut. Cut.
You will what, Pauline?
Bake him a cake?
Knit him a sweater?
Look, your brother here
is... is asking
for an emotional lifeline, okay?
That's great.
Fantastic, Leo.
Can we take it again?
Scene 84. Take 2.
Not "I will try," but "I will."
I will.
Cut, cut, cut.
Take 3.
I will.
Cut!
Can we... Can we talk?
Excuse me.
You've got 10 days
on this picture.
This is your seventh,
and you've yet to show me
that you're not made of wood.
We do too many takes.
I can't concentrate.
I can build myself up to it
in the theater.
I can be a character.
Honey... Honey, this is
motion pictures now, okay?
Look, you've got
everything to learn,
and that's... that's fine.
But you've got to give me
something real.
What's real to you, Pauline?
What matters most to you
in the world?
Acting.
If that is a truthful
answer, there's no hope for you.
Scene 84. Take 4.
Action.
Write to me while I'm gone.
I will try.
Not "I will try," but "I will."
I will.
And cut.
Print.
Fantastic.
You did it.
I just thought about my sisters.
How awful it must be
to live your life alone.
That was wonderful.
Okay.
Let's move on.
Coty Chypre?
Come on.
Have you never wanted anything?
Well, when the war broke out,
I thought I'd like to drive
an ambulance.
But of course,
I didn't do anything about it.
I had you.
Madame, please,
may I change my shoes
before we start my enchaînement?
These were my mother's.
They fit me now.
Small bones.
High arches.
Like you.
She was just like me.
She loved ballet
more than anything.
I know that because
it was the thing she chose.
Excellent.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
And second.
1, 2, 3...
Energy, Petrova, energy!
Bored dancers are boring!
Arabesque!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...
Number 3 for you, Pauline.
You're in with Dandini.
Can't I share with Petrova?
She's on the fourth floor
with the others in the chorus.
Off you pop.
The 3 was going back that way,
wasn't it?
Please report to the stage
for trampoline practice
as soon as possible.
Hello, Petrova.
Hello, Winifred.
Soon a gown of shimmering tulle
and cape of silk
we will unspool.
Hollywood never
called for Pauline, then?
The film
isn't out yet, Winifred.
A pumpkin coach we will create.
Has Hollywood called for you?
It's not all gloom.
I've got an audition for
the Ovaltineys... on the radio.
But first,
to show what magic means,
I call upon the jumping beans!
"A King in Exile,"
world premiere.
Cue for gigantic panic
over frocks.
-What do you think of that?
-Beautiful.
What can you see Pauline in,
John?
Uh, that shiny stuff
that rustles?
Uh, taffeta?
I'm too old for a party dress.
I see her in powder-blue velvet.
With a lace bolero!
Lace bolero?
She'll catch her death.
Beautiful.
I'll get my rifle
and shoot you a mink.
I shall be needing a new dress
very soon.
What for?
The Marmara Ballet's
coming to London
for the first time ever
from Prague,
and Madame Fidolia
is taking me to see them.
You don't need something new
for that.
She's booked us a box
and a smoked-salmon supper.
# All is calm #
# All is bright #
I couldn't sleep.
I thought it would be
a nice surprise in the morning.
We've had such lovely
Christmases in this house.
It was even Christmas
when you came to us.
I think about it
every time it snows.
Why can't you sleep?
Is it your cough?
Not really.
Can you keep a secret?
I wanted to get you
all together,
but I'll tear open
if I don't tell someone.
We can't afford
to live here anymore.
But what about Pauline's wages
from the film
and... and the money we're
getting from "Cinderella"?
This house eats money.
Even with the boarders?
Yes.
And so I'm selling it.
No.
We'll soon be living
in a nice flat with Nana.
There'll be no need for Clara,
and the boarders will disperse.
You can't do that!
You can't!
The house belongs to Gum.
He's been gone for 12 years,
Petrova.
I spoke to the solicitors,
and they've declared him dead.
Remember, Posy,
when Valentin Manoff
got his dancers out of Russia,
he rescued not just a company,
but a system of training
200 years old.
I've brought you here to show
you what you might achieve...
if you are strong enough.
If you have the courage
and the will.
Stand still.
Oh, darling.
You look... grown up.
That's the first and last time
I copy anything from Vogue.
No one made you do it!
Pauline.
Why don't you make me go
in a jersey and skirt?
I feel a complete fraud,
Petrova.
I'm terrible in that film.
Tomorrow night my face
is going to be blown up
as big as a house.
Everyone's gonna find me out.
I will dance like that, Madame.
I don't care how long
the training takes.
Madame?
Help.
Someone help!
Posy?
Posy, is that you?
What's happened?
Madame's had a stroke.
A stroke?
They took her to the hospital,
and she can't move
her arm or leg!
Oh, no.
Poor Madame.
-Poor lady.
-I'm not crying about Madame!
I'm crying about me!
My training
can't be broken off now!
You are a selfish
and coldhearted little madam.
We did not bring you up
to conduct yourself like this.
Nana is right.
Your behavior is disgraceful.
She's ambitious, that's all.
Once upon a time, I thought
ambition was a good thing.
I thought it would help you
to apply yourselves
and help you make the most
of your small chances.
But if it kills off everything
that's nice in you,
then I am not going to have
ambition in this house.
Meaning what?
Meaning that
I will no longer sanction
any of you working on the stage.
You can't do that!
Oh, yes, I can.
I'm your legal guardian.
We will never be rich.
But now the house is sold,
there's no more need for you
to work or train.
You can't stop me.
You can't stop me
from doing anything.
We can stop you from going
to Pauline's premiere.
You can stay at home tonight...
alone.
Good luck.
Your name is really small,
Pauline.
Almost as small as the author's.
Maybe no one will realize
you're in it.
You were fantastic!
Let's get you through the back.
Come on, Pauline.
I wish I was you!
She was good, Nana.
She was wonderful.
-Is she with you?
-Who?
Miss Posy.
I went to check on her,
and she's not there.
Little maniac.
She's hiding somewhere.
It's the thought of her alone
out there.
How cold she must be.
How afraid.
Posy's not afraid of anything.
That's what frightens me.
-Miss Brown?
-No.
This is Miss Brown.
Good morning.
David Montague.
I'm the London representative
of United Artists Studios.
So, you don't speak Russian.
-I dance Russian.
-Hmph.
And who did you learn that from?
Michel Fokine?
Agrippina Vaganova?
No.
Evgenia Fidolia.
I see.
Do you?
You won't see anything at all
until you've watched me dance.
Mm.
No sign of her?
I've been offered a contract
by United Artists.
In Hollywood?
You ought to be smiling.
I'd have to go for five years.
That's five years
without theater
and not learning all the things
I wanted to know.
-Hello?
-Posy!
-Where have you been?
-With Valentin Manoff.
He's offered to train me
at his ballet school.
What?
I made him watch me
dance, and then he said,
"Come to my academy in Prague,
and I shall make you
into a ballerina."
So I said my guardian
would make the arrangements,
and I came straight home.
You can't go
to Czechoslovakia, Posy.
There's no money.
My mother gave me away
because there was no money!
At least your parents drowned
and had the kindness
to put you in a life belt.
I didn't get a life belt,
only a pair of ballet shoes.
Garnie, is Mr. Montague
still upstairs?
He's packing up his bag.
I said you needed time to think.
I don't.
Not anymore.
I'll sign.
Sign what?
Something that means
you can study with Manoff.
And Garnie can go to California,
where the climate's mild,
and get her health back.
Pauline...
I can't live in Hollywood
on my own,
and Nana must go to Prague
with Posy.
Otherwise, she's going to get
completely out of hand.
Where will I go?
Excuse me!
Who sold my house?!
Huh?
Are you... Gum?
Of course, I'm bloody Gum.
Who else would I be?
What I want to know is this.
Who are all these women?
Pauline.
Petrova.
Posy.
I-I brought entrancements home.
I-I brought babies.
Babies grow up, Gum.
Yes, I can see that.
So, a film star
and a ballet dancer.
Well, that's you
and your chaperones sorted.
I never thought I'd be going
to live abroad.
Abroad will get used to it.
So that just leaves you and me
to organize.
Now, what would you like to do?
She wants to be
like Amy Johnson.
Oh, Amy Johnson.
-I know her.
-How?
Well, I ran into her
in the Argentine.
She taught me how to fly.
She's quite good, actually.
Well, we'd better get you
some lessons, then, hadn't we?
Mixed feelings?
I'm not telling.
Theo?
Theo.
I, uh, I need
to ask you something.
Can I borrow your gramophone?
Theo's been giving me lessons.
I wanted to take you out...
...to a hotel.
I wanted to dance with you,
to tell you things.
And I didn't know how.
I thought this...
...this song, it...
...might tell you things.
# The very thought of you #
# And I forget to do #
# The little ordinary things #
# That everyone ought to do #
# I'm living in
a kind of a daydream #
# I'm happy as a king #
# And foolish
though it may seem #
# To me, that's everything #
This was the first room I ever
walked into in this house.
It was full of stone feathers
and the ghosts of things.
# You'll never know how slow #
Not anymore.
No.
It's full of things we made.
# I see your face
in every flower #
# Your eyes in stars above #
# It's just the thought of you #
# The very thought of you #
# My love #
Hello.
Miss Brown is otherwise engaged.
I haven't come to see
Miss Brown.
I've, uh, I've come to see you.
You don't remember me, do you?
Little Theodora, star of
"Miss Rosebud's Bouncing Babes"?
We used to meet at the stage
door every night for weeks.
During the war?
I knew you at once,
even without your bandages.
Do you know who I am
without mine?
Yes.
We two Fossils vow, since
as an actress and a dancer,
it is unlikely
we will ever get our names
in the history books,
to do everything we can
to get our sister's name,
Petrova, there instead.
Because she is ours
and ours alone.
And when she finds
the roads in the sky,
no one can ever say it's because
of her grandfathers.
We vow.
-Amen.
There she is!
Petrova!
Hi!
Full throttle, Petrova!
Subtitles by LeapinLar