This house, this plantation...
this whole damned parish
belonged to my family...
before your people stepped aboard
the stinkin'cattle boat...
that brought 'em to this country.
Don't you dare
talk back to me, boy.!
My family's seen this state...
crawlin'with
lousy carpetbaggers...
that knew more about
behaving like a gentleman than you do.
I can't even look at Charlotte...
without ugly thoughts
rip my guts.
I'd sooner it'd been
one of my field boys.
I could've killed him.
Do you know what it's costin' me
not to kill you?
My daughter and
Jewel Mayhew's husband.
You gutless, soft,
sucklin' swine!
My daddy sat out there
on that veranda.
Let this whole place
slide to dust.
When he died, there was nothin'
but debts and dirt.
I touched that dirt
and made it blossom.
I fought to keep this house
and to bring it back up.
I don't have a son to give it to.
Only Charlotte...
and she ain't gonna
give it to you.
You ain't gonna have
my home or my child.
I created both,
and I'm gonna keep 'em.
I ain't watched
over my girl all these years...
to have some...
to have someone...
to have some creature
like you take her away.
Listen, I'm gonna
tell you somethin'.
Your daughter ain't
a little girl anymore...
and there's gonna be
other men in her life besides you.
That's not funny.
Tell me somethin', boy.
How did you have
this elopement planned out?
How were you fixin'
to go about it?
Tomorrow night
during the dance...
Charlotte and I planned to meet
out in the summerhouse.
She was gonna have
her bags packed...
and we were gonna
go away together, that's all.
And I had got us a room in Baton Rouge.
We're gonna stay there.
I don't wanna hear about that.
Well, you asked me,
so I just told you, that's all.
Now...
you shut your filthy mouth...
and you listen to me.
Charlotte doesn't know
about this.
She doesn't know
you're here now.
She doesn't even know
Jewel was here last night.
How do you mean,
Jewel was here last night?
You mean to tell me that my wife
come over here to talk to you?
As I recollect, she was sittin'
right about here.
Now...
you're gonna come to that dance
tomorrow night with your wife.
You're gonna meet Charlotte
in the summerhouse...
just like you planned...
but what you're gonna
whisper in her ear...
it's gonna be
somethin'else again.
Come on, baby.
We haven't even danced once.
Champagne wouldn't
be half the fun without prohibition.
Sure would like to meet
Sam's bootlegger.
Sam Hollis sure knows
how to give a party.
I just love to Charleston.
Ginny Mae? Ginny Mae,
you seen Charlotte anyplace?
I got some killing news to tell her.
I haven't seen her
for a long time now.
The last time I saw her,
she was dancin' with John Mayhew.
Yeah, and it looks like it's gonna be
quite a spell before you see her again.
I just gotta find...
I made a mistake, Charlotte,
that's all.
Don't cry.
Look, l-I know
it's no consolation to you...
but I really loved you
at one time.
Try and understand that.
I really loved you.
I could kill you!
James! You ought to know you can't open
them cases with a thing like that.
Look here. Why do you think
I brought this special?
- Good evening, Mr. And Mrs. Howard.
- Oh, Geraldine.
Hasn't this been
just the loveliest evening?
We have to go now.
Be a dear and thank Mr. Hollis for us.
- I just can't find him anywhere.
- I'll do that little old thing, Mr. Howard.
Thank you, dear.
Good night, ladies.
- Good night.
- Good night, Mr. And Mrs. Howard.
-
- Charlotte?
Charlotte...
Aah!
No!
Oh, my God!
Come on. Once more.
Okay. Now, one more time!
Oh, there's Charlotte.
Somebody ought to call a doctor.
Charlotte, honey...
you come with me now.
No, Papa.
L- I don't want to, Papa.
- I don't want to, Papa.
- Come with me, baby.
No, Papa.
Boy, it sure is spooky around here.
Especially the graveyard.
Gets spookier. You'll see.
- Hurry up. It's gettin' late.
- You think there really is a ghost?
- Who knows?
- Sure, there's a ghost. There's the house now.
Gives me the creeps
every time I see it.
- What if she catches me?
- Shh!
Then you tell her you'reJewel Mayhew
from down the road...
and you come a-lookin'
for your poor, little old husband's head.
What if she catches me?
Now, look, you wanna join
the Spiders, don't you?
Well, get on in there.
Don't forget to get somethin'
she touched with her own hands.
Watch out for that cleaver, now.
She's just liable to chop off your little head.
Now, go on!
We haven't got all night.
Go on! Go on!
John?
- Get out of here!
- Hurry! She'll catch us!
- She ain't catchin'me.!
- Come on.! Move.!
- I'm scared!
- I'm runnin', I'm runnin',
Chop, chop
sweet Charlotte
till he's dead
Chop, chop
sweet Charlotte
Chop off
his hand and head
To meet your lover
you ran, chop, chop
Now everyone understands
Just why you ran to meet your love
chop, chop
To chop off
his head and hand
Chop, chop
sweet Charlotte
till he's dead
Damn you!
Get off my property,
or I'll shoot!
I told you
to get off my property.!
Stan, look out!
Look out up there! Stan!
- Man, oh, man!
- That crazy woman. I'm tellin' you.
I wouldn't go out there
if I was you.
Now, what do you think you're doin',
firing on my man like that?
That's my land
he's plowin' up down there.
Damn it.!
Ma'am, you could have killed him.
If I'd been aimin' to kill him,
I would have.
Now, see here, Miss Hollis. We done
everything we could to accommodate you.
But this time,
you've gone too far.
Now, we got a bridge to build
and roads to lay...
and we ain't got no more time
to fool with ya.
Where you are,
I could spit in your eye...
with no strain at all.
Now, Miss Hollis,
I ain't in no mood for jokes.
I'm goin' straight into town
and see the sheriff.
I don't care where
you go straight to...
just so long as you go
and take that and them with you.
Now, Miss Hollis, you know as well
as I do the State of Louisiana...
requisitioned this whole area, includin'
your house, more than six months ago.
Just because some old fool in Baton Rouge
signed a little bitty piece of paper...
doesn't make it so.
Nobody ever asked me
to sign anything...
and nobody's gonna
tear down my house...
to build a piddlin' bridge
or anything else.
So you just clear off
my property once and for all!
I don't know.
Some folks seem to think...
they got a natural-born right
to get away with murder.
Hey, look out!
You sure had yourself a good time today,
didn't you, missy?
You just cool down now.
What are you gonna do, boss?
I'm goin' into town, and you keep
those boys out of sight till I get back.
- Okay, boss.
- I'll bring that sheriff back out here...
in a half hour
if I have to drag him out.
Ah. You fixed things up for fair.
Come on. Come on.
But they're gonna dig up the graves.
Papa's grave.
They wasn't within
100 feet of them graves.
Anyhow, they're fixin'
to tear down the whole house.
I don't see what difference
plowin' up the grounds is gonna make.
Come on.
Come on, now.
They offered to move your pappy's remains.
You should've let 'em.
They can't do him any harm now.
Now, go on in there
and get yourself quieted down.
You've done enough
for one day.
Let me tell you somethin',
Ain't gonna be but a half an hour
before that sheriff comes over here.
So you get yourself
dressed up real pretty...
and you come on downstairs
and get your breakfast.
If Luke Standish ever comes out here,
he'll be real sorry.
You hush. That ain't no way
to talk, Miss Charlotte.
Now, you come on.
Get yourself dressed.
Velma'll go downstairs
and fix you a nice breakfast.
Don't you worry about that sheriff
when he comes out here.
Velma'll get rid of him.
Yes, sir.
It's not very often
we have a homicide...
and never able to find
the victim's head and hand.
I'm not much concerned about
examining your credentials, Mr. Wills.
I'm happy to go along
with anything you say.
I just have my doubts about
what you can expect to find.
We've had newsmen and all sorts
comin' down here for 35 years or more...
and none of'em any the wiser.
I don't expect to unearth
anything extraordinary.
After all, there's
nothing really unusual...
about an unclaimed
insurance policy.
It's just that
I don't want to upset anybody.
So if you'll just go along
with my little masquerade...
of a reporter from one
of our more esoteric crime magazines...
I'd be most awfully grateful to you.
Well, Mr. Wills, since you've come
all the way from London, England to see us...
I guess we'll just
have to oblige you...
esoteric magazines and all.
I'm sorry, Mr. Standish.
You're gonna to have to come out to the
Hollis place. We got real trouble this time.
What a remarkable coincidence.
By the way, Sheriff...
I wonder if you could arrange
for me to meetJewel Mayhew?
I guess we'll just
have to oblige you.
Thank you very much.
- Velma!
- What?
The sheriffs comin',
Get rid ofhim. Hear?
Oh.
She's not really crazy.
She just acts that way...
because people seem
to expect it of her.
You can wait in the car.
She ain't a-gonna come down.
You can't see her. She's sick.
All that dust and all that racket
from your machines...
has made her real sick.
She's waiting for Dr. Drew
to come and tend to her right now.
That's too bad, 'cause there's
a little matter of an unlicensed gun.
- I was hopin' Miss Hollis
maybe could help me find it.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, I reckon I'll just
have to look for it myself, Miss Cruther.
Mornin', Miss Charlotte.
Get out, Luke Standish!
You smirkin'Judas...
comin' around here
with your lyin' tricks!
You oughta be ashamed of yourself.
Papa gave you the first job
you ever had in this town.
- Without him, you wouldn't
be Sheriff or anything else.
- I know that, Miss Charlotte.
- That's why I'm trying to help you.
- Help me?
You had orders
to leave this house long ago.
If I'd been doin' my job,
you'd have been long gone by now.
If you are so anxious to help me...
why don't you leave me alone?
And tell everybody to stop threatenin' me
with cuttin' off my water and electricity.
I can't, Miss Charlotte.
What you did today
puts it right out of my hands.
Threatenin' people's one thing,
but shootin' at 'em's another.
I got orders now to see
that you're gone within 10 days.
They can hold up on the blastin'
they've gotta do...
and keep the men and equipment workin' on the
approach road on the other side of the river.
But if you aren't out of here
by the end of next week...
the county commissioner is gonna
have you up for criminal action.
But this is my home.
I haven't any other place to go.
- They can build their damn bridge anywhere.
- No, ma'am.
They have to build it to meet up
with the road on the other side of the river.
There isn't any alternative.
End of next week,
this house is comin' down.
When my cousin Miriam comes...
she'll know how to deal
with the county commissioner.
- I didn't know you were expectin' her.
- Well, I am.
Afraid she won't make a bit of difference
as far as the bridge is concerned.
We'll wait and see.
I reckon we will. I ain't gonna take
that gun away from you, Miss Charlotte.
I certainly hope you aren't
plannin' on using it again.
Comin' in here to fetch you out
is the last thing I wanna do.
Then don't come!
What'd you wanna go tellin' him stories
about Miss Miriam for?
She ain't even answered your letters.
Well, she's comin' anyway.
Be the saddest day of your life, missy,
if she does come.
Your cousin Miriam ain't never had
but one idea in her head...
and that was
lookin' out for herself.
She's gotta come.
She's the only kin I got left.
Miriam's just gotta come.
She's the only one
who can help me now.
She's just gotta come.
I guess there's been
a whole heap of changes...
- in this part of the country
since you was here last, miss.
- I imagine there have been.
'Course, things ain't changed much
in this parish...
exceptin' folks are gettin'
a lot older than they used to be.
I suppose they are.
There's absolutely no point
you're gettin' so upset...
the way you did this morning.
Anyone who knew you
less well than I do might be forgiven...
for thinkin' you had
a persecution complex.
Yes, Dr. Drew.
Charlotte...
they are asking you
to leave this house...
because they are going
to tear it down...
not because of any
of the ulterior motives...
- that you seem to imagine.
-
- What's that?
- Oh, Charlotte, please.
- Don't get so jumpy about everything.
- It's Miriam!
Miriam isn't expected
till tomorrow evenin'.
Now, come on.
Calm down.
Well, ma'am, this is it.
They say that places
you knew as a child...
always seem smaller
than your memory of them.
It's not true.
Huh.
Velma.
Velma Cruther.
Shall I take these in, miss?
Thank you.
Just put them up there.
It's just as I left it.
- How much is that?
- $2.50, ma'am.
- Keep the change.
- Thank you, ma'am.
You nearly beat your telegram here.
I know I'm a day early.
I hope it won't inconvenience anybody.
Miriam.!
I just can't believe it.
- You look marvelous.
- What is it that you can't believe, Drew?
That I'm here,
or that I look the way I do?
Come on. Don't make fun
of an old man.
You know I never was any good
at expressin' myself.
Oh, that's not so at all, Drew.
You were always very quick
with your compliments.
It was just your intentions...
that were sometimes a little vague.
You all want this stuff upstairs?
I'll give you a hand
in just a minute.
I suppose you wanna see Charlotte.
I think I already have.
- Won't she be coming down?
- I think we'd better go up. She's a bit upset.
- Well, there was a little trouble here this mornin'.
- Trouble?
Nothin' serious.
And, besides, you took us by surprise.
We weren't expectin' you till tomorrow.
There was a mix-up.
I had to take an earlier plane.
What kind of trouble?
Just plain, blind stubborn.
With her money, she could live anywhere
in the world like a queen.
But as it is, I'm afraid you'll have more
than your hands full...
gettin' her out of this place.
The three of us used to slide
down this banister.
I was always the champion.
We just let you win
because you were the youngest.
An old house is difficult
to keep clean.
If you can get anybody out
from town to work in this place...
you're doin' a lot better
than I can.
Don't misunderstand me, Velma.
I know how exhausting
it must be...
having to do all the work
out here alone.
There's a lot more bags out there.
Charlotte, it's Miriam.
How good it was getting your letter
asking me to come.
Miriam! I knew you'd come!
I just knew you would.
- And you're gonna help me.
- Of course I'll do whatever I can.
I've thought of you and the house.
It's like coming home.
Oh, but everything
is-is-is such a mess.
You see, I wasn't expectin' you
until tomorrow.
Don't worry. We're together again.
That's the important thing.
Yes. Of course it is.
Miss Charlotte's room.
Remember the night you taught me
how to smoke my first cigarette, and you...
or was it I... set the drapes on fire?
I was the one
they whopped, I know.
No! That's Velma's job!
Yes, but Velma's...
well, Velma.
It's just that we haven't
seen each other in so long...
you'd think we'd have
other things to talk about.
I mean, arguing about
who's gonna make up the bed.
If you all want me
to fix supper for you...
you better eat early...
because I gotta get home.
Well, thank you, Velma.
- Is that an invitation?
- No!
I just reckon you'd be
sniffin' around here more than usual...
now that Miss Miriam's back.
There's nothin' like a family reunion.
I think I'll just get
the key to the cellar.
Hmph! Just thinks he's gonna get
Well, it's the only thing.
I didn't know Ida told you
where the keys to the cellar were.
Thank you, sir.
I can't remember when
I last dined in here.
Papa used to say
this was his favorite room.
I guess maybe that's 'cause
he loved to eat so much.
You know, Miriam...
when all this nonsense
about the house is straightened out...
we could give parties here again.
Why not? What's so
impossible about that?
It would be lovely.
Yes, it would be nice.
Aren't you forgettin' about the limit
they put on vacatin' the house?
You've got to be out of here a week from
Monday, and there's no two ways about it.
Drew, you carry on
as if you're a member...
of the Department
of Roads and Bridges, or somethin'.
Miriam will tell them where to get off,
won't you, Cousin, darling?
I wish I could.
Charlotte, you have just
got to understand...
that there's nothin',
absolutely nothin'...
that Miriam or anybody else
can do about it.
Now, they are going to tear down
this house, and that is final.
Oh, you're so stuffy.
They took their smelly old equipment
out of here, didn't they?
Miriam isn't frightened of
a bunch of crooked politicians.
You know, it wouldn't surprise me
to find out...
thatJewel Mayhew is behind all this.
Charlotte, that is ridiculous!
Is it? You notice they're not laying
a finger on her land.
They're destroying my house,
but they're not touching hers.
I've rented a car for you, Miriam.
- You can go tomorrow.
- Go where?
To Baton Rouge to put that damn
county commissioner straight.
Charlotte...
there's nothing I wouldn't do
for you if I could.
You know that.
But I'm afraid Drew's right.
There isn't anything
we can do about the house.
You have to leave.
What do you think
I asked you here for?
Company?
I thought you were
gonna help me!
But I shall. That's why I came...
to help, to be with you.
To be with me?
I've lived alone here
ever since Papa died.
The only people I've ever seen
are Velma and Drew...
who comes out when he feels like it
just to see if I'm still alive...
- Charlotte, that's not true.
- and a bunch of sniggering idiots...
who come out here
to make fun of me.
Do you think
I'd ask you back here...
just-just to be with me?
Charlotte, she's only tryin'
to lend a helpin'hand.
Oh, yes. I can see that.
She's just breakin' her back.
God, do you have gratitude!
When you first came here
after your precious papa died...
you acted as if
we weren't good enough for you.
- And your mama, a sorry, up-north waitress...
- Charlotte, that's enough.
Let her talk, Drew, if insulting me
gives her any satisfaction.
When you first came here, Papa took you
downtown, bought you a whole new wardrobe.
- Does it insult you to remember that?
- Yes, I remember.
You took your poor, up-north cousin
downtown for a whole new wardrobe...
down to a sleazy store
he wouldn't even let you set foot in.
Oh, that wasn't good enough for you?
Papa didn't give you enough?
Well, maybe that's what
you came back here for...
to get the rest of Papa's money.
Charlotte! I have a career,
and I've given up valuable time to come here.
I know. Now, let me see.
What-What is it you call your job?
Oh, yes. Public relations.
Sounds like somethin' pretty dirty to me.
The dirt, Charlotte,
is entirely in your own mind.
I wouldn't dwell on it
if I were you, Charlotte.
She didn't come here
to be insulted.
No, most likely she came back here
to helpJewel Mayhew...
- drive me out of my own house.
- Charlotte, you don't believe that.
Why wouldn't Miriam conspire
with Jewel against me?
Who was it went
sneakin' off toJewel...
and told her about her husband
and me in the first place?
Didn't know about that,
did you, Drew?
That's somethin' you never told
your precious boyfriend, isn't that so, Miriam?
Isn't it, Cousin, darling?
Yes, I told Jewel.
And I told your father too.
Why wouldn't I? After all,
I wasn't much more than a child then.
And all I ever got in this house
was people telling me how lucky I was...
and your father always favoring you
and holding you up as an example!
Why wouldn't I tell him
that his pure, darling little girl...
was having a dirty little affair
with a married man?
You're a vile, sorry little bitch!
How was I to know it would end
in murder with John being butchered?
No, you couldn't have known that.
And you couldn't have known
that when Drew found out...
he was so frightened of having
his fine old name linked with ours...
that he'd walk out on you.
But Drew's still here...
and you're both still alive and...
and I'm still here.
But, John...
John never even...
John? John?
John?
John.
She is deranged, Drew.
She must be.
Well, no. She's certainly worse
than when I last wrote you...
but not to the extent
of being committed.
I'm sorry. There's just no way
to avoid the problem.
There are times when...
she genuinely doesn't know
what she's saying, but...
On the other hand,
I thought she described...
the way you left me
rather accurately.
If it's any comfort,
I've always regretted...
having let you go.
We don't have time
for regrets now, Drew.
And there is a lot to regret.
John?
What a shame.
With all that money...
she could have done
such wonderful things with this place...
made it so beautiful again.
How could she stand
being alone here all these years?
People who oblige to live alone have
a habit of creatin' company for themselves.
Innocent fancies
can become fixed delusions.
I think she never fully accepted
John Mayhew's death.
At least, part of her mind hasn't.
Sometimes, she speaks of him...
as if he were still alive
here in this house...
as if she could still
feel his personality.
She plays that old harpsichord,
the song he wrote for her.
Often at night,
she sits up dressed...
as if she were still young...
and expectin' a beau.
I seem to remember expecting
something like that once myself.
You going to be all right here?
I could stay over.
You've been content to let me get along
on my own all these years.
I don't think another night
is gonna kill me.
I guess you're right.
Oh, uh...
maybe you'd better have this.
- What on earth for?
- Well, you never know.
You do have people
skulkin' around here occasionally.
- Anyway, you'd better take it.
- Thank you.
Good night.
My dress.
Somebody slashed my dress.
They certainly were
attractive youngsters.
Yes, sir. That was just about the biggest story
that ever broke in this town.
Yes, I can see you gave it what you might call
"the full treatment."
Well, we couldn't very well bury it
on the society page, could we?
Anyhow, help yourself. I think
you'll find everything that you need here.
And that's a pretty good picture
of Miss Charlotte.
Yes, it is.
I was working for the press
when she arrived in London.
Not one of us succeeded
in getting an interview with her.
Well, they said that
Big Sam sent her over there...
to prevent her from being
charged and tried.
But that wasn't so.
Sending her out of the country
wouldn't have helped.
I reckon Sam's political connections
had more to do with it.
As I remember, the district attorney
tried hard to make the charge stick...
but the whole thing was transferred
over to Baton Rouge.
I reckon Sam's friends in the capitol got busy,
because nothin' ever did come of it.
Lack of evidence
was the official explanation.
You wouldn't think so
from the headlines.
Hi, Mr. Blake.
Thanks for the use of the hall.
Tell me, are you running anything
on the return of Miriam Deering?
Just an insert
in the social column.
The social column. You gotta be kiddin'.
Excuse me, Mr. Wills. This is a colleague
of yours, Mr. Marchand from New York.
- How do you do?
- And who are you covering the story for?
Don't worry about me, old chap.
My status is that of an amateur.
By the way,
what journal do you represent?
Crimes of Passion
and Century Crime Classics.
You know, that Hollis dame hit the news
again over that business with the bridge.
We did a special issue on her.
Here, take a look.
No head, no hand.
Just like the way it was.
Yes.
- Very colorful.
- Yeah, we're really going to town on this one.
Hey, Mr. Blake.
You never showed me this stuff.
Well, one thing they didn't do then was
to play up the sex angle like you can today.
Miriam Deering.
Miss Deering!
My, it's good to see you back.
- Jewel! Jewel Mayhew!
- Joseph.
- Oh, here. Let me help you.
- You leave me be.
If I ever prayed for anything...
it was that you would never
dare show your face to me again.
After all these years,
what do you mean?
Do you honestly believe...
that time can excuse all the things
you've done to me?
- Jewel, please don't. Not here on the public steps.
- Oh, I see.
Not in public.
We mustn't speak the truth
out in the open, you and I, huh?
It's not about me that I'm worried.
Well, right here
on the public street...
in the light of day...
let me tell you, Miriam Deering...
that murder starts in the heart...
and its first weapon
is a vicious tongue.
At the time, would anyone else
have been as kind to you as I?
- Would they?
- Go away from me.
I'm ill. I'm very ill.
I won't give up
one more thing to you...
not even one more minute.
It's all right, Mrs. Mayhew.
Come along.
A world full of monsters.!
Don't you ever show your white-trash face
in this house again.!
Damn.! Just some damn meanness
all day long.
Just one filthy mess to clean up
after another. She's nothin'but a child.
She never does anything anyway.
- Velma.
- Huh?
Who brought this
into the house?
I did.! I brought it in.
It was in the mailbox
just like that.
I reckon somebody put it there.
You know...
she broke that
dadburned teapot up there.
Tea runnin' all down the wall.
Shoo-ee!
Incidentally, I've managed to find
some women to do the packing.
- Please let me know when they arrive.
- Oh!
Them women, they just steal you
out of house and home.
I got to get something
to fix this filthy stuff.
"Incidentally, please tell me
when they arrive."
I told you to stay out.!
Charlotte, you're behaving
like a child...
throwing a tantrum over a trivial bit
of rubbish like this.
How can you touch
that piece of filth?
It's only a magazine,
cheap and disgusting...
and only cheap and disgusting people
will read it.
It's Jewel Mayhew
deviling me in my own house.
You thinkJewel Mayhew
brought it here?
- She couldn't have.
- Why couldn't she have brought it here?
I just saw her.
She's seriously ill...
much too ill to be running around
playing silly games with magazines.
Well, she deserves to be ill.
She deserves to die!
Charlotte!
It's just possible thatJewel Mayhew
hasn't given you a sustained thought in years.
Oh, you think so, do you?
You think she's never
given me a thought?
I've been gettin' these in the mail
ever sinceJohn died.
That idiot Luke Standish told Papa they were...
they were crank notes.
But then some reporter got a hold of'em
and put it in the newspaper.
And then they started to come in
from all over the world.
But the first one was mailed
right here in Hollisport...
and that's where
the last one came from.
And nobody can ever make me believe that
Jewel Mayhew didn't send them!
- You saved all these?
- All of'em...
to show how mean
and unforgiving she can be!
Well...
it's time you got rid of them.
- What do you want now?
- I come to tell her somethin'.
She could use some tellin'!
Them packin' women
you've been lookin' for, they's arrived.
I'll take care of it.
This is my favorite place now...
here in the shade.
Yes, it's very pleasant here.
Very pleasant indeed.
Tell me, Mr. Wills,
weren't you a little surprised...
when I agreed to see you?
After all, you must've been told
that I don't normally receive visitors.
Well, yes. But then,
I found the hospitality...
of this part of the country extraordinary.
Besides, I imagine
you had your reasons.
Would you have
anything else, ma'am?
Um, no.
- Thank you, Lewis.
- Thank you, ma'am.
I did have my reasons, Mr. Wills.
- I did.
- I hope you won't regret it...
but I did warn you I'd have to touch
on some painful subjects.
Which leads me to confess...
to my own reasons for this meetin'.
I have a particular need
for a stranger now.
Yes, they...
they have their uses, don't they?
Well, in this little town...
our interests are all too, uh...
too tightly interlocked.
If you confide in one person,
you confide in the whole community.
You mean you'd like
somebody to talk to?
Only in a sense.
I'm not a well woman.
You can see that much for yourself.
Who was it said,
"This long disease, my life"?
Well, it's... it's comin' to an end.
Perhaps a month, a few weeks.
Who knows?
I'm terribly sorry.
Oh, no, no.
Don't be, not for me.
I think I'm even glad.
But never mind that.
I take it you're no stranger...
to the unhappier aspects
of people's lives.
In fact, the only way to trust someone
is on instinct alone.
I want you to have this.
I only ask that you don't open it
until after I'm gone.
Then I want you to use
your own judgment and experience.
You'll know what to do
when the time comes...
or what not to do.
It seems a dreadful responsibility.
Oh, it is. A terrible one.
My honest advice is to refuse it.
You know I won't, of course.
I know.
Ruined finery.
That's all I have left.
I'm, uh, stony broke.
Is that the phrase?
It's a relief to admit it.
- But your... your policy with Lloyds?
- Oh!
You know how long it would take
to process an old claim like that?
By the time I received it, I'd be past needin' it.
Well, now I think you're ready
for another cup of tea.
Would you?
I hold two roses within my hand
Two roses I give to you
The red rose tells you
Of my passion
The white rose
My love so true
Hush, hush
sweet Charlotte
Charlotte, don't you cry
Hush, hush
sweet Charlotte
I'll love you till I die
And every night
After I should die
Yes, every night
When I'm gone
The wind will sing to you
This lullaby
Sweet Charlotte was loved
ByJohn
Charlotte.
Charlotte?
Come. Come to bed, Charlotte.
Come to bed.
Miriam...
he really... isn't here, is he?
Just now I thought I heard...
Sometimes at night
when I wake up...
it seems as if he really is here.
Don't turn on the light.
It's not real when it's light.
It's only real when it's dark...
dark and still.
I won't turn on the light.
Come along.
You must go to bed.
He's dead.!
He's dead.! He's dead.!
He's dead! He's dead!
- Dead! He's dead!
- Charlotte.!
- No, no, he's all right.
- He's dead.!
He'll be fine.
- He's dead! He's dead!
- Charlotte, don't...
Stop starin' at me!
Man, she sure acts...
like she's crazy sometimes.
That's what all the folks
in town say...
but I wouldn't bet on it.
I wouldn't bet on it at all.
Well, upon my word.
Charlotte Hollis.
Now I've frightened you.
I'm terribly sorry.
Please don't run away.
I'm quite harmless, I assure you.
Would you like a cigarette?
Well, I won't either.
What are you doing
on my property?
Yes, my dear,
it is your property, isn't it?
Well, as a matter of fact,
I'm snooping. There's no other word for it.
- Are you one of the surveyors?
- Oh, no, no.
- I have nothing to do with all that sort of thing.
- Then what's that camera for?
This is a sort of conversation piece.
I say, may I introduce myself?
My name is Harry Wills.
I've come all the way from London
in the hope of meeting you.
Why?
Well, we have met before,
you know...
a long time ago.
On the first night
you arrived in London...
when I was a newspaper reporter...
and stood as close to you
as I am now...
for two delightful minutes.
But I didn't talk to any reporters.
I know you didn't,
and you had every reason not to...
the way they behaved toward you.
That's one of the reasons
why I've always hoped I'd meet you again...
to apologize.
- You really were there?
- Indeed I was.
And I can prove it to you.
Let me see now.
You were dressed in, um...
a sort of, uh...
gray...no, green...
a green suit with a sort of...
Tam-o'- Shanter to match.
Am I right?
You see, I was there.
You know, ever since that night I've read almost
everything they've ever printed about you.
In fact, I'm quite
an authority on you.
- You are?
- Yes, indeed I am.
You're my favorite living mystery.
Have you ever solved me?
No.
But then you wouldn't
be a mystery anymore, would you?
No, I wouldn't.
And I'm your... your favorite case
when you got so many to choose from?
That's only natural.
You have everything.
You're unsolved.
Perhaps even insoluble.
And you have passion
and glamour in your past.
I say, I hope
I'm not offending you.
It's the oddest thing.
You're not.
I don't usually talk to people.
Not about that.
That's why I'm so flattered
that you're talking to me now.
I say, let's go and sit up there
and have a nice little chat, shall we?
Mr. Wills...
since you're an authority on me...
you think I'm a murderess?
Do I look like one?
Well, now, let's see.
It's rather difficult, isn't it?
But that's as it should be.
They've told you I'm crazy.
Everyone says you are.
Are you?
I used to be positive I wasn't.
But just lately...
at night, it...
it seems as if...
I really don't know anymore.
If it comes to that,
how does anyone know?
Would you like to see
inside the house?
I've been wanting to see it for years.
Come on.
Papa used to give the most
beautiful parties here.
They went on for days and days.
You're very fond
of this house, aren't you?
I'll show you Papa's library.
Papa built this place
up again, you know.
He bought back a lot
of the original pieces.
Oh.
You're Miss Deering, aren't you?
I had the pleasure of seeing you yesterday.
- My name is Wills. Harry Wills.
- How do you do?
Your cousin's kindly considered
to show me around this lovely old home.
I see.
Excuse me.
Come on.
Papa's library was like a playroom
to me when I was a little bitty.
That's Papa.
He never minded me underfoot.
He never minded a thing I ever did.
He was always so...
Take your hands off that.!
You give that to me!
Now you get out!
You get out, all of you!
- Get out, do you hear me?
You get out and stay out.!
- Go outside. Wait for me outside.
- You get out and stay out!
- Charlotte, what's the matter? What did they do?
And you, too, snooping around.
Don't you think I know
what you're looking for in my house?
But what does it matter
if you haven't anything to conceal?
Oh, but I have.
I have things concealed. Vile things.
Where do you suppose I keep 'em?
Haven't you guessed?
In here.
A memento of my sinful romance.
My lover's hand.
Look! Just look!
It's all... all I have
left of him.
A love song he wrote for me...
and gave me in a music box.
My dear, Miss Charlotte. Please.
- Oh, John.
- You better leave now.
I was trying to help her.
If you hadn't come here,
this might never have happened.
I'm sorry.
Who put that box in there?
How in the world would I know?
Charlotte.
- John?
-
- Charlotte?
Charlotte? Charlotte, let me in.
The mirrors.
Charlotte, what happened
to the mirrors?
-
- Charlotte...
what have you done?
It was Papa.
He was so... so tall and so angry.
He still hasn't forgiven me.
- No, Charlotte, he loved you.
He wouldn't have harmed you.
- But it was Papa.
It was Papa.
I know it was.
- No, it just seemed that way.
- He was there. He really was.
- He really was.
- No, come along.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
- Miriam, what are you doing?
- Charlotte.
I'm taking you away
from here today.
- No.
- Drew and I have talked it over.
- And we found a place where
you'll be real comfortable.
- No, I won't go.
- You just get some sleep.
- You have to go before next Monday anyway.
L... I won't go, not while
Jewel Mayhew's still down there.
I won't have her see me
driven off my own place.
- Would you rather she sees you
arrested and taken off to jail?
- Luke Standish wouldn't do that.
They'll be policemen and reporters
and photographers everywhere.
Charlotte, after last night,
you must leave here.
You must.
- Last night?
- The music room.
The mirrors.
Where will you take me?
To a nice place...
where people will be kind to you.
You'll see.
But I won't go in the daytime. I won't go
till it's after dark 'causeJewel will see me.
Now, Charlotte,
what difference does that make?
Jewel will have to know
sooner or later.
Now I want Charlotte
to get some sleep.
I'll go downstairs and see about
cleaning up down there.
- What are you gonna do to me?
- Now I want you to get all the rest you can.
You're going to feel a lot better
after you've had a little sleep.
Drew, I didn't break those mirrors.
Really, Drew, I didn't break those mirrors.
Oh, of course
you didn't break the mirrors.
Mr. Wills's room.
Yeah. Will you hurry it up?
Mr. Wills? Velma Cruther.
- You told me to call you if...
-
Oh. I'll talk to you later.
I was just using the phone.
So I see.
Miss Charlotte will be
leaving tonight, Velma.
You'll be given your wages
till the end of the month.
You trying to hand me
my walkin' papers?
No, it's just that
you won't be needed any longer.
Is that so?
Well, what about when she comes back?
Or ain't she comin' back?
Since the house won't be here,
I hardly think that's relevant.
Oh, you think so, huh?
You know what I think?
I think if she leaves
this house with you...
she ain't never gonna be
seen nor heard from again.
Anyways, I take my orders
from Miss Charlotte and not from you!
It should be obvious,
even to you, Velma...
that my cousin is in no condition
to run a household.
Oh, is that so? Well, there's a whole lot
of things that's obvious to me.
The childish tricks
you've been playing here...
trying to frighten me into leaving are more
than sufficient reason to dismiss you.
Tricks?
What are you calling tricks?
Wasn't me that ripped
your dad-burned old dress.
But you seem to know
it was ripped.
And I haven't mentioned it to anyone.
Besides, it isn't just the dress.
I don't even know what
you're talking about.
But I do know
one thing, though.
You're just jealous because
Miss Charlotte always favored me!
You're trying to dupe me
out of the money...
that she promised me
when she passes away!
Oh, that's charming.
Quite charming.
My cousin just happens
to be a little ill...
and you're already
dividing up the spoils.
I didn't mean it.
I did not mean it that way,
and you damn well know it!
Anyways, you don't have no call to be
so high and mighty.
I seen all that fancy foreign mail
that you've been gettin'.
You think I don't know a due bill
when I see one?
You had it in for me since the first time
you come to this house.
And you know why?
'Cause I can see right through you.
You didn't fool me then,
and you sure as hell don't fool me now.
My dear Velma,
I wouldn't dream of trying.
But the point is you're fired.
You're just not needed any longer.
Well, I'm not gonna clear out
just 'cause you say so.
I've been lookin' after Miss Charlotte
since before you come here, and she knows it.
Where do you think you're going?
I'm goin'upstairs, and I'm gonna tell her
what you've been up to.!
Don't you dare go up there
and bother her.
Mm-hmm.
What's going on up there
that you don't want me to see?
Now, Velma, Miss Miriam's
more than qualified...
to look after Miss Charlotte...
and to take care
of closing up the house.
Oh.
So you're in on this together, huh?
You and her.
You ought to be
ashamed of yourself.
Miss Charlotte's sick.
You're not gonna help her
get well by kicking up all this ruckus.
Oh, all right!
All right, I'm goin'.
But don't think
you're not gonna be sorry!
Both of you!
What in the world does she think
we're gonna be sorry about?
She's always been
insanely jealous...
of anyone who was
close to Charlotte.
I guess it's something
she just can't be rational about.
You haven't got much
to go on, really.
I got what I know, don't I?
I know the state Miss Charlotte's been in
ever since that fool woman come here!
She wouldn't have smashed
them mirrors that way...
if somebody didn't have her good
and worked up about something.
She loves that old house.
She really does.
Yes, but even allowing that there may be
some cause for concern...
what can I do?
You could do somethin'!
She likes you.
I seen how she was with you.
Now, if you was to...
if you was to go out there...
and you were to tell her
not to listen to them...
I think she'd mind what you say.
I must admit, the whole thing
seems strangely odd to me.
If they take my Miss Charlotte away
from that house...
I ain't gonna never see her again.
I knows it. I just knows it!
You feeling all right, Charlotte?
Somebody has to finish
your packing for you, don't they?
You don't want to leave
all your things behind, do you?
Do you?
Papa.
Papa, I'm going to have
to leave the house.
I tried to keep the house,
but they're tearing it down.
I can't help it.
Don't be angry.
I've lived alone here
all these years to protect you.
You know that.
Just because I loved John
more than I loved you...
didn't give you the right
to murder him just to punish me!
John never hurt you.
John never even...
One more time, baby.
Just one more time.
Nice. Now hold still.
Once again.
Thanks. Remind me to
send you one for Christmas.
Charlotte?
Charlotte? Charlotte, what is it?
How is she?
She'll keep. Oh.
Wanna help me get rid of this?
It's almost too real, isn't it?
Your artist friend in New Orleans
has quite a talent.
- And a minimum of curiosity.
- Do you think it's done the job?
Not quite. We could probably achieve
the rest with this drug...
but the effect
wouldn't be permanent.
Besides, chemically it's traceable.
Then we'll have to
go through with the rest?
Don't you worry.
After the last phase of treatment...
there won't be a doctor in Louisiana
who wouldn't commit her.
Then establishing
your right to handle the estate...
should take...
oh, just a few days.
Good morning, Charlotte.
- Where's Velma?
- You let her go yesterday.
You fired her.
- Fired?
- You're not going to need her any longer.
I had a terrible dream.
- Terrible.
- I know.
You'll stop having them
once you're away from here.
Now you eat your breakfast.
And I'll come back later
and see how you are.
Miss Charlotte?
Miss Charlotte.
What have they
been givin' you?
That's some kind of drug, ain't it?
Oh, Miss Charlotte.
- I thought you'd gone.
- Well, I was gone. They kicked me out...
Miss Miriam and your friend
Dr. Drew.
I told that to Mr. Wills,
but he wouldn't listen.
You can't go that way.
Miss Charlotte, I've gotta get your coat.
Your shoes.
You can't go there.
Come on, Miss Charlotte.
I've gotta get you out of here.
- Come on, honey. We gotta go outta here.
-
Miss Charlotte. Come on, darling.
Don't you say anything.
You hush now, ya hear?
Don't you say a word.
Come on, Miss Charlotte.
Miss Charlotte,
don't say anything. Shh.
Shh. Be quiet.
Don't say anything.
Oh, my!
Shh, Miss Charlotte.
You'll be able
to eat something later.
I'll take this away.
Is there anything you want
before I leave?
I'll look in on you later.
Now get some rest.
Come on, Miss Charlotte.
You gotta wake up now. Come on.
- No. No, Velma, no!
- Shh! You gotta be quiet, honey.
Come on. Put your legs over here.
That's right.
You gotta put this coat on.
Put your little hand in here now.
Come on. Put your little hand
in there. That's right.
Come on. Now give me
your other hand.
That's good. Get it in there.
Come on. Give me your other one.
You just can't keep hogs
away from the trough, can you?
I come to get my things.
Is my cousin one of your things?
I'm taking her outta here...
away from you.!
The only thing
you're taking out of here is you!
Miss Charlotte! Miss Charlotte!
So you're finally showin'
the right side of your face, ain't ya?
Well, I seen it all the time.
That's some kind of drug
that you've been givin' her.
You've been makin' her act
the way she's been.
Well, I'm goin' into town...
and I'm goin' to tell them
what you been up to.
Dr. Bayliss, please. Yes, Bayliss.
And hurry. Please hurry.
Sit down.
You seem awfully nervous.
He was always fighting
to keep two things...
his daughter and his money.
And now he's gonna lose both.
Gotta hand it to him. He held on
to both of'em an awful long time...
even after he died.
I suppose in a way he's got Charlotte
to thank for that.
If she hadn't deluded
herself into believing...
it was dear old Papa
who killed John Mayhew...
she might never have stayed here
guarding that so-called, uh, secret.
She might have gone off
and spent the entire fortune.
Are you sure it's all right?
Sure what's all right?
Don't make fun of me!
Oh, you mean Velma.
Of course it's all right. Nobody's ever
gonna know it wasn't an accident.
Except me, of course.
Which rather tends to make me
the senior partner...
in our little enterprise,
doesn't it?
Charlotte's still asleep.
Do you want me to give her anything else?
No, no. She'll do
quite nicely as she is.
Well, I'd better put in
an appearance in town.
Oh, come on, Miriam.
Don't start weakenin' now.
This may be our last chance
of acquiring the wealth...
to which I'd like
to become accustomed.
See you.
It's all yours, Mr. Wills.
Thank you, Sheriff.
Hi, Mr. Wills.
I'll bet this is the first time...
you've ever seen the county coroner
operate out of a funeral parlor, eh?
Yes. It's a bit different
where I come from.
It's a bit different most places.
Still, for a town of this size,
it's kind of handy.
I just heard the news about
Velma Cruther's death...
at the newspaper office.
- It was Miss Cruther he came to see, wasn't it?
- Oh, yes, indeed, sir.
She certainly had
a nasty accident, all right.
- Would you like to see the body?
- No, thank you.
Oh. Well, step inside anyway.
May I ask how it happened?
Well, it seems she, uh...
she fell off a ladder.
She must have been
up there fixing her roof.
The roof in her place
has always let in the rain.
And, uh, well, it's done it for years.
You mean this happened
at Miss Cruther's home?
Well, I'd hardly
call it a home, sir...
but she did fall in her own backyard.
I see. Who found her?
Well, I couldn't tell you that, sir...
but it was Dr. Bayliss
that brought her in.
Charlotte.
Hush, hush
sweet Charlotte
Charlotte, don't you cry
Hush, hush
sweet Charlotte
I'll love you till I die
Oh, hold me, darlin'
Please hold me close
And brush the tears
From your eyes
You weep because
you had a dream last night
You dreamed
that I said good-bye
Hush, hush
sweet Charlotte
Charlotte, don't you cry
Charlotte.
John?
John, wait! Don't go.
Hush, hush
sweet Charlotte
Charlotte, don't you cry
John?
Don't go away.
Please don't go away!
Papa?
Charlotte.
John.
You idiot.
You wretched idiot!
He's dead.
And you killed him.
Miriam!
Don't call the sheriff.
People staring at me
and hating me.
It will be just like the night
when John was murdered.
But you killed Drew.
We can't just pretend it never happened.
You don't know what it's like when hate
is everywhere. You can't feel it.
Oh, Miriam,
don't you hate me too.
Oh, please, Charlotte.
Please, please don't.
I didn't mean to kill him.
The gun was just there in-in my hand.
And-And when I saw him,
he looked so horrible.
It was just like the night when...
when the mirrors were all smashed...
and just like the night
when I saw that hand.
Oh, Miriam... Miriam, please don't call
the sheriff. I just couldn't stand it!
Oh, Charlotte, don't.
We could get rid of the body.
We could hide it somewhere.
Then people would think someone else
had done it. That's the only thing to do.
Miriam... Miriam,
I've got lots of money.
I'll give it to you, all of it.
We really could get rid
of the body if you'd help me.
We could get rid of it
if you'd help me.
- Oh, I wish to God I'd never come here.
-
I'll get the car. You turn out the lights.
Well, go!
- Get in there and stay quiet.
-
Get in there!
Miss Deering, I hope you'll forgive me
for popping in at this time.
I happened to be out driving
with a friend when I noticed the lights.
I've heard the news about
Velma Cruther's death.
What a terrible thing.
She was such a loyal person.
I'm quite sure Miss Hollis
must be terribly upset about it.
I wonder if there's anything I can do?
It's very kind of you,
but, no, there isn't anything.
Charlotte was upset.
I've given her a sedative
and put her to bed.
- It was a dreadful shock for her.
- I'm terribly sorry.
Please give her my sympathy.
I'm sorry I can't ask you in.
It's quite all right.
I shouldn't have come.
It's very late. I just happened
to be passing, that was all.
- You understand.
- Yes, of course. Thank you, Mr. Wills. Good night.
Uh, by the way,
I understand you'll be leaving...
this house in a matter of days now,
you and your cousin.
Well, of course our plans
are indefinite now.
Naturally, they would be.
Mr. Wills,
you'll have to excuse me.
I must look in on Charlotte.
Excuse me, please.
Good night.
I don't think I can help you.
You can't help me?
I'm the one that's helping you!
Do you want me to wash my hands
of the whole thing?
Call the sheriff?
Is that what you want?
Well, all right, then.
Hey, turn your lights on.!
I must be the worst person
in the world...
to have killed Drew.
Will you please shut up?
Miriam, l-I can't touch him.
- Don't make me do it, Miriam.
- Get out!
Do what I say!
Well?
Will you stop that!
Miriam, they'll... they'll be
finding him soon...
and-and they'll be asking questions...
and l-l-I don't think
l- I could lie to 'em.
You-You-You... You'll have...
You'll have to tell 'em, Miriam...
I'm not able to answer questions.
'Cause they'll find out if you don't.
They'll find out, Miriam.
Damn you!
Now will you shut your mouth?
You'll do as I tell you.
And if I tell you to lie,
you'll do that too.
I'm never going to suffer
for you again.
Not ever.
Do you understand?
Get out.
Get out and go up to your room.
Go ahead!
I'm going to clean out the back,
and I'll be up in a minute.
Well, go on!
Go up to your room.
Well, go on.!
Go on.! Go on.!
Hush...
hush, sweet Charlotte.
I'm sorry to have
kept you waiting.
To your very good health.
- You look absolutely ravishing.
- Thank you, sir.
I bet Lazarus never felt
as good as I do.
To Venice in the spring.
Venice?
Well, as a matter of fact,
I'm not certain...
that I shall want to live in Europe.
I don't see that what you want...
has anything to do
with where we go.
You forget that Velma's tragic departure...
has allowed me to become
the senior partner of our little enterprise.
Are you sure you have the brains
to be the senior partner?
I, uh, don't think I follow you.
Who do you suppose
helped to set up cousin Charlotte...
for this little comedy by sending
her all those charming notes?
Well, naturallyJewel Mayhew.
Jewel?
Jewel Mayhew hasn't done a thing
in years and years...
except keep me in comfort
until her money ran out.
I sent Charlotte all those notes.
You...
And Jewel Mayhew?
My notes toJewel had
a more practical purpose.
The one good thing that ever happened
to me in this house...
was seeing Jewel Mayhew
go out to the summerhouse that night.
She paid me handsomely
for that indiscretion.
She paid you?
Jewel murdered her husband,
and you could actually bring yourself...
to make both her and Charlotte
suffer for it all these years?
Yes, darling.
That's exactly what I did.
Do you still feel
you have the imagination...
to be the senior member
of this partnership?
Evidently not.
I didn't know you had
such a dulcet baritone.
Well, you attended the wrong Sunday school
when I was a choirboy.
So, you see, my dear...
you've joined this game
somewhat later than you thought.
I did indeed.
If you'd known earlier,
would you have trusted me...
not to put real bullets
in that gun tonight?
No, ma'am, Miss Miriam.
I don't believe I would.
I would be careful
not to over-celebrate too soon.
We've still got one more show
to put on first thing in the morning.
- So early?
- Yes.
I asked the folks from the state institution
to come over here about 10:00.
You mean I shall have
to wring my hands...
in abject misery
and humiliation...
at the disgrace of having a member
of our fine old family...
committed to
the local madhouse?
Fine old family, indeed.
Sam Hollis was nothing but
a thieving, fat fraud. And...
-
- And furthermore...
he and John Mayhew...
were the biggest
two damn womanizers...
in the whole state of Louisiana.
Oh, dear, all that lovely money...
that Big Sam sweated
to get his hands on.
While we're spending it
like water...
Charlotte will be weaving lots
and lots of little baskets.
Oh, don't distress yourself, darling.
There's nothing wrong
with basket weaving.
Of course,
it never cured anybody...
but it is most therapeutic.
I can just see Charlotte's face
when those doctors at the institution...
call you in
to confirm their opinion.
When she sees me
walk in there tomorrow morning...
she'll let out such a scream
that they'll never let her out.
The way I heard it,
that Deering woman...
didn't have nothin'
but a flimsy peekaboo dress on.
Yeah, me too. I heard that.
She and that Dr. Drew...
you didn't have to guess
what was going on there.
Ya ask me...
you go to live with
a bloodthirsty maniac...
you're just asking for it.
She went on a real rampage.
I'll bet they'll never pin it on her,
just like back before.
Martha! Dora!
Ooh, whee, is this a day.
People dropping like flies
every which way.
What happened?
- Well, what, Nellie?
- You won't never in this world believe it, but it's so.
Jewel Mayhew... And I know
because I got it straight from Bessie...
- What? What?
- What happened?
- Jewel Mayhew just went
and dropped dead this morning.
- Oh, no.
She had her third stroke
and she was gone...
before they even got
the doctor on the phone.
- No!
- And just guess what brought it on.
- What?
It was when she heard what happened
over here last night.
Isn't that the most
extraordinary thing?
What is?
It was just a thought.
But suppose it was Jewel Mayhew...
who really murdered
her husband back in '27.
And supposing there was
a witness to the murder.
So?
That would explain why
she didn't try to collect...
on her husband's insurance.
She was afraid a routine investigation
might reveal her guilt...
thus enabling the witness...
to take advantage ofher silence
and blackmail her...
bleeding her white.
What does that give you?
Well, it would at least give us...
the timing ofJewel Mayhew's death and...
all this sort of bizarre irony,
wouldn't it?
Hey, you're not kidding, are you?
It would mean that Charlotte Hollis
has suffered all her life...
for a murder
she hadn't committed.
- You mean that's true?
- How should I know, old chap?
I'm just guessing.
Merely speculating, that's all.
Here she comes now.
-  It's Charlotte Hollis.
- Look. There she goes.
- Here she comes.
- Hey, Miss Hollis, over here.
Now give me another one.
Thank you, Miss Hollis.
Can I have one too, Miss Hollis?
She looks right pretty, don't she?
Sometimes they got their sane moments,
just like you or me.
Maybe so, but you ain't seen Dr. Drew...
or that Deering woman lying in there.
Oh, she has to be crazy as a loon.
- I wouldn't wanna be in her shoes.
- Y'all step back.
All right,
let's move back, everybody.
Miss Hollis, this letter's for you.
I think you've been waiting
a long time for it.
Sorry. Everybody has to move back.
Okay, let's go.
Step back.
- Stop pushing!
- Get back over there!
Hush, hush, sweet Charlotte
Charlotte, don't you cry
Hush, hush
sweet Charlotte
I'll love you till I die
Hush, hush
sweet Charlotte
Charlotte, don't you cry
Hush, hush
sweet Charlotte
I'll love you
Till I die