The Lost Bladesman
Guan Yunchang
Righteous and loyal
What ill fate that met him!
Would there even be another like hỉm?
The word "righteous/moral" composed of the word "sheep" and "self"
He's as kind as a sheep
General Guan stays true to his principles
He's kind and forgiving
His death is a tragedy
You are a wolf on the outside
But has a heart of a sheep
But this world belongs to wolves
World of wolves!
20 years ago....
Kingdom of Han invasions were widespread
This Cao Cao commanded a small troops
Fighting across the land to bring back peace and balance
Then Yuan Shao began to gather his own troops to betrayed our army
With their larger army,
Yuan Shao's commander attacked Boma City
Our small number of troops always fight with cunning and resiliency. Winning every battle
But seeing all the bloodshed,
Our lieutenants were losing their morale
I can lose my cites
But I cannot lose the heart of my men
At the time, Guan Yunchang was under my command
An individual capable of anything
Praised with strength of thousands
I knew very clearly
With this weapon at my disposable
It can determine the outcome of my battles
With him, I will not lose
Unfortunately...the 'ace card'
is in the hand of Liu Bei
The battle card of another, How can I play it?
Brother Yunchang..Let us eat
Eating at times like this sir?
- How are you?
- I want you to help me with one thing
I don't know if you'd agree brother
This Guan situation is weak. It doesn't matter what I say.
Then good, go and kill someone for me
If he's dead, then the fighting would stop?
Correct
Who?
No rush, lets eat then talk
No Rush
Lets kill then eat
The gate is almost breached, stop it
Yes
Sir, Guan Yu is of the enemy
How can he help us?
Anyone in my camp is considered my men
Letting him go is like releasing a tiger back into its jungle
Brother Yuanchang, the Cao's camp has 5000 troops
Can anyone stop you?
I need 30 elite men, who's with me?
This Guan and everyone follows different leaders,
we never fought side by side as brothers
But with battle of today,
Everyone ignored the danger head to help me
No different as if you guys are my brothers
If everyone would accept me
I would like to call you my brothers
My brothers, please accept one bow from me
This Zhang Liao likes to fight, who else?
- My brothers, kill!!!!
- Kill!!!!!
- Kill!!!
- Kill!!!!
- Kill!!
This is your men?
That's his men?
His highness arrives!
Hear his highness
Guan Yunchang is promoted to Han's Marquis of Hanshou rank
General Guan please bow to receive
Guan Yunchang has no talents? I cannot accepts awards without merits
Brother Yunchang,
You are a loyal person, only you can accept this
To see his highness being oppressed, but us subjects can't do anything
How can you call that loyalty?
So you feel like...his highness is being oppressed here?
It's always been that there'd be no sword in the palace
But nowadays everyone carries one
Is that not disrespect to the king?
It's chaotic out there, all must carry a sword to protect his highness
How can you say that’s disrespectful?
Under his heavenly's presence, How can you Cao Mèngdé not bow?
If you don’t like that, you don’t have to
Guan Yu dare not
What's the big deal anyway
Everyone go back to normal, No need to bow
Stand up!
Stand up..
Brother, the king has spoken
Brother Yunchang , please stand up
Official Guan
Stand up, no need to call me that
You saved my life
it's only right to call you that
You saved your own life. Don't look down on yourself
Sir Guan is a...big hero.
Saving my life is as if you allow me to be reborn.
Guan Yu is not like that
Me and Cao Cao must've misunderstood each other
Sir Guan...
Does have a misunderstand with me
I'll go back to work
Right.
Then how can you explain it sir Cao?
Drink some water first
Sir Guan,
This paddy used to be wild and abandoned
We came here, explored, planted barley
From Luoyang to Xuchang there are thousands
Within 6 years, nobody died from starvation
This Cao Cao is kinda good huh
The Liu's house is crumbling
So our Cao helped them fix it up
But then there’s people saying I tore down his house
Can anyone see this injustice?
You do have poetic words Sir Cao
What poetry, the truth is clear as day
The truth is Cao Cao borrowed his heavenly's word to do it
Using his heavenly's word
I've heard this
It's completely nonsense
It's really His highness that used my Cao Cao name to order such a thing
I know, some will always believe rumors
Even 2000 years later, there'd still be believers (lol. foreshadowing?)
But it's still nonsense rumors
Only 2 type will believe these stuff
1 is stupid, the other is bad guy.
Liu Bei is the bad one, and you're the dumb one.
Liu Bei is taking advantage of you!
Good! I like you brother
Dare to accept your act, dare to love and hate
Stay with me, work for me
If it weren't for 230 Liu members you held
You dare say those words?
Sir Guan
You never kill those that doesn’t deserve it
Right?
Cao Mengde, what are you talking about?
Hurry and work
Your Highness, Cao Cao make you do such labor work?
Sit down
Just look, even generals are out here
What?
You feel that officials, and heavenly bloodlines that
doing things like this, is out of place right?
But unusual times calls for unusual things
Don't stress too much over it
Your highness, you ever thing of leaving here?
These past decades,
Do you know how this King been living?
I move from this palace to that palace,
From this dog hole to this shit hole
I eat spoiled wheat and drink dirty water
And those around me,
They eat off of theirs fallen comrades
Even drinking their blood.
A world so big, but no place for a King to stay put
What kind of world is this?
Do you know what Cao Cao brought
the first time I met hỉm?
White steamed buns, and sizzling meat balls
And a warm cozy bed
Can buns and meatballs be traded for the Han Kingdom like that?
Cao Mengde never said he wants to be king
He doesn't believe that one King can change the world.
Your highness is of heaven's orders.
How can you change the world when you don't believe in the heaven's above
Potential, having potential can change the world.
My kingdom now belongs to Cao Cao
Because Cao Cao is stronger.
But I believe that I will be stronger than him one day
By then, Cao Cao will willingly present the kingdom back to me
If it's true about the heavenly's orders
Then sooner or later the kingdom will be mine.
Sir Guan...
Little Hầu,
How's your father? He's well?
He's a lot better, the doctor say he needs to continue taking medicine
Sir Guan
Are the rice cooked? I'll go check
It's okay sir, we're just early today
It's no rush big brother.
He is....
It's Cao Mengde, sir Cao
- You are...
- We'll return later
Let's go
They are....
They came to the city 1 month ago
Can't find jobs, nor any food
They in your kingdom. Can you think of something for them?
Don't worry, I'll take care of this situation
Big Brother Guan, He's an evil person.
Don't say that Lil Hầu
Lil Hầu
Sir Cao is our golden ticket
Take this and buy medicine dad, hurry!
Sir Cao,
Yunchang brother,
Goodbye
My ladies,
I've returned those dirty things
2nd Brother greets sisters
Qi Lan, why don't you greet 2nd brother,
With people like him,
there's no need for manners
Qi Lan, it's all Cao Cao's plan
Big brother always trust 2nd brother
You bout to marry into the Liu Family
Don't you trust Liu brother
You can't predict a person mind
Everyone knows that if Guan General
Wants to leave then
No one can stop him
I want you to meet up with Liu brother
Especially while Cao Cao is busy fighting with Yuan Shao at Xuchang
That's helping big brother Liu
Lil sis is right
2nd brother need not worry about us
Why not do it like Qi Lan said.
2nd brother
I beg you
Please go find big brother Liu
Qi Lan ,
2nd brother himself knows what to do
You and him are from the same town
You of all should know who he is very well
Please give Guan Yu for cannot comply
Please excuse me
Then why are you here?
Not tired today?
Not tired!
Let us rest for a bit
Okay.
This are the things I painted today
Is it pretty?
Check it yourself
Do it more careful
Let me help you
- Mom...
- My daughter is home?
- Dad...
- You're home?
- Are you tired daughter?
- Not tired
Heard the cow carriage guy did it
You didn’t know?
He ran away early this morning
Alright, stop gathering here
Disperse
General Liu is here, we can live in peace now
General Liu
Look sis, isn’t that the cow carriage guy?
Don't speak nonsense
The guy is now big General Guan Yunchang
Our peasants can live in peace with the General here
General Liu
This is our daughter
Little lady..
Right!! Cheers to everyone
Cheers!
Cao army is here...
2nd brother, hurry
Dad...Mom...
You say that unofficial wife of Liu Bei
doesn’t know Guan Yu
from her home town Hedong ?
Correct
Any news about Liu Bei?
Liu Bei's fighting Yuan Shao
In battle of Boma, Guan Yu slain general Yan Liang
Yuan Shao got upset and wants to kill Liu Bei
Then is he dead?
For now there isn’t any news
Come on!
Get up son
Dad, lets play again
I told you many times.
General, you are from Hedong right?
Yes
Do you know how to cook Hedong food?
No!
You know general
Yeah, general know for sure
Hedong food has strong flavors, suitable with my liquor
Here, try it
Master brewed it himself, its called (don't understand) Liquor
Just invitation to drink, why prepared troops outside?
Afraid that Guan Yu will attack?
There isn't enough supply for the war
I ordered that supplies couldn't be use to brew liquor
If we brew liquor , penalty is 'head-off'
Then what about the person that drinks it?
Guilty as well!
Then it's General Cao that want to use liquor to kill
Looks like you're scared to drink
Having liquor to drink, why scared?
Good!
General Guan
Us two sitting here drinking and enjoying,
Isn't that against the norm a little bit?
General makes the law, I don't follow it, that is normal.
Well said, General Guan
Good food is rare in this chaotic time
It's the best we have of your home town food
Try it
Do you miss home?
I do not have a home
I let all Liu family members home already
Commanded Zhang Liao to take 50 men and escort them
I respect your act of righteousness
Guan General say that I’m righteous
I dare not accept it
I said you acted righteously
Not saying that you are righteous
Lets just say I'm a nobody
Come, General Guan
Drink with me
I don’t understand one thing
Why are you lowering yourself like this
If it brings me days of peacefulness
Then I'm always willing to lower myself
Guan Yu only know a few barbaric fighting skills
How can that bring tranquility?
Plus the Cao's camp has many talents
Me staying here will only be a bother
Then what about your brothers Liu Bei and Zhang Fei
Everyone knows brother Liu Bei moral
Cause we don't have hatred here?
Also no love
Then its easy
Guan Yunchang join my side, you can have anything
How’s that
You released the Liu Family, I'm indebted to you
I know how to repay it
But in the end Liu Bei is still my sworn brother
When there is news of him , I leave right away
If General Cao thinks that it's like letting a tiger back home
Then its best you kill me
Why are you only loyal to Liu Bei?
If I, Guan Yu, only sway with the wind
Me staying here will bring you trouble eventually
Well said
Only liquor can release sorrow
One's life doesn’t have much chance of drinking, singing
I wrote that line.
Did you know that?
You are not the first to break my liquor law
Who else is there?
The grandson of Kong Qiu (Confucius)
General Kong Rong ?
What general?
Kong Rong giving a pear is easy
But him giving up a bowl of liquor
Is harder than me convincing you to stay
Come
Drink up
Alright, I'm here, thank you
You said you don't have a home!
I'll gift one to you
Would you like to stay brother?
You say this is the place?
This is it!
Thank you
In your heart, you never forgot Qi Lan right?
For so long, my heart has been empty
Why not let me have a good dream?
Your heart is empty, how can you have a good dream?
Sir, the potent is in the food
The potent lasts 4 hours
I've paralyzed the girl using pressure points
Before dawn, no one is allow close
Sister, please respect yourself
It's only a dream
No need to be afraid
Even so, I cannot be disrespectful
Even in a dream, you dare not love me?
You weren't scared to kill for me in the past
I only killed to save you
If you won't say it, how can I know what you think?
If you won't say it..., how can I know... what you think?
Let me know....what you are thinking...
Outrageous !
I only know that you're my sister-in-law
Get down here!
How dare you!
Who are you?
General Liu sent me here
Sir Liu is at Ruyang...Yuan Shao's Camp
General Guan, I cannot live
General Guan...
I want to see Cao Cao
General Cao left the city to handle things
Don't know when he's back.
Tell General Cao, Guan Yu say goodbye!
He wants to go, let him go
Sir, that is not very wise
I've made a promise to him before
Now that the battle stage is set
But that's the exact reason
We have to discuss carefully
How to handle the Yuan Shao situation
Now, Liu Bei is with Yuan Shao's Camp
If we let Guan Yunchang go, that’s like letting a tiger grow wings
The advisor is right sir
Guan Yu knows we poisoned him
For sure he is upset with us
I already said it
If he wants to leave let him leave
You all hear me clearly?
You said that
One of Yuan Shao's General wants to defect?
General Trương is smart and brave,
But is not seen as important, so he defected to us
Not seen as important then you defect?
Don't know what's the guy thinking
You recommended him, you take care of it
Thank you sir
Yuan Shao is about to invade
Sun Quan from Jiangdong will take advantage of this
What must we do?
Select 5000 to invade Jiangdong
Send 39 assassins to eliminate Gen. Tôn Gia
Then proceed as you said
Sister
Hello!
We can head out
Thank you for your gifts Brother Guan
Thank you big brother Guan
Stand up...
Everyone stand up
Everything here is from General Cao
If you wanna thank someone
Thank Sir Cao
Sir Guan, we were just there
General Cao is done with our residence permit
It's all done
That's good
Big brother Guan, bring this with you on the trip
Keep it to take care of your dad
Remember to listen to your mom! Be good!
Everyone take care of yourself!
Brother Guan...
Let us go sister-in-law
- Take care
Wait...go go....
Look, it's still fresh
- No thank you.
- Just take it
I don't really need it
How much for these?
This?
Exit the carriage
Travel papers?
I am Guan Yu
How can I believe that
just because you say it?
2nd brother...
General, everything okay?
The lady must get out also
She has to get out too?
Please don’t make it hard for me
Sorry to bother sister
Kong Xiu of Dongling,
by his highness order, To capture Guan Yu
2nd brother...
Hurry!
Cao Cao made me a promise
If Guan Yu wants to leave
Then you must let me pass
That's between you and General Cao
I'm just following orders
Is it Cao Cao or someone else
That wants me dead?
Order to Kill came from the King
Why must you kill I, Guan Yu?
Can't object the king's order
Looks like things calmed down
We'll head North tomorrow
I won't bother you further.
2nd brother,
What happened today
No one wants that to happen.
I should only kill on the battlefield
Seeing how determined he was, you had to do it
I know you have moral and values
But the heaven gave you this gift of martial arts
To let you restore order, fight off evil
Guan Yu is just a normal martial artist, not deserving like you said
Sister-in-law
Keep this knife
In case of dangers
But you saved my many times
Times I've killed is even more
It's almost dawn, lets go to we can make it
Careful sister, stay close to me
Han Fu
Still remember me?
Big Brother Guan
How are you now?
This is the wife of Liu Bei
Sir Guan, how are things?
Can't be compared to how you're doing
I think all the subordinates here
All of them are your brothers
It's all because of Dong Zhuo
I'm like this after he started that fire
How's your situation?
No matter how hard I try, it's not like before
Such a shame!
Everyone knows,
weapons from your family are the best
May be they were too good,
Causing my family to be like this
If it weren't for brother Guan's help
Then it's not only an arm that I'm missing.
Chaotic times, nobody can predict the future.
To be honest.
I want to return to Brother Liu Bei
Why don't you and other brothers
follow big brother Liu as well
I won't go.
I've followed the 2 general for 10 odd years
Also, I'm not as daring to kill anymore
Then I wont force you
Today, I'm came with a favor
Hoping you could lend us a boat to escort sister back.
Brother Guan, why must we keep fighting?
Haven't this country got enough deaths?
Back in the day we fought
Only wanting to seek peace
Every since General Cao ruled till now
Things have been good.
You can even call it peaceful
You are now under Cao Cao?
I've just a normal person
General Cao only wants me,
To live righteously
Can you let me go just for today?
Brother Guan
I'm no match for you
But orders are orders
Brother Guan,
Why didn't you dodge it?
You know it's poisoned
Because we are brothers
You are not my opponent little brother
So I allow you one move
This move,
Ends our ties!
Why won't you fight back?
Because we are brothers
How can I kill you with my own hands?
Meng Tan...
Big brother...
I will kill him...
Kill him....
2nd brother...
Run!
Hurry!
After them!
2nd brother...
Sister
Sister-in-law
It's alright now.
I will kill you with this sword
To revenge my brother
There's no pity in my death
Let my sister go...
2nd brother...
Who are you?
Everyday you come to visit me?
General
Who are you?
General..
General's awake
I'm a monk here at the temple
Buddhist name is Pu Jing.
Thank you for saving me
Please sit!
I've only help with the medicine
These past days,
Lady Qi Lan took care of you
Praying for you day and night
Pray that Buddha would look over you
That's debt
Your poison has soaked into your bones
Sorry that I'm incapable
I can only cure the outside.
Later on with cold days and rainy nights,
You will be in deep pain
Just being alive is good
Live you must, live righteously
One thing tho... don’t live in suffering and pain
I, Guan, don’t have the smarts
Only know to seek pain and suffering
Not quite.
Sufferings sometimes seeks us
But that's OK
Where's General Guan
He asked me to escort you to General Liu
Where did 2nd brother go?
He did not say
The general only asked the way to head North.
I think...he wants too
Divert the trailing enemy North
So that you'll make it back safely
You are Guan Yu?
And you are Bian Xi, the one that killed 5000 innocents in Peng Chau?
It's 5000 rebels
There's no pity in their deaths.
I've heard you were a rebel once.
Had to do it, when you don't have anything to eat
But even so you won't have anything to eat
You see how good I eat now?
You must right your wrongs
You're just like me
- Not the same
I don't kill to make a living
Wrong!
You're just like me!
Kill!!!!
Yuan Shao's 10000 men arrived at Guandu
Hundreds of ships on the rive
They're boasting , making noise
Looks like an all attacked, lion praying on rabbits
This Yuan Shao is barbaric, wanna be a lion?
Divide up into small formations and ambush him
Even the mightiest lion can't handle that
Where is Liu Bei troops?
Ruyang, only 1000 men
Liu Bei's at Ruyang, why's Guan Yu heading North?
Bian Xi of Sishui,
All died under Guan Yunchang's blade
Can you guys tell me why?
The four generals acted on orders to kill traitor Guan Yu
Orders? Following whose orders?
I gave an order, but that's to let him go.
You guys don't understand, or want to object.
My Lord, I gave the order.
I gave the order...
Why is everyone bowing?
Perhaps they wanna betray me
Sir, Tuần Do didn’t meant to object your order
But Guan Yunchang is too powerful. Can't release the tiger back to its jungle
You're bowing too, you wanna betray me too?
Sir, the battle's about to be fought. Please
Only kill I, Tuần Do.
Only have to kill you right, right?
Sir, his general crime doesn’t deserve death
Better have others let you down, don’t let down others
It was you that said so
What did I say?
Better have others let you down, don’t let down others
Right, I did say that
Stand up!
You guys are right, I'm wrong
Guan Yu said there's no love here, he's right
He's so right
Give me your hand!
Can't control my men.
How can you control a nation?
Can't be control cause there's love here
Please, where's the court house?
The court's closed
I heard that the official here is a greedy official
Even done things against the law
He drove away almost all the citizens in this city
You're mistaken
Because there's trouble here,
That’s why they left
I want to find that official, not you
It's the same thing
What’s the relationship between you and him?
I was his 'Vice Official'
But last month I chopped him dead
With his highness kindness,
I, Wang Zhi, is now the official of Xingyang
You're the one drove the citizens away
Allow me to ask, on your way here, killing men and generals
Causing chaos, causing citizens trouble
Wang Zhi is here to stop you
Cause I don't know anyone else to suffer
You're a good official
Never mind it!
Sword skill is not bad!
Sword skill's mediocre, it's the sword
The sword is good, but your will is not strong
I know!
Forget it! You're tired!
I'm not tired!
Continue to fight and you'll lose your life, still wanna fight?
Delaying you even just a little bit further
Worth it.
You believe that I, Guan Yu, would hurt the innocents?
These days, can't never tell
Cao Cao said he'd let me go
Then order to kill me
Who's the unpredictable one?
The law's been laid down
If this Guan did wrongs, I will accepts my punishment
Wang Zhi,
Let me finish this task,
I'll return to Xingyang
And take your punishment
You don't have to return cause your task won't be completed
The other day, a monk and a lady...
going toward Ruyang...
I myself lead them to Nam Dương road
invited them to Xingyang
Where's that lady?
I've used swallow bird to report their location
Go to Xu Du and surrender
Must hurry!
If not
They will starve to death
Where?
Tell me, else I won't have mercy
No need!
It's your fault
Lets go back
I am Guan Yu
Looking for a lady with several monks
Have you seen them?
He killed General Wang
Let me kid go!
- Devil...
- It's him...
Let's kill him....
Kill him to revenge General Wang
Kill him...
Kill him to revenge General Wang....
Wang Zhi doesn’t kill innocents
We've found Lady Qi Lan outside the city
Alright, we can go
Open the gate!
Stop...
Can't kill them
They're all Wang Zhi's people
No matter how much I ask they won't say
the location of Lady Qi Lan
Only when General Cao arrived, they said it
These people must die.
General Guan,
We can  let them live
But if this gets out
the lord would have a bad rep
A bad rep for thousands of years
Whoever dares I'll kill that person
Looks like you can't become a hero
Just give up
I said Whoever dares I'll kill that person
Alright, General Guan doesn't want to kill
Then let them go
Everyone, if what happened today gets out
There's only one word
Kill!
Up to you
Brother Yunchang
You keep being the hero.
Bad guy? Let me
Luoyang was a hell hole
But they saw daylight
Your deed was too big to be measure
Unfortunately, outside of Luoyang is still hell hole
But the hell that you speak of, is only a way to look at things
Heaven or hell
Is all up oneself
I wish I can build a heaven
But perhaps it's not my time
Frankly, if thinking too far about anything
Is like creating hell for yourself
Wants me to think simple and not far ahead. That’s hard!
There's heaven within hell and vice versa
Please rethink carefully and then decide
Then I'll rethink about it
The horses are fed. Thank you sir
I wish to say goodbye
Thank you for pointing things out to me
Thank you
Good bye!
Sit
To you, am I heaven or hell?
Heaven or hell all comes from what you think
Back then, when you wanted to keep me
You only need me to kill for you
How much must I kill for you?
Guan Yu is a hero.
Are there any heroes that doesn't kill in chaotic times like this
How much must I kill?
Yuan Shao has 20 thousands troop, kill 2 thousand
Then he will lose
What about after Yuan Shao is defeated?
How would run put order to the world?
Put Ru Ngủ Tôn at Giang Đông.
Tây Lương troops will watch the seas
Then what
After that..
Unify the whole country, take a few years off.
I think...the world would be in peace
Are you sure about that?
Can't be.
Human values are not enough
You need laws
But human to human,
If there's no moral terms, where's can you find laws?
In this world hatred keeps piling, where’s principle in that?
Killing Yuan Shao's 2000 men,
Isn't that piling up hatred?
That's the small price that must be pay
What if Guan Yu can kill Yuan Shao
Great, that way,
You saved 2000 people
Let me know, where is Yuan Shao?
So you will help?
I can't promise
After Yuan Shao's killed, I want to live normally
I don't believe you
A hero can never live a normal life
After it's done, Liu Bei will not forgive you
You stay and come back to Xu Du with me.
Brother Liu can see through things, he's just.
If it's must be, then he won't force it
If we're talking
bout me staying here, Guan Yu cannot comply
I'll rather go home to tend stocks and grow crops
So?
Okay, I'll promise you.
Sir, Guan Yu's really staying?
You know why good horses doesn't eat re-grown grass?
Re-grown grass's not as fresh
right
Liu Bei's time is up
I, Cao Cao
is still on my way up!
Sister!
Ahead is Huang He River (Yellow River)
Guan Yu wish to withdraw
2nd brother...
Sister...
2nd brother....
Thousand steps of goodbye, yet we still must part
When you were hallucinating, I wasn't
How you feel...
I, Qi Lan knows
When I reach Ruyang, I'll ask brother Liu
to be married to you
Nonsense!
Sister, you're of Liu household, how can you say that?
Today, I, Qi Lan,  willingly wants to marry Guan Yu
You risked your life for Qi Lan on this journey
Qi Lan seen it clearly
Back then, you had to murder for me, why didn't you let me know?
Is it
because you never loved me?
If you do have feelings for me
Liu Brother would give us his blessing
- Come back with me.
- What if I don't go back?
Would you still love me?
Goodbye!
You cannot work for Cao Cao
Put it down!
You betray Liu Brother
just because one girl doesn't love you?
Guan Yu never thought of that
Only when Brother Liu's on the throne, the country can be united
If Cao Cao's in control, there'd be more chaos
I only want to good deeds for the people
Must I, Guan Yu, be dead?
Looks like Guan Yu have to die!
Sister, please tell Big Brother Liu,
Guan Yu is dead.
I'm sorry
You have no fault in this
Worry not sister-in-law
Guan Yu will never wrong brother Liu
Take care!
Sir, want me to go check on things?
Let it be, heroes cannot get past beauty
No rush!
Protect the lord
Who ordered you?
Who?
Chop him!
Where are they?
It was my order!
Letting Guan Yunchang go back...
The world will be in turmoil
You think I dare not kill him?
Then you be sure to kill him
If not from today on
The world will surely be in turmoil
Okay!
I’ll be sure to kill him
Your highness, lets go
You can't leave
You must have to kill Guan Yu?
Can't object the king
Can't object the king?
You no longer wish to live?
My life's been lost a long time ago
You're the same
Brother Guan, don't force me
Get lost! I'll kill whoever's in my way
I'll chop whoever touches Guan Yunchang
Brother Yunchang, don't fight anymore
This scoundrel is not worth it
Can't object the king? I despise it
I'll chop you dead
Stop!
I am of the heaven's, you can't kill me
You're of the heaven's? I'll bring justice in the name of heaven
Guan Yunchang
The king cannot be killed
If the king is dead
Everyone'll have a reason to rebel
Then even more will die
Do you not understand this?
Because of a woman,
A woman that doesn't love you,
You turn your back on the world?
She is your sister-in-law
Another man's lady
There's nothing for you, even if she's alive
I promise, when the country's at peace
I myself will kill this scoundrel
I, Cao Mengde, said it and will do it
Cao Cao
This kingdom...
You cannot bring it to peace
Sister...
Let us go.
Today I want the world to know
It was the other wolves that killed Guan Yu
You're speaking of Sun Quan?
Sun Quan, is just one
There's Liu Bei...Kong Ming also...
I want the world to know,
It's them that killed Guan Yu
Looks like war is inevitable
Of course, with Guan Yu gone.
Shu - Wu, who wins who loses
Cannot be said yet
Even when someone's dead
Sir Cao can still uses him
I never said I was a sheep!