Something's wrong with it.
Could you check the magazine?
Let's have a look at it.
Maybe the release is stuck.
I'll replace it. Won't take a minute.
Just hold on.
Don't move!
Don't breathe, don't hit the alarm!
We want guns and ammo!
Stay there and you won't get hurt!
Freeze! Make a move and you're dead!
You, drop your gun, slowly.
You, put your hands on top of your head.
Get down on your knees.
Down on your knees!
Stay!
And, you, get on the counter.
Slowly.
Stay.
Hands on top of your head.
Okay, fellows.
The tip paid off. I got them. Come on in.
Roger.
Doug, your buddy Forrest
doesn't answer from Tampa.
You want me to keep on trying?
I'll try him later.
-By the way, is this your first flight?
-Yes, it is.
A helicopter is like a woman,
a beautiful woman.
It's very delicate.
You like music?
Imagine you're dancing a waltz.
I feel sick.
I don't think helicopters are for me.
Are you sure?
Why not? It's so easy. Come on.
This is Doug Bennet.
I'm calling from New York.
May I speak to Steve Forrest, please?
He's still flying? Okay, I'll call him back.
-What's going on?
-He asked for it!
Let him go.
You bastard, you're worse than he is.
That's the only picture I have
of my friend Steve.
Just get rid of him.
I'm sorry about that, Steve.
Tampa Flying School. Can I help you?
Hi, this is Bennet again. Has he landed?
One moment, please.
Hi.
Who is it?
Come on.
This is Steve Forrest's answering service.
I am out right now.
So please leave me your name, number,
and message after the beep.
Very funny, Steve.
My favourite voice.
Listen, Joe Garret got out of jail yesterday.
Why are you calling me?
It's the only case we never solved
in our whole career.
It's your career, Blue Eyes.
I resigned two years ago.
You're not getting me back
until they give me permission...
to use my fists on bad guys.
I've got no time for Boy Scouts.
Listen, about Garret.
After he left jail,
he got in touch with someone in Miami.
He's on his way down there
this very minute.
Yeah? I got news for you.
Ten of my students are having tests
in the air next week...
and you're trying to tell me
about an old robbery.
Robbery? The robbery. $20 million, Steve.
Even if it was $200 million,
my students' tests still come first.
Come on, Steve.
Garret's on flight Eastern 181.
He'll land in 45 minutes.
That'll give you enough time
to get there and trail him. I thought--
You thought wrong! Over and out.
Keep on driving.
Get the wallets, the jewellery! Hurry up!
This money is all I've got.
No, there's nothing in here. Just documents.
Okay, stop right up here.
Come on, let's go.
All right!
Calm down, folks!
We're not far from the police station.
I'll take you there, okay?
-Chief?
-Come on in, Lyon.
One of the passengers is missing.
He must have slipped.
-What makes you think that, Lyon?
-His bags are there, he ain't.
Great thinking. Go through the bags
and see if you can come up with a name.
Done that already.
This is a release from San Quentin.
The guy's name is Garret.
He got out of the pen two days ago.
-Garret. That name mean anything to you?
-Afraid not, Captain.
Didn't think it would.
Joe Garret was convicted...
of robbing the Detroit First National Bank
of $20 million.
He was arrested immediately
by two real cops, friends of mine.
He served nine years,
and he never snitched on his accomplices.
I wonder what brings him to Miami
in such a hurry.
Sooner or later, everybody comes to Miami.
The sun's always shining.
Right, the sun's always shining.
Hey, have you got a light?
Why, I hardly touched you.
You could at least say hello to me.
I'm sorry.
I guess I don't know my own strength.
-I didn't mean to hurt you.
-Bill, looks like you found some company.
Friend, cut the sunshine. I'm a nightbird.
He's dead.
Dead? I'm innocent!
I wanna talk to my attorney!
Richie, get two ambulances.
One for the hospital, one for the morgue.
Com. Risner just won't get off my case.
The minute we heard Garret was in town,
we tried to pick him up.
-But we missed him. Result: Garret's dead.
-Yeah, I heard.
We at the Bureau
are taking an interest in the case.
Why don't you let me handle this thing?
I can't let Risner force me into retirement.
You know things haven't been going well
at the station with me lately.
Risner likes to remind me of that.
As far as I'm concerned,
you're welcome to work on the case.
As long as you don't get in the way
of my boys.
I want the Bureau to work on it,
but with the agents of my choice.
-Who do you have in mind?
-Doug Bennet and Steve Forrest.
I don't know the names.
They're with the New York office.
Class agents.
A long time ago, when I was up north,
they were on the police force with me.
To be exact,
they're the ones that caught Garret.
What do you want me to do?
Lend me Bennet and Forrest.
They can pass as city cops.
Undercover?
Can do. I'll call the New York office today.
Agent Bennet, the Chief wants you
in his office on the double.
You wanted to see me, sir?
You interested in handling the Garret case?
Yes, sir. I had him trailed
from the minute he got out of jail.
And naturally, you asked for help
from your old buddy Forrest.
But because he's still upset,
he turned you down.
You got it, sir.
-In the meantime, they killed Garret.
-Right.
Which leads us to believe that
his accomplice and $20 million...
is somewhere in the Miami area.
Your assignment is to fly to Tampa.
Convince Forrest to work with you.
You'll be taking orders
from your old acquaintance...
Capt. Tanney of the Hialeah Police.
All right, sir.
By the way,
how are you gonna convince him?
I'll twist his arm a little.
One more step and I'll break your legs.
Hi, Steve. Long time no see.
Let's keep it that way.
What a way to greet your buddy.
Save your breath. You're wasting your time.
Look, Steve,
I came to ask you to come on back.
Are you deaf?
You're wasting your time. Go home.
Steve, you're gonna change your mind.
No way, Blue Eyes.
Not even if I tell you they killed...
our old chief, Capt. Tanney?
When? Who?
It could have been the same guys
who bumped off Garret.
-Let's go.
-Yeah, let's go.
Funny. After seven years in prison...
Garret comes down here
to get the $20 million.
Instead, he gets killed.
Life's strange, isn't it, Steve?
Charlie, isn't it exciting
getting away from New York...
and the constant threat of violence?
Keep on rolling, pal.
Okay, monkey face, give me the loot.
Wake up. He's talking to you.
Steve, wake up! He's talking to you!
Freeze. Get them up there!
You two up front there!
Don't try it!
Freeze! Stop!
Sit there.
Just like old times.
Back in the saddle again.
I'm gonna leave you my bag
and these punks to take in by yourself.
-Why? Where are you going?
-To visit Tanney's widow.
What's the hurry? We can go later.
Sorry, Doug, I prefer to go now.
-Hi, Mrs. Tanney.
-Steve.
There was a time when you called me Carol.
Come in.
Thank you.
I heard what happened and I...
Yes. Very kind of you. Thank you.
-Sit down.
-Thank you.
I'm going to miss him so much.
He was so sweet.
His loss is a real tragedy.
Intelligent, sensitive.
Yes, a real loving companion.
That is so true. I wrote it on his tombstone.
He was always so happy.
Happy?
He jumped and licked and gnawed,
pawed all over the place.
Jumped?
And he was so polite.
-Polite? If you say so.
-He never messed on the carpets.
He'd wait at the back door...
so he could be let out
and do it in the garden.
You've got an outhouse?
Steve, he'll be so happy to see you.
-See me?
-He's coming home early tonight.
Listen, Carol...
I know when these things happen
it comes as a terrible shock...
-but I'm a bit--
-That'll be him. Excuse me.
Hello? Yes, honey.
Not those young hoods again?
It was Doug? Tell him hi from me.
Honey, you'll never guess who's here.
No, it'll be a surprise.
You're going to be late?
Never mind, honey. Bye.
He said he'll be...
Steve? Isn't that strange.
Can I help?
-Did they take anything from you?
-No, thanks.
-Do you wanna file charges?
Can I help you, sir? Can I help you?
Sir, wait a minute. Where are you going?
Hi, Steve. What took you so long?
I was waiting for you.
Me, too.
-Steve?
-Yes.
Yes, what? I'm Steve. Hi, Chief.
-How you doing?
-All right.
You know,
this bastard told me you were dead.
Doug, you didn't have to go that far
to help me out.
What are you talking about?
Police Commissioner's giving me
a hard time.
If I don't solve the Garret case,
he will make me retire.
And after all these years on the force,
I wouldn't know what to do.
What can I do for you?
I don't have the guts to ask you,
but I really need your help.
He does.
Will you shut up? I decide for myself.
If I had the students' tests
postponed for a while...
Okay, I'll help you, Chief.
We're having a lot of robberies
in the north end of the city.
We've got a BOLO out for two white males
operating a 1984 dark blue Ford.
No other info on that.
Now I want you to meet
a couple of new cops. Stand up, fellows.
This is Jess Donnel and L.A. Wray.
Look a little grown-up to be rookies.
Hey, funny boy, what are you laughing at?
It's not his fault.
He was born that way, right?
"Born that way"? Yeah, that's right.
All right, guys, let's hit the streets.
You two guys wait.
Remember, nobody here's
supposed to know who you are.
Just go out on patrol, handle anything
that goes down in your sector.
But remember,
your main object is the Garret case.
Here's the keys to the address
where you'll be staying.
It's small but comfortable.
What's with this collection you've got here?
Terry Clay was a good cop.
He was killed about three weeks ago.
He was very close to getting his hands
on the expressway robbers.
But he had this thing for working solo.
-Put in $20.
-Yeah, I was going to.
That's yours.
I just put it in.
Put in another $20.
-Really?
-For me.
-Why don't you put it in yourself?
-Forgot my wallet. I'll pay you back later.
Come on, won't you ever change?
Always generous with my money.
I don't know how we're gonna meet tonight.
It's just impossible.
You know, I'm a little sore at you also.
That guy. What's his name?
With all those muscles?
I'll tell you something...
I bet you're here to talk about
that guy Garret in Room 5, right?
Right, you win the bet.
Hey, look here.
He registered under his own name.
Anyone visit him?
-Visit who?
-Garret.
Well, besides the cockroaches, no.
What did he do?
Nothing. Unless you call coming in
and going out...
and coming in again doing something.
You know what I mean?
No, we don't. You wanna tell us?
A guy comes in and checks in, right?
What does he do?
-What did Garret do?
-He goes out, he comes in.
He sleeps, etcetera, etcetera.
It's the "etceteras, etceteras"
that interests us, considering he was killed.
What do you know about him?
-You must know something.
-Not me. Listen here.
-He wasn't killed in this hotel.
-We know that.
-Did he make any calls?
-A bunch of them.
-Are they registered?
-No way.
He used the public phone over there, right?
-Yeah, that's right. How did you know that?
-One of my many talents.
Who did he talk to?
Listen, rule number one
in this business is you never...
never listen to guests' phone calls.
-Come on, get the key. Show us the room.
-Yes, sir, right away.
Pardon me.
This way.
This is Room 5.
What happened in here afterwards?
-Afterwards when?
-After they found him dead.
Anything you didn't connect with Garret.
There was one thing.
I don't think you'd find
that very interesting.
Why don't you try us?
After the cops left,
some guy checks in this room.
-Were all the other rooms full?
-That's the point.
There was Room 3, Room 7.
This guy insists on Room 5.
I mean, he insisted.
What else did he do?
He checks into the room, locks himself in...
and doesn't come out until the next day.
He paid and split.
-Weird, isn't it?
-What's so weird about it?
He didn't even sleep.
He left that room cleaner when he left
than when he first came in.
No kidding? Describe the guy.
B-l-G.
Big. I mean, a brute. Indian.
-Did he sign the register?
-Of course, silly. Sitting Bull.
At the time,
I thought the name was very familiar.
Do you happen to know him?
Very funny.
Do you remember
anything unusual about him?
Muscle upon muscle upon muscle.
Okay, we understand you like muscles.
What else?
Has to be an ex-fighter.
I know, I could spot one anywhere.
All these guys look like heavyweights to me.
Yeah, but our guy's a carpenter.
A carpenter.
What makes you think he's a carpenter?
He took the whole room apart
and then put it back together.
-He's a real pro.
-What the hell was he looking for?
Maybe he's a cockroach collector.
Chief, do you know a carpenter around here
who used to be a wrestler?
Freeze! Hold it!
Let's give him a hand.
-They got you mad, Sitting Bull?
-I didn't need your help.
I know. We need yours.
Why?
What were you doing in Garret's room?
Follow me.
I don't like to be seen
talking to Gen. Custer's boys.
By the way, the name's Charro.
Okay, Charro,
what were you doing in Garret's room?
You were in there for 24 hours.
Dismantling and putting things
back together. That's my job.
-What were you looking for?
-$20 million would be a good bet.
All the money in the world
ain't worth a damn compared to a friend.
Very touching.
Go on.
All I found...
was a screwdriver and a hammer.
-Maybe they didn't belong to Garret.
-Maybe.
Okay, what's the story
between you and him?
We shared a cell in San Quentin.
He saved my life once.
-To pay him back, you stabbed him?
-No. I read the news in the paper...
and decided to do a little investigating
on my own. I felt I owed him.
-Did you see him before he got killed?
-Yeah. He needed money.
Some punks ripped him off on a bus.
Figures. What else?
He said a guy who pulled the robbery
with him had to be here in Miami.
Garret wanted his share.
He knew how to get it because
he had the goods on the guy who has it.
Yeah, and unfortunately
the guy found him first.
And shut him up for good.
Then took the goods with him, right?
No, Garret was too smart.
He went to the appointment empty-handed.
He hid whatever he had on the guy so well...
even I couldn't find it.
Don't suppose he told you the guy's name?
No.
Okay, Charro, thanks.
If you think of anything else,
give us a call at this number.
If you find Garret's killer, let me know.
I have a few things I'd like to say to him.
Okay, Charro, you do the rest.
If Charro finds Garret's
killer before we do...
there won't be much left for the autopsy.
Route 31, north,
between the bridge and the gas cisterns.
Hurry. I mean, hurry.
They're blasting at me with cannons.
Hold them off, honey. This is Car 27.
We're on our way. Hit it.
Freeze! Hands up!
You, get up! Hands on your head!
Turn around, slowly.
Okay, down on your knees.
Stop.
You, left hand behind your back.
Right hand.
Is she okay?
-Everything all right?
-Yeah, thanks to you.
Good.
Not as bad as I thought.
Broken window, a few scratches.
Hey, congratulations. You hit the jackpot.
-What do you mean?
-You get the $50,000.
The reward from the Truckers' Association
for catching them.
Hey, we're rich.
Yeah, now you can pay me back
what you owe me.
I'd have paid you back anyway.
And apart from
the Governor's congratulations...
and the City's, of course, you also get this:
a cheque for $50,000.
Which, of course, you can't keep
since cops can't accept rewards.
Nuts, I really wanted to get a Porsche.
And there goes the down payment
on the new chopper.
We've got a better idea.
Now that'll take care
of the Clay kids' college.
Guys, we all thank you
from the 8th Precinct.
-Okay, it's from all of us.
-Since we can't have it.
Okay, you can go, guys.
-Jess.
-Yes, Chief.
You're off today.
But tonight, put on your best threads
and go to Club Violins.
You'll meet a C.I. there
who's got something on Garret for you.
How do we recognise him?
He'll recognise you. You just be there.
See you later.
It's gonna be tough on you.
Why?
Putting on your best threads
and looking human.
Speak for yourself, ET.
Gentlemen, what will you have?
I'll have a piña colada,
lots of piña, no rum.
Blonde Mary for me.
We ain't got no blonde Mary.
I've got a red Kitty, a brunette Barbara...
a black Diane, or a yellow Mingto:
a gorgeous thing, just in from Hong Kong.
How long have you been doing this?
Just fix it with tomato juice, vodka,
and pepper.
Oh, you mean a Bloody Mary.
Come on, I'm anti-violence.
What's in a name?
Got you.
We're here, where's the informer?
How come they're always late?
Informers? Rats is more like it.
Would you mind passing me
the peanuts, please?
Sure.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Not only are they always late,
they smell like a latrine.
That's because they're scared.
It's the adrenalin.
Considering the kind of work they do,
it's not surprising.
To our meeting.
As you can see, not all informers are late.
And they don't all smell like a latrine.
And as for rats, I won't even discuss it.
My name's Irene.
-Hi, I'm Jay.
-And I'm Wray.
To avoid suspicion, I think one of you
should ask me to dance.
-You, twinkle toes.
-All right.
-Madam, would you care to dance?
-Love to.
You know, I have the feeling
we've met somewhere before.
I don't think so.
You look familiar.
Were you in Boston two years ago?
No.
Funny.
How come an attractive woman like you
ends up in a job so...
Raunchy?
Yeah. No, I mean dangerous.
That's a long story.
Maybe someday I'll tell you.
-Hello.
-You need nuts with what you're drinking.
-Thank you.
-Mind if I sit down?
Are you kidding? On this side.
-Surprised to see me?
-Nothing surprises me anymore these days.
I was passing by and I saw you come in.
I'm glad you did. How's your truck?
Looking pretty. Between you and me,
I made a little extra on the insurance.
What do you mean, "between you and me"?
It's just between you and you.
I don't wanna know
if you're screwing your insurance.
-Who's the good-looking gal?
-She pushes an 18-wheeler.
We can't talk in front of her.
-I'll take care of it.
-Okay.
So you pump iron?
There you are.
I wanna introduce my friend...
Annabelle.
-Hello.
-Hi.
By the way, me and Annabelle
are gonna take a moonlight ride.
I didn't know you were such a romantic.
Really? There's a lot of things
you don't know about me.
Nice meeting you, Irene.
-Hey, is this yours?
-Sure is.
You're not gonna tell me you use this
easy-to-park little compact all the time.
Always. Get in.
You'll find it's a lot more comfortable
than a Rolls-Royce.
-Am I gonna be safe?
-Who knows?
-I'll risk it.
-I've got some great tapes.
I hear you're interested in finding out
about a certain corpse: Garret's.
How did you know about it?
It's supposed to be top-secret.
-The ways of the Lord--
-Are infinite, I know.
So, what have you got for me?
Garret, while he was in Miami,
met a man named Fletcher.
-Who's he?
-Florida's major wheeler-dealer.
-What's his gig?
-Gambling. Anything illegal.
-So how do I get to him?
-I heard through the grapevine.
He intends turning the Orange Bowl game
between Washington and Oklahoma...
-into the biggest rip-off of the year.
-How?
Rumour has it he intends kidnapping
the Washington quarterback, Joe Ranieri...
-just for the day.
-Come on, that's hard to believe.
Anyway, it won't cost you anything
to keep Joe Ranieri under surveillance.
-I've been thinking--
-Yeah, I know.
Foil the kidnapping, catch Fletcher,
and give him the third degree.
Right.
Then let's go for it.
I don't understand a single word,
but what a voice.
It really reaches me all over. You, too?
Like I told you on the phone...
Joe Ranieri does not ride on the bus
with the rest of the team.
He's superstitious.
He goes in the limo with me.
Okay, no problem. We're the same size.
-You guys got a plan for this?
-Sure.
Can I hear it?
Well, it's very simple.
If someone wants something from you...
the important thing is to be sure that
something is where someone can't find it.
Get it?
Mr. Fletcher...
this is the betting situation
up to about three minutes ago!
Looks like we're all gonna retire, boys.
Eight figures. Zero, zero, zero.
-They're behind us.
-Great.
-Go on, gun it!
-But, sir, what's going on here?
Come on, burn rubber.
You drive.
Move over.
-This is not a Ferrari.
-It is now.
Car 21 to Station.
Stand by, we're almost there.
You've got three minutes.
Okay, slow down.
Let's go.
All right. The play is over, you guys.
It's too hot to fight.
Hold it.
Here come the troops, fellows.
They'll take you to the showers.
Mr. Fletcher, we've gone way past
the $10-million mark.
Before the start of the game...
there'll be a presentation
of the Robert Delmann Award...
to Joe Ranieri,
the best quarterback of the year.
And here comes Joe now.
Let's hear that applause.
Who the hell is that?
Ranieri's there.
-Where did those guys screw it up?
-Something must've gone wrong, boss.
Something? You mental retard, we're ruined.
Something upsetting you, Mr. Fletcher?
Who the hell are you guys,
and what do you want?
-We want to talk to you.
-The rest stay here and enjoy the game.
It looks like Washington just scored.
That's bad news. Right, Mr. Fletcher?
What did Garret want from you?
Who's Garret? Who are you guys anyway?
I want my attorney.
Come on, you jackass, start thinking.
Get over there!
What are you doing?
I don't even know the guy!
We have proof that you did.
-I didn't know--
-You didn't know what?
What's the difference?
I'm not a stool pigeon. You guys are--
We can arrest you for illegal betting
and kidnapping.
They'll lock you up and throw away the key.
What if I talk?
We won't report you
for the kidnapping attempt.
-Right, Steve?
-Absolutely, Doug.
Hold on.
Any way you look at it, I'm clean.
I didn't know Garret.
And I don't know how he knew me.
Everybody knows me.
But he made me a crazy offer.
He said if I'd help him find a guy
named Ralph Duran...
that he thinks is in Miami now
living under a different name...
we could split $20 million.
$20 million, that's a lot of money.
But I told him to get out...
because I don't go for those sneaky,
dirty things, really.
Well, maybe not that dirty.
What about Ralph Duran?
The first time I ever heard his name...
was when Garret gave it to me.
That's the truth. First time.
Okay? Can I go now?
-Sure.
-Thanks a lot. I could--
Do we look like the kind of cops
who'd make a deal?
-Right, Steve?
-Absolutely, Doug.
Well, for once,
Fletcher appears to be telling the truth.
There's nothing in the file to indicate
he had anything to do with Ralph Duran.
But here's where the plot thickens.
"Ralph Duran, highly dangerous...
"suspected of various murders
and robberies.
"On March 5, 1978, his body was found
in a Detroit garbage dump...
"burned beyond recognition.
"There was no prints.
"The only identifiable thing
was a scorched credit card."
Credit card? If you ask me, I smell a rat.
-Yeah. A crook with credit cards?
-Right.
Wait a minute.
The robbery took place on March 1, 1978.
We arrested Garret two days later.
You remember that?
Sure, March 3.
And then Duran's body
was found on March 5.
With his record,
he could have been in with Garret.
Remember, the witnesses said
that there were three robbers.
Duran's dead. Garret's dead.
Number three is your man.
Yeah, but why would Garret
be looking for a stiff?
It doesn't make sense.
It don't make sense with me, either.
So you handle it, Blue Eyes.
I would've been better off
if I'd stayed with my flying classes.
Three, four, five...
six... It's open.
Hi.
-Hi.
-I'm early, huh?
No, I always do 100 lifts before dinner.
Builds up my appetite.
Pour yourself a drink. We can eat anytime.
-I'll take a fast shower and be right back.
-Okay.
Smells great. I'm starving.
-If you came here to eat and run--
-Of course not.
I never run on a full stomach.
Listen, Irene...
from the very first moment I saw you--
Don't tell me. You fell in love with me.
Well, that wouldn't be too hard.
No. What I wanted to say is...
from the minute I saw you,
I felt like I'd met you before.
And now I know where:
the Demolition Derby in Tucson last year.
The Demolition Derby?
-Remember?
-No way.
No?
-The door.
-That's the timer. Dinner's ready.
The Indianapolis 500?
I haven't been there in 10 years.
It'll come back to you sooner or later.
Hey, you're pretty good.
You bet. I'm gonna get you.
You're the first man to beat me
at arm wrestling.
Well, you're tougher than Mighty Mouse.
You can't imagine
how important that is to me.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah. Squeeze me.
-Squeeze me tight.
-What?
-Like so?
No. Tighter.
-Tighter.
-You know I could break you in two?
No, you won't. I love it.
Excuse me.
Steve, a guy named Charro called
looking for you.
He wants you to call him back
at this number: 473-8329.
I checked it out.
It's a public phone booth
in the Miccosukee district.
473-8329. Yeah, I got it.
Yes, hi to you, too, paleface.
Something's just come up.
Maybe it's important, maybe it's not.
I'll be waiting for you.
Here's to you.
Which me: the informer or the cook?
-All of you.
-Thank you.
Why don't you tell me all the places
you've been in the last two years?
Well, I spent a year in Philly.
That's it. Philadelphia.
I've never been to Philadelphia.
-Don't answer it.
-It might be important.
I know who it is.
Answer it.
Yes, right away. It's for you.
-It's that pain.
-Jack.
That's you.
The other day, shortly after you left...
I received this. It's from Garret.
"The eagle assures your future."
What does that mean?
I thought about it for three days.
One thing's for sure.
The letter, the screwdriver, and the hammer
are all connected.
"The eagle assures your future."
I don't get it.
When we do get it,
we'll have the key to the mystery.
When you saw Garret alive,
you don't think maybe...
No way.
Here, take them. They are the clues.
And another thing.
Garret said the guy he was looking for
had a face-lift.
Come on, the guy he was looking for
died seven years ago.
There's an old Indian saying:
"Not all the dead are buried underground."
Sure.
Some get buried at sea,
some get burned up.
Burned up.
Yeah, burned.
Hey, wait a minute.
Coming.
-Who is it?
-It's me.
-Hi.
-I'm glad you could come back.
Sorry, but I need the names
of all the plastic surgeons...
who worked in Florida from '77 to '78.
-Now?
-Yes.
But it's midnight.
I can't wake up my contacts.
-Please.
-All right.
Hey, Detroit.
A Formula One race in Detroit, right?
Never been there. Hello?
It's got to be Danaisser.
He worked on a lot of criminals.
And he died on March 30, 1978.
Right. That's 25 days
after Ralph Duran died.
And that's enough time
for scars to heal, right?
What's with this saying "right" all the time?
Ain't you sure?
So it figures then that
Ralph Duran had the operation on his face...
-and then killed the surgeon.
-Right.
There you go with that word again.
You know something? I get the feeling
this is a job for gravediggers...
not for cops.
-We keep coming up with corpses.
-Right.
It's an animal clinic.
Maybe he practiced his craft
on delinquent Dobermans.
Could be. Personally,
all Dobermans look alike to me.
All bite no bark.
Mrs. Danaisser?
What do you cops want?
You wanna check my license?
No, we just wanna ask you a few questions
about your husband.
-My husband's been dead for seven years.
-We know that, ma'am.
We're interested in the circumstances
of his death.
There's a coroner's report.
He was hit by a truck.
If you'll excuse me,
I've a dog who's getting an IV...
and I have no assistants. Goodbye.
-Hey, want a hand?
-Yeah. We're trained paramedics.
Okay, Bounty, I'm sorry I kept you waiting.
I'll take that out of there right now.
If you wanna help me, you can go out
and feed the dogs and goats.
The dogs' food's in the yellow pail,
the goats' food's in the green pail.
Sure. I'll feed the dogs, you feed the goats.
No, you feed the goats.
I'll feed the goats, all right.
There, now you're gonna feel much better.
These are all stray animals
abandoned on the streets.
Of course, someone who doesn't love
animals is capable of anything.
-Like your husband's killer.
-What do you know?
To tell you the truth,
we don't really know anything.
But we think the truck that hit your husband
did it deliberately.
We want to reopen the case.
-Seriously?
-Why do you think we're here?
But who could it have been?
Theoretically, all your husband's patients...
could've had an interest
in getting rid of a witness.
That's true.
Do you remember the last client
he did surgery on?
How could I forget? Come with me.
He paid so well,
we took a long vacation in Europe:
London, Paris, Madrid.
-Almost a month?
-Yes.
And when you got back to Miami,
the accident happened?
Exactly. Two days later.
Did your husband keep files
on his patients?
No. But I have
all of Mel's appointment books.
-Here, this is the one, 1978.
-Thanks.
You know, these operations were illegal.
No names, no receipts.
Here we are. March.
Look at this: "R.D."
Ten'll get you a hundred that's Ralph Duran.
Ma'am, what's this "F.T." after the $75,000?
It was a code my husband used...
when the operation
called for a total physiognomy.
Here you are, ma'am.
Thanks for letting us feed the animals.
You think you can catch the killer?
Our record's pretty good, ma'am.
"R.D."
I bet you're thinking
the same thing I'm thinking.
Maybe Delmann's actually Duran.
Give him a tip.
Thanks a lot, mister. Have a nice day.
Are you guys out of your minds?
Delmann is probably
the most important man in this city.
He's a political heavyweight.
He heads the Consolidated Realty
and he's a big shot over at the country club.
What about his initials?
R.D. One hell of a coincidence.
Come on, Steve,
millions of people have those same initials.
Where does this money come from?
What's his story?
Pretty simple.
He was expatriated out of Cuba...
like a lot of other people,
to get away from Castro.
-When?
-About seven years ago.
But he's loaded.
He made a lot of money on the stock market.
Could you get us the exact date
he got here?
April 2, 1978.
A month after Ralph Duran's body
was found.
Coincidence number two.
Number one: the initials.
Number two: the date of arrival in Miami.
Just three days
after that plastic surgeon died.
And that's coincidence number three.
Oh, come on, you guys.
Okay, forget it.
We haven't got a hope in hell
of getting in there.
All we need
are some of Delmann's fingerprints...
to compare with Duran's.
Good thinking.
It's the only way to prove our theory,
once and for all.
Hey, didn't Tanney say
Delmann's chairman of the Golf Club?
Yeah.
His locker's gotta be loaded
with his fingerprints.
That's right.
Hey, Doug.
The comb.
-Relax, you don't have a hair out of place.
-No, I had Delmann's comb.
Do we have any aspirin in the patrol car?
Hello?
Speaking.
A comb?
I see.
Are you sure they didn't take anything else?
I don't like it.
This time, those two
are too close for comfort, understand?
-Hey, sir, orange juice.
-Make it two.
We're getting close to cracking this case...
and here we are,
cruising around in a patrol car.
We're wasting our time. Let's do something.
Kick off by paying for the juice.
Look, I forgot my wallet again.
Will you take care of this
and I'll pay you back?
He forgot his wallet again.
You're lucky it's me and not a mugger.
Come on, tightwad, let's go.
Hey! Help.
You come back here with my bag!
Lucky.
Mister, was that your car?
Beat it before the cops get here.
The man said beat it!
I just can't believe it.
Delmann might be capable of a lot of things.
But we're talking
about attempted murder here.
If Delmann's our man,
that's right up his alley.
I think he's writing us a letter.
Let's forget about the initials for now.
But not the way
he just turned up in the city.
And now a bomb...
put in our car the day after
we tried to lift his fingerprints.
But how does Delmann know
you want his fingerprints?
Well, some guy almost killed me
to get his comb back.
Listen, Chief, we need a search warrant.
If you give us that,
we'll give you Duran on a platter.
No, guys. It's too big.
If you blow it, we're dead.
What if we come up with proof
that will nail him?
Such as?
Check the computer
and see if anybody at the Golf Club...
reported an attempted robbery last night.
No, it's a negative report.
Don't you think that's funny?
Well, Tom?
God help us all,
I wanna make one thing perfectly clear.
I'm not giving you a search warrant.
You can work it
as a couple of private citizens...
but I don't wanna know anything about it.
There's been too many corpses already.
So remember, no more blood.
Friends, may I have your attention, please?
In addition to my past contributions
to the city of Miami...
I am proud to announce...
that this will be
Miami's biggest ever construction project.
And I could never have done it
without your help. Thank you.
What a nuisance.
They should ban helicopters
from flying over residential areas.
How dare you interrupt my party!
-You'll pay for this.
-Sure. Bill my partner.
Who? Who are you, anyway?
Can we have a little talk?
Come into the house. Excuse me, please.
Take a seat, please.
Take the chair. It looks stronger.
The only excuse
I can find for you gentlemen...
is that you're from a loony farm.
What do you want?
We wanna tell you a piece of old history.
Just to see how good your memory is.
Eight years ago...
three bandits held up
the Detroit Federal Bank for $20 million.
And?
We caught one of them.
Only one of them: Garret.
But he wouldn't rat on anyone.
Very interesting. Continue.
Then Garret got out of jail
and came here to Miami...
to find his friend, Ralph Duran,
and his share in the robbery.
Garret found Duran.
But Duran had a new face and a new name,
and the same old killer instinct.
You can guess what happened next.
They found Garret's body
with 6 inches of cold steel in it.
And we're convinced
that Ralph Duran lives in this mansion...
and is sitting in front of us.
Right, Mr. Duran?
Fantastic. It's a bad joke.
You should be fiction writers.
You're wasted as cops.
I'm gonna ruin you.
Oh, yeah? Look at me.
I'm trembling all over, sir.
-I'll give you a chance to ruin us.
-How?
We wanna take your fingerprints
and see if they match Duran's.
-If we're wrong, you can bury us.
-Okay with me.
I've got nothing against
you taking my prints.
But first, I'd like to make a call.
Miami Police Dept. Can I help you?
Robert Delmann speaking.
Get me Mr. Risner.
He's the Police Commissioner.
My dear Robert, what can I do for you?
Joe, two of your men are in my house...
with some cockamamie story
about me not being myself...
but some hood named Duran.
A bank robber, a killer.
-What?
-There's more.
I believe these two are the crooks
who broke into my locker...
at the Golf Club the other night.
I didn't report it then, so I'll do it now.
This is outrageous, Robert.
You have my utmost apologies.
They insist on fingerprinting me.
Don't ask me why.
Naturally, I'm more than willing
to cooperate.
But I shall make a formal complaint
to the City, suing for damages.
I'm telling you all this
because you're an old friend.
Unfortunately, these jokers
are gonna cost you some headaches...
what with the elections coming up.
Yes, of course. Put those two on the line.
Go ahead, they can hear you.
Identify yourselves.
Officer Jay Donnel, Hialeah Department.
Officer L.A. Wray, ditto.
Get back to your precinct
and consider yourselves under arrest.
Tell Tanney I'll be in his office
in half an hour.
This country can boast of having
the greatest constitution in the world.
And you harass this city's
most influential and illustrious citizen.
I'm amazed at you, Tanney.
I don't need to tell you
I expect your resignation.
And you two,
hand in your uniforms and badges.
I've already notified your superiors.
They'll be taking the necessary action
against you.
That's all.
Sorry, Chief.
It's my fault, too.
We tried. It just didn't work out.
Thanks.
It's people like Delmann
that make the world a garbage dump.
I'm off the force, huh?
I'm going back to my helicopters.
Hello, Mrs. Clay. Can I help you?
We were just passing by,
so I said to the children:
"Let's go in and thank those two angels."
Donnel and Wray?
Right now, they need all the gratitude
they can get.
-Why is that?
-You see, they had a problem last week.
Here's the lot.
If it makes any difference,
the men are on your side.
Excuse me. I'm Mrs. Clay.
I heard about what happened,
and I'm really sorry.
The children and I wanted to thank you
for what you did.
-Yeah, sure.
-Take care, kids.
Good luck.
-And chin up, ma'am.
-Thank you.
Now you know why I quit the Bureau.
It's all politics.
At least we did something
for the Clay family.
Hey, taxi.
You wanna say adios to Irene?
No, I don't think so. What about Annabelle?
Are you kidding?
I'm not in the mood to arm-wrestle.
Let's just go and get our bags
and then head straight for the airport.
Hey, that sign!
"The eagle assures your future."
That bird's outside Room 5.
Turn around, immediately.
What the hell is going on here?
What is with you... I like your nerve!
Fellows, if you know how to pray,
now's the time.
Charro.
There it is.
Now we know why he needed
the hammer and the screwdriver.
All right!
Thanks, Charro. We'll be right back.
Listen, Chief.
Aren't you guys supposed to be
on an airplane?
Your resignation, did you hand it in?
No, I just got to writing it.
I'm gonna turn it in tomorrow.
-Well, don't.
-Why? What's going on?
Listen, by the time we've finished,
it'll be Risner's ass, not yours.
Excuse me, sir.
What is it, Ramon?
This special delivery just arrived for you.
Thank you.
-May I?
-I'm finished. Thank you.
Hi, Ralph.
Your charred body was found March, 1978.
But you and I know it wasn't you.
It was our unlucky partner, Phillips.
We heard in the pen he disappeared
the same time your body was found.
You always used to talk about Florida
and disappearing...
and doing a plastic job on your face.
And who lived in Miami back then?
The number one
underground plastic surgeon, Danaisser.
It was only a month after your,
excuse me, Phillips' cremation...
that a truck blew Danaisser away.
Very neat, Ralph. Right off, I figured you...
Who is it?
Right now, I bet
you're even paler than usual, paleface.
If you want the original of that tape,
come and get it, when and where I say...
and with $10 million,
plus eight years' interest...
which makes an even $20 million.
-And if I don't show?
-You'll show. This is blackmail.
Any tricks,
and I'll send the original to the FBI...
with a note suggesting they match your
fingerprints with those in Duran's old file.
$20 million is a lot of money.
You have eight hours to put it together.
We meet at 10:00 tonight.
The Yankee Company's portside warehouse.
Naturally, you'll come alone.
Ramon, I want all the men in my office
within a half hour.
Kill him!
What are you waiting for?
Turn on the lights!
-Damn. I thought so.
-Look, I'll give you the money.
Yeah, so will Santa Claus.
You're a mean shot, paleface.
They must be out of ammo.
Come on, let's go round behind them.
Come on.
Talk about a shocking sight.
Boss. Come on, let's get out of here.
Lots of deadwood.
Chief, what happened?
The next time,
I don't want just a bulletproof vest.
-I want a crash helmet, too.
-Where's Duran?
I have no idea,
but he didn't bring the money.
It ain't surprising.
-Let's see how you get out of this.
-Don't kill me. Name your price.
Maybe.
Maybe I'll give you a second face-lift.
No charge.
This is your lucky day, Duran.
Hi, Chief.
The 52nd floor.
That's where I saw you. The 52nd floor
of the FBI building in New York.
Special Agent Irene Allen.
I was sent to Miami to act as your cover...
and I just couldn't miss the ending
of your brilliant operation.
This is really too good to be true.
But I thought I told you no blood.
Come on, this is tomato sauce.
Well, you've got to go
make a little visit now.
Where?
You've got a score to settle.
Your friend, Com. Risner.
Well, Doug, I enjoyed every minute.
But next time, I won't let you trick me
into helping you again.
So your mind's made up?
You're going back to your flying lessons?
If I still got my students.
Well, good luck.
I forgot my wallet.
Would you pay the cab
and give him a tip from me?
Remember Charro and his Indian saying?
"All the money in the world
ain't worth a friend."