Damn it!
Rear armor?
Shot to hell!
You better drop back..
It's the last lap
We can win this.
Why don't the son of a bitch just die?
Oil
Out
Smoke!
Finished!
Give me the napalm!
-Nothing works!
Drop the tombstone, on my mark
Three...
Two...
One...
Got you now, motherfucker
Mark!
Shit!
Fuck!
Thats how you wanna do it?!
Okay!
He's still coming, our tank is exposed
He got us, Frank. You have to drop back
It's a quarter mile to the line, I can make it.
Sayonara, Frankie
Punch out
I'm sorry
40 years...Longer than my marriage
Sounds like you're gonna miss this place
Still can't believe they closed it down
Just like that
The only thing I'm gonna miss
is my paycheck.
Well, it was an honest work
for honest men.
I got a family to feed.
Theres no work out there
I heard that they might be hiring, down at the docks
5 men, maybe
Hey.. thanks man
Thanks Jensen
Collect your final paycheck, and leave
The main gate will be locked in 15 minutes
Get ready to be ripped off boys
Collect your paychecks, and leave the premises in orderly manor
The main gate will be locked in 15 minutes
Cash or check?
Better make it cash.
Three hundred dollars..
I've worked 120 hours in the last two weeks.
Cash fee..Next!
Cash fee??
You wanted cash? There's a fee.  You want check instead..?
Seeing as the company is out of business, not exactly.
You don't like it, there's the complaint box.
Next!
I never get it, self fulfilling prophecy
We're honest workers, we're just like you guys!
What the hell are you doing here?
Are you ok, Ross?
Hi honey.
Sorry I'm so late.
Nice day at work?
Yeah... Just fine.
Give me that shirt.
They called the riot police, it got ugly.
I don't deserve you.
You're a good man, Jensen Ames
And it doesn't matter what anyone else thinks, but me.
So 300 dollars, thats all they gave us
We'll make it last,
We always do.
I'm gonna start tomorrow
I think you're forgetting that I married you,
for your non-financial assets.
Did you now?
Daddy's home
Is it you who's making all that noise?
What does little Piper want?
You want a story?
You know you won't understand it..
..But it'll be good practice for me.
What the hell..
Let's go crazy.
Something smells good
Honey!
Suzy!
Stay on the ground!
Stay where you are!
Don't move!
Get up against the wall.
Stop!
Prisoner, step back
Happy Holidays.
Good morning
Good morning, Warden
Good morning, Ma'am
There goes the baddest ass in the yard
Sounds like you in love, homie.
I am.
Damn, I had to wake up for this..
Is it my imagination, or is
this shit getting worse?
Whats this supposed to be?
Oatmeal
I think..
How do you fuck up oatmeal?
Who's the new guy?
Jensen Ames
The driver?
Never heard of him.
Oh yeah. I saw him race years ago. He was good.
He did some time upstate.
Killed his career.
Holder of the fastest laps at Willard, Union, and Butler.
I hope he's as fast off the track as he is on.
Never a dull day
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Heads up, its Pachenko
So you're the wife killer?
It takes a big man, to kill a woman..
Suppose you rape kiddies too
You hear that everyone?
The guy kills women...rapes kiddies.
What do you think we gonna do about that?
Get on the ground, now!
Nobody move!
I guess he didn't like the oatmeal either.
Prisoner No. 77119, ma'am.
Thank you, Mr. Ulrich
This prison is the home to murderers, rapists..
..And violent offenders of every kind.
The United States Penal System sends me the worst of the worst.
But the men you've provoked..
Well, let's just say Mr. Ames
that the life term you've joined us for may be
a lot shorter than you think.
I understand tradition. Soften up the new guy
And a slipping good time had by all.
Foul language is an issue.. for me.
While looking over your record,
I couldn't help noticing your occupational history.
It seems you have some talent behind the wheel.
Out of curiosity, when was the last time you raced?
It's been a while.
I lost my license.
What if I could help you?
Get my license back?
I had something else in mind.
You're familiar with the Death Race,
and the driver the fans call Frankenstein?
A man so disfigured by crashes,
that he's forced to wear a mask.
His return to the track is highly anticipated..
And therein lies my problem.
No one knows yet, but poor Frank died on an operating table
Not long after his last race.
Anyone can wear the mask,
But not just anyone can drive the car.
You have the skills required to keep the legend alive.
I want you to become Frankenstein.
No thanks.
He's dead.
Why don't you just tell the truth?
The audience wants to see Frank again.
He moves them. Inspires them.
And in this world that's not so easy to come by.
What makes you think for a second,
I would risk my life doing this for you?
Win five races, you go free.
Those are the rules
And Frank has won four.
Win one more, you walk.
Call it intuition, but
I don't think you belong in here with the rest of these animals.
I might surprise you.
The race is Friday, and I need your decision.
You're a skilled driver.
Your chances are good
I'm offering you your freedom, Mr. Ames.
If it's not worth risking your life for,
what is?
Now turn her up, and tie the lines.
Ma'am
You don't have to call me Ma'am, you know that.
This is Mr Ames
You know why he's here.
I do now..
Race is less than a week away
I have great confidence in you.
Well then, I'll leave you two to get acquaintant.
Jensen Garner Ames.
Moved to the states at twenty-four years old.
Named after a car, the Jensen Intercepter.
A three time local speedway champion.
You've done your homework, or do you just know everything?
Jensen Intercepter. I had one.
Handled like a school bus.
Call me Coach, everyone does.
Gunner.. Lists.
This's Frank.
I'll show you around
We have a fully functioning autoshop.
Just like you'd find in the outside world.
Each team has their own shop.
We don't help them, They don't help us.
With the inmates you're Jensen Ames, new greasemonkey.
Nobody will know you're Frank, except us on the team, and a handful of the guards.
Nobody will talk.
How can you be so sure?
-Hennessey..
In here, she's Judge, Jury and Executioner
The race is her baby.
Anyone who threatens it, she kills.
The audience for the race is half,
since Frank has been out of the game
And so is the corporations profit
Thats why she needs you.
What's back there?
Thats a good question.
Hennessey has had a whole wing of the prison in isolation for a month.
Working on something.
Time to meet the monster.
Mustang V8 Fastback
Took the best, and made it better.
That's a V8 Rouch 5.4 liter, with a Ford Racing supercharger.
Putting out 850 horsepower, and close to..
750lbs. of torque with sequential module port fuel injection.
Looks like there's a 250HP NOS unit.
Just in case.
Then we had some fun,
Customizing a personal protection package.
3 quarter inch steel plate, front, sides.
Bulletproof glasses will here.. here.. and there.
And in the rear.. the 6 inch solid steel shield we call
'The Tombstone'
Oil.. Smoke
And napalm for defence.
Twin 30mm belt fed machine guns for offense.
So where's the ammo?
We get that on race day.
Pity.
Yeah, everyone thinks that...the first time.
Thinks what?
About turning the guns on the guards. About escaping.
No, I wasn't thinking that.
Well I'm glad, because Hennessey's got electric kill switches on all the guns on all the cars.
And all the guard towers are fortified,
and their guns are bigger than your guns.
Oh, did I mention the helicopters and also the fact that
we're on an island here a mile from the nearest shoreline?
The only way in or out of here is on that one skinny bridge you came in on.
What's that?
The most important part of the car.
The race takes place in 3 stages over 3 days.
The first two stages you just gotta try
and get rid of as much of the competition as you can.
While getting your own skinny ass over the line alive.
Third stage is where speed counts
First one over that line wins.
Tomorrow morning you'll meet your navigator Case.
She'll help you navigate the course, reload your weapons,
and help with the running of the car.
I'd like to talk to her ahead of time before the race.
Yeah, I'd like a big-tittied girl to lick peanut butter off my toes.
But it ain't gonna happen.
This is still a prison, man. She's a chick.
They get bussed in from the women's facility upstate.
It's all about ratings. Fast cars, pretty women...
Machine Gun Joe's the only one that has male navigators,
'cause he's gay.
Actually it's because he goes through them so fast,
and audience gets squeamish.
Yeah he goes through them...through their ass.
He cuts each kill into his skin as a souvenir, right here.
What about the rest of the drivers?
Lists?
14K
First generation Chinese-american.
10th generation Triad.
His father sent him to business school
He's the only man in here who holds a degree from the MIT
He's killed 4 men off the track (That we know of)
Another 7 on it.
Hector Grimm, The Grimm Reaper.
The man is a master. clinical psychopath.
Three time consecutive life sentences.
He's killed 6 men off the track,
Another 12 on it.
You've already met the local chapter of
The Brotherhood.
Their driver, Pachenko, has killed 9 men on the track.
Nobody knows how many off.
Travis Colt, our local superstar.
Used to race for NASCAR.
-Yeah,he was good too.
Until he fell asleep behind the wheel of his Mercedez,
with the help of a bottle of scotch and a handful of ludes.
Wiped out the entire patio of Moscala, sent a dozen people to the hospital...
Killed three of them.
Technically, best driver in here but
a mean son of a bitch quitter.
Ladies..
I hear your man Frank's still in the infirmary with
15 unhealed fractures
I also hear he's not gonna make the race.
You hear a lot.
Who's the new fish?
Greasemonkey.
Well well. Monkey.
I got a new name for you.. Igor
Because you about the ugliest motherfucker out here in this prison yo!
It's funny, huh?
You tell Frank when you see him
This race is between me and him.
This time won't be infirmary, it'll be the morgue.
I'll be sure to pass it on.
Lets get out of here..
Man, that's one angry homo.
Who're they?
Work detail..
Get to work on the track,
for good behavior.
Those are GPS tracking bracelets.
In case someone decides to go for a swim..
The ring.
This was the old Frank's.
It got melted to his hand.
Frankenstein! Frankenstein! Frankenstein!
Asshole
He's all yours.
Don't talk to the other drivers. Frank never did.
Part of the mystique.
Let the mask do the work.
Here comes trouble.
Thats your girl.
I'm Case.
Frank.
Well you don't sound like Frank.
Don't sweat it, I know.
I drove with Frank.
I'll watch your back.
Better then you watched his, I hope.
You're still here.. I guess I got to work
a little harder.
Get back to your car, prisoner
You sure know how to make friends.
Case, this is mirror glass. No one can see in,
so you might want to take the mask off.
Unless you like it under there..
How the hell does he drive in that thing?
What?
You're better looking than the last Frank.
Few crashes should change that..
Start the transmission.
3, 2, 1
We're live, Worldwide.
Welcome to Death Race!
Terminal Island Penitentiary hosts 3 days of the ultimate of Auto Carnage.
Stage 1 begins streaming live in 10 minutes.
Subscribe to stage 1 now for 99 dollars!
Or subscribe to all 3 stages for the low price of 250!
Access to over 100 live camera-feeds.
Watch from the cars of your favorite drivers!
See the action your way, uncensored and unedited!
A full-on fight to death!
Featuring, 4 time winner Frankenstein!
3 time winner Machine Gun Joe!
Pachenko!
Travis Colt!
Audience favorite Frankenstein resumes his bitter grudgematch with Machine Gun Joe!
Frankenstein returns to the track after his 6 month absence!
-They've missed him.
He's the man, that just won't die!
12 millions hit, on his angle alone
And he hasn't even started the engine.
We'll do 45 million viewers today.
So what are you in for?
They say I killed a cop.
Did you do it?
Yeah.
Bad cop?
Good cop..
Lousy husband.
Frank, Case.. you read me?
We hear you.
This is a 3 lap race.
Hennessey doesn't activate the weapons 'til lap 2.
Remember it's first come, first serve. So it pays to be out in front.
This is it.
Countdown
Are you sure he can deliver?
Dive left toward 100 feet.
15 ... 20
Now
Punch it, hard left up ahead.
He seems to be handling himself.
Wakey!
Fuck!
We're being passed, you gotta catch up!
Bro, I know what I'm doing!
Man just leave them!
-Shut up man...I know what the hell I'm doin'!
What you gonna do?
You can't go head-to-head with Joe like this, he'll tear you apart.
Listen to him, before you get us both killed.
You read me?!
There's a shortcut to the left.
Case, help him out of there!
There!
You don't think I see that?!
He's takin' a shortcut!
Activate Swords and Shields.
Swords are the main guns.
Shields trigger the napalm, oil and smoke.
Activate Death Heads.
Death Heads activated.
Get it baby!
Score that one for the Reaper, baby!
Thank you!
-Don't mention it. -Come on it's all clear.
Fuck you puto! Fuck you!
Got guns!
Oil!
Damn!
"Tu hermanos puto!" mother fucker!
Oh yeah!
What the fuck?!
We gotta get back in the race!
Fucking Reaper baby, can't kill me.
You can burn me.
You can fuckin' shoot me, but you just can't fuckin' kill me!
Get that off my window when we get back.
Streaming to 46 million viewers ma'am.
I'm back!
Thanks
- My pleasure.
Shield, up ahead!
Son of a bitch!
Just stole a Shield from Colt!
Defense weapons are on!
Let him have it.
Napalm won't fire!
Smoke!
No smoke, no oil...no napalm!
Again?!
Fuck man!
Remember me motherfucker?!
Coach!
The Tombstone won't take much more of this!
Frank, Case...those 50 caliber shells will be through the Tombstone in a matter of seconds.
My advice...either lose him or kill him.
Unhook the napalm.
Get on my lap!
What?
What the hell?
Merry Christmas asshole!
Aw shit!
Nice work.
Where's he goin'?
Shortcut! Punch it, we can beat him!
Look out!
Grim, Colt, and Siad are gone.
Six remaining drivers alive.
Subscribe to stage 2 now.
We have 14 hours gentlemen, so let's get to work.
Starting with this...
So what happened out there Case?
-Got distracted.
He got distracted?
Coach!
What?!
-Look at this!
Oil sprays were fine.
Well I'll be damned.
Stop
What can I do for you Mr. Ames?
You're all lucky a driver like me just happened to turn up in your prison when I did.
I'm more than lucky.
I'm blessed.
Sometimes it's like the right hand of God is sitting on my shoulder.
I'm not racing tomorrow.
Go fuck yourself.
Wait.
Take his shackles off.
Excuse us Mr. Ulrich.
And take Mr. James with you
Do you recognize these people?
Because your daughter will.  They're her new parents.
What's her name?
Piper.
That's the man she'll grow up calling daddy.
Unless you do something about it.
Where's she now?
Oh I'm sure I have her address around here somewhere.
You're a smart man Mr. Ames.
Play my game, we both go home happy.
The man who killed my wife is in this prison.
I wonder what he'll say when I ask him why he did it.
Why don't you look in a mirror, and ask him.
Poor Piper...Must be hard growing up without knowing.
That your father killed your mother.
You wanted a monster?
You've got one.
She has your eye.
They're her mother's.
So why do you wear a number, Coach?
Because I'm not a prisoner.
I qualified for parole 3 years ago.
I got as far as the gate.
They got a name for it...something or other -Syndrome.
Simple fact is...the world's changed since I've been in here.
Don't know it, don't much want to.
But this? This I know.
What'd they send you away for?
Oh plenty...or nothing.
To what do we owe the pleasure of your company?
I killed my wife.
Bullshit.
You're a hard man but you ain't no wife killer.
How do you know?
I've met my share.
And you, the way you look at her.
Couldn't do that if you killed her mother.
So...
I say bullshit.
Coach
What would you say if I told you Hennessey had my wife killed?
And me framed for it so she could bring me in here to be her Frankenstein.
What would you say to that bullshit?
Her name was Suzy.
Was always headed here, always knew.
She didn't.
She was my chance at something else.
That bitch took her away from me.
The days may be long on the land which the Lord, I giveth thee.
Kill...
Thou shalt not...
You should take a break, get some sleep.
I'm okay Lists.
Concentration for the race...
Concentration that's what you need.  You gotta get your rest.
Maybe you're right.
I'll take that break after all.
Good call.
Got can't grind for shit.
Lookin' for me?
Him him!
You killed my wife!
Well then...maybe I did.
I don't care if the queen bitch wants to save you for the track.
Nobody disrespects the Brotherhood and lives.
Put him down.
I'm gonna take your head.
Who is this fuck?!
Just let me go.
Let me go man.
I'll do anything.
You're gonna die here.
Fuck you!
Now now boys.  Let's save that for the track...huh?
Coach!
Take a look at this!
What the hell are they building here?
You'll find out soon enough.
Prisoner
Time to get ready.
Welcome to the next installment of Death Race.
Stage 2 begins...
Grim, Cold and Siad are gone.
6 remaining drivers alive.
14K, Pachenko...
Riggins...
Carson...
3 time winner, Machine Gun Joe.
And starting from the back of the grid, his archrival Frankenstein.
This could be the last time we see Frankenstein race.
Just one more victory and he wins his freedom.
If Joe doesn't kill him first.
Over 50 million viewers have already subscribed.
Don't miss this epic battle.
Subscribe to stage 2 now.
Pay attention.
Where is he?
What are you doing?
What's he doing?
He's dropping back.
We're gonna have a little talk.
We're gonna be done by the time we leave the tunnel.
What?
Did you kill the old Frank?
Tunnel comes in fast.
Remember what happened to that napalm canister?
It'd be a real shame for that to happen to you.
Did you kill the old Frank?
I sabotaged his rear weapons.
Why?
Hennessy...
She said she signed my release papers.  It's my life back.
I didn't kill him.
And you killed him too...
He wouldn't quit. I just wanted to make sure he didn't win.
Why would Hennessy want that?
To keep Frank here...racing.
Yesterday?
She wanted me to set you back.
So...I'm not supposed to win either?
Just to make it exciting.
That's all I wanted to know.
Hold tight.
Come on! Lap 2!
Damn!
He's going after Pachenko.
Shield ahead, take defense.
No
There's someone I need to kill.
You're out in front, who you gonna shoot at?
You're a dead man!
I told you to take defense!
He's too heavily armored!
Fuck!
Hit the smoke.
This is a race, you don't go backwards.
You don't get out of the car.
It was Hennessy...
Hennessy!
-I know...she's next.
Frank's out of his car.
What?
He stepped out of his car!
-Okay, I see it.
I need guns.
-Yeah, Sword coming up in 50 yards.
What happened?
-I don't know, somebody must've grabbed them.
What you mean somebody grabbed them?
Look man...I thought it was lit.
-What you mean you thought?
Man get the fuck outta my car!
What?
I said get the fuck outta my car!
Hell no!
Wait man, wait!
Don't let me down boy...
Release the Dreadnaught.
Coach!
Well I guess we know what she was buildin' now...
Activate weapons.
Christ!
Coach, any ideas?
-Just have to tough it out I guess.
Hennessy will take it off once she's pumped up the ratings.
You sure about that?
The hell is that thing going?
Fuck me..
Lists.
Receiving?
Need to patch me through to another car.
On it...
Joe!
Who is this?
-Frank
-What do you want?
How about we play a little offense?
I hope you know what you're doing.
Now that's entertainment.
Damn it!
Frankenstein! Frankenstein!
Nice reflexes there, Igor.
Race car reflexes.
You look lost pal.
Not this time.
Got this feeling that you and Frank are close.
Real close
That weird accent, you even kind of sound like him.
I was wondering...what if you...got in an accident.
Would that throw Frank off his game a little bit?
I doubt it. The sick fucked up guy that he is.
He just want to kill you?.
He's cool.
So I guess I'll...see him later, right?
Let's roll.
Ma'am with all respect...
What're we going to do?
-We're going to kill him of course.
You want me to kill Frankenstein?
Don't be stupid.  Frankenstein can't die.
After all, he's just a mask.
Tonight is the final leg of the Death Race.
And perhaps a new champion will arise.
A five times winner.
The first man ever to gain his freedom.
The world gave you to me because you are not fit to be a part of it.
You are not fit to be husbands.  You are not fit to be fathers.
And were to dangerous to live with the rest of us.
What is this shit, man?
But when you race tonight.
Know that the eyes of the world are upon you.
And know that the very same world that rejected you, now lives and breathes with you.
And it draws inspiration from your courage.
No one's ever gonna win 5 races.
So...race well.
Nobody's ever getting out of here.
And know that I consider you all, my heroes.
I wanna show you something.
Can't kill me...
I'm the fucking Reaper.
You can burn me, you can shoot me.
But you can't fucking-
There...
Gunner, Lists...
Will Hennessy's inspectors care if we add a half gallon of reserve tank?
Another half gallon?
You got a fuel tank that holds 35 gallons.
What the hell do you want another half gallon for?
Coach.
Let's give the man what he wants.
Where are you going?
This is not good
Real brave coming over here.
I'm gonna win this race, because I want out of this shit hole.
I've already won 3 races. Two more, and I'm smoking cohebas in Miami.
Frank might wanna think about that.
Because I'm gone...outta here.
Then maybe it's his turn.
Maybe he's thinking it's the other way around.
From here on out, stay the fuck out of my pit.
Hey!
Think you and Frank should have a little talk.
Welcome to the final installment of Death Race.
Seven men dead.
Siad
Grim
Colt
Pachenko
Carson
Riggins, and 14K are all dead.
Just Frankenstein and Machine Gun Joe survived.
Frank racing for his freedom.
And Joe doing anything to stop him.
It's "mano e mano" and there will be no mercy.
Tonight, only one man will walk off this track alive.
A record 70 million are already watching.
Join them! Subscribe to the final stage now!
It's an honor to navigate for you Sir.
They call me Nathan
-Save it...
We won't have time to get acquainted.
The hell are those?
Model 7 Russian State's Armory RPGs.
Armor piercing, self arming...accurate to a thousand yards.
That's what I thought.
Prisoner, step back.
I thought maybe you could use a little inspiration.
Your release papers.
All you have to do is walk off that track alive.
Well...and win of course.
But if you do win, I want you to think about staying here.
As Frankenstein.
Pfft...yeah.
I can see the appeal.
What would you do with your freedom?
Go back to your daughter?
That's the idea.
The thing is...are you really the best future she could possibly have?
Are you really daddy material, or deep down are you something else?
If you decided that out there on that track is where you belong.
It would be the most unselfish act of love, I've ever seen.
Just something to think about.
What's this?
-Small modification.
So Hennessy tells me, if you're going to win.
I'm supposed to stop you.
Oh yeah?
-Yeah.
Sounds like the odds are staked against us.
Then do what you do best.
Drive.
Gentlemen, this should be interesting.
Lit Sword up ahead.
Deactivate that.
Sir?
-Just do it.
Push it back on.
Weapons are up!
Damn it!
Shit
Lit Shield up ahead.
Damn it!
What happened?
-Hennessy must've deactivated it.
Bitch!
Light me up!
It's party time.
Coach, we gotta get some fire power.
Nothing lit for a half lap.
We won't last that long!
Drop the Tombstone.
-What?
Do it.
On my mark.
Three ...
Two ...
One ...
Mark!
Damn it!
That shit don't work twice playboy!
Shit!
Shield at a quarter lap.
You hear that? Lit Shield at a quarter lap.
He's coming up fast!
Let them get the Shield.
Keep the viewers interested.
Son of a bitch, he got the Shield.
Arm the explosive...Just in case.
Yo Franken'freak!
This Villager's got a pitch fork, and it's headed straight up your ass!
What just happened?
Yeah boy!
They're off the track. They're escaping!
They're headed for the bridge.
Their weapons, hit the killswitches!
Seventy million viewers ma'am, they're all watching!
Shut the webcast down!
Shut it down!
-Shut the fucking computers down now!
Get out, get out, get out now!
Get out!
Yo Frankenstein, it's good we had that little talk.
You gave that bitch a good show huh?
Give me that!
Okay cock sucker.
Fuck with me, and we'll see who shits on the sidewalk!
Somebody's mad right now...
Nobody fucks with my car.
Son of a bitch!
Get the choppers in the air!
We're not gonna get very far.
You're right
Now would be a good time?
Very nice modification.
That extra half gallon reserve tank should see you through to the finish.
Bon voyage, Frank
Choppers have a visual, ma'am.
Joe?
Give me a pilot, I need to talk to a pilot right now.
You're on.
Stay with Frankenstein, don't lose him!
Sure you're up for this?
-I'm sure, I owe it to Frank.
Besides, Hennessy already gave me my release papers. They have to left me out.
They stopped him, ma'am.
Keep your hands where we can see them.
You are under arrest
I repeat: keep your hands where we can see them.
Hey Igor, Merry Christmas.
Let's get out of here.
Nice.
The fact that you have clothes like these, makes a man question you're-
My taste.
Yeah, so to speak.
I don't know about you but I'm headed to Miami.
Yeah, Miami's good.
I'll meet you down there.
Once I got my baby girl.
It's a shame I didn't get to take care of that bitch, Hennessy.
Yeah, it is a shame.
Frankenstein has been retrieved.
And ma'am...ratings are off the charts.
Gifts and congratulations are already coming in.
You win again.
Mr. Ulrich...
I always win.
Damn...
I love this game
So we had to fix this car?
Don't know how many times we're gonna keep doing this.
Damn it!
You say you want me to live a life of an honest man, huh?
Yeah, you better get used to it.
Igor!
What took you so long?
Had trouble getting my release papers approved.
Wait here, there's someone I want you to meet.
Look at her...she has beautiful eyes.
They're her mothers.
Where'd you get the rims?
I won it...card game.
-Yeah right...
No really!
How many horse power is in this engine?
500...
Someone once asked me, did I think I was the best future for my little girl.
No one in this world is perfect. Heaven knows, I'm not.
But I love her more than anyone else possibly could.
In the end...
That's all that matters.