How long?
A day, maybe two.
They're away and gone, Rob,
and the beasts sold.
There's a wee glen on
the other side of Ben Duh.
If I were tinkers with a two-day start,
I'd lie out there and kill me some meat.
We'd not get there
before dark, Rob.
Not stood here,
we won't.
You can smell them
through the meat.
Aye, if they fought as
strong as they smelled,
we'd be in trouble.
They're there right enough,
just like you said, Rob.
We can rush them
when they're asleep.
Ten of them to six of us.
Nine.
One of them's a woman.
Half of them would be dead
before they were awake.
How are we going
to take them, Rob?
I'll go and talk to them in the morning.
I'm getting
too old for this,
lying wet-arsed in the heather,
chasing other men's cattle.
Come away to the Americas with me.
They say there's fine acres
for the clearing in Virginia.
Aye, and they'll likely be
as hard as these to sleep on.
Why are you going in
to talk to them?
I know one of them.
Up!
Get up, you bunch of
ragged-arsed tinker cow thieves!
This is Robert Roy MacGregor
come to reclaim the 32 beasts
stolen from His Lordship James
Graham, Marquis of Montrose.
Tam Sibbald.
Still at your thieving.
Throw down now and I'll
spare you, all but one.
There's a price to being
a leader of men, Tam.
By God, MacGregor,
if there's any killing to
be done, you're the first.
Who do you think you are,
acting the great chief?
And I know you're a bigger
thief than any of us.
Aye, but if I had stolen
His Lordship's cattle,
you would not have come
walking into my dreams so easy.
I can call the Gregorach
and kill the half of you,
or it can be between us
and nothing more.
Think on it, man.
Would you not rather
be dead this morning
after a good hump and a
belly full of stolen beef,
or would you have me
march you back to Montrose
so you can shit yourself
on the gallows a month hence?
Throw down! Now!
And you have my word
no one else will die!
Come, lads.
And any man with a blade
in his hands, cut him down.
Are you men,
or what are you?
He killed Tam,
and you stand and live!
And him as much an outlaw as any of you!
No man among you!
Your mothers curse you!
You're spittle!
You're leavings!
Listen to me well,
and remember this,
or I'm going to remember
you, every last one.
When next you think
to steal cattle,
have a care they're not
under my protection.
But if they are, you're not
stealing from their owners.
You're stealing from me,
Robert Roy MacGregor.
And no man who steals
my beasts makes a profit.
If you doubt me,
ask Tam Sibbald.
What are you going
to do with her?
Be on your way, and tell no
man you fared ill at our hands.
Go on.
Cut him down!
Slash him!
Go on.
Yeah!
Ladies and gentlemen, the
winner of the contest is Guthrie!
Montrose, come hotfoot
from the court to the cockpit.
May I present
Archibald Cunningham.
His Grace,
the Duke of Argyll.
I am Your Grace's
humble servant.
Another of your
likely lads?
Archibald is sent me
by his mother,
in the hope that our climate
might cool the fever in his blood.
So, Mr. Cunningham,
what are these principal sins
that distress your mother?
Dice? Drink?
Or are you
a buggerer of boys?
It is years, Your Grace,
since I buggered a boy.
And in my own defense,
I must add,
I thought him a girl
at the moment of entry.
What say you, Guthrie, that Archie
could not tell arse from quim?
I've heard that many Englishmen
have that same difficulty.
Spoken as well
as you fought.
Did you see Guthrie here
at work, Mr. Cunningham?
He has a fair hand with the
cleaver, it must be said.
You do not think much of
our Highland tools, then?
If I had to kill an ox, a claymore
would be my first choice, Your Grace.
You best use a musket and
save the beast a slow dying.
I would not need a
musket for you, Guthrie.
Splendid!
I'll wager 100 of what you
like on Guthrie and his cleaver.
At odds?
Now, come, James,
you're a fox. What odds?
Three?
Two.
English pounds.
There's more of
a jingle to guineas.
Guineas it is.
Excellent, excellent.
A bumper of Rhenish for my
Lord Montrose and myself,
and show Mr. Cunningham
what blades we have.
You honor me, sir, to
serve me with your own hand.
I tell you, James,
I forget how much you dislike
me until I'm in your presence.
So, what news at court?
What else
but the succession?
Our poor queen cannot find
the time to die in peace.
I fear she may pass over and
leave the matter unresolved.
Would that she had seen a child of
hers live to comfort the kingdom.
Aye. One might have hoped that
a field so regularly ploughed
might have yielded
one good crop.
In truth, I have seen healthier
graveyards than that woman's womb.
Come on!
I am asked continually on what side
Your Grace will declare himself.
Where Argyll goes, the
path must be firm and broad.
And now all watch
to see which way to jump.
One cannot go
to the closet
but what some adherent to
James is praising your pish.
And I confess to a certain
weariness in this whole issue,
and look for the light of
Your Grace to give some lead.
And all I could answer,
in honesty,
was that it would be the one
most inclined to his own benefit.
Damn it, man. But you talk too
much. Can you not tend to your wager?
Argyll,
my wager is well won.
Damn it, Guthrie!
Is it not enough that you're beaten,
but you must turn backstabber?
My factor will call upon
Your Grace's factor.
Well done, Rob, man.
Cut out another
of the cattle.
If the tinkers ate one,
they could have eaten two.
Montrose will charge you, nonetheless.
I'm weary of seeing children
hungry and old folk cold.
It'll take more than
a cow to fix that, Rob.
Aye. Well, you'll be in the
Americas, living off the fat,
so it won't worry you.
Will you have some broth,
Rob? No, Coll. I'm for home.
God bless you, Rob.
And then Rob just walks in among
them, his sword still in its sheath,
And says, "Up. Get up, you
bunch of ragged-arsed... "
Hello, Rob.
Hello, Rob!
"Get up, you bunch of
ragged-arsed tinker cow thieves!"
And Rob up to him
and says,
"Tell your crew to lay down
and I'll only cut your throat,
"else I'll call my men. "
And we're all there.
We are ready.
Get up, boy.
Come on.
Go on. Get.
I dreamed
a selkie came.
And what did he do
to you, your selkie?
You wakened me
before the best of it.
But he would have
ravished me for certain.
How do you know
you're awake, wife?
Mr. Killearn.
I'm on my way.
Aye. Well on the way,
I'd venture.
Let me be, Mr. Killearn. You'll
wake him. Don't, Mr. Killearn!
I'm sure the young master has
you nicely greased, does he not?
Betty, you'd hardly
feel me going in.
A wee whiff of quim in the
morning, Mr. Cunningham, sir.
Just the thing
to clear your head.
Mr. Cunningham, I hope
I'm not disturbing you.
Of course you're bloody
well disturbing me.
Do you think
I want to wake up
and find some great smelly
Scotchman staring down at me?
What are you doing here?
I wanted to tell you that
some of the local trades people
have been pressing
for payment on your debt.
And you woke me
to tell me that?
A thousand apologies, Mr. Cunningham,
but they've also writ to His Lordship.
Damn it, man.
I but recently earned
His Lordship 200 guineas.
What are the complaints of a
few tradesmen for such services?
This country does
not agree with me.
I cannot wait to be
out of the damnable place.
The sentiments of
a great many of us, sir.
Would you like me to take
away your chamber pot?
I know many a Scotsman would be
glad of this on a cold morning.
It's almost pure spirit, and
I'm no judge of a pint of pish.
Come back.
Come here!
I killed Tam Sibbald
yesterday morning.
We played ball
once at Crieff market.
I remember shouting, "Well
done, Tam," when he made a run.
And there he was, hung on
the end of my dirk like meat.
Aye.
Well, likely
it was necessary.
Aye, it was. Necessary
enough to save worse.
But those tinkers weren't
all born broken men, Mary.
Some of them
had kin and clan.
They made me fear I might have come
across one of our own among them.
MacGregors are not tinkers.
But a hard winter or
two away, some of us...
What's gnawing on you,
Robert?
I've made up my mind to
borrow money from Montrose
to buy cattle at Crieff
market and sell at Carlisle.
How much money?
£1,000.
Believe me, Mary, it will turn profit.
£6 in Crieff is £12 in Carlisle.
And I know cattle.
I can drive them faster
and deliver them fatter
than any man
in the kingdom.
And why would the Marquis of
Montrose lend a MacGregor £1,000?
For profit, what else? It's an
investment as much as a loan.
So it's business partners you
are now, you and the Marquis.
Keep that tongue
for your boys, woman.
I didn't tell you my
mind to be flayed for it.
You know I love the bones
of you, Robert MacGregor.
But you take too much to
heart that cannot be helped.
It must be helped.
All right,
but not today.
I got yous.
I got the two of yous!
Got the two of yous!
Move on.
Father, will MacGregors
ever be kings again?
All men with honor
are kings,
but not all kings
have honor.
What is honor?
Honor is
what no man can give you,
and none can take away.
Honor is a man's gift
to himself.
Do women have it?
Women are
the heart of honor,
and we cherish and protect it in them.
You must never mistreat
a woman or malign a man,
nor stand by
and see another do so.
How do you know
if you have it?
Never worry on
the getting of it.
It grows in you
and speaks to you.
All you need do is listen.
All right, lads,
enough of the finer things.
You've animals to tend
to and water to haul.
Away with you.
Your mother and me
will be down directly.
Take the basket.
Come on! I'll race you down the hill.
Do you know how fine you
are to me, Mary MacGregor?
So fine.
Is that why
you sent them away?
To tell me
how fine I am?
Or did you want to make a silk
purse out of my sow's ear again?
What a wanton I'm wed to.
You know what the old wives
say about these standing stones?
No.
What do the old wives say,
old wife?
Come here.
What do they say?
So, what do they say?
They say the stones
make men hard,
and women fertile.
We've no need of them,
you and me.
You know how fine you are
to me, Robert MacGregor?
This tailor in Glasgow
to whom you owe £87
extended this credit
because you were my guest?
Or as you prefer to frame it,
"a member of my household"?
I can assure Your Lordship I
have in no manner indebted him.
And now Killearn
tells me
that you are saddling
one of my serving wenches.
Damn it, sir! Your mother did not send
you to me to debauch innocent girls.
I regret that I have
so offended Your Lordship.
By your leave,
I will remove myself.
And to where,
might I ask?
You are penniless.
You have no mount.
You know no one.
To where will you
remove yourself?
Have you some notion
of presenting yourself
at the Duke of Argyll's door,
and soliciting his patronage
as his new champion?
I am Your Lordship's
to command.
Remember your place, sir!
That's all I ask
of any man.
What is next?
MacGregor, my lord.
You may go, Archibald.
You bear no arms?
I hadn't planned on demanding
terms at sword point.
Robert MacGregor of
Craigrostan, my lord.
So, MacGregor,
I knew your father, an
able man, if not a wise one.
Have you taken on
his mantle?
As best I may,
my lord.
So, how many men
are you master of?
Master of none,
my lord,
but some 200 souls
live close by Craigrostan,
and are in my care.
But you are a prophet
and provider to them,
is that not so?
What I can, I do.
It is no great matter compared
to Your Lordship's world.
To know one's place, MacGregor,
in the order of things
is a great blessing.
And what terms, Killearn?
A fifth, my lord.
A fifth, you say?
What, is this man kin that
you offer such kindly terms?
Am I not accustomed to a
quarter on unsecured loans?
MacGregor has 300 acres
at Craigrostan, my lord.
A man of property
intent on growing richer.
Well, we have more in common than
I would have suspected, MacGregor.
£1,000 for three months, you say,
and these acres of yours as security?
And my oath.
Yes.
Tell me, is there something
in what Killearn says,
that you might have
driven off my cattle,
and returned them with stories of
tinkers caught and summarily executed?
I have, in my day, thieved
cattle, Your Lordship,
but none that were
under my watch.
Is that what passes for
honor with a MacGregor, then?
What passes for honor
with me
is likely enough the same
as with Your Lordship.
When my word is given,
it is good.
Well, you are to be congratulated
on such cheaply bought nobility.
Killearn will draw papers.
And I will expect
the terms to be met.
My thanks
to Your Lordship.
Aye, but it's a fine,
bold signature you have,
worthy of
a chieftain himself.
Are you Rob Roy MacGregor?
I am. And what's your
name? Davey Anderson.
Hello, Davey Anderson.
Hello.
Even the servant boys
know who you are.
You've become a famous reiver and
retriever in your own lifetime.
Business and profit.
And a soft winter.
Are you
Rob Roy MacGregor?
I am.
I'm Will Guthrie.
You heard of me?
No, I have not.
Well, I've heard of you.
Indeed.
And what have you heard, Mr. Guthrie?
I heard you backstabbed
Tam Sibbald.
Were you and Tam kin?
Near enough.
I shagged his sister.
Likely so did Tam.
You want the wind
let out of your bladder?
What's your business
with me, Guthrie?
Business
best done outside.
We have no quarrel.
That can be remedied.
The first cut?
Aye.
Well done.
Some other time,
when we're both sober.
Tam Sibbald has a longer reach
dead than he ever did living.
I'm away home.
Keep the pony and stick to
Killearn till you have the note.
I'll see you back in Craigrostan. Aye.
I'm to wait here
till the note is signed.
Aye. We are
the obedient one.
Fetch and carry
at command.
Tell me, McDonald, why has
a smart young lad like you
attached himself to
such a bunch of tinkers?
I would have thought you more
fit to serve a man like my master,
the Marquis of Montrose.
I do not serve Robert
MacGregor, Killearn.
I'm his friend, and count
myself fortunate to claim it.
My God, what a crew
you Highlanders are.
With your airs and honors,
come begging £1,000 as if you
were doing the lender a favor.
Sheep shaggers,
the lot of you.
My mother could come no nearer than
three candidates for my paternity.
The Earl of Rutland.
Now, there's a name
for a whore master.
A secretary to
the Spanish Ambassador,
whose name she hazarded as Ferdinando.
And some young buck she never saw who
raised her skirts at a masked ball.
He ravished her?
I would put it no higher than surprised.
Archie, take me with you.
Wherever, whatever.
Take me away with you.
I am away, Betty, and God help
me, this is where I've landed.
You think me a gentleman
because I have linen
and can manage a lisp.
I am but a bastard abroad,
seeking my fortune
and the favors of great men,
as big a whore as
my mother ever was.
I'm pregnant by you,
Archie.
Well.
When it asks for its father's name,
at least you'll have it to give.
Mr. Cunningham,
it's me, Killearn.
A word with you.
Don't let him see me.
You are a carbuncle on this
arse of a country, Killearn.
And if you ever inform against
me to His Lordship again,
I'll squeeze the pus out
of you with my bare hands.
My, Archie, but you have
a rare contempt in you.
I gave you no leave
to call me familiar.
Could I pay
for the privilege?
At a fair price.
What are you
gibbering about?
Money, Archie.
Money. What else?
How much money?
Let's talk inside
over a dram.
It's chill on the stairs.
Say what you have to say.
I am engaged within.
You've Betty
on her back.
How much money?
£1,000.
£1,000. What does
£1,000 look like?
Will we have enough
ponies to carry it?
Not coin.
A note of credit drawn
on His Lordship.
At what interest, Rob?
One fifth.
And he gets £200 profit
for three months?
Aye. That's
the price of cash,
and we must plan the
matter to the last penny.
When Alan returns, he'll take three
of you, and you'll go to Crieff.
There you'll bargain
with the drovers,
and have the herd assembled when
I come with a kit for the drive.
How many, Rob?
How big a herd?
300, maybe more.
And whatever we can
acquire along the way.
No harm if a dozen
or more stick.
We'll drive them into
Carlisle like an army.
So let's have
all hands to it.
And we'll stay warm this
winter, within and without.
And to celebrate, we'll hold a
gathering and drink to our success!
Right, McKinness. That's
two shillings still owed.
Next.
Colqhoun.
Colqhoun, what have
you got? A rabbit?
Aye, a rabbit.
Well, you're still
a week behind, Colqhoun.
Must I wait all day
for my note, Killearn?
Patience, MacGregor's man.
Your turn is marked.
Take you that goat
to the pen.
Come, young Davey Wilson.
What have you got for me?
A rabbit.
Another rabbit.
Does nobody have any money?
No, sir. Only a rabbit.
Dreaming of the New World,
were we?
I hear tell in the New World
they have tribes of noble savages
with paint on their faces
and skins on their backs.
You'll be well at home
among them.
Enough of this tripe.
Have you the note?
His Lordship is to
Edinburgh for the assize,
then to London direct.
Great doings at the court.
And he's away without signing the note.
The best I can do
for you is coin.
This was not agreed.
Agreed or no, there's £1,000
here. Take it or leave it,
it makes no difference to me,
nor to His Grace.
Aye, it's a terrible shock,
the sight of such a fortune
within reach, is it not?
It's just as well you have
the trust of the MacGregor,
or I'd be hard pressed
to sign it over to you.
Angus.
It's a great gathering, Rob!
That Alasdair Roy
is a fierce dancer.
The last time I saw you in such a
lather, you were flat on your back.
Do not affront me
afore these folk.
Rob, do you know why Calvinists
are against shagging standing up?
No, Coll. I do not.
They fear it might
lead to dancing.
Stay back, or by God,
I'll shoot you dead.
For a moment there,
I thought you might take the
road to Greenock with your £1,000.
Killing is not so easy
as it seems.
He sat out there all day,
pondering on this.
You gave him coin.
He insisted upon it.
When I told him His Grace
had not signed the note,
he said you must have it,
or the beasts could not
be bought at the best price.
I'm hard put to see you
hand over such a sum
on the demand of one who
couldn't bear the debt.
He was your man,
present at your signing of the
terms, ordered by you to wait.
For a note, not a bag of guineas!
It was not all guineas.
These farmers pay in
small coin, I assure you.
He signed for this
bag of coin?
Indeed.
He did.
Almost as bold
a hand as yourself.
And best be no
skullduggery here, Killearn.
Alan McDonald stands
under my protection.
Well, that's a great comfort
to us all, I must say,
what with
£1,000 at risk.
Now, listen.
We must search for Alan.
I fear he's come
to mischief hereabouts.
I say we look for him
in Greenock, Rob.
It comes quickly to your mind
that he has robbed us, Alasdair.
He spoke of the Americas often enough.
And what?
He walked to Greenock from Buchlyvie,
and sent his pony home without him?
£1,000 would be enough
to buy him 10 ponies.
Alan McDonald
did not betray me.
Now to it,
and find his trace.
Come on! To it!
Go to Greenock, then, since you
have that stink in your nose.
But, Brother,
bad enough that it might be
so without you wishing it.
Well, what news?
The ship sailed the
day before I got there,
and McDonald's name was not
on the harbormaster's list.
But he wouldn't have
likely used his own name
and him run off
with 1,000...
Aye.
Your Lordship, the Duke
of Argyll this way comes.
John, you look like a man
who means to play hard.
Do not presume to speak
above your station, sir!
I will have
my rank from you!
Your Grace.
I have word from court
that you are putting
my name about as a Jacobite,
as one who would rise for the Stuart
should he land here to claim the throne.
Great men such as yourself draw
rumors as shite draws flies.
You are the shite, Montrose,
and the flies upon it!
For all the flowers in your great
gardens, I know you in my nose.
Keep your stink off my name,
or by God, I will clip you as
close as one of your gelded trees,
and this carrion you keep
will not come between us!
What pride to use a
fellow peer in public so!
Damn his pride!
Forgive me.
Damn His Grace's pride.
Why is it so beyond
your belief
that he might have yielded to the sight
of all that money put into his hand?
Unguarded, unasked, but there,
a lifetime's wages in a bag.
Because I know him. I know
him more than half his life.
But was he ever
handed £1,000 before?
He was handed a hundred times more. He
was given trust, and he repaid in kind.
Why do you not believe me?
All right, Rob. He
did not steal from you.
But he has gone,
and the money's gone,
and Montrose will not care if you
believe one thing or the other.
That's another matter. No.
That is the only matter now.
For all our sakes, Robert,
you must take off your high
hat and make what terms you can,
else our home is lost, and
ourselves His Lordship's tenants.
Here comes
the bold Highlander.
No arse in his breeks, but
too proud to tug his forelock.
No doubt the rogue seeks
to blame his servant,
for I hear there is
no word of the man.
I see you're back in favor
with your tailor, Archibald.
He must be a happy man.
So, MacGregor,
how is it with you?
As it was, my lord.
There is still no word of
McDonald or Your Lordship's money.
What are we to do, then?
If Your Lordship would contract
with me for another sum,
I would turn over all profit
and so repay my debt.
I have but lost £1,000.
You ask me to risk another?
My lord, the money was
stolen from me and from you.
I am no part of your
incompetence, MacGregor.
You signed a paper.
And I will honor it.
Ply me not with
your honor, man.
Let us keep
these matters simple.
You are indebted to me.
On that we are agreed?
We are, my lord.
Know you the Duke of Argyll?
By his repute alone.
My report is that
Argyll is a Jacobite,
and would declare for James Stuart
should he seek to reclaim the throne.
These are intelligences
unknown to me, my lord.
They are known to you now.
I'm uncertain of
Your Lordship's meaning.
Damn it, man!
You and your clan are
Jacobites, bred to the bone.
Argyll is nothing to you.
I want your word
against him.
Give it, and we will come to
some reckoning on what you owe me.
I can be of no assistance to Your Lordship
in this matter of the Duke of Argyll.
You owe me.
I owe you money.
Nothing more.
What you have asked is as below me
as it should be beneath Your Lordship.
You misspeak yourself,
MacGregor.
It is the Marquis of Montrose
who has misspoke himself,
to ask my perjury
against his enemies.
Leave the blade be, sir!
This is not your quarrel.
You do not hear me, MacGregor.
I did not ask if or whether.
Your land is forfeit to me
against your debt.
Until that is settled, I will
have you lodged in the tollbooth.
Take him into custody, Archibald.
You have my commission on it!
My father spent
two years in that jail
for no cause but the will
of great men like you.
And I will not
go there, sir.
Call out the watch,
damn you!
Call nothing,
or I'll cut his throat!
You are damned,
MacGregor. Damned to hell.
Come, Your Lordship.
Leave the devil some work.
You've done enough
for one day.
Well, call out the watch!
Yes, sir.
Call out the watch!
Do you hear me?
You have slept your last
peaceful night, MacGregor,
you and yours.
What is John Campbell,
Duke of Argyll, to us, Robert,
that you must defend him
against Montrose?
I did not defend him.
I refused to bear
false witness against him.
Gregor, send men to the
passes and set watches.
And the lochside?
They'll not likely come along
by the shore, but watch all ways.
Now, listen, lads. I have to
go to the hills for a time.
You stay by your mother
and be her help, you hear?
Let Argyll know that you
are persecuted for his sake.
I'm persecuted for no
man's sake but my own, Mary.
What?
Would you have me lie against
my conscience to suit Montrose?
No! To suit me
and Duncan and Ranald,
to stay home with your wife and children
instead of taking to the hills like a fox.
Out!
Out! Out! Out!
He'll be with you
soon enough!
Take the boys and go to
Morag's. She'll make a place.
And let Montrose's
troopers foul my house?
No harm will come to you.
Montrose's quarrel is with me.
And you revel in it.
The great man against all.
And likely you'll slip down in
the night when the mood takes you.
Or will you just find yourself
a sheep to comfort you?
Aye, well, if I do, it will be
one that doesn't bleat so bitter.
No trouble between them
and you. Give no cause.
This is between me
and Montrose,
and likely when he's broke a
few horses, he'll quieten down.
Watch Alasdair. Put him
where he can do no harm.
Keep up the watch
for McDonald.
Rob, he's long gone.
Aye, but is he over
the seas or under them?
And, Coll,
ask Morag to go down to Mary.
She's sore at me for this business.
That Montrose is a stoat of a man.
Heaven protect us from his like.
When the king comes
across the water again,
we'll see him hung.
Your Lordship will not regret
leaving this matter in my hands.
I have some knowledge of how
best to bring such rogues to heel.
Broken but not dead,
Archibald. That is all I ask.
"Broken but not dead. "
It has a ring to it.
Your health.
Goodbye!
Instead of spying them out,
we should lay for them,
and cut them down as they
come through the passes.
Aye, a wee war with
Montrose would suit us fine.
Listen, Alasdair Roy.
Keep your watch, give
warning, and stay your hand,
or you'll answer to me.
Damn that McDonald
has brought this on us.
I never trusted the man. Always
at Rob's arse like a collie dog.
Morag had a dream
on him. Saw him drowned.
Maybe his ship sank, and him
loaded down with the theft.
Give me your musket.
Boys, wake up! Wake up!
Quickly! Quickly!
Get out of bed!
Go, go!
Bring the Gregorach!
I've come for the outlaw
Robert MacGregor.
If you think he'd be lying
in his bed waiting for you,
you're more of a fool
than you look.
Search the outsheds.
Burn them.
Kill the stock.
You best stand aside,
Mistress MacGregor.
You don't ask a whore.
You make her.
No!
Do you want yours now,
Killearn?
Now that I've loosened her
up for you.
Think of yourself
as the scabbard
and me the sword,
Mistress MacGregor.
And a fine fit
you were, too.
I will think of you dead
until my husband makes you so.
And then I will think
on you no more.
Indeed.
Such a man as he will need
to see blood on his blade
before honor is satisfied.
Tell him Archibald Cunningham
is at his service.
What are you gawking at? Have
you never been to war before?
You're a warrior, Archie,
and no mistake.
If she doesn't come out, Archie,
there will be a reckoning.
Shagging her's one thing,
burning her's another.
She'll be out. She's a
hater, that one. There she is.
Back to the boat!
They say it's not a sin if
you don't take pleasure in it.
Come on!
I am Alasdair
Roy MacGregor!
Come on! Come on!
Is that the best
you can do?
Do it again,
bastards!
Come on!
Come on! Come on! Come...
Mary, are you hurt?
Did they wound you?
Mary.
What have they done?
We will avenge you.
Rob will kill every
last one of them.
He will not know.
Rob will not know.
Mary, Rob must know.
He will not!
He will not know!
I will not tell him,
and you will not.
Do you hear me,
Alasdair MacGregor?
But, Mary, no.
It is what they want!
It is what the Englishman
wants! It is his plan!
You swear it to me.
Swear it!
I cannot! I cannot! Swear it! Swear it!
You can!
If I can bear it to be done,
you can bear to be silent!
Now, you swear it!
Swear it.
Swear it. Swear it.
Swear it! Swear it!
I swear. I swear. I swear.
And I will hold you to it.
Mark me.
But of MacGregor himself,
still no word?
We will have him
soon enough.
I have set such an affront
to his Highland honor,
that he will come
to redeem it.
Very well.
See to it that I am not
mocked, and in the meanwhile,
make my claim against these acres
in Lomondside for the debt he owes.
Still no word of this
man of MacGregor's?
He who took the coin?
No, my lord, not a word.
Nor will there be.
This was a ploy of MacGregor's, to
take the money and blame another.
His man is well hid, and Your
Lordship's money well spent.
I wager it.
You have a rare grasp of the
conspirator's mind, Archibald.
You're to be
commended on it.
He sees through it, Archie.
I know him and his gibes.
And you think it would
count against us if he knew?
He has another 300 acres
to plant and prune.
And all for the price of a
paltry 1,000 Scotch pounds.
A fair price by any
reckoning. Archie, sir!
I must speak with you.
I am dismissed from service
on account of my state.
And what is your state,
pretty Betty?
You know well.
I'm with your child.
And he, this one,
has made report of it.
Betty, my report did nothing your
belly wouldn't announce on its own.
Archie, what am I to do?
Root it out.
If Killearn here does not know an
old crone with a twig I miss my guess.
It's gone
too far for that.
Then it will not be the first
bastard born in Scotland.
Archie, I love you.
Love is a dunghill,
Betty,
and I am but a cock that
climbs upon it to crow.
No!
It's a sore thing they have
done to us, Mary and me.
Far past any wrong I had expected,
even from such as Montrose.
He must pay for it, Rob!
Else what are we?
Pay he will till
his teeth squeal.
Think on it, now.
Think on it.
Even if we raised all the
MacGregors, we could not, must not,
fight Montrose
in open battle.
He has 10, 20 times our numbers and
the strength of the Crown to back him.
There is honor here.
You were wronged.
Mary is wronged.
Honor will be satisfied.
You know me well enough.
But consider this.
One house burned,
cattle killed,
but none are dead,
none injured.
Rob is right.
Rob is right!
It is not within our reach
to harm such as Montrose.
Wheesht! Wheesht! Wheesht!
Wheesht! Wheesht!
I will harm him.
Never fear.
Aye!
The tenderest part of
the Marquis is his purse.
We'll hurt him there.
Thieve his cattle.
Steal his rent.
Rent and cattle,
until his coffers are bled.
Aye!
Wait! Wait!
Wheesht!
Wheesht! Morag.
We have not heard
Mary on it,
and in truth, she was
the one most affronted.
Rob is right. What cannot
be helped must be endured.
It will look more like
itself when the sun shines.
Eh, lads? Yeah.
When we have our bed in it
and us in our bed,
it will seem home enough.
All right, play can wait.
We have work to do.
Duncan.
I should have been
with you, Mary.
It wasn't right that
I was in the hills.
Then you would
be dead now.
No. They would have
taken me to the tollbooth.
No. I think you
would be dead.
I could not hear
all of it,
but Killearn talked of money
that Archie might take.
This is Cunningham,
this Archie?
He is wild,
but it's not him.
It's that Killearn.
He has the devil in him.
Tell me about this money.
Did you hear a sum spoken?
Archie said it would be the
easiest £1,000 he'd ever earned.
The only pity that it would be
in Scots and not English pounds.
How did he mean
to earn this £1,000?
I know not.
Save that Killearn said
no trace must be left.
My husband will appreciate
that you came with this word.
Will you take some supper and
rest, Betty? For you look ill-used.
I'm no worse used than I
deserve, Mistress MacGregor.
For I have a bastard's
bastard in me.
And no home for him
when he comes out.
Well, we better feed you, or he
won't have the strength to try it.
Lass, lass, lass.
Bear up now.
Your bairn will have you,
and you will have it.
But I will not
have Archie.
Mistress MacGregor,
I love him,
even after all.
Is that not a worse sin than any other?
No, Betty.
Love is never a sin,
only the lack of it.
I knew it. I knew
they plotted against us.
Damn them that
they carried it through.
I will have them
before the assize.
Killearn and Cunningham. Aye, and
Montrose, too, if he were part of it.
You think such men
as these will admit this,
because wee Betty Sturrock, with
her belly under her chin, says so?
What's her belly
to do with it?
She's carrying
the Englishman's child.
They'll call her a
whore come for revenge.
Now, they can say what they
like. She'll speak the truth.
Robert, to these men, the
truth is but a lie undiscovered.
I will have justice!
Alan McDonald is dead,
woman.
Then take your case
to the Duke of Argyll.
It's known he bears
Montrose no favor.
You hold great store
by wolves of different shades.
They're all alike at lambing.
And you will have nothing
but your own way!
I tell you, Killearn and
Cunningham will not be condemned
before any assize
on Betty's word.
Aye. But I know one
that will condemn them.
And I'll have them before it,
or I'm not Robert MacGregor.
The Englishman will
never find him.
MacGregor knows
every rock and track,
and can walk faster
than the troopers can ride.
Look, put me
onto His Lordship
as a man that knows
the highways and byways.
I'll find him.
I swear it.
On your feet, Killearn.
You and I have business.
Now is your moment, Guthrie. It
would stand well with His Lordship.
This is not your fight,
Guthrie.
And if I make it
my fight?
Then give Tam Sibbald my
regards when you see him.
Fight him well and you'll
win His Lordship's favor.
I warrant it.
Please, please, please don't kill
me. Don't kill me. It wasn't me.
Outside.
It's him the lass
wants revenge on. Cunningham.
And I grant it,
he treated her sore.
If you harm me, His
Lordship will hunt you down,
and you know it.
I'm past caring, Killearn.
The lantern.
Go back, get Betty, and we'll
try him before morning. Now.
Inside.
Mary! Mary!
Who is it?
It's Alasdair.
Rob's holding Killearn, and he
wants to see Betty straightaway.
I'll wake her.
Treat her gentle. She's
near the end of her tether.
Where's my father?
Wheesht.
Are the soldiers coming?
You two should be sleeping.
No!
Stay there!
Get my knife!
Mary? Where's the girl?
Betty Sturrock hanged
herself in our shed.
She made me bring her. I
told... I made him bring me
for I have dealings
with this Killearn.
Me and Betty Sturrock
and Betty Sturrock's child,
the three of us will
bring it out of him.
No. This is no
matter for him.
This is between us.
As I am your wife, Robert, I
will have my way in this, I will.
Betty! Is that you?
Betty is dead.
She killed herself this
night, and her unborn with her.
Mistress MacGregor.
So the poor girl is dead.
Spare me your hypocrisy,
Killearn.
You are as much her murderer
as she, you and that Englishman.
I had no part
in her child
any more than that
matter at Craigrostan.
You stood and gloated.
You did all with your eyes.
You have not told him.
You think me such a puppet that
I would put my husband's head
in a noose fashioned
from my own dishonor?
You have a proposal
for me. I can tell.
You will sign your name to a statement
telling how you slew Alan McDonald,
stole my husband's money,
burned our property.
Before a judge
you will sign it.
And let them hang me in the
tollbooth for my trouble?
No great inducement,
Mistress MacGregor.
When it is signed,
you may go where you will.
Where you can.
I shall not soon
forget, Mary,
the last time I saw you.
How nobly you walked from
that burning, like a queen.
You will sign it or else.
Or else what?
You'll tell Rob how Cunningham used you?
I have another picture,
not so noble,
of you stood in Lomond water,
washing between your legs.
I've wondered many a time
since that morning,
did you wash Archie out of
you, or is he still in there,
growing into his father?
Yes.
Well, I have a proposal
for you, Mistress MacGregor.
Persuade your man that
Cunningham alone killed his man
and kept the money entirely,
and I will not speak
of what you have
inside you.
Rob would be hard pressed to
love such a bastard, would he not?
But you know
the saying, Mary.
'Tis a wise father
knows his own child.
And if you'll not say
anything, neither will I.
You have my word on it.
Cut me...
She cut me.
The bitch cut me!
Mary, are you hurt?
Are you hurt?
What have you done, woman?
Am I cut bad?
Not bad enough for me.
I mean, my God, what
made you do such a thing?
I have as much cause
as you in this. More.
He has to be
made to confess.
He will never confess.
Betty was right.
He has the devil in him.
Devil or no, he's my
prisoner. Don't you understand?
Robert, there are things
you must know.
Things I have to tell you.
So? Tell me.
There was...
Well?
He's dead, Rob.
I could do nothing.
Robert, listen to me now.
There's no time
for talk now.
Alasdair,
can you sink a man?
Aye.
Cut the wind out of him,
put a rock in his belly,
take him out where it's deep.
Montrose will scour us
out now for sure.
We must make sure you and the
lads are safe before he comes.
Deep, mind you!
I am mocked by this rogue who
you took to deliver me broken.
'Tis myself who will be
broken if these raids go on.
Now my factor is abducted in plain view.
Am I gone mad?
Your Lordship...
Do not...
Do not, I say,
speak in my stead.
There's something here
that I do not see.
Killearn and you have
some hand in matters
that is hid from sight.
This tells me that you are in cash,
yet I know you are without means.
Gaming, Your Lordship.
The cards favored.
Do you take me
entirely for a Whig, sir?
I care not what you and that
greasy capon have cooked up,
but put an end to this
impudence against me.
I am James Graham,
Marquis of Montrose.
And I will not be mocked.
You hear me?
On the roof!
On the roof with it!
Take it from the back!
We can't let them burn,
loot, and ride away.
We should hit them, Rob.
Cunningham is there.
He's the one that took...
I know who he is.
Have you no thought
to avenge Mary for that?
There's 30 or more men.
They'd ride us down like sheep.
Alasdair MacGregor
is no sheep.
Coll's right.
We can do nothing.
Company, make ready!
Attention, men!
Damn the wee fool! Scatter! Into
the mist. Find your own way home!
There they are!
After him!
I want MacGregor!
Fire, you fools! Fire!
I hit one of them.
And it will cost us,
I'm thinking.
Move! Move!
God's curse on you
for a brother, Alasdair.
I want MacGregor!
You're getting too old
for the wars, Rob, eh?
Come on!
Fire! Fire,
you fools! Fire!
Put me down. I can run. Shut your mouth.
Run, Rob, run!
Go on, Rob!
Run for yourself!
I want MacGregor!
I want MacGregor! After him!
Be quiet!
Hold still.
Knocked the breath
out of me.
Rob, I can't feel my legs.
Are they there?
Aye, aye.
Your legs are fine.
Forgive me, Rob, for
I can't forgive myself.
Save your breath, lad.
I couldn't have
saved her, Rob.
They were done with Mary
before I reached them.
She made me swear
not to tell you.
I'm sorry.
Done what with Mary?
Done what?
She said...
She said if
she could bear it...
What of Mary, Alasdair?
Rob, I can't see.
I'm here, Alasdair.
What of Mary? What of it?
They...
They violated her.
Alasdair, who did this?
The mist is clearing.
Be ready.
Be ready
to search upwards!
You men,
search upwards!
There was a shot
on the ledge.
Forward!
Where is he?
Over there!
Get the horse!
Well, well. The great
MacGregor come to hand at last.
Well, how does it seem
to you tonight, MacGregor?
Is God's great plan for
us all to your liking?
"Broken but not dead"
was His Lordship's request.
Well, I will do my part
if you will do yours
and not die before
the bridge at Glen Orchy.
Tell me,
what did you do with that
bag of guts, Killearn?
Vex me not, MacGregor. Or I
shall have you dragged awhile.
I'm a man of my word.
You're a thief,
a murderer,
and a violator of women.
I had hoped you'd come to me
long since on that score.
If I had known earlier, you
would have been dead sooner.
I will tell you something
to take with you.
Your wife was far
sweeter forced
than many are willing.
In truth, put to it, I think
not all of her objected.
I appreciate the honor you do me,
Mistress MacGregor, in bringing your case.
But from all I'm acquainted
with your husband,
he has earned the enmity
of the Marquis of Montrose
by borrowing money
that he cannot repay,
and ever harrying
his stock as blackmail.
There is more to the matter, Your Grace.
I'm sure there is, but it is not
part of mine to intrude myself.
Sensible as I am
to your condition.
It's a hard thought,
but men make the quarrels
and women and weans bear them.
Your Grace, Robert finds himself in
this condition for taking your part.
My part?
What cause had he to do
that and in what manner?
He refused to condemn
you by false witness
when the Marquis asked him
to say you were a Jacobite,
to injure your name
at court.
Montrose asked this of him?
In remission of this debt.
But Robert refused.
I did not know your husband
bore me such good will.
Indeed, Your Grace, I think he
favors you no more than any great man.
"As wolves at lambing"
is his word for you all.
It was not done
for Your Grace
but for his own honor,
which he holds dearer
than myself or his sons,
his clan or kin. And for
which I have oft chided him.
But it is him
and his way,
and were he other, he would
not be Robert Roy MacGregor.
He would not come
here before you
nor would he favor me
to do so in his stead.
But I have no choice, unless I
give him up entire to his enemies.
And though
I love his honor,
it is but a moon-cast shadow
to the love I bear him.
For the grace of God,
I have his child inside me.
And I would have
a father for it.
You do your man
no dishonor, Mary.
Faith, he is a man
much blessed by fortune.
They have MacGregor,
my lord.
Cavalry, halt!
Broken but not dead, Your
Lordship, as you requested.
Ungag him.
So, MacGregor,
what have you
to say for yourself?
I have been wronged
by Your Lordship
and by those
who serve him.
You are wronged?
You?
If I am not much mistaken, it
is myself that is short £1,000,
whose cattle is reived, and whose
factor, Killearn, is abducted.
Then ask this thing here
where your money is
and where he sunk Alan
McDonald after he killed him.
Same accusations he spat
at me, Your Lordship.
Desperate words
from a desperate man.
Do you have proofs
of these matters?
You have my word on it.
I think it will take
more than that.
Then you have the nature
of this man here.
If Your Lordship cannot tell
what is true from what is not,
then I fear his judgment
is beyond repair.
Hang him from the bridge.
MacGregor!
Cut him free!
Bring him back here!
I want him back!
Bring him
back here!
In the water!
I see him!
Right through that gap!
Just through there!
Get off your mounts and walk.
What a stench!
Get after him!
What a stink!
Wait till you smell this.
Let's get downwind
of this.
Is this
where we may stay?
Aye, by His Grace's goodness,
under his protection.
Will Father come here? If he can.
Coll!
No!
Robert?
Robert!
My Robert!
What have they
done with you?
You should have
told me, Mary.
Robert, I should have,
but I could not.
Forgive me, my love.
I was wrong.
It was wrong.
No. It was me
who was wrong.
You were right when you told
me I must have it my own way.
It's that which brought
all this on us.
I should have packed my pride
and given Montrose his way.
No, Robert. And all this has come on us,
all this you have endured. No.
Craigrostan would still be ours.
Alasdair and Coll would be alive.
And wrong would
have been done you!
And what of the wrong done
you, wrong past bearing?
No, not past bearing.
Not past bearing.
Not if I have my Robert
and he has himself.
And you would not, not if you
had done a lesser man's bidding.
Honor is the gift a man gives
himself. You told our boys that.
Would you have stolen from yourself
that what makes you Robert MacGregor?
My Mary.
How fine you are to me.
And you to me.
Robert, there is more.
What more?
I am carrying a child
and I do not know
who is the father.
Ach, Mary.
Mary.
I could not kill it,
husband.
It is not the child
who needs killing.
This point of honor
might likely kill you, sir.
I have seen the man at work
and he is no dunce with a blade.
If Your Grace could arrange this
I would be more beholding to him
than I already am.
Very well. I will see
what I can make of it.
MacGregor.
Sir?
He will kill you, MacGregor.
I would lose money
if I wagered other.
Your Lordship has my permission
to profit what way he may.
I have had a correspondence from
His Grace, the Duke of Argyll.
It would seem that our
MacGregor is holed with him.
He offers us a match.
You and the Highlander.
Argyll would recoup his
loss from his last wager.
Bring him on.
You speak, Archibald?
One must never underestimate
the healing power of hatred.
How long must
you go, Father?
Just for a while.
Is it business
you have with the Duke?
Aye, business.
So, boys, have you heard there's going
to be another addition to the family?
Show them where
it's hid, Mary.
Is it inside you?
How does it get out?
The same road it got in.
Robert...
Robert, what if you don't... Wheesht.
No, I cannot.
What if...
I cannot.
What if you do
not return to us?
If it's a boy,
call him Robert.
If a lass,
name her for my love,
Mary MacGregor.
My man Guthrie was like
an ox at the knacker's yard
under Cunningham's blade.
You will need to be twice
as quick as poor Will.
Tell me, MacGregor,
is this matter of honor
concerning your wife?
It's concerning me,
Your Grace.
Mr. Cunningham and I
have matters outstanding.
She will not thank you for
making her a widow, honor or no.
Perhaps you'd like to wager
a sum for her maintenance.
If it will help you die any
easier, I'll lay 20 guineas for her.
50 would go further.
By God, but you have a
style to you, MacGregor.
I like that. Aye.
So, what are we to wager
on this outcome, Your Grace?
Guineas again?
I want no part of this. There
are more than champions here.
I think these men
hate the other.
Aye.
They are none too fond.
You offered MacGregor
amnesty from his debts
if he would lay
charges against me.
So, that is how he cozened
you to give him shelter.
I know the truth
when I hear it.
And here was me thinking that
that was God's gift alone.
Do not think that all sins go
unpunished in this life, Montrose.
Well...
I see one set soon
to be paid for.
Will you not take
my odds, Argyll?
I give you five
on the fop.
I wager you but this,
if MacGregor lives, you will
acquit him of all he owes you.
And if he loses?
I will pay his bill.
My factor will call upon
Your Grace's factor.
You are here on
a matter of honor.
I am here to assure you
settle it honorably.
There will be
no backstabbing.
You will not
throw your blades,
nor will you use weapons
other than agreed.
If quarter is asked...
No quarter will be asked.
Or given.
Attend upon your weapons,
and commence upon my mark.
Neither asked nor given.
I will hold you
to our bargain.
Those wounds will need care.
By Your Grace's leave, I'll
go where it can best be found.
As you will.
I will know who to
wager on the next time.
I hope Your Grace
will live so long.
Mother! Look!