Prepare profit and loss
statements after taking..
..into account the
following adjustments..
One..
Returns outwards Rs.1000
were wrongly included in sales.
were wrongly included in sales..
In sales.
Included in sales..
"Listen to what I have to say.. "
"You know what time is. "
"The night is sleeping and
a new day has awakened. "
"This ambience is still in slumber. "
"Wishes are leading my way. "
Returns outwards Rs.7000
were wrongly included in sales..
"Wake up, Sid! The time says!"
"Wake up, Sid! Let's go somewhere!"
"Wake up, Sid! Listen if you can.. "
"..the voice from all the directions. "
"Wake up! Listen. "
- Bhaiyya.. Bhaiyya!
Bhaiyya! Open the door.
Brother!
What are you doing in there?
Bhaiyya!
Open the door!!
Chhotu! Why didn't you
wake me up sooner?!
You said you were going to
study all night..
..I thought you'd be up by now.
Did you fall asleep?
You fell asleep! You had 4 cups of coffee
and you still fell asleep!
What will you do now?
How will you give your exam now?!
Just try not to fail, I guess..
Shut up! This is all your fault!
Now you sit here and
eat this breakfast! I'm off..
Move.
- Best of luck!
The same bloody situation again, Sid..
..you should've at least studied
for this one last exam..
Ten questions out of thirty?
That's not so bad..
you'll probably pass..
Or, maybe you won't..
What are you going to do, Sid?
You're never going to do anything,
Sidharth Mehra.
You'll definitelyfail in this exam.
Because that's what happens..
..when you don't attend
a single lecture the whole year.
This is just what you deserve!
But what do you have to worry about, Sid?
Who cares if you fail?
Your father will still be loaded..
..and you'll still have the best car
in this college! Right!
Shut up!
- Relax.
Don't listen to these losers,
Sid.. don't worry.
I'm your friend..
..and I know that you're going to pass,
like you always do!
By the way,
where were you last night?
I kept calling..
why didn't you answer?
Did you read the notes I gave you?
Oh shut up Laxmi..
Can't you at least let him dream in peace?
Sid! I'm in the same situation as you.
I couldn't study last night either.
I was with Neha, dude..
She was studying economics and
I was studying her. All night long!
Anyway don't worry brother..
Ifwe fail, we'll fail together.
We've been together since kindergarten.
What's one more year, right?
Don't worry, pal.
Everyone, pens down! Stop writing.
Make sure your exam roll numbers
are entered correctly.
Come on, stop writi ng.
Guys farewell party!
Tomorrow night! Do come, Ok?
You can do this dance there!
Farewell party tomorrow night!
There's going to be food,
dance everything! Do come!
Farewell party!
Tomorrow night! Do come, Ok?
Students hostel..
Tomorrow night.. Farewell party..
Please arrive..
Hey Nisha. Stop there!
What the hell is Debbie's problem?
I don't want to go to her farewell party.
It'll be bloody boring anyway..
Shut up Sid! We have to go!
We might never see these people again.
This is it.
College is over.
Where did the last 5 years go?
Life is going to change now..
there's so much to do!
You're right, there's a lot to do!
Now that the exams are over,
I can finally start my diet!
From tomorrow.. I swear!
You don't have to diet.
I'll marry you!
Please, don't be silly..
Ok, can we go now?
- Yeah let's go.
Come Rishi.
What is this?
Sid! Give it back! Sid!
What the hell is this?!
He bought it for Neha.
I think her name's engraved in there too..
Give it back Sid.
Rish, you gotta be kidding me..
Sid, I love her!
Dude, you're pathetic!
Don't be an idiot.
Rish.. are you actually
going to propose to Neha?!
Put that ring away!
Have you gone mad?
Why are you being so serious?
You know, everyone has
to get serious after college..
..you'll have to do it too.
Right, which is why I've made
a really serious plan.
What? - Tell me.
- Lets go and get drunk!
Sid! Be serious!
- Be serious.
Yeah but I don't want to
be serious right now!
We've finished our exams today..
who cares about tomorrow..
..as long as we can have
some fun.. tonight? Come on!
Let's go!
- Yes.
"What to do, my heart is singing?"
"What to do, my Iife is intoxicating?"
"What to do, slowly
I am getting intoxicated?"
"What to do, I am getting
a Iittle effected by it?"
"What to do, my slept
desires have awakened. "
"What to do, my Iife is Iost in the way?"
"What to do, I have new
dreams in my eyes?"
"What to do, I am getting
a Iittle effected by it?"
"What to do?"
"These days and nights. "
"All these talks. "
"Fragrant. "
"Intoxicated. "
"Let this time stand still
and I stay the same way I am. "
"What to do, my heart is singing?"
"What to do, my life is intoxicating?"
"What to do, slowly
I am getting intoxicated?"
"What to do, I am getting
a little effected by it?"
"What to do?"
Is that Rishi, no?
Maa! Why don't you knock..?
You are being my son..
Why knocking?
What do you want, ma?
I came to meet you..
So much time not seeing you..
Ma please stop speaking in English..
You don't know how to..
How your exam Siddy?
It was Ok..
I'm so proud of you..
You're a graduate now.
Now you must learn
some organization Siddy..
What mess.. Why do you keep
ordering pizza all the time?
I make such good food at home.
And stop playing videogames all day.
You have way too many clothes!
Throw them all away now.
These tiny-tiny tshirts
don't suit you anymore.
You are the man now.. Not boy..
You are mature.
You should wear shirts..
you'll look handsome..
Maa, I always look handsome!
Stop bugging me!
And don't touch my things!
I've told you this before!
Ma.. Here, you can fold it.
And don't feel bad now..
Will you eat dinner with us?
I made it myself..
Eating? - Yes Ma.
What a car man!
Sid, you should join the office.
Whoa! Where did the office come from?
Your college is over, right?
And you don't have
classes to skip anymore..?
No..
Then you're joining the office.
But pa.. what am I going to do there?
Work, what else?
But pa! Office?!
I mean.. our company
manufactures bathroom furnishings!
'Flower Showers' for heaven's sake..
It's just.. it's just not my thing!
Just not your thing?
Do you know that 'Bathroom Fittings
and Furnishings Association'
Rated those same 'shower heads'
number 1 last year?!
Everyone from millionaires to mailmen are
buying our showers!
Do you know what that means?
Our company has taught lndia
how to shower in style!
No! - No!
No way! I'm not joining the office!
Ok then Sid!
Actually, I was thinking that..
..this car would look
really good in our garage.
You're not serious? Are you?!
Just work at the office for 6 months.
The car is yours..
6 months?!
That's too long, pa.. 1 5 days..
Do I look like an idiot?
At least 90 days..
No pa.. twenty days..
Minimum 60 days..
No more than 30 days.
Thirty days? Ok done!
You can start work tomorrow.
Wake up.
- Tomorrow?! Yeah ok..
"Wake up."
Pa.. What kind of a deal is this?
A Porsche for a month's work?
My son is joining my office.
That's the biggest deal!
"Wake up, Sid. Wake up. "
Sid..
Sorry ma, I have to go.
My friends are here.
Eat something before you go..
Mother I will be going to office
from tomorrow.
Last night of freedom..
Bye! Love you.
Friends Hello!
DJ cut the music!
Laila.. got any plans after college?
I'm going for the Miss lndia contest!
I've been training for a year now..
Dieting, workouts..
Hey, you wanna feel my abs?
Have you seen Taare Zameen Par?
You know, my life is
exactly like that film..
I don't want to be
a journalist anymore.
I can't handle
this tabloid culture..
Rishi! This party is so tacky!
I wanna go home!
Baby! Not everything can be
as perfect as you, can it? Lemon tart?
I wanna go home, Rishi.
I'm leaving. Bye.
But what about the lemon tart..?
Do you love lemon tart more than me?
I'm going home!
I am going home.
- Listen, please. I love you.
Hi everyone.
This song goes up to Aarti.
Aarti, I love you.
Stop! Please don't!
I hate being photographed..
Why?
Because.. Because
I don't look good in them.
Not at all, I think you'll look nice.
Some other time, Ok?
You're not from my college, are you?
Nope..
Thought as much.. you look
a little older than this crowd.
Thanks! Only a little I hope.
So what are you doing at this party?
I came along with some
girls from the hostel..
This girl Debbie,
she's one of the organizers and..
Wait a minute..
You came here with Debbie!?
Yeah..
Oh God, if she sees you with me, she's..
What's WRONG with you?
With me?
She's the one with the problem.
That freak! Anyway, you're lucky,
my company is way better than hers.
Is that so?
- Yeah, seriously.
Ok.. Iet's find out.
So what do you do?
Me? Er.. I spend my dad's money.
Nice. And what do plan
on doing after college?
I plan on continuing to
spend my dad's money.
Sit.
What about you?
What do you do?
I'm new to Bombay.
Here to earn my own money.
Oh? So you're not from Bombay?
Uh-huh..
Do you like it here?
Actually I haven't seen much yet.
I got off the train and
went to the hostel, and now I'm here.
Wait a minute..
You got here TODAY!?
Yeah..
And out of all the places
you could have gone to,
You chose THlS boring party?
Why?
It was too late to go anywhere else..
Listen, this is Bombay..
It's never late here..
And you know what?
The city is at its best at night.
Less traffic, less heat..
Really, you should have
been out there right now..
So let's go for a walk!
Walk?
- Yeah..
When?
- Now..
Ok.
- Ok?
Sure.. Ok, Let's go..
One second, hold on.. I don't want
to give you the wrong idea..
But it was your idea..
I know, but I don't
even know you and..
Well, I don't knowyou either..
Yeah but listen, it's not like
I want to sleep with you!
Whoa! Did I say that I wanted
to sleep with you?!
It didn't even cross my mind..
Oh come on, be honest.
You met a girl at a party,
and you're leaving with her in 5 minutes.
Of course it crossed your mind!
Ok, it might have..
But if you have a problem with that,
it won't again.
It's all good.
Really? Ok let's go for that walk then.
Ok. Wait a second..
What's your name? I'm Sidharth..
I'm Aisha! Hi!
No one.
Really? You don't have
any friends here?
Family?
Nope. - Then you must have a job..
Not yet!
You ran away from home, didn't you?
Really Aisha..
why have you come to Bombay?
To meet you..
Come on, tell me seriously.
Seriously, to become independent.
I'm from Calcutta, Sidharth.
I've lived there all my life.
I wanted to give my life a new direction,
so I came here.
To try something new..
Like a holiday?
No Sidharth..!
Not like a holiday.. Iike.. Iife!
Do you know the feeling
when you cook your own food..
..make your own money, and spend.
Live a life you've made for yourself..?
Independence! Know what I mean?
No..
Forget it.
But what are you going to do here?
I'll work, what else?
Do you know this magazine?
Mumbai Beat. Of course!
It has great photographs!
And good articles too.
I'm going to their office tomorrow,
for an interview.
Aah.. Of course! That diary at the party..
You're a writer, aren't you?
Well, not professionally.
But soon, I hope..
So Sidharth,
tell me something about Bombay.
What would you like to know?
If there was one place in Bombay you..
..could show me tonight,
what would that be?
The sea has always been really
special for Bombay, hasn't it?
I guess I can see why..
..In a city where anything
and everything can change,..
..the sea is a constant.
It'll always be here. It's beautiful.
Actually Aisha, you should see
the sea when it rains.
The Bombay monsoons are to die for!
People might complain
about the traffic and the flooding..
but, I just love the monsoon.
When it rains,
the sea looks amazing!
I can stare at it for hours..
it's really awesome.
Wow.. I'm going to remember that..
Can I ask you something, Aisha?
How can you still have more questions?
Ask..
You're all alone here, aren't you scared?
Are you kidding Sidharth? I'm terrified!
I've never lived alone before.
But you know what.. I'll get over it.
Coming to Bombay was a dream.
And now that it's actually coming true.
I can't let fear stand in my way.
There's so much to do that
I won't have time to be afraid!
Well.. I think you're
really tough, Aisha.. really.
I can't even imagine doing
what you're doing.
So, I guess, cheers to your dream!
Cheers.
.. my father made a fortune
manufacturing bathroom
furnishings here..
It's quite an impressive story,
but 'flower showers'!
I mean isn't that ridiculous?
Well this is me..
Single Women's Hostel!
So, when can I call you?
Actually, I don't have a phone yet.
Sidharth, I don't wanna
keep saying this but..
I really don't want to
give you the wrong idea..
God, I get it! I have
the same idea as you.
That we should be.. friends.
Friends is great..
Why don't you give me your email lD?
Pen?
- Right there..
Sidharth..
You're my first friend in Bombay.
Sid.. friends call me Sid.
Thanks for tonight, Sid..
What are you doing in there?
Sir got tired of waiting
for you and left already..
Stop bugging me, Chhotu!
I just need 5 more minutes, Ok?
Yes? How can I help you?
Mr. Ram Mehra..?
Sir is out. And you are..?
I'm his son.. Sid.. Sidharth..
Oh?! Sorry! I'm really very sorry!
How nice to see you
in the office Mr. Mehra!
Er.. call me Sid?
Ok, Mr. Mehra. Please come.
You're so whipped, dude!
She's your girlfriend,
not your boss! Be a man!
Oh hi pa! Rishi I'll have
to call you back..
Okay, bye.
Can we start work now, Sid?
Of course, that's why I'm here..
Ok then Sid! This is going to
be your last pizza in my cabin.
In fact, you won't even be
allowed in here without my permission.
This is not our house Sidharth.
This is my office. And we have
rules here. Is that clear?
You will work outside,
with rest of my staff.
And because you know nothing
about Mehra Furnishings.
You'll have to read
company's literature.
You will have to read up
on the company's background..
..our locations, our turnover,
our clients.. everything.
Okay?
By next Tuesday, you have to pick
a department to work for.
This might all seem
a little dull to you at first..
..but eventually, it'll get interesting.
Lastly, you are not
my spoilt son in here Sid..
..but a young boy
with a chance to understand..
..the workings of a very big company.
Consider yourself lucky.
Hello 'my first Bombay friend'.
How are you?
I was thinking about you today..
so, here I am!
Anyhow, the news is..
I went in to the magazine office
for my first interview today..
..and Sid.. it was amazing!
Some places have such character..
..that you immediately
identify with them.
Do you know that feeling?
I had a meeting
with the Creative Director.
It went off quite well actually.
Amit is also Head Photographer there.
Didn't you say that you liked
the photographs in this magazine?
If I get this job,
you should come visit sometime.
My final interview is in a few days.
Keeping my fingers crossed!
That's it for now. Aisha.
Hello 'new girl in the city'.
Good to know that you had
an interesting day.
Because I just had the
worst day of my life!
Dad's office is a prison!
The people around me come
to work at the same time..
..Ieave at the same time.
I think they even
wear the same clothes!
Don't they get bored?!
You're so lucky you're not stuck with a
thousand pages of tax returns!
Later, Sid.
Dear Sid, I'm sorry that
you're not enjoying work
But I'm sure it'll get better..
Just keep at it.
Take me for instance.
Remember how scared I was
when I first came to Bombay?
I couldn't even take
a walk by myself! And now..
I've been all over the city, Sid!
Everywhere!
I wake up and walk out.
Without thinking about
where I'm going or what I'm doing..
just aimlessly walking.
And the funny thing is
that I don't feel scared anymore.
In fact, these days,
I feel like I'm finally..
Free!
And then.. Iast night..
Papa!
I can't live here anymore!
It's time I found
a place of my own. Till then.
Aisha.
Ma..
Ma.. do you have a good housing
broker's number?
900888000. That's the number
for Prem Dubey
The best broker in Bombay.
Also, it's time you got a phone..
..so I could invite you to
rocking parties! Ok bye!
Wake up.
Sid. It's Tuesday.
I'll see you in my cabin in half an hour.
Get up!
Thank you so much
for Dube-ji's number Sid.
You're a saviour!
I'm going to look atflats today.
Wish me luck..
Make sure everything
is delivered by tomorrow.
Yes, sir.
- You can go.
Let's go, Sid..
He left, Sir..
Mrs. D'Monte..
Yes?
I just wanted to see your flat.
Mr. Dubey told me..
So why the hell are
you bothering me?
Didn't Dubey tell you that they
keys are with Sonia on the fourth floor?!
That idiot.
Take them from Sonia!
Where do these people come from..
Hi!
Hi? Sid? Sid! Oh my god!
What are you doing here?
Me? I'm.. staking you!
Shut up! You're kidding, right?
Yeah man. I called Dubey
and he told me you'd be here.
So I thought I'd come and help you.
Oh how sweet!
So this is where Dubey has sent you,
- Yes. - That idiot!
This building doesn't
even have a watchman, or a lift!
And this gate,
it belongs in a museum!
Aisha? Aisha!
Shit! Mrs. D'Monte never
told me Sonia's flat number.
God, I can't climb four
floors again! You do it..
401. Sonia Gill stays in flat 401.
You've come to see the flat,
haven'tyou?
Just one minute.
Oh Sanju.. it's you..
Hi.. they've come to see the flat..
Aww.. have they now?
Sanju.. Sanju! - Ok, bye. - Get in here!!
Stay away from that tramp!!
That old dried-up prune!!
Oh, so you're interested
in the flat, are you?
Actually, I am. Hi, I'm Aisha.
Sonia.
Anyway, I should warn you.
The flat's really dirty.
No one stayed here since a year.
Mrs. D'Monte can't climb up the stairs..
..so there's been zero maintenance.
But, here, see for yourself.
Thanks.
Aisha.. it's like a haunted house in here.
Let's go. This place is a 'dump'.
Sid.. you're going to
think that I'm crazy..
Why?
Because I actually like this flat..
What?! That's impossible!
I'm taking it, Sid..
But Aisha, it's filthy..
So we'll clean it..
You know, Chhotu's room is
bigger than this.. I swear..
Well, good for Chhotu!
I'm taking this flat.
But this is the first flat we've seen.
We could keep looking!
Of course we could..
but we won't! I've made up my mind!
You know what? You were right..
You really ARE crazy!
Where are you off to now?
To check out my building's terrace!
'MY' building?
Aisha wait..
What?
Are you really sure
you wanna live here?
If it's about money,
maybe I can help you..
I'll ask dad for some.
Sid, that's really sweet.
But no thanks!
Aisha..
You're so stubborn! Listen, I don't
think this area's very safe.
Why don't I do some research
and send you an email?
Look, you're not from here,
you don't..
Whoa..
What a city!
Sid, do you really
want to help me?
Then help me turn
this 'dump' into a home.. Yeah?
Ok.
- Thanks.
"The colors offun belong to me."
"The colors offriendship belong to me."
"The colors offun belong to me. "
"The colors offriendship belong to me. "
"The color of happiness
is hidden in these colors. "
"See to that they don 't fade.
These are the colors of life. "
"Life is crazy.
These colors are beautiful. "
"Life is crazy. There's a new desire. "
"Life is crazy. Sing along with me. "
"Some moments filled with colors. "
"Sometimes there 's silence all around. "
"Sometimes there's intoxication. "
Your credit card statement..
It's been taken care of.
"Painted so many colors day and night. "
"Like somebody tells us something. "
"Everyone belongs to us
and are colors of Iight. "
"Look.. these are the colors of Iife. "
"Life is crazy.
These colors are beautiful. "
"Life is crazy. There's a new desire. "
"Life is crazy. Sing along with me. "
"Life is crazy. "
Happy Happy Anniversary
to you Sarita!
Thank you so m uch!
You look so gorgeous!
This is my wedding saree.
Sorry l' m late.
- Hello Sid.
Look at you! How handsome!
You should become a film star!!
Bye.
You are handsomest my son!
I'm also feeling that
you should become a film star.
You sit around doing nothing anyway..
Ma! Stop it!
Congratulations.. On the anniversary..
Madam Mehra!
Thanks. - This is my Mrs.
and my daughter Tanya.
Ram, Tanya just
got back from the US.
She was getting a design
degree at Parson's University.
She's brilliant!
I told herto join my company,
but she says she is still thinking..
This generation, I tell you..
Wants to be independent..
right, Sidharth?
Sidharth?! Made any plans
for your future yet?
Excuse me.. Hello. Aisha?
What's up? When did you get a phone?!
Busy man! So, Mehra, your son's
all grown up now, huh?
When is he taking
over your business?
Who knows?
He's also still thinking..
Hi. - Hey, thanks Aisha.. you keep
rescuing me from every boring party.
By the way, you were right.
The flat's looking really nice.
So Aisha..
it's the middle of the night..
you and me.. alone in your apartment..
what's going on?
Sid.. I feel silly saying this..
..but I just didn't want
to be alone tonight.
You see, tomorrow,
well in ten minutes actually..
It's my birthday! I've never been
alone on my birthday before..
Your birthday!?
Why didn't you tell me before?
We would have gone out
and really partied!
Well, this is kind of a party, isn't it?
You, me and two cups of tea?
Yeah.. but something's still missing.
What?
We still have ten minutes
though, don't we? - Yes.
Ok then!
Sid, this is so stupid!
What are you doing?
Don't turn around, Aisha.
You better not be
messing up my kitchen!
No no, it's very clean.
Spotless.. just give me ten seconds.
Aisha..
Happy Birthday Aisha!
Thank you Sid.
What for?
You've done so much for me.
If there's ever anything
I can do in return, just ask, ok?
Anything?
Ok, not 'anything'!
You're a good friend, Sid.
Can I ask you something, Aisha?
Ask away..
You and l.. we've become friends now,
which is great.
But if you think about it..
..we could've become more than friends..
So, why do you think
that never happened?
Sid! It just didn't.
We're better off as friends, anyway.
Besides, I didn't really think I could..
fall in love with someone
like you.. That's why..
Why not?
I mean, I'm kinda perfect.
No seriously Aisha..
what's wrong with me?
There's nothing wrong with you..
Sid, I don't want to talk about this.
You'll feel bad..
Why would I feel bad?
It's not as if I'm in love with you!
Come on, we can talk about this..
Ok! I think.. you're still a kid.
A bit immature.. childish.
You're just not what I'm looking for.
Ok, this is going to be fun!
What are you looking for, Aisha?
I guess someone who is..
independent, for starters..
Someone with a career,
a goal in life.
Somebody I can relate to.
In short, a MAN.. not a boy!
Basically, the exact opposite of me!
Basically.. You're the
wrong profile for me, Sid.
Actually, you're right.
I'm too young for you.
You should go out with
someone your own age.
I knew you were going to feel bad!
By the way,
how old do you think I am?
Thirty.
Seriously?!
- Yeah..
I'm 21.
And if you bug me any more,
I'm throwing you off this terrace..
Relax! I was just kidding!
Come now, make a birthday wish.
What birthday wish..
I just hope I get this job..
You're next.
Vidhi Nayak?
Aisha Bannerjee.
Aisha Bannerjee.. Right.
You've already had an interview here?
Then why wait 2 weeks
for the second one?
Uhh, you were busy,
Sir.. That's why..
Oh yes of course..
I was busy.
But, you know.. Well, you should
know that I'm a very busy man.
My last assistant, Edna..
She was brilliant.
Absolutely brilliant.
And then she had to go
and get brilliantly pregnant!
My bad luck, I suppose.
And your good luck!
So, Aisha Bannerjee, your
application letter seems interesting..
But your resume is pretty weak.
Two months at the
Calcutta State Library? That's it?
Yeah but I was also the editor
for my college newspaper for 2 years!
I'm talking about actual experience.
Serious work.. Iike we do here.
I am a workaholic. I'm extremely
hard to work for, Ms. Bannerjee.
Think you could keep up?
Absolutely..
I won't disappoint you, Sir.
I've come here all the way
from Calcutta only to become a writer..
I will learn much from you.
Writer? Why did you apply for this job
if you wanted to become a writer?
An assistant's work is very clerical.
Cleaning up my desk
doesn't require any creativity.
Besides, this is a magazine
about Bombay..
..and you're not even from here..
But, you weren't from Bombay
either when you joined this magazine.
And now you're
the Chief Editor here.
I know everything about you.
I applied for this job
after a lot of deliberation.
In fact, I've pictured myself giving you..
.. this interview
a thousand times already.
I just didn't imagine
that I'd be this nervous..
..and you'd be this good looking..
Believe me.. I'll clean your
desk very creatively.
God knows, it needs
a good cleaning. So.
Sid! I've got it..
The new editor's assistant
at Mumbai Beat is Aisha Bannerjee!
I finally have a job!
Aisha.. that's great.. Super!
Can I call you in a bit?
I'm a little busy right now..
Okay. Bye.
What?! Stressed spelled
backwards is desserts.
I'm stressed!
And where were you guys?!
Never on time..
Baby, I passed I passed!
I got more than 40 in every subject!!
I thought I'd get like 35!
I'm so happy I passed!
Neha, that's like.. third class..
Whatever, at least I passed.
Come on hurry up you guys..
Excuse me..
Guys, excuse me.
- Let me see if I've passed or failed.
As per plan.. one by one.. OK?
You go first.
Sure? Ok..
Here.. here.
You're a genius Laxmi!
You're probably one of the toppers.
I don't know, man.
I could've done better in Economics..
Where's mine.
Please God, let me pass
this one last time.
I'll walk barefoot to the temple
every week if you do. Please..
Hey Rishi.. you did it!
You passed!
I passed Sid! I passed!
Sid, let's check yours now..
Sid..
Maybe we're looking at the
wrong number, lets check again..
Show me your exam card..
Sid.. Sid.
Where have you been?
Baby you passed!
Aren't you proud of yourself?
I know baby.. But..
Sid!
Sid! Don't worry dude.
It's going to be alright.
Sid, listen.
These things happen, Sid..
It's just one year, Sid.
You'll pass next year..
It's not that big a deal!
Damn you, Rishi!
Don't tell me that its not a
big deal just because you passed!
I don't need a lecture from you.
Okay Sid, but relax Sid..
How can you tell me to relax?
I thought we were in this together.
Now you've gone and passed
and I've.. I'm alone here.
Yeah but.. why are you
taking this out on me?
Because it's all your fault!
You didn't deserve to pass either,
and you know it!
Maybe if I hadn't wasted my time with you,
I would have passed too.
Screw you Sid..
Yeah right, screw you too Rishi!
Stop fighting guys..
Sid we could reevaluate the papers..
Laxmi please leave me alone.
Siddy.. me cooking tonight.
Are you eating at home?
What happen, Siddy?
Are you in a bad mood?
Do you need money?
What happened?
Maa.. My results are out.
Sid? You didn't passed?
How could you let this happen,
Sidharth?!
This is because you
waste all your time roaming around..
..with your friends!
You were such
a good student in school..
What happened in college?
We give you everything
you want, don't we?
Then why?
Say something Sidharth..
Did I do something wrong..
you failed.
Shut up Ma! Stop this
stupid melodramatic lecture!
I know exactly what happened.
There's no need to keep reminding me.
I'll pass next year.
Why are you panicking?
Why do you care so much anyway?
You didn't even go to school..
Say you're sorry, Sid..
I said apologize, Sidharth.
Please don't interfere in this, Dad.
Don't interfere?
And continue to ignore what an ungrateful..
..spoilt brat you've become!
How dare you speak
to your mother like that!
Her life has revolved
around you every single day of..
..the last twenty years.
She couldn't go to school,
so she wanted you to do well.
So you could get everything
she couldn't have..
Wow! Another lecture..
Sid! Don't you dare walk out!
You are going to stand there
and listen to me tonight.
When I was your age
my father had died,
I was married, and working day and night,
trying to make enough money
so that you can have
everything you have today.
This lifestyle.. this arrogance..
So what do you want from me?
Do you want me to be grateful?
You're damn right.
The least you can do is be grateful!
Thank you so much, Pa.
There, I said it.
Now can I go?
I am not done yet!
You can't just walk away from everything!
This is exactly why you failed.
Why you didn't last at the office
for more than a week!
You ran away without
informing anyone.
Oh God.. Not again..
your office.. your company..
Can't you see? I don't care
about your stupid office!
Then what do you care about Sidharth?
What? You don't care about yourself..
..about your family, about your future..
You're wasting your life Sidharth.
Can't you see that today
you've failed your exams..
Tomorrow you're going to fail at life?
No I can't see that!
And I don't want to see that!
I don't give a damn
about what you think!
You'll start caring
when I stop giving you money.
Do it then! I don't want
your bloody money anyway!
Ok, Sidharth.
Let me clarify one thing.
This is MY house,
and if you want to live in it..
..you'll have to live by my rules. Ok?
I don't want to live in your
damn house then! I'm leaving.
"No one is with me today. "
"I have to Iive up to my Iittle dream. "
"This day has passed by. "
"There's solitude around me again. "
"Let's go from here. "
Sid? What are you doing here?
Can I stay with you?
What? Sid?
Ok, why don't come i n first..
What's wrong, Sid?
Thank you Aisha..
Good night Sid..
Chhotu! Chhotu!
Shut these bloody curtains, Chhotu!!
Chhotu!!
Kabir overlooks all the writing..
I'm so sorry..
So whenever the articles come in..
Aisha! Where were you?
Why didn't you pick up your phone?
Were you so busy?
I tried and tried and tried..
I got so bored today.
And you should really get an AC..
it's so hot in here!
Aisha, you're not even listening to me!
Sid, I was working all day.
I'm really tired, ok?
Ok.. Iet's go out for dinner then.
I don't want to go, Sid.
I ate at the office.
I just need to clean this up, and..
You ate already? Without me?
Yeah! You're not my husband!
Just cook something for yourself,
I'm going to bed.
You don't know how to cook, do you?
You can't cook anything?
Then what did you eat today?
Shit, Sid, you haven't anything all day?!
Why didn't you just order something?
I didn't feel like it..
Hungry?
Yeah..
You're so silly, Sid!
Why didn't you tell me!
I'll make you something.
"This is strange story. "
"Where it starts and where it ends. "
"Which destination is this?"
Aisha, my coffee..
Yes, just a second.
Kabir.. I wrote this
and wanted your feedback..
If you get a moment..
Aisha, can I please get my coffee?
Pizza.
Don't worry.
This treat, I'll pay.
Sir, your card has been declined..
Are you sure?
Yes sir.
Would you like to pay cash?
Yes.
Actually..
That's ok.. I'll get it..
Debbie, that's really sweet ofyou..
Thank you so much.
I'll pay you back..
Sidharth it's Ok.
Save the grateful speech for another time.
It doesn't suit you.
Anyway, I just got a job
so I'm treating all my friends to lunch.
Not exactly friends, are we?
No.. Not exactly..
I'm sorry that you failed, Sidharth.
Just wanted to say that.
Hey Debbie,
why do you hate me so much?
Three years ago,
I came to Bombay to join our college.
I had the right grades,
but I was late with my application.
I didn't get in that year. You know why?
Because you took my seat, Sidharth.
Your father called a few people,
and you got the last seat in the batch.
I am smarter, I work harder,
and I'm more deserving than you.
But life has always been easier for you,
hasn't it?
Bye, Sid.
But Sid,
you have to go home some time!
He cancelled my credit card, Laxmi.
There's no way l' m going back now.
But he's just angry, Sid.
You need to understand..
You're the one
who doesn't understand, Laxmi!
You topped the whole damn college.
How can you know
what it feels like to have failed?
Just leave me alone!
Oh Shut up, Sid!
I don't know what it feels like to fail?!
Look at me.. I'm fat as a whale!
I keep trying to lose weight
but I fail every single day!
You're not the only one with problems,
so stop being a jerk!
Wipe that silly look off your face!
Ok, fine.. I know I'm being a jerk!
It's just been tough, you know..
I know. That's why I got this for you.
College application form.
And..
Some of your things.
I knew you wouldn't go back home.
Just thought I'd try..
Hey Laxmi.. I never knew, you know..
That your weight was such an issue
for you..
It's ok, Sid.
You know
I don't think you're a whale, right?
Maybe a shark!
Ma, no!
"You are angry,
but I know, you'II be okay. "
"You are very good from heart. "
Right there! Yeah hold it!
"Life, you are just Iike me. "
"You Iook smart, but naive. "
"Why are you sitting far..
.. forgetting everything? "
"Hold my finger. "
"Walk with me..
..wherever I go. "
"Walk with you..
Sonia?
Yes Sid?
Do you know how to make eggs?
And call Karan and follow up with Amit.
Is that all?
Yeah, just get rid of all this stuff.
Aisha, leave.
"Walk with me..
..wherever I go. "
"Walk with you..
Hi.
- Hi.
You'll never believe this..
Why are so late today? I was waiting!
I made an egg for you!
Sonia taught me.
You were right, she's so cool..
Shut up Sid! Look at this mess..
You made an egg.
Wow! Congratulations!
And who is going to do those dishes?!
Your servant?
Or did you forget,
you don't have a servant anymore?!
This is my home Sid,
and you have turned it into a garbage dump!
But Aisha.. I made you an egg..
"Wake up!"
Sid.. I think you should go back home.
Your dad has such a successful company..
And you are sitting in my house
making eggs!
What are you doing Sid?
You know.. You look at me
and you see my father's success..
But I'm not like him, Aisha..
I went to his office for a week..
But that place.. it just wasn't ME!
But I'm beginning to realize
I'm nobody without him.
I don't have an identity!
Which is why I decided last night
that I want to work.
I know that I can't do anything.
I don't know who would hire me.
All I know is that I want to work.
Please don't kick me out right now.
Just give me one more chance. Please.
Ok, Sid.
Aisha, where were you last night?
At Sonia's.
You mean.. across the hall? Damn!
Sid, about that job.. I've got an idea.
Have you done any kind
of photography course?
No..
Any kind of work experience
with photography?
No..
Any kind of work experience at all?
Amit, Sid's been taking photographs
for many years now.
Even as an intern,
he could learn a lot from you.
I truly think this is something
he'll be good at.
Ok Sidharth.. Let's try you out
as an intern for a few days..
Thanks Amit.
See you at 1 0 tomorrow.
But tomorrow is Sunday!
I mean, yeah..
Cool.
I am going to be working
at Mumbai Beat.
How totally neat! Hey, that rhymed.
Oh what heat!
We live together,
now we're going to work together.
Should we just get married?!
Yeah, let's go! Come on!
Go home, you idiot!
4th Road Juhu Scheme please.
- Bye.
Sid!
See you at home honey!
Stop here.
Why did you bring me here? I said..
Sorry..
Turn around. We'll go to Chapel road.
One second.
Wait here, I'll be right back.
Really..
He listened to the conversation between..
The Chief of guard
and the king with great attention.
Why? What did the poor fellow do?
The King inquired.
Hello everybody, welcome to Mumbai Beat!
- Thank you.
The theme of our next issue is
Bazaars of Mumbai.
I'm sure you guys know all about them..
Sir..
- And..
The idea is that there will be two interns
for every three articles,
except for the cover story.
So let's get down to work..
You're Ram Mehra's son, right?
We met at your parents' anniversary party,
remember?
Oh yeah.. Hi.
So, I'm guessing you didn't join
your dad's company then..
Tanya Lathia? Design in turn.
That's me.
Sid Mehra?
You two are going to assist me
on the cover story photo spread.
And you are?
- Rasha.
Rasha.. you are also design in turn.
What do you want to do?
What you want to design?
Sid?! Hold on, l' m coming..
Yes?
Aisha?
Yes.
I'm Sidharth's mother.
Oh.. Hello auntie..
Can I come in?
Of course, please come in.
Actually.. Sid isn't here..
I know. I had asked Chhotu
to call me once he left.
I just wanted to see
where Sid was living these days.
Now that he's staying with you..
I thought you might need some money..
No auntie, please..
I can't take money from you..
Thank you.
I brought some mangoes too..
they're Sidharth's favourite..
At least keep those.
Ok.
Chhotu!
Yes, put it here.
Just don't tell him I got them.
He won't like it.
Ok Aisha, I will take your leave.
Ok aunty.
Auntie..
I just wanted to say..
I mean,
I hope you don't get the wrong idea..
Actually, Sid and l,
there's nothing going on between us..
We're.. we're just friends, you know..
"Life, these days.. "
"..is telling me. "
"lfyou listen to me,
come with me to the lane of dreams. "
"Take all the fragrances
and brightness in your arms. "
"Wherever you are..
.. the days and nights are new. "
"New desires..
..and new emotions. "
"There are new ways for you,
why don't you go and explore?"
"There's new earth and new sky for you. "
"Write a new story on the winds. "
"When Iife knocked;
heart opened all the windows. "
"Heart opened all the windows. "
"The solitude on the Iips has melted. "
"Has melted. "
"These moments have surprised me. "
"So many talks have touched my heart.. "
"Many desires have awakened in my heart. "
"Many desires have come to tell me. "
"Recognize the smile
and fill your heart with happiness. "
"There's new earth and new sky for you. "
"Write a new story on the winds. "
Thank God we have tomorrow off.
I really need a break.
Let's go out to dinner tonight.
I can't tonight.. I already made plans.
Really? What plans?
You know Tanya?
I'm going out with her.
Tanya? That design intern?
She's pretty, haan?
Yeah she's pretty.. and fun too.
We're going clubbing..
Why don't you join us?
It'll be fun!
No, you go.
I don't want to go clubbing.
But you'll get bored, all alone at home..
I'll just cancel the whole thing.
Don't be silly! You should go.
Don't worry about me.
I've got a lot going on.
Really!
Up for a drink?
I didn't have anything going on, so..
I'm always up for a drink darling!
Come.
Hi.
Hey, what's up?
Sid, this is my best friend, Saira..
Hello! I've heard a lot about you!
- Oh, you have?
Tanya.. Vikram. Come here.
Sid man! - Bro.
- Where have you been?
Back in action now brother..
You totally disappeared..
- Actually..
Sid!! What are you doing here?
Wow, he knows everyone here..
Anyway, have you met Rishi?
Tanya! - Hey..
- Hi.
Yes.
Hi.
Hey Rish..
Hi Sid. Do you want another drink?
Yes please.
I hated when l..
What the hell are you watching?!
Hey..
Come, let's gossip..
How's your sex life?!
What?!
Oh don't be such a prude!
What about your boss?
How's that going?
Do you still think he's sexy?
Tell me.
Yep, still sexy..
and he's my type too..
Just jump him then!
Sonia! He's my boss!
And I don't even know him..
And Sid?
What about him?
You know him, don't you?
At least hook up with him!
Please Sonia! We're just friends.
Plus, he's a kid!
Oh what a cute kid!
I think he's quite sexy..
You know, like those boy band singers..
Sid? And sexy?
Yes.
Of course!
Please.. not Sid!
Yeah!
Oh God!
Guys! Drinks?
Vodka Red Bull!
Oooooh!
Weird! I'll get them!
Sid!!!
Two Vodka Red Bulls please.
Laxmi?
Sid?
Where did Rishi go?
Why do you wanna know?
As if you care..
He left.
Of course. For Neha's.
No Sid! Why would he go there?
Let it be.
What?
- Nothing..
Tell me.
Neha and Rishi broke up.
Nobody knows why or when..
And that stupid Rishi won't talk about it..
Poor thing. He's really upset.
You know how he is..
Hey Rish..
Why didn't you call me?
Rishi! What happened with Neha?
What happened man?!
You gotta be kidding me..
And she said no?
Not only that.. She dumped me, man..
I'm a bloody idiot!
You're a bloody idiot!
You told me this would happen!
I told you this would happen!
Then you should've been there
to remind me!
Yeah man. I should've been there.
Sorry.
Sanju, have breakfast.
Come on.
Aisha! Good morning.
Morning Sid.
Aisha? Why are we sitting
with the door open?
Cross ventilation, Sid.
There's no electricity in the flat.
It's really hot.
Just a few more days..
and the rain will be here.
You don't know
how much you're going to love it.
Aisha?
What Sid?!
This dress really suits you.
You're looking nice today.
Don't I look nice everyday?
Nope.
No seriously..
you look a little extra nice today.
Thanks Sid.
Aisha.. Sidharth..
I made my special Sunday breakfast today.
Do you want some?
Yes, Mrs. Bapat. I'm always starving!
Umm Sidharth.. will you take
Sanju's photographs today? Please?
Of course, Mrs. Bapat.
Right after I polish off this food!
Tell me if you want more.
Sure.
Here.
Smile.
Smile for me, Sanju!
Can I go play now?
Come, we'll play together.
Do you like cricket?
Show me how you hit the ball!
Yeah! Once again. 1.. 2.. 3! Superb.
Thank you.
You're welcome, sir.
Sanju! Take one with just me and him,
Sidharth.
Sure.
- Come.
Sit here.
Smile Sanju!
What happened?
Why do you have to be so naughty, huh?
He's taking such nice pictures.
Always up to mischief, my little brat.
Hi ma.
Thought dad would be
on his evening walk now..
I'm going to leave before he gets back.
And I haven't come back to stay,
so we're not going to talk about that.
Ok?
I just.. wanted to see you.
I miss you ma..
Sid.. in shirt you looking so handsome..
Ma, I always look handsome.
That's true.
Siddy, you're 4 years old here..
It was your first day of iscool.
School Ma, not 'iscool', school.
That's what I said.. Iscool.
I have no idea
when you'll stop trying to speak English.
Why should l?
Maybe if I know English like your friends,
then we can become friends too.
Look at this one. You were so fat then!
Ma, you look stunning here!
These photographs are lovely..
who took them?
Your Dad did, who else?
Really? I'm surprised he found the time.
He always had time to take your pictures.
As soon as he got back from work,
you two would start.
He'd take pictures, and you would pose.
I thought you'd become an actor!
Really Sid, your father has really captured..
..your childhood in these albums.
Ma.. I should go..
Siddy, I hope you're eating properly..
Yes Ma. We're fine, managing.
And there's always the mangoes
that you send.
It was kinda obvious..
Bye..
I really want take a photograph
for the next issue.
I know I'm just an intern,
but I want to prove that I can do better.
'New Girl in the City'. Nice title.
You read my articles?! All of them?
I've decided that you're going to write
an article for the next issue.
If I like it, we'll make it a regular thing.
Thank you!
Your writing is fresh.
Really.
Thanks! Thank you!
Aisha..
- Yes.
I'm going to a jazz bar
with a couple of my friends tonight.
There's going to be a live performance.
It's going to be a nice evening.
Would to like to join me?
Yeah sure.
Unbelievable! Superb!
Wonderful.
What could be better than this, Aisha?
You haven't heard much jazz, have you?
No.. not really..
What kind of music do you like?
Umm, I don't know.. Old Hindi Film songs.
At least they're easy to sing along to.
You like Film music because it's easy?
Yeah..
Interesting.
What?
You know, there's maturity in your writing..
But you're still a little childish.
Anyway, stick around with me
and you'll learn what real music is.
Aisha! Hi!
Tanya? Hi. What are you doing here?
I came to drop off some books.
Thought Sid might need them
for his new assignment.
He's so excited!
What new assignment?
You don't know?
Amit asked him to take a few photographs
for the next issue.
Isn't that cool?
Yeah, it's cool.
Anyhow, gotta run now. Bye!
Bye.
By the way Aisha,
your place is so cute!
Thanks.
Hey.
Hi.
I'm starving. I think I'll cook something..
want some?
I ate already. I made some pasta.
There's some in the fridge for you.
Oh God
I hope you cleaned up the kitchen!
You always make such a mess
when you cook..
You know,
I'm actually not that hungry.
I should change though.. it's so hot.
I haven't done laundry in days..
I don't know what I'm going to wear.
I washed your clothes along with mine.
They're in your cupboard.
Sid! You should have asked me
before washing my clothes!
I sleep in this white kurta
and I never wash it!
Washing ruins it and besides..
I like it being dirty!
Aisha what's wrong with you?
Instead of thanking me for washing
your clothes, you're yelling at me?!
Because I want to wash my own damn clothes
and cook my own damn food!
This doesn't even feel like
my house anymore!
I don't like it when you do my work or..
..when you call strange girls into my house!
You have lost your mind!
I think the heat has gotten to your head!
Of course it has!
So what can I do?
Make the heavens rain for you?
Why not?-Now that you're so efficient
at everything..
Iets see you do this too!
Here's your rain!
I can't believe you just did that!
Aisha you'll ruin my iPod!!
Shit sorry sorry.. Sid!!
Stop it, you idiot!
Okay. Okay.
Aisha.. are you Ok?
I'm sorry, I was just kidding..
It's Ok.
I am sorry, Aisha.
You sure you're Ok?
Yeah.
Ok then!
Enough Sid! Don't behave like a kid.
Sid.. if you keep helping me like this,
I'll get used to it.
So?
So it's not right.
What will I do when you're gone?
I'm not going anywhere.
Come now. The food's getting cold..
"O heart, you are crazy. "
"Only you know what you think?"
"Why do you show me dreams all the time?"
"When dreams shower drop by drop. "
"Close your eyes. "
-"Close your eyes. "
"When dreams shower drop by drop. "
"Close your eyes. "
"How can I walk?
I can't see unknown ways. "
"Like the string instrument plays. "
"I am Iistening to a story completely Iost. "
"Who knows it is full story or not. "
"I didn't even realize
even after becoming someone's..
.. that it is for some moments or life time. "
"Who knows. "
"When dreams shower drop by drop. "
"Close your eyes. "
- "Close your eyes. "
"When dreams shower drop by drop. "
"How can I walk?
I can't see unknown ways. "
What's up?
Sid.. I' m really worried about my article..
Why? I'm sure it'll be great.
How do you know?
I just know.
"Like the string instrument plays. "
Nice. Just proofread it once
before you submit it.
Thanks. Can I take off now?
One second, Aisha.
I have two tickets for a jazz concert tonight.
And you're coming with me.
No Kabir. I can't come.
You know, I thought if I spent time with you,
I'd start enjoying jazz..
But, the truth is, I just don't like jazz.
I'm sorry but it's just not me.
So.. I'll see you at work tomorrow?
"This evening Iooks empty. "
Sid! I've selected one of your photographs
for the next issue.
Thanks..
- Thank me later.
Just get drunk for now.
Have fun! You're doing well.
"I find everyone.."
Hey!
"The silence is around.
The ambience is glittering. "
"These moments are here today. "
Ladies and gentlemen!
I'm Sidharth Mehra from Mumbai Beat.
On the dru ms we have Laxmi..
and this is my friend Rishi.
Thank you, thank you.
And this is our favorite song. Hit it!
Dude, not me not me!
Go Sid!
"First Iove and first.."
Sid's crazy, isn't he?
Oh he was much crazier before!
You can't even imagine the things
we've done!
"What state I've come to. "
"Restless heart.. " - Go Sid!
- "Restless heart.. "
And now?
- Now?
Now he doesn't have time for us!
New job.. new friends.. you know?
"You tell me. "
"First Iove and first.. "
Doesn't that make you feel bad?
Are you kidding? Of course it does.
But it's Ok.
Sid mig ht have changed a lot..
but it's all for the better.
"Restless heart.
- You tell me. "
"You tell me. "
You're really drunk Sid.
You should go to bed.
Sid?
Are you Ok?
I know we're not talking to each other..
And that you're still angry.
But I thought that you would call one day
and ask me to come back home.
But.. you never did.
So I decided that I wouldn't come see you
until you called first.
But today..
I got a job, Pa..
As an assistant photographer for a magazine.
And I want to do this job!
I've been working really hard this past month
and I'm actually happy!
I know I never mentioned photography
as a career..
And that we have a family business
to take care of..
but I feel like you'll understand.
Because photography is something
I got from you.
I'd forgotten that photography
was your passion too.
You used to take so many pictures..
why did you stop?
You grew up, son.
You didn't have time
for my photographs anymore.
And photography had meant
nothing more to me..
..than taking pictures of you.
My first paycheque, Pa. For you.
Promise me.. that from now on you..
..will put your heart into everything you do.
I'm sorry, Pa.
I love you.
What's going on, Sid?
Why did you ask me to rush home?
Thank God you're home!
You won't believe what happened today.
What?
I went to see Dad today.
Everything is fine now.
He asked me to come back home.
I'm going home, Aisha!
Finally back to my own house
Aish.. say something.
That's great, Sid.. that's really great..
When are you leaving?
Now. Dad's on his way to pick me up.
You're leaving so soon..?
Yep. Now this garbage dump
will look like a house again.
Aisha.. you let me stay here for so long..
Thank you so much for everything.
This is for you.
I don't want it.
Aisha, I know it's not much,
but I made it especially for you.
I don't want your stupid gift, Ok?
What are you getting so upset for?
You're so right.
Why am I getting upset?
After all, I knew this would happen.
You fought with your parents,
so you moved in.
Now that you've made up with them,
you're moving out!
So? I'm moving back to my house.
I can't stay here forever, can l?
Why can't you?
Aisha.. I don't understand..
Of course you don't!
You never understand anything!
You didn't even talk to me before taking
such a big decision!
Didn't even stop to think about
how I might feel!
How can you be
so thoughtless and immature?!
I should've known.
You're a kid and always will be a kid!
Damn you Aisha!
Why do you always do this?
Nothing I do is ever good enough for you!
Yes, I'm a kid and always will be a kid!
God, l' m tired of this..
tired of you calling me immature..
Tired of proving myself to you!
All these days, I've been trying
to change your opinion of me..
..hoping that you'll see that
I'm not a kid anymore, but it's useless!
You just don't see it!
I'm sick ofyou Aisha!
I'm just so sick of you!
Aish..
You're right Sid.
I'm the one who doesn't see it.
Go home. All the best.
"Like the string instrument plays. "
"Your string instrument is of no use. "
"The bird is angry..
..it has Ieft its nest. "
"When I close my eyes,
tears roll down my cheek. "
"Tears roll down my cheek. "
"When I close my eyes,
tears roll down my cheek. "
"It makes me restless.
Why does it sing sad song?"
Hello Ma.. It's me, Aisha.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
I was just missing you guys..
Where's Dad?
"A stale night..
..is close to my pillow. "
"The morning returned
seeing the close doors. "
"The fire has extinguished
and the walls are cold. "
"Voice of the heart is echoing. "
"Voice of the.. "
"..heart is echoing. "
"When I close my eyes,
tears roll down my cheek. "
"Tears roll down my cheek. "
"When I close my eyes,
tears roll down my cheek. "
"It makes me restless.
Why does it sing sad song?"
"Your string instrument is of no use. "
Bhaiyya! Wake up Bhaiyya!
Bhaiyya? Are you Ok?
Aren't you happy to be back home?
I'm fine, Chhotu. Now go, don't bug me.
Make sure you eat your breakfast
before it gets cold.
And your magazine came this morning..
"The feeling came from the melting drops.. "
"The moment has come close to my heart. "
"It touched the heart, but I couldn't know. "
"Now when I Iooked; I Iiked the moment. "
"I can't do this. "
"I'II send the message through the wind. "
"Or should I come to you on the wind? "
"I Iove you. "
"Where do I get the words from?"
"Life is coming. "
"Life is coming your way. "
'New Girl in the City' - by Aisha Bannerjee.
Like many others before me,
I came to Mumbai with many dreams.
The biggest one was to become a writer.
With this column, Mumbai has made
that one dream come true.
But, even after a lot of struggle,
I couldn't do it justice.
Everything I wrote seemed lacking.
What could I say about this city
that hadn't been said before?
So I tore up my approved article
and began writing again.
In just two months..
I've begun to feel a strange love for Mumbai,
as if its my own..
What lay at the core of this love?
My exciting new job?
My little flat? Or my independence?
What has this city given me
that makes me love her so?
Actually the answer had been
in front of me all along..
I just didn't see it.
I met someone the first night
that I was in Bombay.
A boy, a friend, a room mate,
a companion - just someone.
He didn't really have
any ambitions or goals..
.. but he sure knew how to enjoy his life.
When I look back..
I wonder if the joy
of making a new home..
.. would have been the same
without his help..
I look back upon a lonely night made
less lonely by a shared cup of tea.
When I had first come here,
I had my goals straight.
But now I know, that the joy of achieving
these goals is meaningful
only when shared with someone else.
Only now do I see that my strange love.
for this city is actually one with my love
for this person!
He's the one who taught me
the essence of love.
Mumbai is as tough as it is beautiful.
Sometimes, while running after our goals
we lose sight of the things
that really matter.
So close your eyes for a second,
Look for your special someone,
and see the city through their eyes.
You'll see that Mumbai is even more beautiful
than you ever imagined.
Who knows, even you might get
a companion like me.
"Life is coming your way."
"Like the string instrument plays. "
Why did you write such a long article?!
Couldn't you have told me
all of this at home?
You know that I'm an idiot!
Aish.. I love you too! I love you!
I love you, Sid!
"Like the string instrument plays. "
"Listen to what I have to say.. "
"You know what time is. "
"The night is sleeping
and a new day has awakened. "
"This ambience is still in slumber. "
"Wishes are Ieading my way. "
"Wake up, Sid! The time says!"
"Wake up, Sid! Let's go somewhere!"
"Wake up, Sid! Listen if you can.. "
"..the voice from all the directions. "
"Wake up!"
"Listen to what all say. "
"Choose the one which you feel is right. "
"You decide what you have to do. "
"Think where you have to go. "
"You are the traveler
and you are the caravan. "
"Wake up, Sid! The time says!"
"Wake up, Sid! Let's go somewhere!"
"Wake up, Sid! Listen if you can.. "
"..the voice from all the directions. "
"Wake up!"
"See to that today's day
shouldn 't be like yesterday's. "
"Don't sleep today Iike yesterday. "
"Why are you so Iazy? Say something. "
"Listen to something and do something. "
"Cry or laugh.
Fill some or other color in your life. "
"Wake up, Sid! The time says!"
"Wake up, Sid! Let's go somewhere!"
"Wake up, Sid! Listen if you can.. "
"..the voice from all the directions. "
"Wake up, Sid! The time says!"
"Wake up, Sid! Let's go somewhere!"
"Wake up, Sid! Listen if you can.. "
"..the voice from all the directions. "
"Wake up, Sid! The time says!"
"Wake up, Sid! Let's go somewhere!"
"Wake up, Sid! Listen if you can.. "
"..the voice from all the directions. "
"Wake up!"