¶¶ We'll meet again
¶¶ Don't know where
¶¶ Don't know when
¶¶ But I know
we'll meet again
¶¶ Some sunny day
¶¶ Keep smiling' thru
¶¶ Just like you always do
¶¶ Till the blue skies drive
the dark clouds, far away
¶¶ And will you please say hello
Dr. Dutton... My aunt is in town.
- And she's sick too.
- I'm goanna need you to stay late, tonight.
- You know... You should probably
- Oh, you are?
text your "aunt" Scotty and tell him
you can't make it to the baseball game today.
Oh, wait a second...How...
Okay look, Scotty and I were...
Oh, c'mon Becky.
- I mean...
- It's the worst kept secret in town.
Now, that's saying a lot! Go on,
get out of here. Go and have some fun.
Thanks, Dr. Dutton.
Well, I don't care what the calendar says.
Opening day, that's first day of spring.
- No, no, no, Sheriff never pays for coffee.
- Well, that's kind of you Ben...
But the Principal's star
has to pay his parking tickets.
- Start him a tab.
- Yes, sir.
- That kid throws fast.
- Just like he drives. Nice pitch, Scotty!
See middle-field.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Tommy!
- Stay there.
- Boys, get in the dugout.
- Get them off the field!
- Get them in the dugout, Principal.
Hey Rory,
we got a ball game going on here.
We are playing ball and you come out with a gun?!
What the hell are you doing?!
Oh Rory... You are drunk. That's all.
Now, let's just...lay the gun down.
Rory... Lay the gun down...
Lay it down.
Rory.
Rory?
Now, you lay the gun down.
Oh, my God!
I'll have the blood alcohol report in the morning.
Full tux screen take about a week.
How are you holding up, David?
- Is Peggy here yet?
- She just walked in with the boy.
David, perhaps now is not the best time.
Son... Settle down.
Hey Curt...I'm so sorry.
I liked Rory...
I liked him a lot.
- What he was doing out there?
- He's been drinking.
- That's all.
- Rory quit two years ago...
You know how proud he was of that.
Is that what you are saying?
That he was drunk?
- Is that what you are telling people?
- No...
You had to do it?
Had to shoot the damn drunk?
You did the right thing.
- I need to blame for this.
- Hey, David..
You did the right thing.
She's been sleeping?
Sheriff's department.
No Ma'am, we can't comment on that.
That's an ongoing investigation.
No Ma'am... the Sheriff is not here right now,
but I can see if the Deputy will...
Amateurs.
Sheriff's department.
That's the medical examiner on line two.
Good morning Jim.
What've we got?
- The results were negative.
- Tell me again?
There was no alcohol...
No, I heard what you said Jim,
but that's not right.
- Rory was...
-David, I did the test twice.
Rory wasn't drunk,
there's no use of alcohol in his bloodstream.
It takes sometimes a couple days,
a week or so. I don't know what's going' on.
Yeah okay. Thank you.
Ben!
Hey Ben. Ben!
Ben! Hey, you alright?
Don't worry... The kids are resiled.
They'll be alright.
I'm late... I got to go.
- Deidra, Bill.
- Hey Judy.
Little man. How are you all doing??
- Would you mind take a look at Bill?
- Sure, what's wrong?
I don't know.
He's just... not alright.
How are you feeling, Bill?
Any pain or discomfort?
- Bill?
- She worries too much. I'm fine.
- Just a little tired.
- You got any plans this weekend?
She worries too much. I'm fine.
Just a little tired.
His vitals are fine.
You know, I got to see a patient
in Cedar Rapids on Monday..
I want to take Bill and to get a CT scan...
- Monday?
- Yeah. Let's just make sure it's nothing serious.
- If you need me, you call me. Day or night. Okay?
- Thanks Judy.
- See you Nicholas.
- Bye Judy. - Bye Bill.
What's Dad doing?
Wait here, Nicholas.
William!
- Mom!
- Oh God! Nicholas!!!
Nicholas!
Nicholas, are you okay?!
Nicholas, what happened?
- It's Dad.
- Where is Dad? What happened?
Honey, please talk to me. Please.
He has a knife.
Oh my God.
Stay back. Stay right there.
William!
William, please, let us out of here!
Hello?
I'm coming'.
What is it?
- Deidra! - Tom, did they get out?
- Not Deidra and Nicholas. Just Bill.
I need two men on that edge-cliff border,
how's that.
When we got here,
there was an empty gas can
just sitting' in front, and Bill..
he was pulling' a goddamn mower.
Bill?!
What the hell happened here?
- God! Oh God!
- Judy c'mon.
What the fuck have you done?!
What the hell?!
What you've got?
Russ, did you get in touch with
Sheriff Burns in Cedar Rapids?
Russ?
Yeah, State Trooper is coming
this afternoon to pick him up for transfer.
- How long he's been playing a statue?
- A couple of hours now.
Same look Rory gave me.
The same goddamn look.
Sheriff's department.
It's been there at least
a week by the looks of things.
- I'll check to see if there is any identifications.
- Yeah. Do that.
Lewis, last I checked
the hunting season ended three months ago.
We were just out taking in a little nature.
Fresh air is all.
- Guns away 'till fall.
- Oh c'mon, Sheriff. - Are you kidding me?
Well, the guy is a pilot.
Where is the plane?
Well, last week Travis Quinn
was going around saying he heard
something crashed out by the Hop man bar.
- I didn't think nothing of it.
- On account of him being full of shit?
That's the general rule.
- Well, maybe this is the exception.
- Maybe.
- Shit sounded like a plane truck.
- Sheriff, about the reward?
- Shit. Big plane? Little plane? What? C'mon now...
- Well, if he can explain
the difference how those two sound,
I might be able to figure it out.
You are full of shit.
He's full of shit.
People only ask for reward,
when there's something to be find.
- Is there goanna be a big reward, Sheriff?
- Travis, if you ask about that again,
- I'm goanna throw you out of the fucking boat.
- You're not goanna shoot me?
- Travis?
- Yeah?
Kill the engine.
- It's a big plane, Russ.
- Why is that?
'Cause we are right on top of it.
- Kevin, which way is water flowing through the town?
- Nice to see you too, Dave.
- Waste water or drinking?
- Drinking.
Give me a sec.
Plane that size goes down, and nothing
in the paper, nothing in the news.
- Make any sense to you?
- It depends on what the payload is.
- Exactly what I'm thinking.
- Which is what?
- Hop man bar, where it's draining to?
- Dwight Creek.
- Where it's raising to?
- Black pawn.
- Oh, you remember that monster catfish?
- What do you think we are getting' our drinking water from?
Treated water comes in from the north.
- Breaks east- west.
- What house is to get it first?
Let's see. Rory Hamill.
You want to shut out the entire town's
water supply on a hunch?
Mayor, I've got three dead bodies
in the morgue in the last 48 hours.
David, take a look around you.
This is a farming community.
It is spring time, it's planting season.
You turn off the water, you're goanna kill the crops.
You kill the crops and you bankrupt
every family in Pierce County.
And that is not based on some..hunch.
That's a fact.
Water...Stays on.
Sheriff, I'm on for a little
civil disobedience...
but I think this whole thing
might cost you your job.
You know what, Russ?
That wouldn't be such a bad thing.
What the fuck?
Stay on a second.
Is he dead?
Well, if he is he won't mind waiting'.
Jesus Christ!
Did we or did we not,
request a transfer for him this morning?
Even better.
- You know what?
- What?
We are in trouble.
Hello?
All things wise and wonderful,
and our Lord loves them all.
Jim?
Jesus Christ!
Behind you.
Christ Almighty!
David, I'm not goanna do this.
I can't go to my parents.
- You have no idea what...
- And neither do you?!
Look whatever it is, I can't just leave.
Are you goanna leave?
- I am the Sheriff.
- I am their doctor.
Yeah...Well, if it turns out what
they need is penicillin, I'll call you.
- David.
- What?!
What?
There's somebody outside.
David!
- David, what's going on?? -I don't know...
Right now I don't know any more than you do.
Funny thing happened
on the road to Cedar Rapids.
The bastards fired my tires.
Who are these fuckers man?
Keep moving.
Keep moving, please.
Let's go! Let's go!
Stay in line, sir.
Keep on the group, please.
Inside, please.
Please, keep moving. Let's go!
Keep moving, please.
Why don't you guys tell me,
what's going on?
Sorry Sir,
you have to keep moving.
Asshole!
Don't touch me! Asshole!
Help! Help!
What are you people doing?!
This facility is under command and control...
- What does it mean? Judy, what does it mean?
- They are checking for elevated temperatures.
Barnum was bleeding from the nose
so was Rory.
Well, cerebral haemorrhage.
It's got to be some kind of virus.
Look, I'm a Sheriff, she's a doctor.
We know these people.
What the fuck is going' on in here?
Would you please tell us
what's going' on?
Maybe we can actually help you.
David!
Wait!
- David! David! Help!
- Judy!
David! David! David!
Please. Please. Help me, please.
Keep on moving.
Keep on moving
Please, please, don't please, don't.
No, no! Please, please I'm pregnant!
Please, no!
Let's go! Don, Franklin,
open these doors!
Move people, we are getting' you
out of here. Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Let's go, let's go!
- Kevin, where is Linda?
- They took her.
- Judy?
- They took her too.
They took George and Francine and
Whitney, Simon and whole mass of other people.
- Kevin! Kevin!
- Mom!
- We are going back.
- They got the whole town sealed off.
Road blocks on every highway.
Tim Mitchell tried to run one,
they shot him dead and his entire family.
David, this here,
might be our only chance.
Don't lose it to run off
on some fool's errand.
- Judy is fool's errand?
- You know what I am saying.
I'll tell you what Kiev, don't ask me why
I can't leave without my wife.
And I won't ask you why you can.
We got a breach in the yard!
Move out! Move out! Let's go! Evacuate!
C'mon! Let's go, let's go!
The crazies are breached the corridor!
C'mon! Move out!
We got to get out of here!
Nice to see you too, chief.
Shit!
- How did you get out?
- Tom Alice
went with his pickup through the fence.
And fucking military started shooting.
Town's folks going nuts.
Before you know, the people were just
running' off on the field.
David, Judy was still inside.
I'm sorry.
She's not sick. She's been running
a fever all month. Russ, she's pregnant.
- It's about time.
- I'm goanna go get her.
Boo-fucking-yah...
Let's gobble the high school!
Becca? Becca, is that you?
Oh God! Honey...honey, are you hurt?
- Is this really happening?
- It's goanna be alright. We're goanna be okay.
You don't really believe that, do you?
Becca! Oh shit!
Please, stop! Please, let me go!
Please, don't do this!
No, please don't do this!
Please..No, no, please!
Shit!
No! Stop! No, please!
No, please! Just get out of here!
Oh God!
- Are you okay?
- No, not really.
- Chief?
- We got to get quick to fuel truck stop...
135. They're putting' people on busses
and get them out of here.
We're goanna go. C'mon.
Did Peter call?
- It's got to be me.
- Russell,
I had enough problems
without you and then...
It's easy for you to say. You are at the end
of the pipe, I'm a half-mile from the farm.
- Who is the Sheriff?
- What?
- Who is the Sheriff of the Pierce County?
- You are.
- I am. Who's the Deputy?
- That would be me.
You are. Deputy does what the Sheriff tells him
and that's the balance of power.
And I'm telling... You are not getting sick.
You understand me?
Did Peter call?
I hope you are right, Chief. I didn't
owe the world, but I had plans.
C'mon.
Let's go.
I'll check the truck.
Oh shit! It's brooded.
- They all are.
- I'll check those cars.
It's not brooded.
- Russell, get out of the truck.
- Give me a sec...
Run!
Go, go, go, go!
C'mon, boy. Run out...
Run, little man, run!
- Oh yeah!
- Good shot!
- C'mon. Weft him.
- Straight through the heart.
- Good shot, man!
- You have something about that shot?!
It's a hell of the walk to Quick Falls.
- Get the old cruiser of the blocks.
- That piece of shit still works?
- Yeah.
- Just I can't blow the car without wheels.
- It's only seven miles to my place.
- It's five, if we cut through McGregor's farm.
And one-twenty to Quick Falls from there.
- I'm fine.
- Good, let's go.
They took my blood.
Or at least one test,
that I saw.
What if the reason they didn't
let me go, because I have it?
You're pregnant,
that's why you have a fever.
- David, we can't know that for sure.
- I can, and I do.
You're sick, I'm sick.
We drink from the same tap.
I'm not sick.
None of us are.
We're goanna get through this.
- What the fuck?
- Scotty McGregor.
- It's her boyfriend.
- Russell, stop her.
Yeah, I got it.
- David?
- We don't have time for this.
You had time for me.
Let's go.
- Looks deserted.
- Scotty?
- Get back!
Drop your fucking gun, Scotty.
- I'll blow your head off, do you hear me?
- Scotty, it's me!
Stay here.
Scotty, don't be an asshole.
We're fine.
- Scotty!
- Scotty, put the gun down.
- Put it down!
- Scotty?
Sorry.
- I had to be sure.
- Yeah. Well, that's two-way street here, Scotty.
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- Yeah.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Scotty, where's your mom?
Back at the house. We're just getting
some supplies before the sun woke.
Well, the sheriff got a car.
You two can come with us.
Are you okay?
How's your mom?
Be quiet.
Get in the barn! Go, go, go.
Russ.
We have one civilian.
Coming' out!
- Wait!
- Everything's goanna be okay ma'am, we just need to process you.
Hold up right there!
Stay where you are!
OK, let's go. Split up.
We got to complete sweeping the area.
Take Becca,
go to the back of the barn.
Don't kill me, please.
Don't kill me.
- Oh, fuck.
- How could you do it? How could you...?
You make a sound out of the mess,
and I'll kill you, you understand?
- What the hell was that?
- Orders, sir.
From where, asshole?
- Whoever gives them, I don't know.
- Bullshit. What the fuck is going on here?
All they said, is intervene in
some sort of accident.
My whole unit got flown here,
we didn't even know what's the state,
until we've seen a license of it.
Am I goanna die,
that my mask's gone?
Is that what they told you?
If you took your mask off, you're goanna die?
They said to keep it on.
Look...
I know I don't deserve
any favours from you people,
but if you let me go,
I swear to God, I won't say nothing.
I didn't sign up
to shoot unarmed civilians.
- I'll just leave here, okay?
- Sit down.
- Put the gun down, Russ.
- Chief?
I'm a sheriff.
That's my deputy.
My wife is a doctor, she's pregnant.
Becca here is not even 18.
- He blabs, they'll find us.
- If we didn't let him go, they'll find us for sure.
Beside... he's not goanna blab.
No, sir.
- You got to give it to him, Russ.
- Shit!
Sorry about your folks town.
- Hey! Hey! Whoa! Whoa!
- Don't shoot! Don't shoot.
Any crazies back there, Babcock?
Babcock?
- No, all clear.
- Good. Military's point back to the perimeter.
Let's go, come on!
The barn is clear.
We're secured back there.
Alright. Moving' out.
If what that soldier said is true,
this disease is gone airborne.
We just have to keep going.
We're going to get the car running.
Come on.
It's perfect.
It's a perfect, beautiful morning,
and this is our home.
This is where we're goanna
raise our baby.
We're still got all those things.
Everyone we know,
is dead.
This town is dead,
and it's not coming back.
It's never coming back.
Fuck ya! See if you can
find a tool box.
This is goanna be your room.
Judy?
Look, I know this is hard
but we've got to keep moving....
This is the gun
that killed your father.
Peggy, no.
Not Judy.
I shot him. I-I... I shot...
Yes!
Peggy, I shot him.
Look at me, you crazy bitch!
That's it!
I fuckin' shot him! I did it!
When he walked on
that field, with a loaded shotgun.
Thanks God I did. They could
give me a fuckin' medal.
Finally killed the damn drunk!
- Oh my God.
- Let me see your hand.
Give me the bandage.
Russell!
Just making sure.
He is sick, David.
- We don't know that.
- You saw what he did.
Hey, guys!
Come on, we got to go.
He saved our lives.
That's what I saw.
- Hey. You feeling' okay?
- I'm fine.
Well, I'm just saying,
if she is getting sick, we don't want to be
- in the fucking car with her.
- Russell, she's fine.
I'm not sick.
We wouldn't know. This got to be
the sickness messing with your mind.
Okay, Russell. That's enough.
Don't lose your head.
- What do you mean by that?
- I mean, don't lose your head.
- What do you mean by that, chief?
- I mean...
She's fine.
Now, just...
Fuck!
- Did they see us?
- I don't know.
- Honey.
- Oh, shit!
Guys, turn around.
They're coming' back.
- We got to get out of here!
- Let's go.
-The helicopter is coming.
- Chief, let's go!
We can't stay on the highway.
There's got to be another road we can take.
- What road, Judy? Tell me?
- I don't know. There's got to be something.
What road can they not see?
Tell me? What road can they not see?
What magic road,
can they not see?
- Tell me, how fucking go?
- David, I'm just trying to help.
I'm sorry.
- I saw someone!
- Move. Where?
It was back there.
I know, I saw someone.
Fuck!
David, get us out of here.
- Oh, shit!
- Start the car.
Come on!
Come on, chief.
Let's go.
Come on, get us out of here.
Let's go!
Come on!
- Why aren't we moving?
- Why the fuck aren't we moving', chief?
Because I can't get
a fucking contraction.
Go! Go!
Fuck! let's go.
Get us out of here.
- I don't want to die like this.
- What the fuck was that?
- Russell!
- Russell... Russ...
Russell!
- Russell!
- I saw a movement!
Everything is fucking moving.
Just drive! Come on!
- Stop the fucking car!
- Stop!
- Stop.
- Judy.
David!
Come on. Help me!
Oh, God. Please.
Becca! Becca!
It's my truck.
The fuckers fired my tires.
- Goddammit!
- We need water.
- I know
- Guys! Car coming!
Stay here.
- David, what are you doing'?
- We're taking this car.
- Fuck!
- Russ, what are you... No!
Welcome to Pierce County.
The friendliest place on earth, asshole.
Russ, I want to talk to him.
Okay.
- What the fuck do you think you are?
- I am the guy, standing between you,
and a bullet.
Now, what was on that plane?
What was on,
that goddamn plane?
Trixie. Rhabdoviridae prototype.
- A fucking biological weapon!
- It was headed to incinerator in Texas.
You're telling' me,
that you guys, engineered this crap?
It's designed to destabilize the population.
In this case, the wrong one.
Look fella, we lost a plane.
What do you want me to say?
How about "Sorry, for destroying
your whole goddamn town?"
- David, wait.
- What would you've preferred?
A global pandemic?
I take it up with the pilot.
I came here to help.
- Help who? Help us?
- What.. what is the incubation period?
48 hours. After that,
you're either dead, or you don't have it.
Fine. It's day 3, and we're still
talking. So, you are goanna help us...
Fuck!
- No, no, no, no!
- Oh my God!
What the fuck is the matter
with you?
I said, that I wanted to talk to him.
You talked.
Shit.
- I'm goanna need that back.
- I'll carry it for a while.
- You've been carrying' it the whole time.
- No, not really.
I got it.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
- Russell. We're on your side.
- My side? Shit.
- I didn't even know there were sides.
- There's not. I'm just saying...
- Shut the fuck up!
- no side, I've been...
- Russell! No!
- Tell her to shut up, or I'll kill her,
- do you understand?
- Judy, stop talking.
Let him think about
what he's doing.
One... Two... Three...
That's how many times
I saved your life.
Go on. Walk where I can see ya.
Move!
That's fuckin' heavy.
Move! Move!
- Fuck it. I'm goanna confront him.
- David, don't, please.
If we don't make it to
that truck stop, we're dead anyway.
- David, don't.
- Back off!
- I want to talk to you.
- I'll fuckin' shoot you where you stand.
- Just want to talk.
- David, stop!
- You better listen to me.
- David.
- Put the gun down.
- Final warning, chief.
Put it down. Please.
Just put it down.
I just want to talk.
You and me, man to man.
Come on.
- Shit.
- Okay. Here's a deal.
Remember that monster catfish
I caught last summer?
What the weight you reckon?
35-40 Pounds.
Shit. It's a big
son of a bitch.
I'm not alright, am I?
Can I walk with you guys?
A little while longer?
Please.
If you got through there, you can make it
to the highway on the other side.
- They'll see us.
- No, they'll be focusing on me.
Deputy does what the sheriff
tells him, right? You're the sheriff.
Come on, chief. I am done.
I'm goanna die here, no matter what.
So, let it mean something.
let that mean you two made it.
Give me that.
Boo-fucking-yah.
Attention! You have entered
a prohibited zone of a massive military operation
Please, identify yourself.
My name is, Deputy Russell Clark,
the Pierce County sheriff department.
- It's okay. I'm not sick.
- Keep your hands in the air
make no sudden movements,
or you will be fired upon.
We have a fire operation.
Get up behind the vehicle.
Show yourself,
or we will open fire.
It's okay. It's okay.
Now stop there,
and get down on the ground.
Stop, and get down on the ground.
Get down on the ground, now!
He's down!
Cease fire!
He's still breathing.
Stay on him.
Fuck you,
for what you did.
It was Grand Central last night.
Wait here.
Hello?
Judy? Judy?!
Judy?
Judy, you alright?
They exterminated everyone,
not just the sick.
- Look, there's a ... truck we can take.
- What's...
If we get out of here,
they're goanna kill us, too.
- No, if we get to Cedar Rapids...
- David, can you just stop it?
- If we get to Cedar Rapids...
- Stop pretending everything's goanna be okay!
Alright.
For Christ's sake.
I'm sorry.
You want to give up?
If you want to sit here
and die, tell me.
And I'll sit here and die with you.
You're goanna go, get that truck.
Viper 2, this is TOC. We're approaching
T-10 minutes. Confirm status.
All units, this is TOC.
Be advised
we are all ready stated.
Proceed to countdown.
Countdown procedure initiating.
Clear T minus 10 minutes.
Oh, shit
Honey, it's fine.
It's okay.
- David, honey. how's it going there?
- We're goanna get there.
Come on.
David.
- Goddammit!
- David, come on.
Hurry up.
All right. It's okay.
It's got to be in here somewhere,
David. Come on, just keep looking.
David, what are you doing?
David!
Come on!
Let's get the fuck out of here.
The smallest and straightest road
to Cedar Rapids.
Yeah, perfect.
35... 34... 33... 32...
What happens
when it gets to zero?
T-30 seconds and counting.
27... 26...
- 25... 24...
- Faster.
22... 21...
- 19... 18...
- You see anything?
- 17... 16...
- No.
14... 13... Blow...
Final sequence start.
Clear to T-10 seconds.
9 ... 8 ...
- Trigger engaged.
- 6... 5...
4... 3... 2... 1...
- See anything?
- No.
Oh my God!
Get down!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
I'm sorry, honey.