Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
[ Crowd Cheering, Muffled ]
[ Cheering, Shouting ]
Go, Travis!
Yeah!
[ Man ]
Nitro Circus started
very organically...
with a group of friends.
[ Squealing ]
[ Man #2 ]
It's their childhood dream
just manifesting itself...
in the present moment.
[ Man #3 ] People are so
conditioned in watching movies
that they all think it's fake.
There's real life on the line
in what Nitro does.
[ Children Screaming ]
[ Chanting ]
Nitro! Nitro! Nitro!
[ Man #4 ]
To get to a live tour
and actually pull it off-
lt is insanity.
lt was not possible.
[ Engine Roaring ]
[ Man #5 ]
These guys will never make it.
[ Man #6 ]
Nitro is about trying to find
where it's not possible to go.
And then going there.
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Man Singing Rock ]
♪ There's a time and a place ♪
♪ When we all just
need an escape ♪
♪ From a world that doesn't
understand at all ♪
♪ So we do what we do ♪
♪ It's the life that we choose ♪
♪ You may not get it ♪
♪ We got nothing to lose ♪
♪ So just fire it up ♪
♪ And let's run ♪
♪ I said put your hands up ♪
♪ Hands up ♪
♪ And everybody screams ♪
♪ Put your hands up ♪
♪ Hands up ♪
♪ I'll give you what you need ♪
♪ Bring in the thunder
and I'll bring in the show ♪
♪ So put your hands up ♪
♪ Hands up ♪
♪ I'm ready to go ♪
♪ I said put your hands up ♪
♪ Hands up ♪
♪ And everybody screams ♪
♪ Put your hands up ♪
♪ Hands up ♪
♪ I'll give you
what you need ♪
♪ Bring in the thunder
and I'll bring in the show ♪
♪ So put your hands up ♪
♪ Hands up ♪
♪ I'm ready to go ♪
♪ Ready to go ♪♪
[ Man Narrating ]
Childhood never ended for
this lively band of brothers.
They've always had one mission-
to have more fun
than anyone on the planet.
Oh! Oh!
Go!
[ Narrator ]
The crew is led by
two good old boys...
who met when they
were 12 years old-
Jeremy Rawle,
a hippie lawyer who gave up
his failing law practice...
to fight off the symptoms
of midlife crisis.
[ Screams ]
Am I done, or do I
need to do that again?
You're done.
And Godfrey,
the son of a trucker
and the poster child for adult
attention-deficit disorder.
Under Gregg and Jeremy's
unorthodox direction-
[ Groans ]
the crew recorded
their adventures
in a series of short movies...
and even a TV show.
Through some creative financing,
they made this movie,
shot in 3-D,
which cost a buttload.
They pitched their idea
to Hollywood,
but Hollywood
crapped its pants.
The studio executives
were terrified...
that this movie
was too dangerous.
Pussies.
The end goal
for the Nitro Circus-
the dream they've shared
since childhood-
was to perform their stunts
live in front of an audience.
They set their sights on a show
at the MGM Grand in Las Vegas.
But would anyone
really come to see them?
I mean, who are
these guys anyway?
[ Laughing ]
I'll tell you who.
First off,
there's Travis Pastrana,
the modern-day Evel Knievel,
1 8-time X Games medalist...
and five-time
national champion.
But he can't throw a ball
to save his own life.
He's the all-American
wonder kid...
and ringleader
of the Nitro Circus.
[ Vocalist ]
Yeah!
♪ I wanna party ♪
Then there's
a 26-year-old man-child-
Yeah! Not in my house, punk!
Not today!
[ Ferocious Shout ]
Streetbike Tommy.
He is the most adorable member
of the Nitro Circus...
and the fattest.
He loves cheeseburgers,
soda pop...
and hates
his everyday occupation
of hanging drywall.
But the Nitro Circus is more
than just fat, hairy men.
[ Groans ]
[ Bleeps ]
♪ I don't care
what you think about me ♪
Jolene Van Vugt-
She is tough, sexy
and downright full of it.
She is the only one
with a vagina.
She keeps the boys in line
by not just competing
with them,
but showing them up.
Nitro Girl is the real deal.
Not quite as sexy,
but just as ballsy...
is Erik Roner,
extreme skier and BASE jumper.
He has no business
on anything with a motor.
[ Shouts ]
Although he's completely
out of his element
with this group,
he's always game
to hurl his body
into harm's way.
For a dude with a tramp stamp,
he's one bad mofo.
Come on, Special!
No, no, no, no, no.
Come on.
Hit him, Special!
Come on, come on.
Work it lower to high.
Come on.
Which brings us
to Special Greg,
Travis's cousin.
He's a jack-of-all-trades
and master of none.
Like a cat, he always seems
to land on his feet.
And like a nasty honey badger,
nothing can stop him.
Special-
[ Body Thuds ]
Well, all right now.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
[ Bell Rings ]
At least one member
of the crew...
has a steady job, for now.
[ Horn Honking ]
Jim DeChamp.
He's Travis's oldest friend.
Oh!
He has a super-long neck...
and is somehow always able
to always cheat death.
He's the current
world record holder...
for consecutive
one-handed claps.
♪ My bike, my bike ♪
♪ I want to ride my bike ♪
♪ Take what you like,
but I love my bike ♪
♪ TMX to BMX
Watch out for my bike ♪♪
[ Shouts ]
[ Narrator ]
These guys don't give a rip...
about what most people
think is possible.
They only care about
pushing each other
beyond their comfort level,
givin' it hell...
and seeing if they can come out
all right on the other end.
They've been doing this
since childhood.
This is the Nitro Circus.
So we might as well
pack seven people
into a school bus...
and see how far
that puppy can fly.
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, here we go now ♪
♪ Coming on now
with the new stuff♪
- ♪ Yeah, here we go now ♪
- [ Man ] Aw- [ Bleeps ]
[ Man ]
Yeah!
[ Whooping ]
[ Whooping, Cheering ]
My, uh, 12th-grade teacher
was right,
and I was meant to be
a bus driver.
Hands down, one of
the coolest things I've ever
gotten to do in my life.
Absolutely.
[ Narrator ]
Their biggest goal is
to share what they do live...
in front of a packed house
at the MGM Grand in Las Vegas.
We came from Mexico
to see the show.
We are really,
really excited.
I've definitely never seen
anything like it before.
Those guys are crazy
with talent.
This is the best day of my life.
Rock and roll.
I think the reason people
connect to Nitro Circus-
It's- I think everyone
has a relationship with fear.
I think you can sort of
hearken back to that moment...
where you did something
very stupid...
and somehow, like, just skinned
under the wire of death.
It's almost like that idea
of, like,
if you had the balls
or were willing to do it,
it would be so much fun
to get with all your friends...
and go do sketchy things...
that give you
this amazing adrenaline rush.
It's crazy.
Half the- [ Bleeps ]-
these guys do,
they have to go
out of the States
because it's illegal...
to jump off buildings
the way they're doing it.
It's illegal to do
the stuff they want to do
in America.
That- [ Bleeps ]- illegal, guys.
That should be your-
That's what it should be like.
Ah, this might not be
a good idea.
Travis is like,
"No, let's get on a plane."
Wow.
This is one
of those stunts that-
This is why
we do what we do.
[ Jolene ]
We just got up to the top
of this skyscraper-
63 stories high
above Panama City.
It's going to be
a very interesting BASE jump.
First of its kind ever.
And we're not too sure
exactly how it's gonna go.
When you jump off that,
that ground comes at you
real fast.
I'll tell you that much.
You got about four seconds
to figure it out.
You're good.
What can possibly
go wrong?
Well, for some reason,
me and Crum...
are the only ones
down here on the ground.
We, uh-
I think we're Team "C."
Yeah. 'Cause we wanna see
what's gonna happen down here.
- 'Cause we wanna see
what's gonna happen.
- [ Laughing ]
[ Bonifay ]
So we got Roner
perched on a blob,
and there's two fat
Elvis Evel Knievels
jumping onto it,
and he's gonna shoot off
the blob on top of the building.
You know what happens,
is I get so nervous...
that I have to pee.
For them.
Yeah, I need to pee.
Like, why do I have to pee?
I'm not even doing anything.
You shouldn't pee, man.
I think I'm gonna pee.
Hey, Jer.
You ready for this, baby?
It's go time.
[ Crum ]
Almost 500 pounds up there,
I think. Maybe more.
Of man meat.
- How is it out there, Erik?
- lt sucks!
[ Laughing ]
We've been waiting
our whole lives for this.
We're damn good too, man.
[ Man ]
You got it, Rubs.
You got it!
Three, two,
one!
I love you!
[ Man #1 ] Oh, no. No.
[ Man #2 ] Perfect!
Perfect! Perfect! Perfect!
[ Whoops ]
Yeah!
[ Whooping ]
- Yeah!
- [ Excited Chattering ]
Whoo!
Oh, my God.
I thought he was gonna go way
further away from the blob than that.
That was not far enough.
I about- [ Bleeps ]-
my pants when you
turned in towards the building.
That was heavy.
I didn't go very far out.
I think I saw someone having tea
in their apartment building
real close.
Hi. Whoo.
[ Crum ] I think Roner
deserves a group hug...
that he's still with us.
Get in there,
breathe it in.
Rubberneck,
you sick puppy.
Can we be done with,
uh, skyscraper blob drop?
Look at you.
Did you see
what just happened?
[ Crashing ]
Ow!
Tommy ejected,
missed all the safety boxes...
and slammed
into the ground.
Ow! Ow, ow, ow!
My- [ Bleeps ]- ass.
If Tommy had bounced the
other way, he would have blobbed
himself right off the building,
and that would have been
the end of Tommy.
Tommy, I got
a couple cheeseburgers
coming your way.
Thank you for launching me
over that building safely.
Outside of Streetbike Tommy,
you guys are
far superior athletes.
Uh, we're more theatrical
with our costumes...
and man-on-man contact.
You guys have more things
with motors in them,
and we do more pranks.
I came from Jackass
and when I met the Nitro family,
it felt very familiar to me.
I get the dynamics of it
right away.
It's like all the same
inbred family.
[ Tremaine ] Really,
it just always boiled down to-
The difference
between Jackass
and Nitro...
was our Jackass stunts
are always designed to fail.
Everyone accepts that.
Nitro's stunts-
you have to succeed,
or you die.
Same mother,
different daddies.
[ Chuckling ]
In this game
of Freedom Flyers,
the objective is
for me to leave
my mother's nest...
and fly...
with the help of
a bungee cord...
and a jelly doughnut
inner tube.
Hit that there jump,
launch in and take out
as many of my friends...
and as much of their home
as possible.
In other words,
I'm a wrecking ball...
in the form of a bird.
So, Rubs, this is
your speed test for this.
We need to line up
how you're gonna jump...
and to see how fast
you need to go,
so you're our guinea dive.
The water's
three foot deep.
You're gonna be
20 feet in the air,
goin' 120 feet in distance.
No problem.
Okay. Let's get you
on that tube.
[ Jolene ]
Go, Rubs!
[ Whooping ]
[ Laughing ]
Whoo!
Was that far enough?
They told me it was time
for me to leave
the mother's nest.
I'm ready to go right back
into that nest.
I think that was the biggest
D.D.T. body slam I've ever had.
Oh. I don't know
about this one.
There's just so much that
could possibly go great here.
Great possibilities.
There's a lot
of scenarios.
The goal was Tommy.
Now the goal is
to take out Parks.
Parks is the only one
left on top.
Um, I still think Tommy
should be hit.
All right.
I'm ready to freedom fly.
Go get 'em, Roner.
[ Man ]
Good luck, buddy!
Whoa! Holy-
[ Bleeps ]
Oh, my God!
Yeah!
[ Distorted Shout ]
Parks, you hit the water
so fast!
That was like- boom!
You don't stop!
That was one
of the hardest hits
I've ever had.
The thing about freedom
is you can never stop
fightin' for it,
so we're gonna try again.
Freedom!
Take off.
Oh!
[ Shouts ]
[ People Laughing ]
Oh- [ Bleeps ]
That was a lot
of destruction.
That was awesome.
[ Travis ]
Wow. Special got
knocked the "F" out.
[ Jim ]
Special took it-
[ Travis ]
Wow! What a hit.
[ Erik ]
Freedom Flyers has been pretty
damn rough until this point.
But, unfortunately,
we didn't accomplish what
I was trying to accomplish,
which was take out my friends
and their home.
I think we gotta
do it again,
which sucks for me.
But, um, I'm gonna try to
have a positive attitude...
and, uh, try to catch
some more air.
Red rover, red rover,
send Roner on over!
You can take our land,
but you can't take
our freedom!
[ Shouting ]
Yeah!
Good luck, buddy.
Perfect.
Back up.
Oh!
Oh- [ Bleeps ]
Oh. That's gonna
leave a mark.
We gotta carry him off.
You got blood on there.
Holy- [ Bleeps ]
That's probably where
your teeth are bleeding from.
ls that Roner's blood?
Wow.
[ Jolene ]
As soon as I saw you
take off, I was, like,
"Oh, he's heading
straight for Tommy."
[ Erik ]
For a minute, I was,
"Oh, I got the stars."
Then I was like, "Oh, Tommy."
When I saw you, I was like,
"Yes, I finally got one!"
[ Laughing ]
For all you people
that wanna be on Nitro Circus...
and come out
and do this stuff,
ooh, it's so much fun.
Perfect!
As we found out,
freedom ain't free of pain.
Ka-kah!
[ All ]
[ Man ] To fill
an arena in Las Vegas
is no easy task.
Everyone tells 'em
they can't do it.
A loss in what they do
is different than losing a game.
You miss a field goal,
you miss a field goal.
You miss doing
a double backflip, you die.
And they approach
every obstacle like that.
Those are paying fans
looking to be entertained.
You just can't lose.
[ Shutter Clicking ]
[ Man ] Travis's compound
that he has in Maryland...
is, uh, a true testament
that he lives this life.
It's in such
a beautiful setting,
you know,
with these lush trees
all around,
and it's just- yeah,
the devil's playground, man.
Death is everywhere.
You can smell it in the air.
[ Sheckler ]
The only thing that is
burnt in my brain...
from that dude's house...
is the first time I went there,
we're going into the foam pit,
this random dude
just comes around,
and he's like,
"Travis, can I flip?"
Travis said, "Yeah, flip.
Just don't go right."
That's when the dude
took the 1 1 0 off the side.
Like smoked himself.
And I saw that
with my own eyes.
I was like,
"Dude, don't go right."
Burnt into my brain.
It's a little factory
of bad ideas.
Well, Trav,
after all these years
of talking about it,
you finally built this loop
in your backyard.
Every single thing that we do,
someone in our crew steps up,
and Jolene has volunteered
to step up for us.
Thank you, Jolene.
You came right out
this morning and said you
wanted to hit this first.
I'm comin' in hot.
Everyone's gotta go first once,
and l- just go.
We don't even know if
this is gonna work, Jo.
I don't care.
All right.
Let's get up there
and do this.
This is a way better loop.
[ Laughing ]
You're on your third loop!
Hey, guys, Tommy's
on his third loop!
I'm looking for
a baker's dozen.
Mmm.
[ Travis ] Loops are stupid.
I don't know why we built one.
I guess just to see
all these people that scared
that are such badasses.
And Jolene gears up first.
Crazy girl. Crazy.
I have nothing
but wonderful things
to say about Jolene...
because I'm
scared to death of her.
Being the only girl
in that whole crew,
it must be very difficult.
And she pulls it off
like a champ.
For someone
who doesn't have balls,
she has the biggest set.
lt looks fun though, Jo.
You're in the hot seat,
not me, but it does
look fun.
[ Jolene ]
My main concern is aiming.
I do have a word of advice.
Do you wanna hear it?
I don't- I think
I want to vomit,
so I think
I want to go.
Okay.
We're ready to go.
But aim for the black line.
That's my word of advice.
Just get in there
and hit that thing!
Yeah.
What's taking so long?
Okay.
Just stop talking!
- Yes, ma'am.
- Yeah, JoJo!
Okay.
This is gonna be cool.
You got it.
[ Cheering ]
[ Laughing ]
That was awesome!
That was the best!
That was rad! Good job.
She's pumped!
Look at that.
I own you, Mr. Loop!
You're saying
don't lean too far forward
'cause you'll die?
I mean, I don't know.
I did a tricycle.
You're doing a wheelchair.
Big difference.
Oh, man.
I need some-
some wheelchair advice.
Yes.
And unfortunately,
you're the only one
of your kind,
so, sorry, you don't
get any advice.
So I gotta talk to myself.
You're a unicorn.
You're the only one
of your kind.
The only difference
between a unicorn and you
is that you've been spotted.
[ Laughs ]
[ Narrator ]
Aaron Fotheringham,
a.k.a. Wheelz.
He was born with spina bifida
and can't walk.
If you ask him,
he's not in a wheelchair.
He's just riding one.
- [ Men ] Whoo!
- Makes the rest of the crew
feel like pussies.
[ Travis ] It's my house,
and I am scared to death
to go around this loop,
and Wheelz is gonna try it
on a wheelchair.
And I am scared for him.
Good luck, Wheelz!
You own this one, dude.
Come on, buddy.
It's good.
You got it- Pickin' up speed.
Not too fast.
You got it,
you got it, you got it.
Oh!
[ Bleeps ]
- Oh, my God.
- You are the toughest kid.
You are so tough.
[ Jolene ]
Oh, my God.
Dude, that was, like-
Seriously, the first time I've ever
seen things that are floating.
[ Jolene ]
Oh, my God. Aaron, your head-
[ Man ]
How are you
conscious right now?
[ Distorted Voices ]
[ Man ]
Dude, you hit so hard, I thought
you were gonna start walkin'.
Yeah, Wheelz!
[ Cheering ]
Wheelz, are you ready
to leave this loop
behind you?
I sure am.
This thing broke my heart.
What are you doing
with that?
Oh, no, no. Wheelz!
Not my loop. You're not
settin' that thing on fire!
♪ Rock out, rock out ♪
♪ Rock out ♪
♪ Rock out, no, no, no ♪♪
All right, Tom P.
You've always wanted
to get some respect-
somehow, some way-
as a real athlete.
Yeah.
[ Laughing ]
You're gonna begin
your freestyle motocross
career today.
Awesome.
What are you gonna do?
Oh, I don't know.
Whatever comes natural.
Buckle it up.
[ Groans ]
Oh, boy.
Consider this tryouts
for the Vegas show,
so don't screw it up.
Oh- [ Bleeps ]
[ Groans ]
[ Bleeps ]
Ow! [ Bleeps ]
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
My ankle's- [ Bleeps ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Man ]
We got you, Tom P.
That is a man!
Hey, Wheelz. Why does it
gotta be an ankle, man?
This has to support this.
You know what I'm sayin'?
Couldn't have been a finger.
Yeah.
[ Travis ]
All right, guys.
This is the tallest,
steepest BMX ramp that we have.
- Jim, you wanna calculate
this ramp for us?
- I'll do my math calculations.
I'm going no pedals,
no brakes and just goin'
whatever the hell big the hill is.
I really think
that's about right.
Nice knowing you, Jim.
Oh, he's goin' so fast.
Good grief!
♪ You might survive
Still it ain't hard ♪
[ Yelling ]
♪ When you die,
you're gonna go hard ♪
Giraffe neck down.
Oh, my God!
Jim sort of needs
a little more coaxing,
especially if it's out
of his comfort zone.
He kind of gets guilted
into like, "Yo, I can do it.
I wanna be-
I can do it too.
I can do it too."
Then some catastrophic thing.
Um, if you hit
absolutely perfect,
you have a two percent chance.
Good luck.
Two?
- But he's going really fast.
- Too fast. Too fast.
Oh!
I even thought I was goin'-
My judgment these days
is way off.
I always think
I can go faster.
He's a real wild card,
and he gives great footage.
We're getting ready
to jump a Big Wheel
at way too fast of a speed.
Holy- [ Bleeps ]
[ Man Laughing ]
What's a Big Wheel?
Okay, it's a kids' toy.
They must be
the best-put-together
Big Wheels ever.
Like, these guys
are jumping them
at least a hundred feet...
on some of their craziest ones
and landing, no problem.
Like, it doesn't
make sense.
I think the only way
that I would be able
to get the feeling...
is if I had to try
to ride the trike,
which I don't wanna do, Travis,
so- [ Bleeps ]- off.
All right, guys.
Over the past three years,
the most elusive trick
that we have not
been able to do...
is the double backflip
on trikes.
This has turned
into a mission.
We have a launch ramp.
We have Mount Mulch-more.
And today is the day...
that we beat this trick!
All right. Hands in.
Nitro on three.
One, two, three!
Nitro!
I'm the guinea pig.
I got the short straw.
You know how that works.
Got a long day ahead of us!
Let's get to work!
Fire one!
Oh! Wipe-
No, no, no, no.
No idea what to change
from what Special did,
but... I can hope
for the best.
Fire two!
Yeah, Dusty!
Go!
[ Cheering ]
[ Distorted Voices ]
It's gonna happen!
It's gonna happen today!
It's happening today!
Today is the day
that history's gonna be made!
A double flip
on a Big Wheel
is going down.
Oh.
You just gave them a glimpse
of the great white buffalo.
Who's up next?
Hi, Mom.
You proud of me?
Fire three!
Fire 1 0!
Come on, baby!
Oh! Oh!
- ♪ Do it, do it, do it ♪
- Get the blue mat!
Get the blue mat!
The blue mat!
Firing 1 1 !
Fire 1 1 !
Fire 1 1 .
Dang! He's out.
[ Groans ]
I just got a calf cramp.
Give me a second.
You got a calf cramp.
You landed on your face,
and you got a calf cramp?
Yeah.
This has been
an absolute bear of a trick.
We've had all the top
trike riders come out...
all to Maryland
to do a double flip.
Everybody has
thrown down their best.
Everybody's been concussed.
Everyone's been hurt.
Dusty's taking
the hardest hits.
Dusty's goin' back up.
He's the only one of us that's
even close to doin' this thing.
Fingers crossed for him.
He can ride out of this thing
in eternal glory in Nitro.
It's, uh- This one's
really been a tough one.
I hope I just land this one
so I can go in the pool.
[ Narrator ]
Dusty Wygle.
Dusty is a new recruit
to the Nitro Circus.
Fresh meat, as they say.
Yeah, boy!
He's dripping with talent,
still naive enough
to try anything
the older members say.
He'll definitely work
in the live show.
Fire 12!
Yeah!
Come on, come on,
come on!
[ Cheering ]
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
Oh, my God!
[ Travis ] This was why
we all came to Maryland.
This was the trick,
the stunt, the fun day
that we all wanted to have,
and you conquered it, man.
Hose me down
and dress me up.
Let's go out tonight.
Whoo!
Get so excited about
being the world's first double
on a Big Wheel...
when it's just you
and your friends
that do it.
No one else.
No one else in the world.
You're claiming,
"Oh, this is the greatest day
of our lives"...
because it's like four of you
have ever even tried to do it.
And you're the only ones
with these highly modified,
next-level Big Wheels. Okay?
So it's yours to own forever
because no one's ever
gonna do it.
All right, Hubert.
Somebody's gotta
stick that landing!
We built all that mulch.
What are you thinking?
I'm thinkin' me,
a four-wheeler and an
extra ramp equals success!
Good luck.
Nitro Circus!
Represent.
RedNek power.
[ Narrator ]
Hubert Rowland-
everybody's favorite redneck.
Straight from
the backwoods of Tennessee,
he's handy with anything
from a wrench to a tractor.
He builds the stunts
for the rest of the crew...
and makes a mean batch
of moonshine.
Yeah, yeah!
[ Jolene ]
Come on, Hubert!
ls he coming?
Here he comes.
Yeah, Hubert!
Oh! Yeah!
Whoo!
Dude, l-l had no idea
you were trying to have
the quad ride you...
instead of you ride it.
♪ I'm built for speed ♪
♪ I'm drinkin' gasoline ♪
♪ I'm built for speed, baby♪
♪ So give me what I need ♪
♪ I'm built for speed ♪
♪ Yeah ♪♪
Right now,
the mulch pile is winning.
Yeah, it's- it's kickin' ass
and it don't care
whose name you are.
Gotta be honest.
Don't try to straight edge.
Just flip that baby.
The fact that he
stepped up to do this-
I'm nervous for the guy.
- Here he comes.
- Commit, commit,
commit, commit.
♪ Some people say I'm crazy
for the things I've done ♪
♪ Hell, no ♪
♪ I washed out, but I just
keep on breaking through ♪
♪ Go, go ♪
♪ I'm drinkin' whiskey
and doin' what I want ♪
♪ Hell, no ♪
♪ This is what I'm
never gonna stop ♪
♪ Hell, no ♪
♪ And I'm never gonna stop ♪♪
My shoulder.
lt hurts so bad.
Get me on the floor.
Get me on the ground.
Hubert, I'm so proud of you!
ls it out? ls it out?
Hold on, hold on.
His shoulder's out.
Can we get a shoulder back in
with a side of relish, please?
You know what?
I don't think it is.
Make sure his arm's
not broken.
[ Crying ]
His arm might be broken.
Put it down!
Hubert, I think you're
just shocked that you just
were so amazing right there.
Another guy that has no business
doing that type of stuff,
and you just kicked
its butt, buddy.
Good job.
All right. You hang out
for a bit. We're gonna
go on to another stunt.
You come join up
with us later.
Come on, boys, girl.
Look, performing live is-
it's live.
There is no "let's take two"
on that, you know?
Especially doing
what you guys do,
there's definitely no take two.
Nitro!
I ain't feeling so good
right now.
All I need is 16,000 people
out there- "Yeah!"
Yeah!
- I'm gonna pick it up.
- [ Babbling ]
If you need to take two,
that means someone
probably got hurt.
[ Man ] Always told my boys
you gotta go like hell.
Gregg never went easy.
He always had to push
the envelope.
If Scott jumped a hundred feet,
he had to jump 1 1 0.
Maybe from that,
they got more and more
and more competitive.
So here's the deal-
I am the present
world record holder...
of the longest
and highest semi jump
in the world.
[ Horn Honking ]
Yeah!
[ Cheering ]
My older, fatter,
unskilled brother...
believes that he shall be
the world record holder...
after this day.
In 1 5 minutes,
I will be.
[ Engine Starts ]
♪ Great and tight
You're ready for flight ♪
♪ He wants it all right
Got it in his sight ♪
♪♪ [ Continues ]
[ Horn Honking ]
♪ He's looking all right,
but will he jump ♪♪
[ Loud Crashing ]
Scott! Scott, you okay?
I'm all right.
Look at the truck!
lt is destroyed!
- Holy- [ Bleeps ]
- You full-out endoed a semi.
That's so cool.
lt doesn't count
unless you land on wheels.
Good job though.
That was fun.
You got issues.
Yeah!
We're here
at this beautiful lake.
It's a glorious day.
You got your
Red Bull rocking.
They've got this
amazing jump setup.
We've got tons
of Astroglide.
By "amazing jump setup"
you mean scary ramp of death...
into water filled with rocks-
cool, awesome.
This is Nitro Circus.
I've seen you land on your head
from 30 feet up with
a street bike on top of you.
Oh!
Yeah, and that didn't
work out too good.
This has gotta work out
a lot better then.
It's a win-win for you.
You hang on-
Why do you guys
always say win-win...
when I always
f'ing lose?
You've tried this out?
Like, Jer's chopper out there-
you've got it all modified?
Well, kinda. I tell you,
if he hits it hard,
you're going for a ride.
I'm just telling you guys,
you're goin' for a ride if he
cranks on that throttle, so-
Well, the guys said they
wanted a little horsepower
to pull the rope,
so we brought in
our friend The Colonel
to give us a little help.
You think this is really
what they asked for?
No.
[ Engine Revving ]
Whoo!
[ Jolene ]
This does not look safe at all.
No, you're good.
Don't worry about it.
lt may possibly be
the most redneck contraption
we've come up with.
Crum, I'm about to give you
1 ,200 c.c.'s of freedom.
[ Shouting ]
[ Chattering ]
That was cool!
You all right?
[ Screaming ]
Ow!
Ow! That's what
that felt like!
Dude, if you saw it
from where I was standing-
No, like the side view.
What happened?
Violent. He came in,
picked up that takeoff,
smacked his face dead on his-
like, the lip.
And then he, like- it was-
[ Laughing ]
He was still holding on.
And violently flung himself
lifelessly-
[ Laughing ]
He was just-
lt didn't look real.
There wasn't enough lube.
lt was all dried out.
I got serious burn marks
down my whole entire chest.
[ Laughing ]
No, it was peeling off me,
and I was, like,
"I'm not lettin' go."
I would suggest
wearing protection.
lt started burning.
I was like, "Oh, it's
pulling my skin off.
I can't let go.
It's pulling my skin off.
[ Bleeps ] I gotta hang on."
Boom! I'm like,
"Oh, I'm gonna flip and land."
Then, "I'm still in the air."
I'm so proud of you.
I... just wanted to show you
what glory looks like.
Good job.
Dude, your stomach
is horrible.
lt hurts, dude.
Does anybody have
any aloe vera?
With my experience
and your smart mouth,
we're the best team
to have on safety boat.
Totally.
Worst scenario you can get
is a burned stomach...
from not having enough lube
on the ramp.
Hey, today they started
selling six-packs of awesome.
Parks Bonifay is up next.
Wait, wait, wait.
Sharks Bonifay.
Sorry. Sharks Bonifay
is up next.
[ Narrator ]
Parks Bonifay.
Professional wakeboarder,
who hit the zenith
of his career...
at the tender age
of six months...
when he became
the youngest person on earth
to water-ski.
[ Crowd ]
Oh!
His career has gone downhill
ever since.
[ Engine Revving ]
There it goes!
[ Whooping ]
Oh!
Yeah!
Whoo!
That was so nice!
Oh, my God.
He's floating.
He's breathing.
That was huge!
That was gigantisaurus.
Hey! That was
75 miles an hour,
according to
the Nitro speedometer!
Travis is saying
I went 75?
According to
the speedometer.
I did one, and I was like,
"All right, enough air
to do two."
Do two.
So I go into two
and I come out of two.
And I'm still like
25, 30 feet high up there.
You did like a half
at that point.
Then I was like,
"Do I go three
or just try to dive?"
I think I tried to dive.
That's why my wrist hurts.
That's what happens
when 1 86 pounds of awesome
hits the water at-
Feels like
I tore my uterus.
You're going third gear
on this one. Or second.
You're going third.
Third.
Just basically ejecting
into the stratosphere.
Yeah.
ls that the plan?
If anybody can do it,
it's you, Special Greg,
with your special powers,
special muscles.
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh, my God.
♪♪ [ Rock ]
♪ She's the one
you've been dreaming of♪
Yes! Special!
It's just fun working
with a bunch of amazing
athletes, you know?
That's what
it's all about.
[ Greg ] I think, uh,
that in the heart of
every single one of us,
there's an athlete in there
that just wants to smile
and have fun every day.
You know?
Well spoken, Greg.
It's really what
it's all about, I think.
♪ Makin' love ♪♪
What we need to get is-
Tommy has got to get
his sissy, fat,
doin'-nothin',
white-card, flag-polin'
butt off of there.
[ Man ]
Tell us what
you really think.
Yeah. I was holdin'
back a little.
I- I been talkin' to him.
He is so terrified of this.
And this is a layup.
If Tommy doesn't do this-
[ Man ]
Hey! Who's going first?
I don't know what to say.
Like, I don't know if he
should be on the show anymore.
I mean, I love Tommy
as much as anybody,
but you gotta do something
at some point, right, Crum?
[ Crum ]
Unfortunately, you're right.
He is the fat, funny guy.
He's hilarious.
But we still need him
to launch.
Get up there and get
Tommy into it, Roner.
I'm gonna go pepper Tommy.
[ Erik ]
I like to be talked into-
There's lots of times
I don't want to do it,
and people talk me into it
and I'm grateful they did.
[ Man ]
You're doing it
for you, right, Tom?
Give it
a firm grip.
Get this ankle.
Tommy, I cannot tell you
how proud of you I am.
He's a big man.
Tommy, this is
the thing, dude.
You're scared and
you're going anyway.
That's awesome.
That's what
it's about, buddy.
That's what it's about.
This is why Streetbike Tommy
is Streetbike Tommy.
Tommy,
you're scared?
[ Bleeping ]
Stay loose, Tommy.
Nice and relaxed.
Confidence.
[ Engine Revving ]
♪ When I was young,
I used to do some things ♪
You got it, Tommy.
Make a lot of noise
for the, um, acoustics.
[ Whooping ]
[ Screaming ]
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪♪
[ Cheering ]
- That was a big dive.
That was-
- Hell!
[ Groans ]
lt hurts so bad.
Somebody get me.
You all right?
Hell!
I'll float you back.
[ Groaning ]
Hell!
[ Bleeping ]
[ Groaning ]
Hell!
Hold on. What hurts, Tommy?
[ Groaning ]
What hurts?
My- [ Bleeps ]- head, dude!
Everybody that made me
do that, thank you.
[ All Cheering ]
[ Whooping, Cheering ]
We had to talk Tommy
into every part of that.
I'm like, "Tommy, I swear,
I'll just roll onto
second gear.
Just nice and easy."
As soon as he got going,
I was, like-
[ Imitating
Revving Engine ]
And he hit the pop.
He got his pop in.
He had a lot of weight
goin' up.
I know.
He had suspension.
As everything compressed,
it went- Whoosh!
lt was like
Kung Fu Panda.
[ Laughter ]
[ Travis ]
That was awesome.
Tommy, I'm proud of you.
♪ When I was young,
I used to do some things ♪
♪ People would say
that I'm insane ♪♪
Our job is cool.
Right?
Thank you.
And you go home today
with that glow...
instead of going home
without trying.
I'm not saying-
Here's the thing.
Yes, it is better
than drywall.
But let me
tell you something.
My job's good.
Your job is good,
and you're good at it.
It's not just
better than drywall.
I mean, my job's good.
I love it, Tommy.
I love when you're this happy.
Look at the moment.
Look at the glorious
moment right now.
I'm getting
a little glazed over.
Yeah.
I'm not gonna lie.
That was stressful.
You're gonna cry now.
Oh, look at
the big teddy bear.
I love you, buddy.
I don't like water.
Yeah, I understand.
Or heights or speed-
lt all scares me.
Good job, bud.
Yeah.
Let's go get
that Kobe steak.
Yeah, let's do that.
And a girl.
Ah! lt hurts so good.
[ Laughing ]
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, boy!
God has
a mighty fist.
Yeah.
Wow. Now this-
Always properly lube.
Ow! God!
Oh, don't do that.
Don't do that.
It's so tender.
Streetbike Tommy- legit.
That dude is legit.
Everybody knows,
when he launched
the bike over the foam pit-
[ Engine Revving ]
[ Loud Thud ]
Oh- [ Bleeps ]
No concussion?
You feel everything?
Uh-
Just willing to do
anything not to work.
Like, "I don't want
to have a job.
I just want to, like,
'keep the party going'
for life."
He knows he's gonna get hurt
whatever he gets on.
It's, like, gravity
is not kind to Tommy.
You're like, "Dude,
what else can this guy do?"
You know, why is it
when I show up to set...
and my name
is on the roster-
When I show up,
you guys got something
just completely out of hand.
You think just 'cause
you slapped a couple
of funny stickers on it,
that I'm gonna go all punk?
What happened
to the phone call
last night...
where I was, like,
"Tommy, do you want
to jump a boat?"...
and you're, like,
"Hell, yeah, I want
to jump a boat"?
That wasn't me.
lt was you.
I have a text
as well.
That was some other fat guy
using my phone.
Tommy, you're always
talking about...
as long as it's got
horsepower in the stunt,
you're good.
Well, that's before I need
to talk to the F.A.A....
for a boat-airplane
license.
[ Laughs ]
Captain Awesome,
let's turn up the heat
and make this thing go.
This is your moment to shine.
Let's do this.
Glad you're so psyched
on it, Tommy.
Let's go.
Put this thing
in the water.
[ Engine Roaring ]
[ Travis ]
lt is so windy.
It's like the worst
conditions imaginable.
We got whitecaps
breaking over here.
I've never seen him so nervous.
He has not talked at all today.
We have a jump-
Everyone, in my opinion,
might be a little too close.
But he is coming,
and I gotta go watch this.
That's so rough!
[ Whooping,
Cheering ]
Get back!
Everybody back!
Go get him. Get him.
[ Whooping, Shouting ]
Grab him!
Get him, get him,
get him!
[ Cheering ]
Whoo!
- Looks like your beard-
It's a little singed.
- ls my beard good?
[ Jolene ]
It's safe. It's safe.
There's no singes, bro.
Came out clean.
Then we're good.
[ All Laughing ]
This is the ramp setup
for Vegas, so test it out.
See if it works.
Whoa!
[ All Groan ]
Oh!
That looked painful.
How's your head,
Special?
How's your legs?
♪♪ [ Country ]
♪ I quit my job
on a Friday afternoon ♪
We are here today
to play Nitro Golf.
This is a hole-in-one
contest.
He with the most flair
flying through the air...
in getting a hole in one
wins.
Hands in!
I'll give you three today.
One, two, three!
Nitro!
- Nitro Golf, round one.
- Fore!
Come on, Spesh!
[ Bleeps ]
[ All Groan ]
Okay, not so bad
on the first round there.
That's a mulligan.
I'm goin' again.
[ Greg ]
Dusty's gonna get this.
I'm scared right now.
Get in there!
[ Cheering, Whooping ]
That's a hole in one!
Hole in one!
Dude, this is
so much fun.
[ Jolene ]
Your turn, Special.
It's possible.
Now give us
some flair.
♪ Crawl down in a hole ♪
♪ Never goin' back ♪
♪ Flyin' so high- ♪♪
As bad as that went,
it went really well.
Can we not have to
do that anymore?
That was awesome.
I couldn't figure out
how to get the bike straight.
As I came to land,
I was-
All I'm saying is I think
he got the long-ball contest
on that one.
Push, push!
Whoo-hoo!
[ All Groan ]
He's out.
Really?
I- I didn't have
enough club.
You bastard.
[ All Laughing ]
I needed more club.
Where's my caddy?
Super nervous,
just so you know.
Oh. This could be really good
or really bad.
One more time.
[ Cheering ]
[ Whooping ]
Yeah! Oh, man!
Oh, man!
I'm in the ball!
Yeah! I'm in the ball!
Nitro Golf rules!
[ Shouting, Cheering ]
He goes in the ball!
I got in the ball!
Holy crap!
The winner of the first
inaugural Nitro Golf-
Special Greg!
I was in the ball.
All right,
so a few years back,
I rolled seven and
three-quarter times
in a rally race.
Travis's crash that he had
in Colorado years ago...
was one of the biggest crashes
actually caught on film
in the world of rally.
- Nitro live!
- I'm fine.
How are you?
Holy- [ Bleeps ]
That was a hell
of a ride.
Whoo-hoo!
Today, Gregg Godfrey's gonna
take a crappy Mustang,
driving as fast as it'll go,
hitting this ramp...
and seeing how many times
he can roll the car.
I can't wait to watch.
For Gregg to take that on,
like, "Hey, I'm gonna go
take what you did...
and just try and beat you"...
is actually
a really funny concept.
I give him a lot of credit
for the balls that it takes...
to actually go out
and try and do that.
[ Jeremy ]
What do you think his odds are
of getting your record?
I see this
possibly going good.
And by good,
I mean horribly bad.
I'd hit the ramp
at 1 1 0.
Faster's better.
More speed.
Can't go wrong
with more speed.
No, you can't.
Who said that?
What rule is that?
It's written.
Look it up.
It's in the Rule of Speed?
It's in the dictionary.
[ Groans ]
I'm gonna miss you guys.
[ Laughing ]
Right now, what we're doing
is we're sittin' on set...
waiting for Gregg Godfrey
to have his balls drop...
somewhere from his throat
to at least the mid part
of his stomach, um,
to turn into ovaries-
And then eventually balls.
- So he can actually hit this
jump to try to beat my record.
- [ Jolene ] Ovaries?
Where I didn't
intentionally crash,
and he's intentionally crashing.
- [ Tires Screeching,
Engine Revving ]
- Uh-oh. Here we go.
Wow! He is hauling
the mail!
[ Gregg ]
This is such a bad idea.
What is he thinking?
This has suddenly got
way cooler!
Why is he doing this?
Now I know why
he's taking so long.
[ Jolene ]
That's good.
Oh, you gotta be
crapping yourself,
but that looks good.
You're not
gonna catch air.
You're gonna tumble.
It's gonna be good.
I'm good. I'm gonna go-
Pull me in, and we'll go.
Gregg, you're gonna be good.
This is gonna be fun, man.
Enjoy it.
Yeah, this is gonna
be fun- for us.
I was gonna say,
it's gonna be
a lot of fun for us.
When I said
that is gonna be fun,
that is not gonna be fun.
What kind of a friend are you?
He's gonna get
his- [ Bleeps ]- whipped.
[ Engine Revving ]
[ Travis ] lt looks really fast,
and it's really scary,
and I would never, ever,
ever intentionally flip
at that speed.
Having said that, if he
wants to win, he's gonna
have to go faster.
♪ I'm sailing away♪
♪ Set an open course
for the virgin sea ♪
I love how scared
Godfrey is.
He is totally
out of his mind
over this thing.
♪ 'Cause I've ♪
♪ Got to be free ♪
♪ Free to face the life ♪
♪ That's ahead of me ♪
He's so nervous.
I've never seen this
out of him.
♪ And I'll try♪
♪ Oh, Lord, I'll try♪
[ Band ]
♪ To carry on ♪
[ Engine Starts, Revs ]
♪♪ [ Rock ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Gregg ]
This is really awesome.
- Oh, my God.
- He's going really,
really, really fast.
♪ A gathering of angels ♪
Go, go, go, go, go,
go, go, go!
♪ Appeared above my head ♪
♪ They sang to me
this song of hope ♪
♪ Listen to what they said ♪
♪ They said, Come sail away
Come sail away♪
♪ Come sail away
with me, lads ♪
Come sail away♪
♪ Come sail away with me ♪
♪ Come sail away
Come sail away♪
♪ Come sail away with me ♪♪
[ Engine Revving ]
[ Loud Thud ]
[ Thudding, Crashing ]
[ Groans ]
Boy, that was violent.
[ Travis ]
That is awesome!
Are you alive?
Yeah, I'm not hurt.
Yeah?
[ Laughs ]
You got such good air
at that last jump, man.
You came off that ramp
so fast.
Then you took off,
and it landed.
We're like, "Oh!"
Didn't I just land
on the wheels?
No, it landed on the roof.
I didn't think it was
gonna roll at first.
Then it started
rolling so fast,
and you were flying.
[ Jolene ]
Look at how much it spins
before it caught too.
Wow!
[ Erik ] Godfrey, you are a nut.
An absolute nut.
Why would you
sign up for that?
Now you tell him.
No, I wouldn't have
signed up for it.
[ Jolene ] Your shoulder's
hurting a little?
Stand on that car.
Claim it!
[ All Cheering, Shouting ]
Yeah, Gregg!
[ All Whooping,
Laughing ]
Oh, that was fun.
I'm glad
you're alive, dude.
[ Erik ]
ls that the battery?
Yeah, that's the battery.
[ Laughing ]
As you can see,
the battery is just toast.
lt just launched-
Oh, incredible.
I'm speechless.
I have no words
to describe this.
That's-
That scared me.
Who does that?
[ Chattering ]
Who says I'm gonna try
to roll a car as many times
as I possibly can?
- What an idiot.
- Did we get a count
on the rolls yet?
His entire goal was to beat
seven and three-quarters.
The official count? Seven!
Not that I'm excited,
but I kinda won.
I mean, I lost, but I won,
depending on which way
you want to put that.
Sorry, Gregg.
Better luck next time, champ.
Well, Jim and Crum,
you have been specially
chosen for this stunt.
I'm lying. Nobody else
wanted to do it.
[ Laughing ]
So it's up to you guys.
Godspeed.
We are the last
remaining
stunt meat.
Fly straight.
I got five dollars
that Jim gets closer.
Jim will go up, stall,
ditch it.
Crum will go up, stall,
ride it all the way down
to a back flop,
getting smushed.
I don't think you're
far off right there.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Engine Revving ]
He's coming!
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- Way too fast.
He's goin' way, way, way-
No, no, no!
No!
- [ Cheering, Whooping ]
- Yeah, Jim!
I pinned all the way there,
and I had to do a couple
of corrections on the way.
"Oh, I'm going way,
way too fast...
and I don't know
how to slow down."
♪ No, nobody knows
where I'm gonna be ♪
♪ Soakin' up the sunshine ♪
♪ Livin' so free ♪
♪ Yeah, oh ♪♪
- [ On Walkie-talkie ] Jake?
- One second, Crum.
You got all the things in place
to go ahead and do this right
the second time. Good luck.
[ Crum ] Why do I not
feel as confident
as you, Travis?
[ Narrator ]
Crum.
He's a part-time handyman,
and he doesn't give a-
[ Bleeps ]
[ High-pitched Voice ]
Hi, boys.
He's got just enough talent
to turn girls' heads,
but not enough
to seal the deal.
[ Ducks Quacking ]
He's hoping the live show
will change that.
- ♪ Yeah ♪
- [ Engine Revving ]
- [ All Shouting ]
- Yeah, Crum!
[ All Chattering ]
[ Laughing, Shouting ]
♪ No, no ♪
♪ Girl, I don't know you ♪
[ Booing ]
♪ One, two, three, four, five ♪♪
Crum, you are the first person
on Nitro Circus history...
to bail out of something
once you've started at it.
You're only as good
as your last stunt.
Actually the most
disappointing thing
in my life was just now.
It's okay.
I'm disappointed
in myself.
I let my friends down,
and I let myself down.
You didn't let me down.
You owe me three bucks,
dude.
You don't deserve
to be here!
Jim's the champion!
[ All Cheering ]
Crum, the good news is
you get to try this again.
The bad news is
the rest of the crew
has no faith in you.
They're driving away
right now.
They just left you.
- What?
- [ Laughing ]
Sometimes you get
a second chance in life,
and you gotta take it.
And your friends
ain't there
to watch you.
Who needs friends
when you got a second chance?
♪♪ [ Punk ]
♪♪ [ Stops ]
[ Laughing ]
Hey, it's not in the water.
It's not in the water.
It's not-
The motor died!
The motor died.
[ Laughter ]
Halfway across the water,
it goes-
[ Imitates Sputtering ]
And I was, like,
"It's just not my day."
Oh, that's
just embarrassing.
[ Laughing ]
[ Sighs ]
[ High-pitched Voice ]
Hi. I'm Wheelz,
and I'm jumping
this big-ass ramp
on my wheelchair.
Trying to harness the Nitro cast
before a show or stunt...
is pretty much like trying
to herd a thousand...
clinically insane
stray cats.
Except they all have
skateboards and motorcycles,
and they're all faster than me.
Five minutes!
Go out there
in five minutes!
No, I got fans.
Streetbike Tommy.
Best- Best of
the Nitro crew.
[ Laughing ]
We've had to leave the country
on many occasions...
to get the kind of footage
that's gonna make people flock
to see this movie.
You know
that there was no strings.
There was no special effects.
There was no green screen.
There was no nothing
to say...
that they didn't
actually do it.
And that's what
you guys are doing.
You're just actually
doing it and saying,
"All right. Watch."
[ Erik ]
We just arrived
in Panama City,
and we're gonna
start the day off...
with Jim trying
to hydro-skim across
the Nitro City pool.
In true Nitro fashion,
it's gonna be either
really amazing...
of Jim's gonna eat-
[ Bleeps ]
I'm ready for either one.
I call anything
over the baby pool good.
You said that, right?
Officially?
That anything
over the baby pool is mint.
Yeah.
If you and your bike
make it over the baby pool,
I don't have to do this.
Clear.
Yes!
I have never selfishly hoped
that someone has made it...
as bad as I hope
you make this.
This is probably
the gnarliest hydro-skim
I've ever actually seen.
So, good luck.
Please make it
so I don't have to do it.
Hey. Happy trails.
Nice knowing you.
So he's gonna come
from over there,
through the hotel
and across the grass,
and he's gonna drop
eight, 1 0 inches
onto the pool.
And then he's gonna jump
the little pool,
land on the grass.
Hopefully the bike's
underneath him.
[ Tommy ] Right.
And then over the rocks,
into the ocean
and ride away?
Right.
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Engine Revving ]
Go, go, go, go,
go, go, go, go!
Go, Jim!
[ Shouting, Whooping ]
Are you okay?
Am I hurt?
You're okay!
[ Laughing ]
No good.
[ All Chattering ]
You needed to go faster.
That went as bad
as it could've gone.
Oh, my gosh.
This little blue piece
right here saved his life.
Had that not been here,
it would've been a back
or neck cracker on this.
Whoever came up
with that idea,
Jim owes them
a thousand handshakes.
♪ Stuck in the mud ♪
♪ With my best shoes on now ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪♪
Well, apparently Travis
is going to gear up
right now,
'cause that was
technically a fumble.
I actually don't want
Travis doing this.
I agree with you, but
I think he can do it.
That's the thing.
I think Trav can
skim through here
and get a touchdown.
If he does what Jim did,
Trav's going to the hospital.
If Trav dittos what Jim did-
busted shoulder, concussion.
Trav's head cannot-
He can't take it,
and his shoulder will buckle.
Jim didn't make the touchdown.
He didn't make the field goal.
Unfortunately, he didn't even
make the two-point conversion.
On his last drive,
he got the turnover.
And, uh, now it's my turn.
He didn't have enough speed
on a 450, and I'm gonna
try it on a 250.
This is the part of the show
where I crash, and then
Travis goes back,
"Oh, that's so easy."
He does it, no problem.
I'm gonna go have a beer.
I'm not even gonna watch him.
Ronald McDonald's
on his bike.
God, does he look stupid.
Why's he wearing
a diaper?
Aw- [ Bleeps ]
I am nervous.
[ All Cheering, Whooping ]
- Way to go!
- I don't know what to say.
I can't believe it!
[ Shrieks ]
- Oh, my God!
- How the hell
did he do that?
I don't even know
how he hung on
to that.
He's such a douche.
I hate him.
He's way too good at things.
Way too good.
That speed was intense.
[ Erik ]
I hope he gets stung
by jellyfish right now.
Honestly.
You gotta give it
to Jim though.
"A"- going first.
"B"- on a bike that
weighed twice as much
as my bike weighed.
And "C"- he didn't have
all the goofy-looking
hockey pads.
He just frickin'
pinned it.
And he's a durable
son of a gun,
'cause he landed
flat on his face.
And he's still alive.
Thank you, Jim, again.
I think, a lot of times,
you just never expect
the worst-case scenario.
Hey, Tommy. Ever since
I've seen this stunt
in an old spy movie,
I've wanted
a piece of it.
Where'd you get
your instructions?
The Internet.
[ Laughing ]
We're totally safe.
They don't have fear.
They just don't-
They're scared of stuff,
but, in their minds,
they only think
about making it.
They never think of
what's gonna happen
if they don't.
When it comes to something
like flipping that car,
what you guys are doing
is mega sketchy.
[ Erik ]
Yeah, I know.
If you guys land
on your wheels,
I'll go nuts.
I don't think you're
going to though.
Be safe.
♪ We're the two dumbest people
in this car right now♪
♪ Two dumbest people
in this car right now♪♪
[ Laughs ]
My heart's nervous
for them!
I'm nervous as-
[ Bleeps ]- right now.
- [ Engine Starts, Revs ]
- Here we go!
Yeah!
Oh, boy.
Moment of truth.
♪ What's mine is mine
Don't come for free ♪
♪ Everything you want
Gonna take it from me ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Whoa, yeah ♪
♪ Right about now ♪
Watch this, watch this!
Here it goes!
Oh, no!
[ Echoing ]
Oh, no! Oh, no!
[ Tommy Groaning ]
Jim, you all right?
Jim!
[ All Shouting ]
[ Jolene ]
Jim, are you okay?
[ Shouting ]
Are you okay?
Jim!
[ Siren Wailing ]
Jim, we're coming.
Stay still, buddy.
We need to cut him
out of this car.
Let's bring him
to the ground here.
Then we'll strap him in.
There's something
possibly with his neck,
so we gotta be really
gentle as possible,
okay?
[ Jeremy ]
We're taking care of you, pal.
You're gonna be all right.
We're getting you
to the hospital.
You're all set.
- We need to check you out.
- Nice work, everybody.
The difficult part for-
for any athlete is that,
you know, you have a crash,
if you're scared of that stuff
and you think about it-
When that deal happened
out there with Jim,
we were all scared.
And everybody
was worried about him.
[ Man ]
He's hurt.
He's really hurt.
He's in a situation that most
of us could be in and dread.
Even when it does go wrong,
these guys are mentally
so strong.
[ Dick Godfrey ]
You know, when it goes bad,
it goes bad.
There's nothin'
you can do about it.
When you fall down,
you gotta get up...
and brush the dust off
and go for it again.
You can't quit.
[ Erik ]
Good morning, Panama.
Yet another day
of Nitro Circus,
and we are gap jumping
tricycles and bikes
over 400-foot buildings.
I just remember
the last shoot
that we did...
when the Big Wheels
fell apart.
The first guy
that went down,
the tire fell off.
The second guy that went down,
the handlebars went
all the way down.
Then Dusty went down,
and the bicycle went down.
We had a flat tire.
[ Man ]
We've come a long way
since then.
That was five days ago.
Oh, yeah.
This is so stupid.
God, this was such
a better idea on paper.
Everyone's a little worried
about safety.
Jeremy and I decided
we'd check and see...
what the worst-case scenario
might look like...
just to put
everyone's mind at ease.
Bombs away!
[ Jeremy ]
And launch her.
Oh, God.
Holy- [ Bleeps ]
Oh, my-
[ Laughing ]
Oh, my God!
[ Laughing, Murmurs ]
Seems perfectly safe
if anything goes wrong.
Why is it everything
that we do that's deadly...
also has to be sketchy?
You'd think, if it's deadly,
it would be a perfect setup,
but it's not.
It's always stupid.
All right, Spesh.
Come help me.
We all concur
that he is so scared
of not making the gap-
which, oh, granted,
that's death-
that he's gonna
go too far.
In which case, that's
just a broken back.
Um, so he's getting a push
by Special Greg.
That's a long way down.
I hope we make it.
All right, Erik.
Three, two, one.
[ Bleeps ]
[ Cheering, Whooping ]
Hold on, hold on.
You okay?
You all right?
That was the biggest
jump ever.
Oh, my God.
Oh, man.
That was so high
and so far.
- Fill it up again.
- [ Laughing ]
If you're gonna flip,
then just go ahead
and flip it.
If you're not gonna flip,
then we'll roshambo it.
I'd rather see me crash
than you crash.
No, we're gonna land this.
I'd rather see me land
than you land.
So we'll roshambo
for who gets the privilege.
I'm already over here.
All right. Well, just jump
and meet me over here.
We'll have a cocktail later.
All right.
Good luck.
That's what you call
reverse psychology.
I definitely
did not wanna flip.
I'm scared- [ Bleeps ]-
even trying to jump.
That worked.
That worked great.
Couldn't have asked
for anything better.
Thanks, Greg.
So the plan is to go
twice as high
and twice as far.
ls that the plan?
That'll do better
for you.
That'll work, right?
All right.
Love you guys.
Love you, pal.
[ Cheering, Whooping ]
All right. [ Bleeps ]
Line it up.
I am covered
head to toe.
You look like
a homemade action figure.
[ Laughing ]
All right, well, Rubberneck,
you accidentally
went too far...
and almost got
all the way
in the boxes.
So, Jim, let's
get all the way
to the boxes.
Give me a push.
I mean a push.
All right.
I can tell
Travis is nervous.
Because whenever he gets
nervous, he's, like-
[ Imitating Chattering ]
Right.
[ Laughing ]
I just hear him
chirping up there
like a bird.
You got him, Jim?
Let me get a nice
little spot right here.
You ready?
Good push.
One, two, three!
That was- [ Bleeps ]
♪♪ [ Rock ]
♪ It's dangerous ♪
♪♪ [ Continues, Indistinct ]
♪ Oh, it's dangerous ♪
Oh! You're good!
Hey! What kind of push
was that?
Maybe if you weren't wearing
80 pounds in pads,
I could push you.
Actually, that's
probably a good point.
♪ You're dangerous ♪
♪ Well, I'm steppin' out
tonight ♪♪
I didn't think it was gonna be-
Actually, I knew it was
gonna be that scary.
I was just fooling myself
thinking that maybe
it wouldn't get done.
But be careful
what you ask for,
'cause Nitro Circus will
give you the opportunity
to do it.
We're dream makers.
What can I tell you?
Making dreams
and nightmares come true.
Mostly nightmares.
[ Travis ]
Ready or not,
here we come, Vegas.
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Dyrdek ]
lt is one thing
to watch it on television,
but live and in person,
it is like seeing a U.F.O.
You can never
fully appreciate it
until you see it live.
[ Crowd Cheering, Muffled ]
We're a couple minutes
from showtime.
And I've never been
so nervous in all my life.
[ Girl ]
Go, Travis!
Travis! Travis!
Travis!
I had no idea what the hell
I was even showing up to.
I just walked in the arena,
and it was packed.
- [ Crowd Roaring ]
- One minute! One minute!
[ Dyrdek ]
The Nitro Circus
is like art.
What all these guys
are doing now,
people aren't going
to be doing in the future.
[ Brooks ]
You guys keep getting doors
slammed in your face...
because everyone feels like
someone's gonna die
doing these stunts.
The fact that so many people
did say no...
makes me believe
even more strongly
that this is a great idea.
It's been a long road
coming here.
Let's prove to the world
that we can do this.
We have 1 0 seconds
to start.
- One, two, three!
- Nitro!
[ Crowd Shouting, Chanting ]
Nitro! Nitro! Nitro!
[ Travis ] People always
said that Nitro Circus
couldn't work as a live show.
But with this much passion-
[ Kids Shouting ]
it was always gonna work.
[ Robson On P.A. ]
Are you kidding me?
You have just seen history,
Las Vegas!
♪ We waited together
for the cowards to come ♪
♪ Outgunned and outnumbered,
but we wouldn't run ♪
♪ No mercy, no quarter
They'll pay for their sins ♪
♪ Now lower the cannons
The battle begins ♪
♪ We waited together
for the cowards to come ♪
♪ Outgunned and outnumbered,
but we wouldn't run ♪
♪ No mercy, no quarter
They'll pay for their sins ♪
♪ Now lower the cannons
The battle begins ♪
[ Robson ]
A Christ Air Backflip!
Oh, my God!
I've never seen this!
♪ We waited together
for the cowards to come ♪
♪ Outgunned and outnumbered,
but we wouldn't run ♪
♪ No mercy, no quarter
They'll pay for their sins ♪
♪ Now lower the cannons
The battle begins ♪
♪ We waited together
for the cowards to come ♪
♪ Outgunned and outnumbered,
but we wouldn't run ♪
♪ No mercy, no quarter
They'll pay for their sins ♪
♪ Now lower the cannons
The battle begins ♪
♪ The battle begins ♪♪
[ Crowd Cheering ]
Will you please get loud!
Will you please get vocal!
Get ready to be inspired!
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
Go, Aaron!
Make some noise for
Aaron "Wheelz" Fotheringham!
[ Travis ]
Out of all the members
of Nitro Circus,
I mean, Wheelz really embodies
everything that we stand for.
The desire to push
his own personal limits
is above and beyond.
And by doing so,
he inspires others
to live life to the fullest.
I'm on my wheelchair,
not in it.
Being part of Nitro Circus
is a great opportunity...
to be able to show people
that nothing's impossible.
[ Crowd Roaring ]
[ Brooks ]
They are absolutely grown kids
living their dream,
doing exactly
what they want to do...
in a way that no one's
done it before.
♪♪ [ Irish: Traditional ]
♪♪ [ Irish: Punk ]
♪ She had excuses
and she chose to use them ♪
♪ She was the victim
of unspeakable abuses ♪
♪ Her husband was violent,
malicious and distant ♪
♪ Her kids now belong to
the state of Massachusetts ♪
♪ They've been taken away ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Billy was a bright one
Tommy's off his head ♪
♪ Mother loved them both
the same ♪
♪ At least
that's what she said ♪
♪ I don't predict the future
I don't care about the past ♪
♪ Send them both to D.S.S.
Now you've had your chance ♪
♪ The poison stole your babies
The judges took your rights ♪
♪ You can have your children
or the night ♪
♪ I suppose you've been a victim
I suspect you may have lied ♪
♪ Have you lost all ambition?
Won't you give this thing
a try? ♪
♪ If you can't and you fail,
you won't be the only loser♪
♪ These kids
don't stand a chance ♪
♪ With you in their future ♪
♪ They've been taken away ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Billy was a bright one
Tommy's off his head ♪
♪ Mother loved them both
the same ♪
♪ At least
that's what she said ♪
♪ I don't predict the future
I don't care about the past ♪
♪ Send them both to D.S.S.
Now you've had your chance ♪
♪ The poison stole your babies
The judges took your rights ♪
♪ You can have your children
or the night ♪
♪ The poison stole your babies
The judges took your rights ♪
♪ You can have your children
or the night ♪
♪ Billy was a bright one
Tommy's off his head ♪
♪ Mother loved them both
the same ♪
♪ At least
that's what she said ♪
♪ I don't predict the future
I don't care about the past ♪
♪ Send them both to D.S.S.
Now you've had your chance ♪
♪ The poison stole your babies
The judges took your rights ♪
♪ You can have your children
or the night ♪♪
♪♪ [ Ends ]
♪ I'm lookin' back
down the road ♪
♪ The story has been told ♪
♪ And I don't know
how we ever made it ♪
♪ We ever made it home ♪
♪ Some say we'll never
win the war♪
♪ We're just knockin'
on Death's door♪
♪ But we smile and reply ♪
♪ At least we're livin'
before we die ♪
♪ We faced the trials
along the way ♪
♪ Paid our dues
and made our names ♪
♪ I can tell
your smoke is clearing ♪
♪ For the heroes of the day♪
♪ These roads,
we pave them all in gold ♪
♪ Every chapter must unfold ♪
♪ We're never scared
to fly♪
♪ At least we're livin'
before we die ♪
before we die ♪♪