# Well, you're dirty and sweet #
# Clad in black, don't look back,
and I love you #
# You're dirty and sweet,
oh yeah #
# Well, you're slim and you're weak #
# You got the teeth
of the hydra upon you #
# You're dirty, sweet
and you're my girl #
# Get it on, bang a gong #
# Get it on #
# Well, you're built like a car #
# You got a hubcap
diamond star halo #
# You're built like a car, oh yeah #
# Well, you're an untamed youth #
# That's the truth,
with your cloak full of eagles #
# You're dirty, sweet
and you're my girl #
# Get it on #
# Bang a gong, get it on #
# Bang a gong, get it on. #
Another Terry Leather
low-mileage gem.
Got your glad rags sorted out
for your wedding tomorrow?
Yeah, course, Terry.
New suit...
two buttons,
nine-inch bum flaps.
Nice.
Ingrid will like that.
So you're getting
married tomorrow, Ingrid?
I hope so.
Go on. Get off home.
Go and make yourself
look more beautiful
than you already are.
If that's possible.
Terry.
Promise you won't get Eddie
too legless tonight, will ya?
- At his stag do.
- Just going round to pub.
Couple of pints and a sing-song.
Fucking what are you
trying to do to me, eh?
I've got Jessell's money!
The problem is
it's tied up in these cars
and you wankers want
to trash the lot of them.
Mr. Jessell doesn't care
about your inventory.
Mr. Jessell wants to know
when he's getting paid.
Any day, I swear, Perky.
- What did you call me?
- I called you Perky, Perky.
Everyone calls you Perky
and him Pinky.
- Pinky and Perky?
- Yeah.
They're fucking cartoon pigs
on the telly.
What, people call us that
behind our backs?
Well, they're not gonna
say it to your face, are they?
Well, you just bloody did.
Yeah, well, you got me rattled.
You're very intimidating.
Don't make us come back again.
Not every customer's
a satisfied customer.
What are you doing
around here, Martine?
- What are you doing tonight?
- Tonight?
Tonight Eddie's stag do.
I'm taking him out for a drink.
- Why?
- I've got a proposition for you, Terry.
A proposition?
Can you meet me at the Player's Club
before you see the boys?
And I'll fill you in on the details.
Make it 9:00.
- Morning, Gale.
- Morning, Tim.
Top floor.
- Summoned by the gods?
- Something like that.
Get up to any mischief
this weekend?
Don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm a married man.
What do you think,
am I presentable?
Not sure about the tie, darling.
Oh, what's this?
Peace and love?
Too much of that nonsense,
we'll both be out of a job.
Michael Abdul Malik.
Calls himself "Michael X"
in homage to Malcolm X,
his American counterpart.
The pinko press
would have us believe
this... Michael X
is a crusading champion
of the poor and oppressed.
And the black Robin Hood
of Notting Hill.
The richer, whiter
and more famous,
the more they fawn over him.
The truth is,
he's a slum landlord,
a drug dealer
and a vicious pimp
who should have been
imprisoned years go.
Are you not charging
outrageous rent
to my brothers and sisters,
Mr. Brown?
I'm charging the same as your
slumlord friend, Lew Vogel.
10 quid a week is too much
for this shithole.
You know...
I always wanted to meet a white man
by the name of Brown.
You know what this is?
It is a slave collar,
and the white man
made my mothers and fathers
wear this to bend them
to his will.
Can I bend you
to my will, Mr. Brown?
He's your faithful dog
now, Michael.
Michael, I don't think we should
get our hopes up here.
Kidnapping, extortion,
assault on this man Brown here,
as well as your previous
problems with the law...
I mean, you could be looking
at 10 to 20 years for this.
I don't think so.
I am smarter
and better protected
than whitey thinks.
All rise.
It seems Michael X has managed
to keep himself out of jail
by threatening to release
damning photographs
of a certain royal personage.
Until we get our hands
on these snaps, the police can't move.
The public prosecutor
won't move
and the home office
doesn't want to know.
Has anyone actually
seen these photographs?
Yes. But at the moment
I'm not at the liberty
to say who
that person is.
We've had Michael X under
surveillance for quite a while.
He keeps a safe deposit box
at the Lloyds Bank in Marylebone.
We believe that's
where the photos are located.
Well, seems
straightforward enough.
I'll send a team into this bank
and take whatever he's got
in the safe deposit box.
That would have to be sanctioned
at the highest level.
- And that's not going to happen.
- Ah.
Do you see our problem?
There can be
no connection to 506.
So you want me
to come up with something
that avoids any
accountability for anyone.
We'd welcome suggestions, Tim.
And if it all goes pear-shaped,
I assume it's my ass on the line.
You're young and ambitious, Tim.
Chance to make
a name for yourself.
Thank you, sir.
Passengers arriving on flight 47...
Excuse me there, miss.
Can I have a word?
Yes.
- Where have you been?
- Morocco.
I'll have to check
your underwear.
Be my guest.
- We found what we were looking for.
- Found what?
What were you looking for?
Oh, Tim, thank God.
I'm in a spot of bother.
- What have you been up to?
- Nothing much. You?
I was in Morocco recently.
- Business or pleasure?
- Bit of both.
Drinks are on me.
So are we gonna sit here all night
making small talk?
I know you, Terry.
And I know your mates.
You've always been looking
for the big score,
the one that makes
sense of everything.
I have it for you.
- What?
- A bank.
A bank? As in rob?
How would you know
about a bank?
I've been seeing this guy,
runs his own business...
security systems.
Next month, they're installing
new alarms at a bank in Marylebone.
Seems like the trains have been
setting off the trembler alarms
in the vault
and they've had to turn them off.
So for a week or so,
they won't have any.
Now why would he tell you all this?
We were having a laugh about it.
"Imagine if half the villains in London
knew about this," he said.
And I thought, "I know
half the villains in London.
I grew up with some of them."
Look, me and my mates
might have been involved
with the odd bit of skullduggery,
but can you see us tooled up
taking on a bank like the James gang?
No, this isn't about waving
a water pistol at a cashier's head.
This is about getting into the basement
where the deposit boxes are...
hidden, secret wealth.
Money and jewels
that are safe to steal
'cause people won't report it.
Hold on, hold on.
We can't talk about this here.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity, Terry.
We can't pass it up.
I didn't expect this
from you tonight, Martine.
What did you expect?
I'll have to think about it.
Better get off to your stag party.
Thanks for the drink.
Eddie tells me his brother
invited you to the wedding.
- Are you going?
- I'll see you there.
- Can I get a Campari and soda, no ice?
- Yes, sir.
Thank you. Well, Tim sweetie,
what do you think?
Is he up for it?
Maybe.
Cheers, gorgeous.
- So, are you coming in?
- I don't know, it's late.
Do you need to run home
like a good little boy?
I guess I've got time.
What exactly do you do?
Bit of this, bit of that.
How did you and Hakim meet?
I met Hakim in Los Angeles last spring.
He was raising money
for a black Montessori school
and writing his life story.
And what an extraordinary
life it has been.
The book is called "From the Dead Level:
Malcolm X and Me."
I've read the manuscript.
Hakim is a poet,
the voice of the black soul.
Our friend is throwing a thing
next week to celebrate
the launch of brother Hakim's book.
And you are all invited.
Hakim, tell us more
about your book.
It's about being born
black in America.
Can any of you imagine what it is like
to be born a black man in this world?
Can any of you white women
imagine what it would be like
to bring a black baby
into this world?
Evening, sir.
Go on! Come on!
Yeah!
What are you thinking?
Why are we even
having this conversation?
We're not...
Here's your beer.
We are not bank robbers.
Maybe that's why we could
get away with it.
It's a bit daunting, isn't it?
Do you know
what scares me more?
Living and dying
with nothing to show for it.
Do you know how old Mozart was
when he composed his first minuet?
- No.
- Five.
Five... a fucking minuet.
And how would
you know that fact, Terry?
Because it's tattooed
on that stripper's ass, Kevin.
What the fuck's it matter how I know?
It's a fact and you're
missing the point, Kev.
What I'm trying to say is,
it's time we stop fucking about
and stop picking the shit
from under our fingernails.
Shtum, lads.
Coppers at 12:00.
Oh, what are you two
doing here personally?
I thought you were way past
being your own bagman, Gerry.
Your associate, Sonia Bern,
has raised prices
at that knocking shop of hers.
- 120 quid, up from 100.
- And your point?
A rising tide lifts all ships, mate.
I think we're owed some money.
- 'Cause even Sonia's can be raided.
- Yeah, you'd do that, wouldn't you?
You'd kill the goose
that lays your golden egg.
Well, that would be dumb,
wouldn't it?
But then again, everyone knows
coppers are dumb.
Well, you can do
one thing for me.
You can stop your colleagues
from having their
boys' night out in my clubs.
They're loud, they're lewd
and they expect free oral sex.
Do you know what?
That's disgusting.
I mean, most of them
have families.
We'll pass the word along.
Lew, you tell your
greedy little bobbies
to go and find
their perks elsewhere.
No one's gonna bother me.
My patrons could have a lot of these
bent coppers put out to pasture.
Well, I say spread the wealth around
and keep the peace.
Five quid a week extra.
That's all it's worth.
I'll pass it on.
Drysdale.
Urquhart.
Lord Drysdale,
can I offer you a drink
before your session?
Very kind of you, Sonia.
Good to see you.
As well, Urquhart, as well.
Good girl.
Tighter! Yes.
That's a good girl.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
You have been
a very naughty boy.
Louder. Louder!
- I can't.
- Come on.
Give him a snog, Ingrid!
Come on.
Nice work, Eddie!
Nice work.
- Hello.
- Saw you in a magazine the other day...
Campari ad on the beach.
- Nice.
- Must have been an old one.
- I'm not modeling anymore.
- I don't know why.
- Still a knockout.
- What are you doing these days, Dave?
Me? Bit of film work.
- Extra, you know.
- And you, Kevin?
You're still snapping, I see.
The wedding photos... no no.
It's just a favor for the family.
Fashion's my game,
fashion and passports.
And the odd snap
of a wayward husband.
- Thank you, Dave.
- So what's the verdict, boys?
We're interested.
First thing we should do
is take a look at the place,
suss it out,
maybe open a box of our own.
I've already done that.
We can go and have a look tomorrow.
Tomorrow it is.
- Heads up, lads.
- All right?
- She's adorable, your little one.
- She's off.
What a gorgeous flower girl
your eldest made.
- Thanks, Catherine.
- I do envy you.
- Kev, want to dance?
- Yeah, come on.
It was lovely to see you all. Ciao.
- Ciao.
- All right, Wen?
All right.
She envies me.
She being sarcastic?
I suppose what she meant was
money can't buy what we have.
Didn't you used to go out with her?
No, love,
that was Kevin.
He had this big thing for her.
- And you didn't?
- No.
Not like me and you...
love at first sight.
Oh yeah.
I remember that night. You was
with your mate Audrey at that disco.
Saw this gorgeous little bum
in a pencil skirt.
I thought, "I've got to have that."
But Audrey, she already had a bloke,
so I pulled you.
- Cheeky sod.
- Daddy!
Daddy, come and dance with me.
Come on, Dad!
- I'll just shoot it.
- Piss off, Kevin.
Good morning.
I'd like to access
my safe deposit box, please.
Martine Love.
L-O-V-E.
Certainly, madam.
Taxi!
- You're an actor, right?
- That's right.
I did a couple of films
for you, Mr. Vogel.
Yeah, right.
Where to, guv?
So what were these
films you were in?
- Forget about it.
- Go on.
Technically, it's what you call...
pornography.
- You're joking.
- No.
So you've been going round town
with a 12-inch mutton dagger
hanging down your pants?
That's nothing to be ashamed of.
Nice.
Fake. Got a posh party
at the weekend.
This is the one.
The lease is available.
Finally.
- How do I look? Good?
- Not your best, Dave.
Here we go.
So how come you got the inside dope
on this place, Martine?
She knows this bloke...
runs a security company.
Bloke? Is it serious?
Are you getting married?
He is married.
All the better ones are.
Here we go.
Marylebone Road and Baker Street.
On the corner here's the bank,
next door is the Chicken Inn
and at 189... Le Sac.
In the back here
is an underground car park
with direct access
to the shops' basements.
We can pull in here
from Glentworth Street
into the car park
for drop-offs and pick-ups
without being seen
from the street.
We'll dig a tunnel
from the basement of the shop
under the Chicken Inn and pop up
in the safe deposit vault.
I got a question.
What do us lot know
about digging tunnels?
Nothing.
But I know a man who does.
So what do you reckon, Bambas?
What do I reckon?
I reckon I know you guys.
But I don't know her.
Don't worry about Martine,
she's solid.
We go way back.
Terry, you have been
up to some mischief in your time.
But this... this is
serious shit, my friend.
Don't you think it's a little
out of your league?
Maybe it's time we stepped
up to the first division.
There's going to be reinforced
concrete under the vault.
You're going to need
a thermic lance, a jackhammer,
a generator, lights,
ropes, cables, the works.
About 40 feet of digging
before we're under the bank.
Hey, we could hire some micks
from Camden Town to do the digging.
That's brilliant, Dave.
Why don't we just
pay their National Insurance
contributions?
And then you won't have to get dirt
on your Tommy Nutter suit.
This way, Michael.
One more shot. This way.
Thank you, that's great.
- What are your plans?
- I am returning to Trinidad
to liberate my brothers and sisters
from the enslavement
of the British colonialists.
What about the charges
you are facing?
- How can you leave England?
- They are liars and cowards.
If they had anything against me
but their fear of me,
I'd be tried and jailed.
- See you later, Bambo.
- We're gonna need a front-man on this,
someone who can sign the lease
on the shop and look the business.
I know someone... Guy Singer.
Calls himself "the Major."
It's a load of bollocks,
but he's got this right posh accent
if anyone comes nosing about.
A bit tight under the arms,
don't you think?
Traditional fit, sir.
If one can't raise
one's hands above one's head
it tends to inhibit
any impulsive acts of surrender.
I'll be right back, sir.
What on earth
are you doing here?
Got a bit of business
for you, Guy.
You might be tempted.
Sit down, love.
What do you think you're doing?
Taking the E for a test drive.
Tell your boss he can
have his inventory back
when he settles
Mr. Jessell's debt.
And it'd better be soon
or we'll be back
to tap Terry's kneecaps.
If I was you two,
I'd be looking for another job.
- Lovely. Cheers.
- Cheers.
So, come on then,
what don't I know?
Romantic dinner
on a Monday night?
Look, honey...
I'm gonna be working
some strange hours
over the next week or two.
Don't ask me what I'm doing
because I don't want to lie to you.
What are you doing?
Look, I know I've
caused us a few problems,
but those cars aren't selling.
All I was trying to do
is get out of the game.
- This thing's gonna put us there.
- Will it?
Yeah.
In a better place.
It's for all of us...
for you and the kids.
And how afraid do
I have to be, Terry?
Maybe it'd be a smart thing
if you went and stayed with your aunt...
in case things turn to custard.
So we are settled...
25% to run my girls
till I return from Trinidad.
It's all right,
you don't have to worry.
I'll look after your little flock
of birds like they were my own.
So long as you remember
they are not your own.
Lew, while I'm back in Trinidad,
I can arrange for a shipment
of some high-grade ganja.
Not interested.
You want my opinion?
I think drugs are responsible
for the moral decay
of this country's young.
No, smut smut and more smut...
that's my special area of interest.
You should think about it.
With these goodies you could make
a lot of dough,
especially with the police
in your pocket.
No, I'm paying enough bung as it is,
but probably not as much
as you're donating
to be permitted
to leave our fair shores.
Not a shilling.
I have something so special,
I don't need to pay anyone.
And what would that be, Michael?
Sorry, Lew.
Well...
whatever it is, you crafty bugger,
I hope you're keeping it safe.
Yes, as safe as it can be in the place
that you recommended.
- You're late.
- Sorry.
This is the Major...
Major Guy Singer,
the final member of our team.
I don't know this man.
- Who are you?
- None of your business.
No secrets around here.
The Major's a con artist.
Usually elderly widows.
There's no need
to bring that up.
Now he's the official
new owner of Le Sac.
Handbags and leather accessories
for the discerning lady.
Nice.
I told the district planner's office
about the remodeling.
They gave me the specs
for the sewage, drainage,
gas and power lines.
We'll have to go deep
to miss that lot.
- What's this for?
- That is the thermic lance.
It cuts through
concrete and metal.
We're doing this, eh?
I mean,
we're bloody going for it.
- Let's see what this thing can do.
- Good idea, Kev.
Give us a demonstration,
Bambo.
Okay, hold this.
Hold it. Here.
Kevin, go stand
over there by the oxygen.
Here we go.
- Turn it off!
- Off off off off!
- Right off!
- Loco!
They know what they're doing,
these people, do they?
Oh, absolutely.
Professional criminals.
What's the worst-case scenario?
They get caught and go to jail.
No possible connection to us.
What about this model
you're screwing?
What promises have you made
to keep her in line?
None that can't be broken.
Look, she's our only tie
to the bank operation.
If things do go belly-up,
it'll only take one cut
to sever the knot.
What's Gale Benson up to?
I believe she's working her way
into Michael X's inner sanctum.
Could you sign my book please?
Daddy!
I am so glad you decided to come.
This is my father,
Sir Leonard Plugge.
Always happy to meet
Gale's new friends.
Her new name is Hale Kimga.
It's an anagram of the letters
of our names... Hakim and Gale.
- And your name is?
- Hakim.
- Hakim Jamal.
- Right.
Excuse me.
Hello, gorgeous.
So, where's the author?
He's over there
signing his masterpiece.
Why don't you both drop
by the house this weekend
and introduce Mr. Jamal to mother?
Sorry, Daddy, can't do that.
We're popping on down
to the islands for a while.
Let me get you a drink.
Good luck with your book.
So have you read
this book of his?
- You must be joking.
- Right.
You're probably undercover
spying on black power's insidious threat
to the British way of life.
That's very funny.
Tell me, is our little enterprise
still shipshape?
We're currently on schedule, Tim.
We're taking over the shop
on Friday afternoon.
I know if this stuffs up,
I'm in poo-poo land.
We have a blue transit van
just pulled up,
"Clacy Builders" on the side.
And we have one man
entering the shop.
Construction crew for Le Sac.
I've got a question.
What do we do with all the dirt
we're gonna dig out the hole?
It's all been worked out, Dave.
We'll dig another hole in that corner
over there and put it in that.
Over.
If we're to get the job done before
the bank opens on Monday morning,
- we'd better get a wriggle on.
- Want to do the honors, Martine?
This is it.
Here we go.
Watch your nails, Martine.
- Yeah!
Let's get this show on the road.
Some racket there, Alf.
Bloody hell!
What's going on?
Kev!
Dave, come on, mate.
Dave, you need a break.
- I'll take over.
- Cheers, Major.
Heads up!
Where's Dave?
No idea.
- Where'd you get to?
- Just checking the door was locked.
Of course it's locked, Dave.
I locked it.
Hang on.
What have we got here?
What does this copper want?
Christ, he's not
going in there, is he?
- I'll go.
- Shit! Dave, get back here.
Stop! Hold it down!
Someone's knocking.
Stop! There's somebody
at the door of the shop!
- There's somebody...
- Bambas!
Bambas!
Hold on.
There's somebody at the door.
- I don't mind going.
- It's my job.
- Coppers.
- It's the Old Bill!
Good evening.
You're working late.
Around the clock, Officer.
Expanding our storage, trying
to complete renovations for the grand...
If you don't mind, sir.
Excuse me!
You using a jackhammer
down there?
Yeah, you had
some complaints, Officer?
Yeah, from some
of your neighbors.
We'll try to keep it down, all right?
Right.
I wonder how they talked
their way out of that one.
Tim, Quinn here.
Yeah, we just had a copper
go into the shop.
We're not sure why.
He's gone now.
All clear.
We need a lookout,
someone on a roof somewhere.
- We've got the walkie-talkies.
- What about Eddie?
He's a good lad,
we can trust him.
No, look, we're not
cutting anyone else in.
We won't cut him in on the loot.
Give him the car lot.
Hopefully I won't need
that headache anymore.
- My God, not again.
- Get up there, Major.
Cover that up!
It's not the coppers.
- Yes, can I help you?
- Delivery for Dave Shilling.
- What is it?
- Chicken and chips.
I see.
- Takeaway for Mr. Shilling.
- Thanks.
You can't be serious?
I was starving.
Mind the gap.
Radio's in the bag,
binocs as well.
There's a bed-sit
on the top floor of this building
paid for the week.
The ladder will get you to the roof.
You're in from Liverpool
looking for work.
I don't have a Liverpool accent.
Then don't talk to anyone, Eddie.
I'm up on the roof and...
I got a good view
in all directions, over.
Are you in position, Nightjar?
Command HQ, here.
Acknowledge.
Yeah, I'm in position.
I can see the front of the bank...
Marylebone Road,
Baker Street.
I can see everything really well.
All clear on
the western front, Guy. Over.
- No names, Eddie.
- Sorry, Dave.
Hey, you delinquents,
what have I told you?
No idle chitchat.
Sorry... over.
Fucking hell.
Wakey wakey, gentlemen.
I'll keep an eye
on the shop from here on.
You two go around
to Glentworth Street,
cover the parking garage exit.
Okay.
Nightjar, here. There's some
fella looking through the window.
Oh, hang on.
Wait, hang on, he's going.
He's going.
Yeah, he's gone. Over.
Roger, Nightjar.
Over and out.
I'm gonna go to the pub,
grab some more smokes.
Do you want anything?
Ooh, packet of Seniors.
There you go, sir.
Two packets of Rothmans,
two Senior Service
- and eight bags of crisps.
- Okay.
Hello, gorgeous.
We still on track?
We had a scare last night.
The cops came around.
Can't you pull rank and make sure
it doesn't happen again?
No. We can't show our hand.
We're invisible, remember?
- Wish I was.
- What about your friend, Terry?
Where's he planning
to carve up the proceeds?
Shit.
- Pint here, chief.
- What's wrong?
I had to take a break.
Who's that you was talking to?
I wasn't.
He was trying to chat me up.
It does happen you know.
- Right.
- There you are, love.
- Cheers. Keep the change.
- Thank you.
Anyway, what you doing here?
You following me?
No.
Just wanted a pint.
Then enjoy it.
- Hello, Gale.
- Where have you been?
You're rather impressed
with our friend Hakim, aren't you?
I know.
Rule number one...
don't get emotionally involved.
Doesn't mean
I can't enjoy my work.
You certainly do.
What's your father think of your
consorting with these radicals anyway?
We are not amused.
Of course, if he knew
what I was really up to,
- he'd have a heart attack.
- Yeah.
Here you are.
Credit cards and cash.
If he does have copies of the photos
and negatives there, they'll be hidden.
Find them, destroy them
and then get out.
Michael X thinks he's safe
tucked away in Trinidad.
That'll all change
if we're successful here.
Just remember, Gale,
he's a nasty piece of work.
He's a crazy, dope-smoking,
lunatic, pimp extortionist
is what he is.
Everything okay, Nightjar?
Anything I need to know?
Yeah, everything's
all right, mate.
Listen, what if I want
to go for a pee up here?
I don't know,
use your imagination.
Stay off the radio unless
you see any Old Bill, all right?
Yeah, all right. If I see the Old Bill,
I'll let you know.
I'll speak to you in a bit.
Over.
Hey, Bambas!
What's all this brickwork?
I don't know,
it wasn't on the plans.
- Terry!
- Fucking hell!
Terry! Bambas!
Terry, talk to me!
Tell!
Fuck.
Terry! Talk to me!
- You all right?
- I think so, yeah.
What happened?
The floor just caved in.
Bloody hell, Terry,
don't do that to me.
I thought you was a goner.
Give us a light, Dave.
What's down there?
It's a pile of skeletons.
You're joking.
Let's hope they're not the last gang
who tried to take this bank.
Latin, roughly translated...
"Lamb of God,
forgive us our sins."
How do you know Latin?
Catholic school.
The Bleeding Heart Sisters
of Eternal Misery.
Interesting date, 1665.
You know what year
that was, don't you?
The last time
West Ham won the Cup.
It was the Great Plague
of London.
This must be a burial chamber,
the crypt where
they dumped the bodies.
What, all these poor bastards
had the plague?
It could be infectious.
I don't think so, Dave.
This crypt goes
all the way under the bank.
- It could put us in the vault quicker.
- Well, how are we gonna do that?
Concrete.
Floor of the vault.
- Time to get paid for all our work.
- Right.
If we hit the restaurant by mistake,
we'll be knee-deep in fried chicken.
I'll be happy if
we don't hit the sewage.
When are you guys gonna hit the vault?
I'm freezing my tits off up here.
Over.
In the army, soldiers would
pull on their puds
to keep their blood flowing.
Over.
What regiment were you in,
the Royal Corps of Wankers?
- Over.
- Yes. We welcome new members.
Roger. Over and out.
Emergency operator,
which service do you require?
The police, please.
Putting you through.
- Police here, can I help you?
- Yes.
I'm a ham radio operator
and I think I may be overhearing
a robbery in progress.
We're in.
Dave, get the ladder.
We'll make the move
into the vault after we take a break.
Need to let the fumes clear out.
You're having a laugh, isn't you?
Let's go in now.
Dave, nothing's going nowhere.
You can hardly
breathe in there.
Nightjar, are you there? Over.
Nightjar here. Over.
We're in. Over.
- What, in the actual vault?
- Yes, in the actual vault. Over.
Great. Great.
That's great news. Over.
We're taking a break.
We're knackered.
We need to get some sleep,
get a bit of shuteye
while the fumes clear out.
Over.
Oh, lucky you.
My eyes are like
organ stops. Over.
We can smell the money though.
Over.
Look, money may be your god,
but it ain't mine, all right?
I want a warm bath
and a cup of tea. Over.
You'll get your cup of tea.
Just you hold tight.
Oh, lucky you.
My eyes are like organ stops. Over.
We can smell the money though.
I rang four other
police stations before you,
but nobody took me seriously.
Said it was probably a hoax.
How strong was the signal,
Mr. Addey?
I'd say they were
within a 10-mile radius.
There must be
a ton of banks in that area.
And when was the last time
you picked them up?
They've been quiet
for about an hour.
What about releasing
the tapes to the radio and TV?
Maybe somebody can
recognize the voices.
No no.
They hear themselves,
they'll stop transmitting.
No, we should keep listening.
Maybe they'll reveal where they are.
Alfie, you stay here with Mr. Addey.
I'm going back to the station.
You call me if you hear anything.
Hey.
You scared the piss out of me.
- What are you doing here?
- I couldn't sleep.
Yeah, a bit jangly myself.
I just had to come and have a look.
Our future's in those boxes.
So what you gonna
do with your share?
Vanish.
Martine Love will cease to exist.
Why, you think if you vanish
you'll become someone else?
At least no one
will know who I was.
Why'd you pick Kev and me?
You could've
found better thieves.
Old times' sake.
Most of your old times
were spent with Kevin, not me.
And Kevin has it in his mind
we had this passionate affair.
The truth is, it came down
to four Chinese meals
and a roll in the hay.
And that was a long time ago.
All right.
Let's make some money.
Pull it out.
Look at this!
Look at all this cash.
- Wads of it.
- Fantastic.
Guys, gold bars.
Diamonds.
Diamonds!
Guys, what's going on?
How'd your wife fancy a tiara?
Too bloody right.
- Get the cash. The cash!
- Look at the quality.
- Emeralds.
- This is better than winning the pools.
Dave, give us
a hand with this one.
What's so special
about this box?
It's my lucky number.
All yours, me lovely.
- Here you are.
- Cheers.
Holy shit.
You know who that is.
That's Princess Margaret.
Terry, anything
for the widows and orphans fund?
Will that do?
God bless you, guv'ner,
very generous.
Look, we have to have
some sort of system.
You don't know what you're
throwing and what you're keeping.
Yeah, well, we know
what money looks like
and we're not throwing
that away, are we?
How long does it take
to rob a bank?
We've just about
cleaned this joint out, eh?
More cash.
Look at this.
- No, nothing.
- No, still nothing.
Sarge, what we need is something
that will motivate the robbers
to go on air,
give away their location.
Right.
Bait to lure the fish.
No, they're not there.
- Not transmitting.
- They're not there, sir.
Move to the next bank,
Sierra Lima Two.
No.
We're still getting nothing, Sarge.
Okay, Sierra Lima Two,
move to the next location.
My God, the stuff
that some people collect.
- What you got there, Terry?
- '47.
- '47?
- Sounds like a good year to me.
- Three cheers.
- Hurray!
Pass 'em around.
Come on, Terry, give us some!
Dave!
Here, Major!
Get it down ya!
Fellas, they're onto you.
- Listen, they're onto you.
- Fuck.
Coppers right on your doorstep.
Speak to me, Nightjar.
Coppers right on your doorstep!
Listen, hang on. Hang on.
They're not going in
but they're not going away.
Wait, wait.
Sarge, we just heard.
The thieves' lookout says there are
police outside the bank right now.
- Which bank?
- I haven't got a clue.
We've got patrols outside
half the banks in the West End.
Keep listening. We need to pinpoint
exactly where they are.
Wait, hang on.
Guys, you got a car
just pulled up, some bloke.
He's going up
to the front door with the cops.
Guys, he's unlocking
the front door.
They're going in.
Shit. Over.
- Oh no.
- Shit.
- Where's the vault?
- Downstairs.
Follow me.
Looks fine.
- I want to look inside.
- It's on a time lock.
It can't be opened
until tomorrow morning.
Mm-hmm.
Well, it isn't my bank being robbed.
Thank you.
Fellas, I think they're going away.
They're gone.
We should get out of here.
- They could be coming back.
- Yeah, all right.
- We need to let Eddie know.
- Nightjar.
Nightjar!
No! Fuck.
Shit.
Fuck.
Shit. Oh, shit.
Are you there, Nightjar?
The ambulance reports it's outside
the Lloyds Bank on Baker Street.
Nightjar, can you hear me?
Have you gone asleep, Nightjar?
Nightjar, are you there?
Look, if he's not picking up,
something's wrong.
You're right. Let's grab all the cash
and jewels and get the fuck out of here.
What about our gear? We can't leave
anything that might incriminate us.
- We'll come back for it if we can.
- What about all the other boxes?
Doesn't matter, Dave.
Put everything in a bag and let's go.
He's right, let's move.
Come on!
- No.
- There's nothing there, Sarge.
You sure?
There's no mention
of the ambulance.
Nothing, move on,
Sierra Lima Two.
- That's them.
- Finally.
Come on, let's go.
The van is leaving.
We will follow them. Over.
Stop them as soon as possible.
Open the door!
What have I done, guv'ner?
Open the back door.
Come on.
Some fella paid me 50 quid
to pick up his van
and drop it at Heathrow Airport.
Jesus Christ.
- Where's the van?
- Change of plan.
Precautionary measure.
I've organized
alternative transport.
- Why?
- None of us have met your boyfriend,
the alarm bloke
who clued you up about the job.
Could have set us up.
We bloody well pulled it off!
Done with military
precision, hey, Major?
Now, that I'm physically secure,
I think I'll promote myself to Colonel.
Hey, do you know
what I'm gonna do?
Buy me mum a new house,
something with a garden.
I thought you'd be
off to Copenhagen, Dave.
- Why would I go to Copenhagen?
- Have your cock shortened.
Yeah, well, maybe
what they chop off of mine,
they can add
onto your little pinkie.
How'd you find this place, Terry?
Bloke I know used to run
a chop shop here.
He's in the nick now.
How could you lose control
of the operation?
I thought you were
on top of this thing.
Sir, it worked. They did the job.
They robbed the vault.
And we have no idea
where the fuck they are.
Do you know,
an ugly thought has just occurred.
Lots of money in that vault...
jewelry, bonds.
You and your sweetie haven't cooked up
something between you, I hope.
- You think I'd betray you?
- There are precedents.
Two of our former colleagues
now live in bloody Moscow.
Let's hope they don't
have another bidder.
She won't cross us.
She knows what we're capable of.
How does she even know
who the hell we are?
I'm sure she'll contact me
when she comes to her senses.
Going anywhere else
would be a death sentence.
You'd better hope
she does, Everett...
or it may be yours.
Here you go, Bambas.
That's your lot.
"Never washed after
our magic moment. Snooky."
Hey, Dave.
Look at this.
I've seen this bloke on the TV.
The old perv!
I've seen this face before.
He's an MP.
Lord what's his name?
You know.
Always wears
those poncey bowties.
Not in that picture he's not.
Maybe this is one
of your old movies, Dave.
Piss off, Kev.
Timely suggestion.
I believe I'll take my share
and be on my way
before the bank opens in the morning
and the shit hits the proverbial fan.
I'm with you, Guy.
I don't have to remind you,
keep a low profile.
No buying Aston Martins, Bambas.
The only thing I'm buying
is a one-way ticket back to Cyprus.
I'm never coming back.
We should have a reunion
in 20 years.
The Savoy Grill.
Yeah, right.
Maybe for you, Guy.
They still wouldn't
let us lot in.
- Bambo.
- Goodbye, my friend.
Take care of yourself, mate.
And Major.
Be lucky.
Bambas...
goodbye, old chap.
Okay, what's going on?
You two have been staring daggers
at each other since you left the bank.
What is it, lovers' tiff?
I think Martine's
got something to tell us.
Hang about,
that's Princess Margaret.
Fuck me.
Where'd these come from?
You knew the exact box
this stuff was in, Martine.
You better come clean
and tell us what this is really about.
About a month ago,
I got busted at Heathrow
on a drug charge.
This guy I know said he'd
fix it to keep me out of jail
if I do him a favor.
He knew I knew some villains.
He wanted to set up
a robbery to get these.
Fucking hell.
That would be the bloke you met
in the Player's Club?
Same guy you said was trying
to pick you up in the club, right?
- Yeah.
- So who is he?
He's a guy I met
at the Sombrero Club.
He works for some
shady outfit in Whitehall.
Hold on, hold on.
What, you mean MI fucking 5?
Or 6?
We could get
seriously nicked here, Martine.
No, we couldn't. All Tim wants
is the contents of box 118.
The deal with him
is we get to keep everything else.
And you believed that?
You put your trust in some prick
we've never even met?
You lied to us, Martine.
We were sitting ducks
right from the start.
Thank you very much.
You think it's a coincidence
that you get busted for drugs
and your Tim just happens
to have a plan to rob a bank?
This can work out.
We give them the photos
and everything else in that box
and we get to keep the rest
and we're free and clear.
These people aren't
regular cozzers, Martine.
They're above that.
They do things coppers can't.
If they think we've seen these photos,
we're as expendable as dogshit.
Do you know what?
I've seen those shots.
And I know
we're either dogshit
or about to be dogshit.
I'm out of here.
I'm not waiting for a load
of spooks and coppers
to come cracking my head.
I'm splitting like Guy and Bambas.
- Be better if we stuck together, Dave.
- Why, Tell?
'Cause we've been so truthful
with each other so far? Eh?
- Hey, come on.
- No, I'm going home, Kev,
to see me mum.
And then I'm going far away,
as far as I can get away from here.
We'd better get out of here too
in case Guy or Bambas
get picked up.
Better take the lot of this.
There might be someone else in this
shit to cause us some more grief.
One of those, mate.
Here you go, guv'ner.
- Keep the change.
- Cor, thanks.
They overheard our radio chat.
Fucking hell.
"Police last night
were trying to home in
on a 300,000 bank raid."
They still don't know what bank it was.
300 grand?
It was a bit more than that.
More like three million.
- Hello?
- Martine Love.
Thank God.
Put her through, then run a trace.
- It's me.
- What happened?
- Where the hell are you?
- London.
- I know, of course. I mean where?
- I know what you mean.
- Martine, we have to meet.
- I agree.
Why don't you come over to my place?
I'll make you a cocktail.
We'll have a roll in the hay
for old times' sake.
Oh, right. You've already
been there, haven't you?
Probably have your men
keeping lookout for me now.
You're not in a position
to play games, Martine.
No threats, please, Tim.
Why didn't you tell me what it was
I was set up to get for you?
For your own good.
I care about your safety, Martine.
Right.
I suppose I give you what you want,
we go our separate ways.
- Well, that's what I promised.
- Okay.
Today, Tottenham Court Road tube,
northern line, northbound platform.
10:30 sharp.
Tottenham Court Road, 10:30.
Good.
"London vaults checked
after radio ham
tunes in to a crime."
Christ! What a fiasco!
And now the particular bank
has been identified,
the story will be
all over the news.
We've heard it already is.
If we don't get
onto the case quickly,
the police will have
nabbed these robbers
and God knows what
will happen to our photographs.
Phillip, get over to the bank.
Take control of the situation.
Gentlemen.
I've just had a conversation
with one Martine Love.
- Where is she?
- Call was traced to a public phone box
in Earls Court. The good news is,
she's arranged to meet.
That is good news.
I'll be better off going alone.
Yeah.
- Tim's agreed to meet.
- It's all over the news.
They found the location
of the bank.
So what?
Stand back.
Please stand back.
Keep the change.
I'm sorry, ma'am. You can't go in.
There's been a robbery.
We know there's been a robbery.
That's why we're all here.
Everybody that works here...
that means everybody...
speak to them.
Gerald!
You work in robbery now, then?
You're a long way
off your patch.
Regional Crime Squad now.
Just dropped by to see
what all the fuss is about.
Pretty cheeky,
that radio bit.
These walkie-talkie robbers certainly
caught your lot on the hop.
Makes us all look stupid.
Yeah, well, you're pretty chummy
with all the villains around town.
You got any idea
who could've done this?
None of my informants.
We have been waiting here
quite some time
and so far you people
have told us absolutely nothing.
If you would like to give us an itemized
list of the contents of your boxes,
we may be able to ascertain
what's missing.
Are you mad? The whole point
of having a safe deposit box
is so that people like you
don't know what's in it.
- I want to speak to a Roy Given.
- Yeah, that's me.
This robbery's now a matter of
national security. I want everybody out.
This is a police investigation.
Not anymore.
Call your superiors.
Who the bloody hell
does he think is?
Spooks.
5 or 6,
I can never tell the difference.
They all go to the same tailor
and they all went
to the same bloody school.
Let's get some copies
of the walkie-talkie tapes
out to the news boys.
Maybe the public
can help identify the villains.
So tell me...
which of the boxes
were ransacked?
The lot:
100s through the 400s.
Well, we're in the crapper, Gerry.
Both of us.
Both?
Why is it my problem?
Accounts have to be balanced,
records kept.
And I wouldn't likely keep the books
around here, now would I?
Spell it out, Lew.
Be more specific.
I have a ledger...
a record of every payment
I've ever made
to you and your colleagues.
It was in my safety deposit box.
And I think we can safely assume it's
now in the possession of the robbers.
Jesus wept.
And I think you'll agree,
we have to find those villains
before your honest
colleagues do.
For fuck's sake.
- Who is this?
- Lew Vogel.
Hold on. Get up.
Go on. Wake up.
What you want, Lew?
I'm afraid I've got some potentially
bad news for you, Michael.
Your safety deposit box
at the Baker Street bank...
- what's its number?
- Why do you ask?
Well, over the weekend some thieves
broke into the bank vault and robbed it.
So if your box is
in the 100 to 400 numbers,
I'm afraid all your stuff will be gone.
Mine too, unhappily.
What? How can this
happen in London?
Well, I promise you,
it has happened.
And I promise you, these thieves
will be found and dealt with.
You can rely on it.
I'll keep you informed.
Thank you.
Mind the gap, please.
Anyone touches me,
follows me,
Martine takes your snaps
right to Fleet Street, understood?
You want box 118, Tim.
You have no idea the danger you
and your chums are in, do you?
Is that right?
And why would that be?
You've opened Pandora's Box,
you dumb prick.
- That's why.
- I know what's at stake.
And I know how
expendable we are.
- So I'm changing the deal.
- Is that right?
Yeah.
You get all your nasty pictures,
but here's the twist:
We get indemnity...
fresh passports,
safe passage out of the country
for the whole team,
and an official signed
document guaranteeing
we won't be prosecuted
and we won't be pursued.
- You can't be serious.
- You can bet your bollocks I'm serious.
And we want it signed,
sealed and delivered
by a public figure
of substantial authority.
- How about the Prime Minister?
- Yeah, he'll do.
If you can drag him off his yacht.
You mess with us, Tim...
we can drip-feed
pictures like this to the press.
We've got a stack of 'em.
Oh, dear.
You've got until 4:00 p.m.
To confirm we have a deal.
We'll be in touch.
- Some photographs.
- Well done, Tim.
Do you have any more?
Apparently, there was
a whole rogue's gallery
stored in one of the boxes.
If Lord Drysdale is up
to his usual hanky-panky,
that's his problem.
This operation is about recovering
the photos from Michael X.
Might it not be prudent to get
the committee
to consider issuing
a D-Notice
to protect everyone potentially
embarrassed by this criminal activity?
Which we instigated.
Very nice.
Very nice indeed.
When I came out, there were
a couple of lads taking some photos.
Photos of him.
Now he was standing
right outside the bank
just a few days
before it was robbed.
I thought at the time
he looked a bit shifty.
Oh my God!
Christ, is that thing real?
I've got it:
Dave Shilling.
That's his name.
- Ta-ta, Mum.
- Look after yourself, love.
Go and get yourself inside,
you'll catch your death.
- Dave Shilling?
- Yeah?
I wonder if we could have a word?
- About what?
- About a bank.
I want to tell you something,
Mr. Shilling, 'cause it'll save time.
You see...
I have a very
jaundiced view of life.
From what I see, most of it's corrupt,
venal and vile.
And I'm just saying this so that you
know that I don't have
a better nature to appeal to
or a compassionate streak.
You do understand, don't you?
- I think so, Mr. Vogel.
- Good.
I have a kidney stone.
I don't seem to be able to pass it.
I'm on painkillers.
I could use a couple of those myself.
You stole from me...
and from friends of mine.
- Where's my stuff?
- I don't know.
Look, I don't know anything
about any bank robbery. Honest.
Still an unconvincing actor,
Mr. Shilling.
I would love to say
this is not going to hurt,
but it is.
What are you going to do?
No no!
No! Stop!
Please!
Don't! Please!
- Well, they were here.
- Well, they ain't here now.
Why is the door open?
Who are you?
I could ask the same thing.
Better run along, eh?
Get yourselves a cup of tea
or something.
We're looking for Terry Leather.
Terry said he won't be
coming in this week.
- He's supposed to call in.
- Ah.
So you'd be Eddie, right?
- Uh, yeah.
- Well, you're coming with me.
Leave him alone.
What do you want with my Eddie?
- Shut your noise.
- Leave her alone!
We want to talk to him
about a bank robbery.
- Don't you touch her!
- If you want to see your Eddie
or his mate Dave again, make sure
Terry Leather calls that number.
What?
Walkie-Talkie Gang takes it all!
Read all about it!
That's great news. Over.
We're taking a break.
We need to get some sleep,
get a bit of shuteye
while the fumes clear out.
- Over.
- Oh, lucky you.
My eyes are like organ stops...
Mummy, Daddy's on the radio.
- Oh, don't be so silly, darling.
- He is!
Is he?
I want a warm bath
and a cup of tea. Over.
You'll get your cup of tea.
Just you hold tight. Over.
See, it is Daddy.
Authorities have
released this recording
of the walkie-talkie
communications
between the robbers
of Lloyds Bank in Marylebone
in the hopes that their voices
may be identified
by members of the public...
- Hello?
- Wendy?
We heard you on the radio, Terry.
You're famous, you know?
You robbed that bank, didn't you?
The one in the news?
Oh God, you could go
to jail for years
for something like that, Terry.
I couldn't stand it.
No one's going to jail.
I've got it all under control.
Just stay put,
keep the kids inside.
I love you, Wendy.
I've got to go.
- You be careful, Terry.
- What's the matter, Mum?
Nothing, darling.
Terry, they took Eddie.
- Oh God, who?
- They weren't thieves or...
I don't know, they could have been cops.
They left a phone number for you.
They said if I wanted to see Dave
or Eddie again
then you have to call.
Listen to me, Ingrid.
I swear to you I'll get him back.
- Don't you worry, darling.
- Have you got a pen?
Yeah.
- 0-1-9-4-6...
- Hold on, say it again.
- Yeah.
- Michael, it's Lew Vogel.
- Yes?
Well, we've identified the villains.
And believe it or not,
they're amateurs. Part-timers.
They were put up to the job by a woman
named Martine Love.
- Ring a bell?
- Never heard of her.
Well, we paid a visit to her flat
and some chaps
from Ml5 were already there.
Pulled rank on my tamed copper.
Why do you suppose these people
would be interested in the robbery
of a minor neighborhood
bank, Michael?
- I don't know.
- I think you do.
And I'm guessing
that your box is number 118.
I think what these robbers
were really after were photographs.
Photographs
of a certain Royal Princess.
How you know that?
Because on this point
I believe my captive.
No man could withstand
the pain we inflicted on him.
So don't take me
for a fool, Michael.
You've instigated this calamity
by storing your blackmail materials
in this bank.
Which you recommended.
I will not be lectured
by the porn king of Soho.
Get my pictures back
or you will never see a black man
on the streets of London
without wondering if he's
been sent to kill you.
- What are you doing?
- Oh, hello, Michael.
Hakim was looking
for a copy of his book.
I know what you've been looking for,
bird, and you won't find it.
What are you talking about?
Hakim, I found your book.
You don't understand.
My box and those of my friends
may have been rifled.
Surely you can pull some strings.
You're a minister in the government,
for God's sake.
Sonia, I really don't think
I'm able to help here.
Perhaps you don't
fully comprehend.
I have photographs,
compromising photographs;
live film of you,
Miles Urquhart,
all my regulars,
in this safe deposit box.
You all know each other,
if that's any consolation.
You've got photographs of me?
You conniving cunt!
You be a big boy.
Now's the time to talk to
your Whitehall chums, don't you think?
That's him.
I'm sure that's him.
Guy Arthur Singer.
Con man and petty criminal.
Did a stretch in the Scrubs
a few years back.
Thought he was a wanker.
Spoke with some poncey accent.
Thank you, sir, very much.
- Hello?
- Who am I talking to?
Oh, Terry Leather,
Kevin Swain, Martine Love,
Eddie Burton.
Yeah, Mr. Shilling was kind enough
to speak with me about this.
You put Dave on the phone, eh?
Well, I would but...
he seems a bit
indisposed at the moment.
What do you want?
Just a couple of things
from what you stole.
A ledger with a dark red cover.
And some photos that I'm sure
Ml5 is interested in.
The Royal Portfolio.
All we got is money and jewels.
Then I suggest you look again.
Speak to your friends.
- Hello. Who's this?
- Eddie? It's Terry.
Terry.
Terry, fucking hell.
Dave's all messed up and they're
going to do the same to me.
- You've got to help.
- Listen to me, Eddie.
I don't have what he wants.
What? No!
No you've got to have
what they want, you've got to.
You've got to help.
Eddie, what am I supposed to do?
You tell him we don't have it.
No, Terry!
Terry, you've got to help.
Eddie, you tell him I don't
have his fucking ledger!
You tell that cunt now.
He doesn't have it.
Right.
What are you going to do?
No, don't!
No! No!
They shot Dave!
- Eddie?
- Dave's dead.
- Eddie! Eddie!
- They shot Dave.
I'll give you one hour
to find what I want
or I'll kill this man too.
Fuck.
This is it.
Lew Vogel.
That's who this bastard is.
Payments made
to Soho West End Division Officers.
They're the weekly payouts.
50 quid here, 20 there.
Probably every
bent copper in London.
Nothing like this
was supposed to happen.
- No one was supposed to get hurt.
- It's not your fault.
We've still got our own necks
to think about and Eddie.
Look, we give the photos to Vogel,
all bets are off with Tim.
We deliver them to Tim,
it's Eddie's neck,
Vogel and his lot are after us.
Either way, we are fucked.
Miles, we've got a problem,
a serious problem...
something Sonia Burn
kept in the bank
that was robbed
over the weekend.
She is concerned
that her safe deposit box
may have been plundered.
I'm afraid her fears
are well justified.
Oh my God.
I really thought Sonia was a woman
of more discreet character.
So...
the genie is out
of the bottle then.
For both of us, eh?
Not quite yet.
My operatives tell me
that the thieves are using
the photographs as a bargaining chip.
- Then give them what they want.
- Already in motion.
And the committee
have it in the works
to issue a D-Notice
on the whole business...
muffle the press,
put a lid on it.
What?
Be a pity, wouldn't it?
I mean, if your mates abandoned
you over a few photographs and...
- Hello.
- You listen to me, Mr. Vogel,
or whatever your fucking name is.
You go ahead and kill him.
See if we give a shit.
We got our loot.
Your ledgers and your photos, you can
pick them up from Scotland Yard.
- We're sending them over.
- Don't do that.
Well, if you want your
book of payoffs back,
be at Paddington Station
in person tomorrow 11:00 a.m.
Platform one.
There's a newsstand
near the statue of the soldier.
Have Eddie with you,
hale and hearty.
This is your one
and only chance, Vogel.
Don't blow it.
Don't answer it!
Catherine!
- Daddy!
- Hello, you. Come here.
Here look, I got you a present.
- You been good for Mummy?
- Yeah.
I need to talk to Mummy about something,
so give us a minute, okay?
- Go on.
So do you want to tell me
what's been going on?
Some bloke's worked over Dave.
How bad?
He's dead.
Oh my God almighty, Terry!
What have you done to us?
Wendy, I promise,
I'm going to work this out.
And when I do,
we're going to leave England
and it is all going
to change for us.
If anything goes wrong, use this.
There's plenty of cash...
pounds, francs, dollars.
You can leave the country,
start a new life for you and the girls.
You can do this
if you have to, Wendy.
- Promise me.
- That from the robbery, is it?
My share, yeah.
The papers said
that there was a woman in the vault.
Martine was it,
was she involved?
Yeah, she brought us
the job in the first place.
Oh, and did you
sleep with her, Terry?
Do you know what?
From day one it was always you.
The first day we met,
I said to my friend Audrey,
I said,
"I am going to marry him.
And I am going to have his kids."
And I have stuck by you.
I have stuck by you no matter what!
You bastard!
Fuck.
You can throw me over.
I deserve it.
I've brought you more grief
than happiness.
But I love you
and the kids.
That's the reason I did this, to get us
out of this life once and for all.
Mummy, open the door!
- Mummy, Mummy!
- We'll work the rest out later.
Go and play in your room!
If you'll still have me.
She takes a good picture, eh, Tim?
Lord Mountbatten has
graciously agreed to represent
the interests of the Crown
in this matter.
- He high enough up the tree?
- Lord Mountbatten?
I've always wanted
to meet that bugger.
Yes. Well, I'm sure he'll be
very pleased to meet you too.
He has to be under the main clock,
Paddington Station,
11:00 a.m. Or no deal.
11:00 a.m. On the knocker with your
new passports and documents.
He'll hand them over
as soon as he sees the photos.
There's another problem.
This robbery has pissed off
some local villains.
The guts come with the glory, eh?
One of our mates has been killed.
It's hardly surprising
considering the roster of reprobates
who are the bank's
deposit box customers.
Listen, Terry, our commitment
is for the recovery
of the royal portraits only.
The proceeds and the piss-offs
are both yours to deal with.
11:00 a.m., Paddington Station.
Gale,
Michael wants
to see you in the garden.
- What for?
- I don't know.
Gale, come.
Come and look at this.
Come.
- I want to show you something.
- What's this for?
It's for you.
What have I done to deserve this?
What have I done?
You're a spy
sent to steal from me.
And nobody steals from Michael X!
No one!
See if it mentions
the copper in charge.
Here it is.
"Heading the case
is Detective Sergeant Roy Given
of Marylebone Lane Police Station."
Roy Given.
No Roy Given mentioned.
Let's hope that means he's straight.
And that he'd be interested
in the names of some bent coppers.
Yeah, bit of a long shot.
- Fuck it.
- Nothing in that one?
No.
What, we don't rate a mention?
Strike you as strange?
It's kind of scary actually.
If that news could disappear,
so could we.
Next stop, Edgeware Road.
Well, here's to us.
See you, mate.
Look after yourself.
Take care.
Good luck, Kev.
So where are you headed
if everything goes to plan?
I'll tell you
if you're coming with me.
Morning.
I'm looking for a Mr. Roy Given.
- It's very important.
- Roy Given?
Yeah.
Yeah, well, can I ask
what it's concerning?
No, I prefer to tell him myself.
Look, all I'm saying is
if you're interested
in the rest of this book of payoffs,
the author's going to be
at Paddington Station, 11:00 a.m.,
platform one.
And how exactly did this
come into your possession?
Next stop, Paddington Station.
Change here
for the Bakerloo Line.
Let's hope no one turns up
fashionably late.
- There's your friend Tim.
- Good luck.
It's good to see you in one piece.
You were worried
for your own ass, Tim,
not for mine.
You're a prick, Tim.
You set this whole thing up
from the start, didn't you?
Come on, you get to be rich,
free and clear.
Isn't that what you wanted?
- You stay here with the car.
- Right.
Oh, bloody kidney stone.
It's got to pass soon.
Haven't had this much
excitement since the war.
We're a little late, milord.
So where's your mate?
That's Terry there
by the newsstand.
Wait. I've seen those two cowboys
before at the girl's flat.
- It's a trap. They're Ml5.
- Terry!
Terry!
- Lord Mountbatten?
- Yes.
You know the arrangement?
And you agreed
to our new identities
and immunity from prosecution?
You have my word that the Crown
will honor this commitment.
Your documentation
and guarantees.
If I were you I'd keep them
in a very safe place.
Yeah, well you can bet
it won't be a safe deposit box.
She is a scallywag.
Thank you.
Martine...
it wasn't all business for me.
- What's happening? Where's the book?
- Just open the door.
- No!
- Get in there.
Stay there or you're dead meat.
Where you going, old man, eh?
- This one's for Dave.
- No.
Here, you fucker!
Not so fucking smug now are you?
Oi, you sod...
- Eddie, get out.
- That's the bloke that killed Dave.
Get your hands off me!
Arrest them.
They're the bank robbers.
- Fuck!
- This bloke killed our friend.
- Shit.
- We're innocent.
So are we seriously
assholed now, Terry?
Well, at least we're not dead
like poor old Dave.
- Get up, you filthy bastard.
- I want...
You're under arrest.
- Take him away.
- Right. Come on you.
Get in the car.
I tried, mate.
I wonder if that's Roy Given.
Who's he?
We was hoping
he was a straight copper.
We've got a nice collar here, Roy.
You know these two are part
of the Baker Street bank robbery gang?
- Place this man under arrest.
- Yes, sir.
What are you talking about?
They're part of the Baker Street firm.
I don't know about them,
but I know about you,
you corrupt bastard.
Cuff him...
and the one over
by the wall as well.
But they're the robbers.
No robbers in here.
Watch your head.
Now...
I believe you have
a certain Mr. Vogel's book of shame.
Well, if you'll let me out,
I'll go get it for you.
That belongs to me.
There's your book.
Terry, we were thinking,
a smart fellow like you
might have kept mementos
of the event just in case.
In case what?
Things didn't turn out so nicely?
If they should ever
see the light of day,
don't think we can't find you.
Out! Go on, piss off!
And you, go on.
- How did that happen?
- Fucked if I know.
Just keep walking.
Michael! Michael!
What's going on?
What do you want
in my place?
- What do you want?
- We are placing you under arrest.
What am I charged with?
Conspiracy to import drugs
into the United Kingdom.
Will that do?
But you could still help yourself.
There's a British national
staying with you,
- a certain Gale Benson.
- She was here but she's gone on.
All right.
Over here, sir.
Burn the house down. I want
nothing of this place left standing.
# Those were the days, my friend #
# We thought they'd never end... #
- Were you friends of Dave?
- Oh, yeah.
We knew him
in a professional capacity.
He was one of our favorites.
See you later.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
So where are you off to, Kev?
Anywhere you want to go.
Sorry, I'm doing a solo
from now on.
Yeah, well it was worth a try.
Do you want another one?
Yeah, go on.
One for the road.
Ta, mate.
I just wish Dave
could have seen all this.
Yeah, here's to Dave.
To Dave.
What do you want, Martine?
I'm sorry I've caused you
this upset, Wendy.
Well, apparently we're rich.
I know the business is finished,
but are the cars really ours?
Yeah.
They're all yours.
Jessell's been paid off.
I won't lie to you.
I'd have gone with him.
And I'd have shut you
out of my mind.
But he didn't want to know.
I'm sorry.
Your wife's talking to Martine.
I know, Kev.
I know.
Good luck.
It was always you, Terry.
Go, Daddy!
Oh my God, Terry,
it's a big one.
Last us a few chips, that one.
Don't, Mom.
Fish fingers tonight, eh?
# I want money #
# That's what I want #
# Yeah #
# The best things in life are free #
# But you can keep them
for the birds and bees #
- # Give me money #
- # That's what I want #
# That's what I want, yeah #
# Well, that's what I want #
# Your loving gives me
such a thrill #
# But your loving
don't pay my bills #
- # Give me money #
- # That's what I want #
# That's what I want #
# Well, that's what I want #
# Money don't get everything,
it's true #
# But what it don't get
I can't use #
- # Give me money #
- # That's what I want #
# That's what I want #
# Yeah, that's what I want #
- # Well, give me money #
- # That's what I want #
- # Lots of money #
- # A whole lot of money #
- # That's what I want #
# Give me money
money money money money #
# Whoa yeah #
# Well, that's what I want #
# Yeah yeah yeah. #