(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Hi, kids.
Remember, always look both ways
before crossing.
Mother!
We're having
your favorite supper tonight, Wanda.
Potatoes au gratin.
ALL: Mmm.
Now walk.
Look left, look right.
That's right, then walk. Good teenagers.
BOY: Are you gonna work this summer?
(ROCK 'N' ROLL MUSIC
PLAYING ON SPEAKER)
Wanda, honey.
You want a ride home with Dad?
I got a lift. Thanks, anyway.
We could count out-of-state license plates.
I saw one this morning
all the way up from Virginia.
-Dad, would you just leave me alone?
-Bye, honey.
I am so tired of being good.
Hi.
Well.
You're a pretty little Square.
Want to hang out with us Drapes tonight?
(GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION)
Allison Vernon-Williams, get in this car.
What's the trouble, honey?
These hoodlums bothering you?
No, we were just talking.
Grandmother, Baldwin, this is Wade Walker.
They call me Cry-Baby.
This here is my sister, Pepper.
Greetings, Granny-o.
Allison's my girl, so hands off, Cry-Baby.
You could have fooled me, Square.
Mrs. Vernon-Williams, I hear you're having
a talent show at your charm school.
I can barely imagine
what you would call music.
I can sing pretty good.
"Well," not "good." Haven't you ever heard
of the English language?
-Don't go flip out, mama.
-Yeah.
Sometimes shook-up old ladies
-get cut.
-BALDWIN: Come on, honey.
They're just bums.
Mr. Puniverse wants a fat lip.
I'd like to hear you sing.
MRS. VERNON-WILLIAMS:
I will say this once and once only.
Stay away from my granddaughter,
you common juvenile delinquents.
It was nice talking to you all.
Let's go.
The prettiest and most talented girl
in school
and yet she socializes with Drapes.
We're Squares, Allison,
and Squares got to stick together.
Yeah, but Drapes are people, too.
They just look different.
Maybe Cry-Baby can sing.
Something cool, something hep.
And where did you learn
those vulgar jazz words?
Your poor dead parents
would turn over in their graves.
It's those jukebox records she listens to.
Honey,
his kind of music
isn't even on the Hit Parade.
How can I think
when you're always touching me?
I have told you, Baldwin,
a young lady does not like to be pawed.
(CRY-BABY SINGING) Well, women
and Cadillacs go hand in hand
The woman want a Cadillac
she don't want no man
I used to have a woman
said she loved me so
I think Cry-Baby's got a girlfriend.
Cry-Baby and Allison sitting in a tree,
-K-I-S-S-I-N-G.
-Shut up, Milton.
Hey, Hatchet-Face, you think Cry-Baby's
got blue balls for the chick?
Allison's a Square, Wanda.
Cry-Baby don't dig Squares.
No, she's a "Scrape."
Part Square, part Drape.
I think she's pretty.
-Cry-Baby, want some hooch?
-I don't drink and drive.
(CHEERFUL SCREAMS)
You're too young to know the shameful
truth about the Walker boy's family.
But let me warn you, evil is in his blood.
(CAR HORN BLARING)
(DRAPES SINGING) Love that girl
Oh, please, listen to me
-Move up, now.
-That's not funny.
Why I love that girl
Love that girl
Hold me, baby, squeeze me
Never let me go
I'm not taking chances
You're a dead man, Walker.
Oh, gee
Yes, I love her
BALDWIN: Car! Car!
(EXCLAIMING)
(CAR HORNS BLARING)
(DRAPES WHOOPING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(DAINTY INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen
and welcome
to the annual RSVP Talent Show.
ALL: Good afternoon, Mrs. Vernon-Williams.
First, I must apologize
for my frazzled nerves.
However, this afternoon we were attacked
by a gang of juvenile delinquents.
It's all right. No one was injured.
Juvenile delinquents are everywhere.
Right here in this community.
Boys with long hair and tattoos,
who spit on the sidewalk.
-Can't believe it.
-MAN: How disgusting.
Girls who wear tight slacks.
Hysterectomy pants, I call them.
And if one of these creatures
ever approach you on the street,
you are to silently repeat to yourself
the four "B's" you learned here at RSVP.
And what are they, children, the four "B's"?
ALL: Beauty, brains,
breeding, bounty!
Yes!
Teenagers everywhere, repent!
Let Jesus Christ be your gang leader!
Get out of Turkey Point before it's too late.
Thank you very much for the picture,
sweetheart. Oh, yeah.
All right, who's up next here?
Toe-Joe Jackson's art photography
right here!
Be a nudie-cutie,
make good money to bootie.
I'm paying $3 a shot.
What the hell, you got it,
why not show it, right?
Hey, you.
Yeah, you, the looker
with the class-A sealed-beam headlights.
-You want to pose for Toe-Joe?
-Beat it, creep.
Here he comes now, with that devil woman.
-Hi, Mrs. Hackett.
-Imagine our shame.
Our only child,
and he carries illegal weapons,
drives fast cars
and wears clothes
obviously designed by homosexuals.
But he knows better.
Jesus is still in his heart.
Mom and Dad, go home.
You're embarrassing me.
I'm a teenager. I want to live.
(JAZZY MUSIC PLAYING)
-Looks like somebody lost their laundry.
-Hello, Cry-Baby.
-You scorch me, man.
-Later, Lenora.
But, Cry-Baby, I need a date
for tonight's Jukebox Jamboree.
I'm solo, sugar.
Want to see these gunboats?
I give, Cry-Baby.
-I give bare second on the first date.
-Use your mentality and cool down.
Lenora, your bosoms ain't nothing.
Better watch it, bozo.
You might catch a cold.
My brother wouldn't touch your titties
with a 10-foot pole.
He likes his women bad, Lenora, not cheap.
(SINGING DOO-WOP)
(SINGING) Life could be a dream
If I could take you up in paradise up above
If you would tell me
I'm the only one that you love
Life could be a dream, sweetheart
Hello, hello again
Sh boom I'm hoping we'll meet again
Oh, life could be a dream
If only all my precious plans
would come true
If you would let me spend
my whole life loving you
Life could be a dream, sweetheart
Sh boom sh boom
Sh boom
Now, every time I look at you
Something is on my mind
If you'd do what I want you to
Baby, we'd be so fine
Oh, life could be a dream
If I could take you up in paradise up above
If you would tell me
I'm the only one that you love
Life could be a dream, sweetheart
Hello, hello again
Sh boom I'm hoping we'll meet again
Sh boom sh boom
Life could be a dream, sweetheart
(HILLBILLY INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
CRY-BABY: Uncle Belvedere!
You caught me in my birthday suit,
butt-naked.
Grandma, we're home!
-How much?
-That muffler?
Dupree, for you,
-$15, take it or leave it.
-Come on, Ramona.
$10. This thing's hotter than a pistol.
You guys wanna do business with Ramona
Rickettes or would you rather shop at Sears?
Now, give me the bread
and keep your trap shut.
-You're a hard woman.
-I'm going to see you in hell, Dupree.
(LAUGHS) Go on, get out of here.
(IMITATING GUNSHOTS)
Have you been bothering your
great-grandma all day? She has customers.
-Hell, no. They helped me steal a car.
-It's a '51 Olds.
-It's really cool.
-That's my little Snare-Drum.
-And Ma, I swiped six hubcaps like a big girl.
-Way to go, Susie-Q.
Make those monster faces, Hatchet. Please.
Goddamn gopher's digging up
my front yard.
What are you teenagers waiting for?
Turkey Point is open for business!
Let's celebrate! Yee-haw!
(ALL WHOOPING)
Come on, everybody. Come on in.
Today's a special day for me
and your grandmother.
We've been together 10 whole years.
(BOTH WHOOP)
I'm just so proud of all my Drape children.
Oh, Wanda, you sure is pretty
in them tight clothes,
all painted up like trash.
I wish you and Belvedere were my parents.
Now, Milton,
boy, you are everything a man should be.
You're young, stupid, and mean.
We're gonna play some cool music
for you tonight, Ramona.
And, Hatchet-Face. Oh, honey.
You're just like me.
Now, you put the "T" in "tough."
So hard, you could've been eating nails
for breakfast.
But that's the way
a woman's got to be these days.
I'd kick a Square's ass
for you in a minute, Mrs. Rickettes.
Aw! This is the best gang
my grandson could ever have.
Grandma, I'm so happy all knocked up,
I wish I was having triplets.
We got a little surprise for your young'un
in your oven.
-You show her, Bel.
-Sure will.
CRY-BABY: Pep, ain't that cute?
It's beautiful, Grandma.
(DAINTY INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Cry-Baby.
When you was a boy,
you had to be the man of this family.
But I taught you how to dress,
didn't I, Cry-Baby?
You sure did, Uncle Belvedere.
Yeah, well, you're the future now, boy.
You're the only future
for this godforsaken family.
And I want you to go out there tonight
and sing, boy.
I want you to sing your heart out.
You can show him now, Belvedere.
This took a lot of hubcaps, Cry-Baby.
(ALL EXCLAIMING IN AWE)
(ALL WHOOPING)
Grandmother, Uncle Belvedere,
you've made me the happiest
juvenile delinquent in Baltimore.
And guess what?
(MOTORCYCLE ENGINE STARTING)
I met a girl!
(SINGING) My friends all know it
How I adore him
I've whispered to angels
What I'd do for him
He is the answer
To a teenage prayer
He won't go steady
The crowd has told me
But I keep waiting
To have him hold me
Why won't you listen
To a teenage prayer
I wait by the window at 7:00
And chill when my thrill passes by
His kiss could send me to heaven
Into his arms I would fly
(MOTORCYCLE ENGINE RUMBLING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Stay in your places.
Whiffle!
(WOMEN GASP)
Get back to your room.
BOY 1: Is he here? I can't see anything.
BOY 2: That's him.
Cry-Baby Walker.
(SIGHS)
(DRAMATIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
I'm sorry about this afternoon,
Mrs. Vernon-Williams.
Is Allison home?
'Cause I'm gonna sing tonight
and I thought she might like to hear me.
Baldwin! Mind your manners.
This is what we think of your kind of music.
How dare you hit him!
You don't own me, Baldwin.
I have the right to hear Cry-Baby sing.
Don't get all worked up, honey.
The punk got what he deserved.
Come on.
(WHIMSICAL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Allison!
Get up. Go!
Hop on, honey.
Just one minute, young lady...
I'll take good care of her,
Mrs. Vernon-Williams. I promise.
And it's okay about my face.
It don't hurt much.
Please.
It's not a school night,
and I have been a good girl.
Just one night of happiness, that's all I ask.
-But what if you get your dress dirty?
-Thank you, Grandmother.
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(RAMONA SINGING) I have a girlfriend
She says I'm her only one
We wanna get married
But we're so young
So young
Can't marry no one
They say our love is just teenage affection
But we know our heart's direction
So young
Can't marry no one
You okay?
I didn't get no axle grease on you, did I?
No. I'm fine.
-Been to Turkey Point before?
-My grandmother wouldn't let me.
She calls it the Redneck Riviera.
It's where I live. Beautiful, ain't it?
ALLISON: It's really wild.
But I'm afraid
that I'm not going to fit in here.
You know, with your friends and stuff.
You're cool, Allison. You just look Square.
Underneath it all, I think you're really hep.
Well, what have we here?
First Square to ever set foot in Turkey Point.
Hey, fine mama.
Welcome to the Jukebox Jamboree.
These are the Cry-Baby girls. That's Wanda.
Dig it, babe. You need a new look.
Don't you got tits?
Stick them out, for God's sake.
That's Hatchet-Face.
She don't mean no harm.
First thing a Cry-Baby girl learns,
our bazooms are our weapons.
Now, Pepper's pregnant.
But she can fight like a man.
I wouldn't be caught dead in a full skirt.
Hey, girls. What do you think?
Let's give Allison here
a bad-girl beauty makeover. Are you game?
Sure.
Think I got what it takes?
(GIRLS EXCLAIMING)
You got it, Allison.
You got it raw.
Hey, dig it, all you hep cats and cool chicks.
You know me. Ramona Rickettes!
Now let me introduce to you
the Cry-Baby Combo,
Milton, Pepper, Wanda, Hatchet-Face.
BOTH: Hi, Mom.
And now, the baddest baby of them all,
the man you came here for,
the big boo-hoo,
the terrible teardrop,
ladies and gentlemen,
my grandson, Cry-Baby!
(INDISTINCT)
(WOMEN CHEERING)
(SINGING) Well, one for all and all for one
And all we want is to have some fun
Squares beware of our property
Yeah, if you're looking to rumble
You're looking at me
-'Cause I'm the king
-King cry-baby
'Cause I'm the king
King cry-baby
Yeah, I'm the king
A king cry-baby with a tear in my eye
If you mess with the king
you're gonna cry, baby, cry
Baby cry, baby cry, baby cry, wow!
Well, I was born
on the wrong side of the tracks
In the back seat of a stolen Cadillac
I had my first cigarette before I could walk
And I was strumming this guitar
before I could talk
'Cause I'm the king
King cry-baby
Yeah, I'm the king
Oh, I'm the king
King cry-baby
A king cry-baby with a tear in my eye
If you mess with the king
you're gonna cry, baby, cry
Baby cry, baby cry, baby cry
Well, I'm a lonely king who needs a queen
Yeah, you're the sweetest lump of sugar
that I've ever seen
Ain't got a ring or crown for you
Well, if I had your love
I'd lose these cry-baby blues
She's the queen
-Go on up there, honey.
-Go on.
She's the queen
(SINGING) Well, let people talk, I don't care
Let me prove to you, daddy
that I ain't no Square
You be my queen and I'll be your king
But if you leave my hive
you're gonna feel my sting
'Cause you're my queen
You're the king
A king and queen
A king cry-baby with my queen by my side
And if you mess with us, man
you're gonna cry, baby, cry
Baby cry, baby cry, baby cry
Cry, baby cry, baby cry, baby cry
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Kiss me. Kiss me hard.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I've never given a French kiss before.
Watch. It's easy.
You just open your mouth
and I open mine
and we wiggle our tongues together.
And it feels real sexy.
I won't get mononucleosis, will I?
No, Allison. Just try it.
If you don't like it, I promise I'll stop.
BOY: Break the window.
Come on. Come on.
I'm sorry, Allison.
It's just that you are so beautiful.
I want to let you, but I can't.
For my parents' sake.
Cry-Baby, they're both dead. I'm an orphan.
I'm sorry, Allison.
No wonder we're together, honey.
I'm an orphan, too.
-You are?
-Yes.
And orphans have special needs.
-Just on the outside of the shirt, okay?
-Is it okay with you?
Yes, oh, yes.
My parents were good people
and they loved me.
I want you. I need you.
I love you, too, Allison.
They had to go on a business trip together.
It was their first airplane ride.
Oh, Cry-Baby, your fingers feel so good.
I've been saving it up
for a girl like you, honey.
Mommy and Daddy took separate planes
for safety.
In case one plane crashed,
I would still have a living parent.
But, Cry-Baby, both planes crashed
and I never saw my parents alive again.
Goddamn! Lightning!
-What's the matter, Cry-Baby?
-Everything is the matter.
It's just a thunderstorm. Heat lightning.
-It's sexy.
-It's not sexy. Electricity makes me insane.
Why, Cry-Baby, why?
Here's why. Electricity killed my parents.
-They died in the electric chair?
-That's right, Allison.
My father was the Alphabet Bomber.
He may have been crazy, but he was my pop.
The only one I ever had.
God. I heard about the Alphabet Bomber.
Bombs exploding in the airport
and barbershop.
That's right, all in alphabetical order.
Carwash, drugstore.
I used to lay in my cradle
and hear him scream in his sleep.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G
(IMITATES BOMB EXPLODING)
-But your mom?
-My mother tried to stop him.
She couldn't even spell, for Christ's sake,
but they fried her, too.
But I'll pay them all back, Allison.
That's why, every day, I gotta do
something rotten for my parents' sake
and I cry for what I have to do.
But not much, though.
One single, salty tear
is all that they'll ever suck out
of this Cry-Baby.
Cry-Baby!
(GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION)
(CACKLING)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I'm going to have his baby.
BALDWIN: Allison!
-Oh, my God. What have they done to you?
-Allison, come home.
They beat me and kicked me.
All because I love you.
(ENGINE STARTING)
Get on.
Don't do it, Allison.
No!
ALL: (CHANTING)
Too smart to work, too cool to care.
Come to Turkey Point, man, if you dare.
Too smart to work, too cool to care...
Let her go. She's with me.
Her name is Allison and she is a nice girl.
Allison, I'm sorry to get you locked up.
But tonight, well, you were
the coolest date I ever had.
But, Cry-Baby, who is that girl?
Why didn't you tell me
you already had a lady friend?
Lenora ain't nothing to me,
I swear on my daddy's grave.
I'm burning inside to touch you, baby.
MAN 1: How do you feel about
your granddaughter becoming a Drapette?
MAN 2: Mrs. Vernon-Williams,
a picture, please.
Please, no pictures.
-Get your sloppy paws off me!
-Let go of me!
Order. Order in this courtroom.
What a sad vision of today's youth.
The juvenile authorities have had it
with Drape gangs.
Milton Hackett.
Wanda Woodward.
Mona Malnorowski,
also known as Hatchet-Face.
You are blights on this community.
-Are the parents here?
-Yes, Your Honor.
We have been praying all night for our son.
And praying so hard that we got headaches.
Hi, Wanda honey.
You were on the radio.
Would you just get me
the (BLEEP) out of here?
What's (BLEEP) mean, Hector?
Oh, Meg, it's just a teen nonsense word
Wanda uses to make herself feel all grown-up.
Your Honor,
could we take Wanda the fuck home?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Good God!
Order. Order in this courtroom.
You hear that, Your Honor?
It's a sign.
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
She is speaking in tongues.
God is in her gullet. And he is in yours, too.
Let him out.
Let the words of the Savior be heard.
Order! Order!
No wonder your children are in trouble.
And you, Miss Malnorowski...
By the way, that's a shame about your face.
There's nothing the matter with my face.
I got character.
I see that your parents haven't taken
the trouble to come to get you.
Oh, yes, we did.
You happy now, Mona, huh?
You finally did it.
You put your own mother in an iron lung.
Mrs. Malnorowski,
there is no smoking in this courtroom.
Why not?
I pay taxes on cigarettes, don't I?
And what do I get for those taxes?
Happiness? Hell, no.
I get tuberculosis.
(TIRE BURSTS)
Oh! Christ! Now I got a flat tire.
I'm going to release these delinquents
to their parents' custody.
And if they were mine,
I'd give them a bare-assed whipping.
Ramona and Belvedere Rickettes,
I find you guilty of disturbing the peace
and I fine the both of you $1,000.
-That's all we have.
-How are we supposed to live?
Damn you. Handcuff those brats.
Don't touch my children.
And you, Pepper Walker,
I'm going to have your two children
put in the custody
of the Chatterbox Orphanage
until they're adopted
by God-fearing parents
who at least will give them Christian names.
PEPPER: Not my children. They're my
flesh and blood. They're all I have!
Mrs. Tadlock.
PEPPER: Get away from them.
(ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Don't you touch them kids!
(JUDGE POUNDING GAVEL)
(KIDS SCREAMING)
Come on.
PEPPER: I love you, children.
Wade Walker, better known as Cry-Baby,
what a sad and silly name for a young man.
You were the ringleader
in tonight's gang war.
Grandmother, help him.
We were just singing together.
Judge, let Allison go
and I'll take the full blame.
I didn't mean no harm,
Mrs. Vernon-Williams.
I may be a Drape,
but I love your granddaughter.
And if that's a crime,
I'll stand convicted, ma'am.
I am going to release Allison this one time
because you are a fine
and beautiful woman, Mrs. Vernon-Williams.
But not you, Cry-Baby Walker.
The only place you're going to sing
is in jail.
No!
I find you guilty
of rampant juvenile delinquency
and I hereby sentence you
to the Maryland Training School for Boys
until your 21st birthday.
(EXCLAIMS)
Court dismissed.
Lock him up!
You can't lock up his music!
(ALL CLAMORING)
I'll get out, sugar dumpling,
I'll get out, if it's the last thing I do!
I swear.
Cry-Baby!
Boy, do I have a story for you.
How does it feel to be a juvenile delinquent?
It feels good, man.
I've never been so happy in my whole life.
Lenora, you filthy hag.
I wouldn't let you shine my boots!
Allison's my girl.
A-L-L-I-S-O-N, fellows.
REPORTER: When did he propose?
Just last night.
You see, I'm pregnant with his child.
You know that Cry-Baby is an orphan.
He wants his baby to have a real family,
for the family that he himself never had.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Delinquents, hit the sack!
I swear.
Strip down, asshole. It's beddy-bye time.
Now don't forget to say your prayers.
God bless my probation officer.
ALL: God bless my probation officer.
God bless the draft board.
ALL: God bless the draft board.
God bless the juvenile authorities.
ALL: God bless the juvenile authorities.
We're going to give you a haircut
tomorrow, pretty boy.
You ever hear of a whiffle?
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
That's what you're going to get,
you big old cry-baby, you.
(LAUGHING)
God bless Dwight Eisenhower.
ALL: God bless Dwight Eisenhower.
God bless Roy Cohn.
ALL: God bless Roy Cohn.
God bless Richard Nixon.
ALL: God bless Richard Nixon.
Nighty-night, boys.
(SOBBING)
Cry-Baby.
(SINGING) Teardrops are falling
Teardrops are falling
Cry, go on, cry
Out my eyes
Teardrops are falling
I wonder why
For you made me cry
(SINGING) Yes, teardrops are falling
Falling from my eyes
Yes, yes, yes
You made me cry
When you went away
You stayed away so long
Come back, my dear
My heart is aching
Almost breaking
If you hear me
Come back to me
Teardrops are falling
And you made me cry
Cry, go on cry
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(VIVACIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(SERENE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXCLAIMS)
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO:
Call these Drapettes bold,
call them brazen, but whatever you do,
don't call them Square.
Yes, mothers, you should be worried.
Following last night's disturbance
at Turkey Point,
Cry-Baby Walker, convicted delinquent
had the nerve to announce his engagement
to fellow gang member and known hussy,
Lenora Frigid, mother-to-be of his child.
Cry-Baby is an orphan.
He wants his baby to have a real family,
for the family that he himself never had.
ANNOUNCER: Wade Walker, defiantly entering
the Maryland Training School for Boys
had this to say...
It feels good, man.
I've never been so happy in my whole life.
(VIVACIOUS MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
Hurry, Allison, hide. The newspapers have
blown this completely out of proportion.
He lied to me, Grandmother.
And the whole world knows
that I'm just a Drape fool.
Heavy hangs the head
that last night wore the crown.
(VIVACIOUS MUSIC
PLAYING IN DISTANCE)
Allison!
I'm Baldwin and these are the Whiffles.
And we are proud to be Squares.
Allison Vernon-Williams,
you don't have to decide today.
Give your heart some time to think.
Allison, would you sing with me today?
Hey, man. Your old lady's on the radio.
There's trouble, Cry-Baby, big trouble.
Allison!
There's a new place that's opening.
It's sort of wild, kind of cool.
It's called a theme park and
it's the first one in the state of Maryland.
I'd be proud to, Baldwin.
Cry-Baby Walker,
I hope you're happy with Lenora.
I only have one thing to say to you.
I think you're a liar and a cad
and I spit on your tears.
I can sing better than Cry-Baby Walker
any day of the week.
(RADIO CRACKLING)
(GRUNTING IN FRUSTRATION)
(SCREAMING)
(SINGING) Well, I ain't here
'cause I drive too fast
And I'm too young to have a criminal past
Some good behavior would be all right
But I don't seem to qualify
I'm just out for a little fun
But I'm guilty till I'm 21
I guess I'm doing time for being young
So cut these shackles off of me
Let me go
This kind of suit don't set me free
Set me free
Well, I can't live if I can't ride
Let me ride
And I want my baby by my side
Want my baby by my side
I'm just out for a little fun
But I'm guilty till I'm 21
I guess I'm doing time for being young
Now, I can't let the right thing
stand in my way
Someday, maybe, I'll know better
But right now I'm making them pay
What do I do, who do I thank?
What can I do?
To get me out of this stinking tank
Stinking tank
It's heartbreaking to be this age
Stuck in a cage
Locked in the prison of teenage rage
Stuck in a cage with a teenage rage
Well, I was out for a little fun
I guess I'm guilty till I'm 21
I must be doing time for being young
Stuck in a cage with a teenage rage
I don't want to be doing time
for being young
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Who the hell is this?
This is Inga. She's from Sweden.
She's an exchange student and
she's going to be staying with us for a while.
Inga, this is our daughter, Wanda. Say hello.
Ja?
(SCOFFS) I'm blowing this joint.
Inga doesn't understand English very well.
Inga, say hello to Wanda.
Ja?
(ENUNCIATING) Say hello to our daughter.
Honey, why don't you come over
and sit down? Get to know one another.
Look at all the wonderful presents
she's brought us from her native land.
Let's all put on a folk hat
and learn something about a foreign culture.
Do we have a surprise for you.
Don't we, Meg?
We sure do.
All this silly trouble
you've been having lately...
Wanda, honey, you're going to Sweden
this afternoon at 3:00.
You mean you swapped me?
For a milkmaid?
Oh, honey,
Inga's mater and pater will treat you
just like one of the family.
Ja, Inga?
Ja? Ja? Ja?
(ALL MOCKING)
-Hey, you going my way?
-Oh, it's you.
You ever hear of something
called a theme park?
Yeah, there's a big opening
over there today.
That's where I'm going, stallion.
Well, hop on in. (LAUGHS)
Hold on, homeboy.
Almost done.
I know it hurts,
but being this cool's always a pain.
The pain ain't nothing, Dupree.
I've been hurt all my life,
but real tears wash away.
Ow!
This one's for Allison
and I want it to last forever.
There you go. It's a beauty.
You never have to cry again.
I heard talking in here.
What's that on your face, blubber-boy?
-A booger?
-Are you blind? It's a lonely teardrop.
Ain't that cute? It ought to go real good
with your new haircut. (LAUGHS)
-I ain't getting no haircut.
-You want to bet?
You're next, sniffle-snot.
(LAUGHING)
(WHISPERING) Cry-Baby, look!
It's your only chance, man.
Nobody's going to turn me Square, Dupree.
I want my girl,
I want my family, and I want my gang.
Thanks for the tattoo.
(EXCLAIMING IN FEAR)
Come on, gorgeous.
(LIVELY ROCK 'N' ROLL MUSIC PLAYING)
Look. Is that the prison?
Move over, Milton. Let me try.
Geronimo!
-What do we have here?
-Who is that?
This is a jailbreak!
CRY-BABY: Come on!
Hatchet!
Cry-Baby, where are you?
-Cry-Baby!
-PRISONER 1: He's in the library!
PRISONER 2: No, he's in the cafeteria!
PRISONER 3: No, man, he's in the hole.
PRISONER 4: Come on, man, no, this way,
he's in the movies. That way!
Cry-Baby!
WOMAN ONSCREEN: Hurry, David.
MAN ONSCREEN: I've almost got it.
(SCREAMING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING IN FEAR)
Hurry up!
(SCREAMING)
(MICE SQUEAKING)
(DRAMATIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(EXCLAIMS)
What's down here?
What, this way?
Thanks, pal.
(OFFICERS LAUGHING)
(CACKLING)
Just come right this way.
Now this is Sheila.
She's Caucasian,
but that's about all I can recommend.
Bad table manners.
We were thinking of two children, actually.
-About 6 or 7 years old.
-With some spunk.
Well, what about him?
Little Joey, mother's little helper.
He not only vacuums, he does windows.
Irons. Yes.
Here, these are the ones we want.
A double-header!
They're adorable. We'll take them.
Uh-uh! Now, that's a thing with two heads,
absolutely not.
Siamese twins are a financial burden.
Sewing all those
old school clothes together.
You're not psychologically equipped.
Mrs. Tadlock, these are my children
and I'm taking them with me.
That's right, sister.
You!
(AMUSING INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Let me out of here. Help.
Come on, we got to get
to the Enchanted Forest. Turn left.
No, turn right.
(SINGING) Mister Sandman
Yes?
(SINGING) Bring me a dream
I am the cutest that she's ever seen
Give her the word that I'm not a rover
Then tell her that
her lonesome nights are over
-What?
-Shh!
(ALLISON SINGING)
Mister Sandman, I'm so alone
Don't have nobody to call my own
Please turn on your magic beam
Mister Sandman, bring her a dream
Mister Sandman, bring us a dream
Give him a pair of eyes
with that come-hither gleam
Give him a lonely heart like Pagliacci
And lots of wavy hair like Liberace
Mister Sandman, someone to hold
Would be so peachy before we're too old
So please turn on your magic beam
Mister Sandman, bring us
Please, please, please
Mister Sandman, bring us a dream
Drapes!
Allison Vernon-Williams,
the decision is yours.
You sang with the Squares.
Now sing with the Drapes.
(CHEERING)
WOMAN: Cry-Baby needs you.
We'll get married and live in suburbia.
I love you, Allison.
I don't want to hurt you, Baldwin.
I had my baby. Isn't he cute?
I'm a Square now.
Wave to Allison.
You maybe a Square, Lenora,
but you're still a tramp.
(ALL GASP)
Allison, pick the man
who loves you the most.
(SINGING) Please, Mr. Jailer
won't you let my man go free?
Please, Mr. Jailer
He don't belong in prison
though he's guilty as can be
But the only crime he's guilty of
is simply loving me
Please, Mr. Jailer
won't you let my man go free?
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Please, Mr. Jailer
won't you let this jailbird free?
(VOCALIZING)
Just look into his eyes
Open up that door
Just listen to his guitar
you'll know the score
Please, Mr. Jailer
let an honest man go free
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Please, Mr. Jailer
don't you make no lifer out of me
I'm innocent, I swear it
Let my woman testify
She'll tell you where I was that night
Yeah, I'm his alibi
Please, Mr. Jailer
won't you let my man go free?
Well
I'm tired of pressing license plates
down in this rotten hole
I gotta reach the outside
before I lose control
Please, Mr. Jailer
don't you make no lifer out of me
MAN: Walker. Wade Walker, you have a visitor.
Please, Mr. Jailer
let me out of this penitentiary
Let me out
Please, Mr. Jailer
don't you make no lifer out of me
won't you let my baby go free?
(VOCALIZING)
Let my man go free
Don't make no lifer out of me
Please, Mr. Jailer
Can't you see how much love
she's got for me?
(GNARLS)
Well
Let him go, let him go
Let him go
Let my man go free
Please, Mr. Jailer
Well, let me out
Don't make me shout
Please, Mr. Jailer
Well, let me out
(ALL CLAMORING)
Criminal!
Cry-Baby Walker, society has given you
a second chance.
You're rehabilitated now.
(CHEERING)
(BOOING)
Here is $3.50.
And a pair of clean underwear.
You think you're a big man, Cry-Baby.
But you're lower than your dead father.
Guess who pulled the switch on that jerk?
My grandpappy, that's who.
(PEOPLE LAUGH)
And every Christmas since,
my whole family gathers together
and he re-tells the story of the day
he electrocuted your daddy
and we just laugh.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Let me punch his ugly face.
It's okay, Hatchet. You're beautiful, baby.
But I'll take care of this maggot.
Do you know how to play
the automobile game called "chicken"?
(LAUGHS) Sure, my car and your jalopy.
We head toward one another at full speed.
First one to turn the wheel before we smash
is a chicken.
(IMITATING HEN CACKLING)
Is that legal?
Stop this insanity.
I got some new rules, sucker.
How about you and me on top of the car?
(INDISTINCT)
I'm man enough, you big cry-baby.
That's Mr. Baby to you.
Fellows of the press,
this chicken race tonight is for my daddy.
And I'd like to sing something
in his memory, something hillbilly.
Something colored.
Something my daddy would've loved.
(SINGING) You call us hoods
and say we've gone mad
'Cause we feel so good
when we're being bad
We're high school hellcats
On our own
High school hellcats
Almost grown
Come on and pick a fight
I wish you would
We love being bad
'cause it sure feels good
Baldwin, please. Be a gentleman
and call off this race, it's too dangerous.
Mrs. Vernon-Williams, you were born a Square
and you're gonna die a Square.
You're coming with me.
(SINGING) Yeah, stand back, look out
We're renegade teens
Friends of the devil
But twice as mean
We're looking for kicks
We want them now
We're gonna get them
And we don't care how
We're high school hellcats
On our own
High school hellcats
Almost grown
Come on, pick a fight
We wish you would
We love being bad
'Cause it sure feels good
Come on! Come on! Come on! (WHOOPS)
Well, you lock us up in your schools
We weren't born to live by rules
-Get down from there this minute.
-Sit down, you traitor.
When you say stop I say go, cats, go
We're high school hellcats
On our own
Come on, baby!
Almost grown
What are you doing?
Wish you would
-We love being bad
-'Cause it feels so good
USA, the land of the free
We should be what we want to be
But everyone says we should be like them
But we're high school hellcats
and we never fit in
We're high school hellcats
Allison, help! Help me!
(CRY-BABY SINGING)
Come on and pick a fight, we wish you would
We love being bad
'cause it sure feels good
We're high school hellcats
Come on and pick a fight
we wish you would
We love being bad
'cause it sure feels good
'Cause it sure feels good
Turn the wheel!
Chicken!
(WHOOPING)