Where the hell is Mrs. Sulee's house!
This way!
Mrs.! Mrs.!
Mrs.! Hurry up! Mrs. Sulee!
Open up please! We need your help!
Be strong, Sulee will help you!
It's a Cambodian curse.
ART OF THE DEVIL II
When people are under stress,
the human brain will work harder.
What happens afterwards
is called an anxiety disorder.
The symptoms will be clearly noticed...
...when the person has mild to severe
headaches, and is agitated easily.
People with anxiety disorders will also
have sweaty palms, and be easily
distracted.
For those that are not
treated, suicides are common.
Okay, that's all for today, and
don't forget to do your assignment.
Hey! If you guys want to make
out, do it outside the classroom.
Some people in here are trying to learn.
Hello, Ta, is that you?
What is it?
Just spit it out. I don't
have all day, you know.
I've got a lot of studying
to do, and I'm tired. Goodbye.
Por! What the heck is your problem!
Surprise! Happy Birthday!
It was a joke!
Oh really? A joke huh?
Hey! Kim, we've been friends forever.
You know how I feel about you.
I want to know if we can
be more than just friends.
I think this is a bit more than friends.
Hello?
Hello? It's for you, Por.
Ta!
What? Since when did Ta's dad die?
Yeah, yeah. it's actually good this way.
I haven't seen Ta since we graduated.
Hey there! When did this happen, Por?
Great...
This way we can hang out
together just like the old days!
What? Noot? Oh she's
the same, never changes.
Lover boy, let's be real close.
As for true love, nobody knows.
My wife I love so much.
Why am I going?
I already told you! I'm going
on a trip with my friends!
Listen, if you want me
to go back, pick me up!
Otherwise, don't even
bother calling! Goodbye!
Who were you talking to?
No one.
Come on, let's go. Our train is here.
Shut up, Ko. Don't even
bother getting aboard!
Go away!
Two years after our
high school's graduation...
...we all seem changed somehow, from
a regular group of rural school kids...
...to the grown ups we are now.
But for me, it's as if the
memories of our old path...
...slowly are emerging into clear sight.
If life is filled with
many paths to take...
...then what's most important...
...are all the junctions where we
choose...
...and how it shapes our futures.
For me, this event made me realize that
the future comes from our wishes.
As for our past, it actually defines us.
2 YEARS AGO
Kim!
I'll read it as soon as I can.
I better get going.
Hurry up, slow poke!
So that's why you are always late!
Been hitting on the chicks here, huh?
You're slick, you know
that? Go ahead, drive on!
Hey Kim, what is it? May I see it?
Don't be silly.
He's a cute guy, and the
district's top athlete too!
Come on, knock it off!
Kim, watch out, Kaew is right there.
There are kids everywhere here.
Oh, they're just here to help
the teacher check the homework.
Here is the money.
You want a smoke?
Oh, no thanks. The
teacher wouldn't like that.
Hey, Por, pass me another one.
Ko! Stop fooling around!
Ko! Careful with the marks,
you're going to mess it up!
Why the weird patterns?
Nothing wrong with a little zig zag.
To heck with the zig zags.
A zig zag line to love, babe.
Cut it out.
I've got dessert for us.
Wow, that's so generous of you,
Teacher!
Ko, careful there with the drawings!
So how is it with the grading?
We're almost done now.
Can I see?
Ko slacked off a lot.
Kim, you're skilled with your English!
Why don't you eat dear?
You came all the way to my house and...
...if you go back without
trying my famous pickled mangos...
...you're going to miss
out on something good.
Thank you.
Mom, I need 1000 baht.
I'll be right back, kids.
She is really a nice teacher.
Her brother Ta asked for money
and she didn't even hesitate.
That Nong is a momma’s boy.
But Ta here, is a daddy’s boy.
In this house, the
mother has the upper hand.
Hey, who hit my head?
Want to race? Hurry up!
Por, when Ko said that Ta is a
daddy’s boy, what did he mean by that?
Oh, Ta is Prawaet's son.
Mr. Prawaet fell in love with Mrs.
Panor after Ta's real mom died.
Anyway, our teacher, Panor
gave birth to Nong later.
Ta favors his father
more than our teacher, Panor.
You see Ta being so studious,
but it's all for his dad's sake.
Hang on Kim. See you later, Ta!
Kim, Kim...
We're here.
Hey, Ta...
Ta!
Ta! How are you!
Did you miss us or what?
I missed all of you guys.
Hey Ta!
Sorry about your dad and all.
You doing all right?
I'm fine, and you?
Haven't seen you in a while Kim. You
okay?
I'm okay.
Let's go guys. Your dad
is waiting for us by now.
Ko, you and your filthy mouth!
Hey buddy, check out Noot.
Haven't seen her for two years.
Now, she got a great
body, don't you think?
What I wouldn't do to get me some of
that.
You want some? I'll
share. It's all good.
Ta, so what's up with that story?
Are you going to fill
us in or what?
Well, after you guys
graduated...
Mom had problem after problem.
Actually, I just came back home.
Wait up, so where have you been?
Disciplinary school. Nong
was the one with the problems.
But I couldn't help in time.
He drowned on purpose. I
got caught as the scapegoat.
After that, dad shot himself.
I just got released actually, so now I can
take care of my father's funeral.
It was a long time ago, buddy.
I think you should just forget about it.
Hey, why don't we talk
about all this at Ta's house.
It's hot and muggy here.
Noot, let's go.
Look over there!
There's something going on over there!
Stop! You are under arrest!
Ko, take Nong with you.
Get down on the ground!
You know these hooligans?
No.
Remember this 'til the day you die.
If you want to screw your life
up somewhere, it's your business.
Just don't bring my
son into it! Do you understand me?
You retard! The both
of you, father and son!
Hey! Insult me, not dad. He's
got nothing to do with this.
You dare raise your voice with me?
How dare you even talk back
to me! You pathetic bastard!
Ta!
That's enough! Come on.
And as for you, calm down. Stop
it already. Come on, let's go.
Fine! You hate me so much.
Just remember, when you are a low
life thief, you'll remember this day.
Ta, you are something, you know that.
How come you have to hate her so
much?
If not for yourself, then have
some sympathy for me at least.
After some rubbing ointment,
you'll probably feel better.
Remember, just don't do it again.
One more thing, I want you to love
Nong.
He is your only brother
at the very least.
Wow, this is cool! It's
like heaven.
I love it here!
Take it easy there. Easy does it.
Check it out! Pawn's
stuff is really good.
They say it's from Cambodian rituals.
Nong even came here to do his tattoo.
No knife or blade can
cut through his skin.
Ta? You've seen it, right?
You first, Ko.
Drink up! Drink up!
Cheers!
Everyone who's not my student, get out.
So now you are learning
to drink? Are you not?
Coach...
Shut up! Who said you could talk?
What is your ID number?
Hey!
Want to be a bully?
You want to drink? Want to be a drunk?
Come here! Come here!
Drinking!
Drunken students!
Tomorrow, bring your parents.
I'm going to make you remember this.
You believe him too?
His words aren't believable!
He causes problems everyday.
Him and his crazy friends just got into
trouble with the officials...
...if you remember!
You think it over.
It's his word over mine!
Ta, I've told you countless times
not to bad mouth your stepmother.
But dad! I saw them together.
Make sure this never happens again!
Dad...
We still have to do our daily
cleaning chores in that room...
...I say lets steal that
camera and put it to good use.
Ta, listen to me man, if you
do this both the coach and...
...our teacher, Panor can
kiss their futures goodbye.
Who's there?
Hurry up! Why are you
still standing here?
Hey! Stop it!
Come back here!
Tair!
You all know that you've
just finished up your probation.
And now that you have stolen school
equipment, it will mean expulsion.
I have to hand you over to the police.
Coach, I'm begging you not
to call the police on us.
This would mean I need
something in return.
May I?
No. Please stop. I'm begging you.
Please, I'm begging you.
Let's get out of here!
Go on!
Stop it right there!
Other than theft of school property...
...you'll be charged with
battery and assault.
You all want to go to jail or what?
You are really asking for
jail time? What about you?
What the hell are you doing!
But don't worry, I've got just
the thing to set you all free.
You bastard.
Stop! You better not touch
her! You're not human!
You low life!
You let me go this instant!
You hear me? Stop it! Bastard!
Let me go! You bastard!
Stop it!
No!
You bastard!
Let go of me!
Damn!
Before you decided to come here to
see me, you've thought it over already?
It's like riding on the back of a tiger.
You never know when it
will turn around and bite.
I'm just warning you all.
Things of this nature, once tried, it
will stick with you 'til the day you die.
Understand?
The way to do this right, you
have to get proper mediums.
Birth dates...
Personal photo...
Personal property...
Lastly, you need the dirt he steps upon.
Can you get me all those things?
Don't even think of opening your eyes.
Good day there.
Good day to you.
The food here is good.
I eat here all the time.
Hey guys, did you hear
about the coach? He's dead!
How many time I have to tell you, Ko?
No more talk about that incident.
Anyone seen Ta around?
What's going on?
What's happening?
Hey, where are you going?
Let's go find out.
Get out of the way!
Hey Ta, are you listening?
Uh, yeah. I'm listening.
So, what happened after that?
I wondered, why your stepmom never
went to your father's cremation.
Or is she still angry about it all?
She's back making her living
selling pickled mangoes again.
I don't know man, I just live
my life, and she has her own.
We don't talk much.
Come on Kim. Careful there.
That's fifty baht each?
Yes.
Here's the money.
Thanks for the ride.
Sir, you gave us the wrong change!
Oh, hello there, grandmother.
We'll be staying on this side.
If it isn't necessary, don't go
over there and bother grandma.
Oh boy, your room's a mess.
It's livable.
You guys just leave
your stuff here for now.
First go pay respects to the shrine,
while I make your beds up. All right?
Sure thing. Come on, let's go.
Come on, Kim.
Por, do you think that teacher
Panor will be happy to see us?
Um, I'm not too sure.
Oh for crying out loud.
Just tell Kim that you're not sure if our
teacher Panor is still crazy or not!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Quicken up the pace!
Work hard. Hurry up.
Teacher, are you...
I mean how are things?
And what about you kids?
How do you think I am?
You're still beautiful.
I'm old now.
Um, what's the matter, teacher?
Oh my uncle's calling me.
Excuse me.
Hello.
I hear that my students all moved out
of here to the big city of Bangkok.
How is it there? Further study?
Por is a law student...
...while Ko over here is
an engineering student.
Noot is studying English and
preparing to go to Australia with Tair.
You are always the chatty girl.
And from the number two
student of the class, too.
Well, I'm flattered by that.
But I'd be proud if I was
number one instead of two.
So what field are you
studying in these days?
I'm studying to be a doctor.
Really? Is it true, Mister?
You're not pulling my chain
or anything like that, are you?
Yes, yes I'll try to find a
way to go as quickly as I can.
Hello? Hello?
Anyone here have a signal?
Can I borrow your
phone to call back home?
No luck.
There is no signal here.
You can only get a signal by
that old shrine over there.
Oh great, what am I going to do?
Noot? What's the urgency?
Well, right now my
dad is in the hospital...
And my uncle is waiting
for me at the train station.
So I don't think I can stay.
Woah, really?
So you really have to go back right
now?
Don't be angry at me. Please?
I really have to go back. All right?
Don't be angry. Don't be angry.
Wow! What a view! Next time,
call us before things get hot!
Hey Ko, shut it already!
Oh man...
Noot! Are you finished yet?
The teacher told us to come get you.
Yeah, just finish up doing
what you girls do, and let's go!
Screw you!
Hey, thinking of Noot's tongue?
I'll let you borrow mine for now.
You're really asking for it!
Any of you guys seen Ta around?
I can't find him anywhere.
I saw him in the garden over there.
Por, I think Ta is uncomfortable with
you and Kim being couples and all.
You should clear it up with Ta.
Ta, have you thought
of your future at all?
I think of it all the time and
I put great effort into it.
I made the cut for my
studies as a doctor and...
...mom and pop are
really happy about it.
I really want to give it my best shot.
We should split up.
Kim! I don't understand!
I am proud of you and your grades.
But I don't see why we
can't still see each other.
You don't understand.
You're right. I don't understand.
I don't get why we have to break up.
You wanted to know everything
about me and I've told you.
What else do I have to do?
Ta, let me go! You're hurting me!
Everything that happened... I
didn't start it! You understand?
Tell me the real
reason why. Why the breakup?
Let go of me!
I just want to choose what's good
for me and, you're not the one for me!
You're not the one!
Damn!
Por, if you keep doing
that, I'll really be angry.
Por, did you hear something just now?
What sound?
It's nothing. Probably the wind.
Um, Kim?
If you're finished, I'd
like a word with you.
I have something to say.
So do I.
Ta...
Sometimes I feel that
I am the guilty one.
You can probably see that
Por and I are a couple now.
It was my decision.
It's not Por's fault.
If it was anyone was wrong, it would be
me.
Kim...
For the past two years, I've
tried to get in touch with you.
But you never cared for me.
I never forgot you, Kim.
Please don't do that again.
Forget the past.
Let's go back to all our friends.
Where did they all go?
Ta!
It's freezing!
You guys are something!
I win!
Nice idea for fun.
Ta, you cold or something?
I swallowed some of the water.
I saw someone under the water!
You're seeing things! We're
the only ones in the water.
Hey Ta, your grandma skinny dipping?
Piss off!
It's amazing that two years have past
and everything is still the same.
I think I feel something has changed.
No seriously, I think
something has changed.
I saw it.
Ko, what did you see?
Breasts! Round mounds!
Cut it out, Ko!
Tair, call me when you
decide not to be gay.
Teacher, what's cooking?
Smells good. Spicy
chicken broth looks good.
If it looks good, take the whole pot.
And over there is
plenty of fish curry pie.
Let's setup for dinner!
Hey, kitty, kitty.
Want to eat with us, huh?
You're not going to eat with us?
Help yourself, I already had my share.
I'm going to meditate
and pray for a while.
Is there anything wrong, teacher?
You know, the more I see you kids,
the more I want to go back and teach.
Here kitty kitty. Where are you?
Come and get your dinner.
Here kitty kitty.
I'm going to leave it right here.
Kim!
Grandma!
Grandma! You can't eat that, grandma!
Stop eating it, grandma!
You kids don't care for
me! I'm hungry! Hungry!
You guys, help me out will you?
She is senile. She doesn't
know what she's eating!
Grandma, no. You need to get
some sleep. I'll take you.
But I'm starving. I can't go to sleep.
I'm hungry!
Hey Ta, how is your grandmother?
Don't worry, she's just senile.
Don't fret over it.
Hey, take it easy there.
Tair, are you scared?
Me, scared? I'm scared of nothing.
But I'm scared.
I think there's something weird about
this place. Ever since this evening.
Today, we have many guests in the
house.
Mother will have to
dress up nice and pretty.
You should too, my son.
You will probably need
to clean up a bit as well.
You may be with the three eyed
god, but I'm still worried for you.
You have to understand. I'm
doing this for your own good.
Go stay with the three eyed
god. So you will be clean.
Mother will have to clean you up now.
So that you will be clean, my dear.
We've already paid our respects
to the gods of these grounds.
I don't think there will be
any more problems from now on.
Let's go eat.
Um, this is delicious!
Hey Ko, stop being a pig. Use a spoon.
What? I'm starving.
It's just the sound of the wooden floor.
Ko! That's disgusting!
You can't handle a burp?
Here, have another one.
You freaking bastard
child. You're unclean!
Tair? What did you just say?
What? I didn't say anything.
This chicken soup is delicious!
Thank you.
Hey Ko. Stop hogging up the food.
Hey, try some of this.
Noot! The meat in the soup is Noot's!
Ta! Your stepmom isn't
completely sane yet, is she?
Ta, where is she?
I'm going to see downstairs.
She might be downstairs.
Kim?
Hey Kim!
Kim!
Wake up Kim!
What's wrong with her?
Kim!
You guys check this out.
Why is Teacher Panor doing this?
You guys remember what
Mr. Pawn told us that day?
You must eat the flesh
of those you release.
In order to gain the powers from them.
And why did she do that?
Or is it because she hasn't
forgotten about the past.
I think you should get her
on video for your dad as proof.
Yeah, I think that's a great idea!
That way, dad will finally
believe me for once.
Plus, while we're at it, might
as well show the whole school.
What do you think?
Good! The visions you want...
I'll let you see to your satisfaction.
Ta? Say something.
Your mom doesn't know anything?
I already told you that
for the past 2 years...
I wasn't here with her.
Tair? What's wrong?
Tair? What's the matter?
Calm down, Tair!
Tair!
Por! Let's all get out of here! Please!
Come on! Let's go!
A boat! Help us!
Help!! Help us! Over here!
Damn!
Over there!
Help us! Save us! Over here! Save us!
Don't interfere!
Kim!
Ta!
You want to leave me? Huh?
I think you won't be able to do that.
If you can't walk away, then you
won't leave me. Is that correct?
What do you think?
Kim.
Kim, are you all right?
Hurry up!
Kim? How is she?
Ta. Just now I saw something.
Kim?
That's my dad's gun.
Kim. How did you know
where to find that?
I don't know.
But in my visions, I saw it falling out
of his father's hand and land here.
There's someone in there!
Ta! That's your dad! T a!
What the hell is going on here?
How can this be?
We went to your father's
cremation, didn't we?
I was probably fooled the
same way you guys got fooled.
Tair. What exactly are you seeing?
Quickly, everyone hold
her down! Tair! Calm down.
Let's take her to the sacred room!
Hey guys, hurry up!
Tair! What's wrong?
Calm down. Get a grip of yourself!
I'm not going!
Let's go!
Let me go!
Tair! Tair! Tair!
Kim!
Help me! Por, help me please!
Help me please!
Kim!
Get me out of here! Open up the doors!
I forgot to tell you there is
another way into the sacred room.
Kim!
It's okay Kim. You're safe now.
If we stay in here, we should be safe.
I want you to confess!
Out of all you people
here, who is the mastermind?
I'm going to teach you all a lesson.
Who?
You?
Or you?
Please help me. I don't want to die.
I confess I was wrong.
I don't want to die
yet. Help me, please?
Tair calm down.
Tair?
I shouldn't have been involved.
I shouldn't have been involved!
Tair...
For crying out loud! Shut up for once!
What good is crying going to do!
We already have enough to deal
with, let alone your crying!
You freaking shut your mouth, Ko!
You and your filthy mouth!
I want to know, between me and
you, who's going to die first!
Didn't I tell you to shut it?
That's right, I'm not going to shut up.
I said shut your hole!
What are you going to do about it, Ko?
You guys stay away from me too!
If I hadn't known all of you, today I
wouldn't be here to see shit like this!
I said, shut up Tair!
We wouldn't have planned it out! We
wouldn't have to shoot that video!
We wouldn't have gotten into trouble!
We wouldn't have been sexually
abused by that damn coach!
We wouldn't have to eat Noot's flesh!
Tair! Tair! Tair!
That's enough!
Now will you shut up?
Didn't we all agree to never
mention that incident ever again?
Tair, you listen up!
Right now, everyone is
scared just as you are.
But what you have to do
now is calm down. Focus!
Do you understand?
Come on, let's all pray.
Let's pray that Buddha will protect us.
Tair, what the hell
are you laughing about?
What the hell are you all praying about!
Nothing can protect bad people like
you!
Tair! What the heck
is the matter with you?
I told you to stop it! You hear me!
Por, shoot her! She's not Tair anymore!
Por! Don't do it!
Teacher Panor, please... don't
hurt us. I'm afraid!
Let us go please!
Shoot her! Shoot her!
Damn you!
Ko! Get a grip, don't do it!
You dare raise your voice to me!
Ko!
Talk! You and your
filthy mouth of yours!
Now is your chance to talk!
Talk! Why don't you talk?
Ko! What the hell is wrong!
Hey Ko! What's the matter with you?
Ko! Can you hear me?
Ko! Damn!
Ko! Ko! Hey man!
Tair! Wake up! Tair!
Tair! Wake up please! Tair!
Hey! Ko!
Ko!
What are we going to do now?
Since we can't get out
of here, that means...
...that wacked out teacher is somewhere
around here, placing spells on us!
Por, you mean, you want us to...
That's right. It's our
turn to mess with her!
I'm not going! I'm not going anywhere!
We should stay right here!
Kim, you stay and look after her.
Ta, you're coming with me.
Wait!
Be careful!
The both of you.
Kim, don't you leave me here.
They are all around us!
I don't want to see them!
Tair! What do you see?
Who do you see?
You really see them,
don't you? Where are they?
Where are they? Tair! Where are they?
Tair, where are you going?
Let's check over there!
Tair! Where are you?
Tair, wait!
Kim!
Ta, wait up man!
Ta!
Come out, show yourself!
Kim!
Kim! You okay?
I've got you!
You're ok now.
This is gonna hurt!
Sit for a while.
Ta, you go check on Por.
I can't walk anymore.
You sure you're going
to be all right here?
Stay away from me!
Keep away from me!
I don't want to see any of you!
Tair.
Get away from me!
Tair. It's ok.
I'm here now. You're with me.
You'll be fine. I'm right with you.
Tair, what's wrong with you?
Stay away from me!
Don't you come closer!
Tair. It's okay.
Tair! Stop it!
Don't you come closer!
Tair! Where are you going, Tair?
Get away from me!
Tair.
Go away! I don't want to see any of you!
Get away from me!
Tair.
I don't want to see anymore!
I won't be able to see you anymore!
Tair, stop!
I won't see you anymore! I can't see!
Tair! Tair!
Tair!
Kim!
Tair?
Kim! Kim!
There you go, Kim.
It's all right Kim. There's
nothing to be afraid of.
I'm right here with you now.
So now, you don't love me anymore?
Por, what's wrong with you?
What's the matter now?
Didn't you just point a gun at me?
You really think you can shoot me?
Por! Por! Don't do it!
Shoot me!
Shoot!
I said shoot me!
Pull the trigger!
Por! No!
Damn you Ta! Get out of the
way! I'm going to kill her!
Are you nuts?
Get away from her!
Come on Kim!
So you don't want to confess, huh?
Where do you think you are going?
Why don't you tell me the truth?
You love me.
I'm going to make you confess.
Still don't want to confess?
Are you sure about this?
Hmm, you seem to attract a lot of men.
Ta, I saw your stepmom fooling
around with that coach O-Larn.
They're in the gym.
I want her to be brutally tortured!
You have to help me!
I don't know who else to turn to.
Listen well, Mrs. Panor.
There is only one way that you will
be able to win over this ordeal.
You must eat the flesh
of those that cursed you.
But it may make you insane.
Because all of his powers
will flow in your veins.
Can you remember anything now?
Don't be afraid.
No matter how dirty your past
is, I'll clean you up good.
I think, it is about time.
Please! Don't hurt me, teacher!
I'll confess! I'll confess everything!
I was the one that encouraged Ta and...
...his friends to tape you
and coach O-Larn together.
I was the one that put a curse on you.
I shouldn't have had
that affair with you!
I shouldn't have
thought of you that way.
Teacher let me go please!
Teacher, let me go please!
Por.
Kim? Ta?
Is it true, Ta?
How could you?
Kim, help me please!
Kim, I made a mistake!
I thought that we would
love each other forever, Kim!
I never thought you could be
so cruel. I never thought...
Ta! Ta, don't leave me like this!
You can have her! Just
don't leave me here!
Let's get out of here, Ta.
Ta, you bastard, come back here!
Ta, come back!
Don't leave me.
I'm not going to let you
get away that easy, my dear.
Shoot it!
Teacher! Let me go!
Let me go!
Teacher, you let me go now!
Teacher, please let me go!
Let me go!
I'm begging you to let me go.
Teacher, please I'm
begging you to let me go!
Let me go!
Please, let me go!
Teacher, please don't hurt me.
Just let me go!
Teacher, I'm begging
for you to let me go.
You shall see my face clearly.
And then you will pay a
visit to the three eyed god.
However, I have to clean you up first...
Don't worry...
There, now you are at ease.
It is time to clean you
up from the inside out.
Ta! You go on ahead. I can't go on.
No Kim, I won't leave you!
Listen, you're not going
to do anything about it?
Fine, I'll do something about it!
Hello? Hello?
Hello? Noot my dear?
Who's this?
I'm not going to let you die that easy!
I'm going to send you
to the three eyed god.
Wake up!
Now that you are clean enough, I will
now prepare you for his greatness.
Freeze! Miss, you better drop it!
Fire!
Please move away.
Move away from here!
Give us room!
Please let us pass!
Kim, hang on.
On the path of life with many choices...
...sometimes we never know what
the outcome of our choices will be.
But then again, many times we know
what we should or shouldn't do.
We just neglect to chose wisely.
However, you may be correct in
saying...
...sometimes if we had made the
right choices from the start...
...death wouldn't be so close.
Our lives, both mine and Ta's, were
spared...
...so that we may know what our
purpose in life would ultimately be.
Not for the future, or for the past.
But for the present.
We must choose the correct path
at all times for our own sake.
And I hope to see those
choices at all times.
I'm better, Dad.
Rest up! Here I brought you some
treats.
Thank you mother.
Thank you for staying with me.
Ta, let's start all over again.
Yes.
We are now at the crime
scene of the teacher, Panor.
Police have searched Mrs. Panor's
house.
Kim...
I have something I have to tell you.
I lied to you about my
time at boarding school.
I never stayed there.
I never told you because...
...I didn't think you could understand.
And the last body to be
found in the river was...
... Ta, her stepson.
It's been a long time already, I
think you should just forget about it.
Thank you.
All right, I'll help
you sweep up the place.
Come back to me, please?
Listen, if you guys want to sweet talk
each other, do it outside of school time!
It's distracting.
I want to tell you what I've
discovered after you graduated.
I wanted you to see what I've seen.
To let others experience the
pain, as I've experienced it.
She treated us badly, Kim.
Everyone died a horrible death.
Grandma was locked up in the
closet, and was starved to death.
As for me, even though it wasn't
my fault, I carried all the pain.
Everyone should help me bear the pain.
Por should not be the one for you.
Por wasn't meant for you, Kim.
Kim!
Kim, do you remember, you always
wanted me close. Didn't you?
Hey Kim, you see that guy?
He is star of the
school team. I like him.
Why tell me then? I
could steal him from you.
Don't forget you're always
number two in this school.
Want to bet?
If in one week, he won't date me,
I'll always be second to you.
Things like this, if
you try it, and do it...
...it will be with you
'til the day you die!