In sixteen hundred seven
We sailed the open sea
For glory, God and gold
and the Virginia Company
For the New World
is like heaven
And we'll all be rich and free
Or so we have been told
by the Virginia Company
So we have been told
For glory, God and gold
and the Virginia Company
- Ready to hoist the cannon?
- Right!
- Hey, look. Is that Smith?
That's him, all right.
The old sea dog.
Captain John Smith.
I've heard some amazing
stories about him.
- Are you coming
on this voyage too?
- Of course he is, you half-wit.
You can't fight Indians
without John Smith.
That's right. I'm not about to
let you boys have all the fun.
On the beaches of Virginny
There's diamonds like debris
There silver rivers flow
and gold you pick
right off a tree
With a nugget for my Winnie
And another one for me
And all the rest will go
to the Virginia Company
To glory, God and gold
And the Virginia Company
Haul on the brace!
- Come on, come on!
- Do your best!
Watch out!
Faster!
She's taking on more water!
Look out!
John! Get down here!
The cannons are breaking loose!
- Reef the topsails!
- Yes, sir!
- Steady on your course.
It's all right, Thomas.
We'll get her tied off.
Say your prayers, men!
Thomas, watch it!
Help!
- Man overboard!
- Help!
- Stay your course! He's lost!
- Pull the pins!
- Aye, sir!
Smith! Smith!
Are you crazy?
Hang on, Thomas!
I've got you!
Quick! The rope!
Heave!
Come on, lads! Pull!
- Pull! Pull!
- Put your back into it!
- Pull!
- Hang on!
There, my lucky lads.
Well, that was refreshing.
Well done, Smith.
Of course, you'd all
do the same for me.
- Oh, sure, sure.
Of course we would.
- Sure, yes. Yeah, we would.
Absolutely!
- Trouble on deck?
- Governor Ratcliffe.
- Thomas fell overboard, sir.
- Thank heavens he's been successfully retrieved.
- Well done, Smith.
- Thank you, sir.
Don't lose heart, men.
It won't be long before we reach the New World.
And remember
what awaits us there.
Freedom, prosperity...
the adventure of our lives.
You're the finest crew
England has to offer, and nothing--
not wind nor rain nor a thousand
bloodthirsty savages--
shall stand in our way.
Carry on, men!
A stirring oration, sir.
I'm sure the men
were most exhilarated.
Let us hope so.
I'll need those witless peasants
to dig up my gold, won't I?
This New World's
gonna be great,John.
I'm gonna get a pile of gold,
build me a big house...
and if any Indian tries
to stop me, I'll blast him.
You just worry about
that fortune of yours, Thomas.
- Leave the savages to me.
- You think they'll give us much trouble?
Not as much trouble
as Smith'll give them.
We'll kill ourselves an lnjun
Or maybe two or three
We're stalwart men and bold
of the Virginia Company
What do you suppose
the New World will look like?
Like all the others, I suppose.
I've seen hundreds
of new worlds, Thomas.
What could possibly
be different about this one?
lt's glory, God and gold
And the Virginia Company
Steady as the beating drum
Singing to the cedar flute
Seasons go and seasons come
Bring the corn and bear the fruit
By the waters sweet and clean
Where the mighty sturgeon lives
Plant the squash and reapa the bean
All the Earth our mother gives
Oh, great spirit, hear our song
Helpa us keepa the ancient ways
Keepa the sacred fire strong
Walk in balance all our days
Seasons go and seasons come
steady as the beating drum
Plum to seed to bud to palum
Steady as the beating drum
It's good to be home.
The Massawomecks are defeated!
With the help of our brothers,
our villages are safe again.
Your return has brought much joy to the village.
Look at all the smiling faces.
Yes, but there's one smiling face I don't see.
- Where is my daughter?
- You know Pocahontas.
She has her mother's spirit.
She goes wherever the wind takes her.
Pocahontas!
Your father's back!
Come down here!
He's back, Flit.
Come on, Meeko!
No! Not that way.
Show-off.
Uh-oh!
Pocahontas?
Pocahontas! Are you all right?
Well, you better be all right
because I'm not coming in after you!
Don't you think we're getting a--
a little old for these games?
Help me turn this thing over.
- What were you doing up there?
- Thinking.
- Meeko!
- About the dream again? Have you figured it out yet?
I know it means something.
I just don't know what.
You should ask your father about it.
Maybe I should.
Come on, Flit.
Quit playing around.
We have to get back.
...faced a determined enemy.
The battle lasted from the rising of the sun
until the evening shadows fell.
Our warriors fought with courage, but none
as bravely as Kocoum...
for he attacked with the fierce strength of the bear.
- He has proven himself to be the greatest of warriors...
- Oh, he is so handsome.
- and the finest among us...
- Hmph. I especially love his smile.
destroying every enemy in his path.
Tonight we will feast in his honour.
- My daughter.
- Wing-gapa-o, Father.
Seeing you gives me great joy.
I'm so glad you've come home safely.
Come with me.
We have much to talk about.
I want to hear everything you've been doing.
Father, for many nights now
I've been having a very strange dream.
I think it's telling me something's about to happen.
Something exciting.
Yes, something exciting is about to happen.
- Really? What is it?
- Kocoum has asked to seek your hand in marriage.
Marry Kocoum?
I told him it would make my heart soar.
But he's so serious.
My daughter, Kocoum will make a fine husband.
He is loyal and strong and will build you a good house
with sturdy walls.
With him, you will be safe from harm.
Father, I think my dream is pointing me down another path.
-This is the right path for you.
-But why can't I choose--
Pocahontas, come with me.
You are the daughter of the chief.
It is time to take your place among our people.
Even the wild mountain stream...
must someday join the big river.
As the river cuts his paath
Though the river's paroud and strong
He will choose the smoothest course
That's why rivers live so long.
They're steady
As the steady beating drum
Your mother wore this for our wedding.
It was her dream to see you
wear it at your own.
It suits you.
He wants me to be steady
like the river.
But it's not steady at all.
What I love most about rivers
is you can't stepa in the same river twice
The water's always changing
always flowing
But people, I guess can't live like that
We all must pay a price
To be safe we lose our chance of ever knowing
What's around the river bend
Waiting just around the river bend
I look once more just around the river bend
Beyond the shore where the gulls fly free
Don't know what for
What I dream the day might send
Just around the river bend
For me
Coming for me
I feel it there beyond those trees or right
behind these waterfalls
Can I ignore that sound of distant drumming
For a handsome sturdy husband who builds
handsome, sturdy walls
And never dreams that something might be coming
Just around the river bend
I look once more just around the river bend
Beyond the shore
Somewhere past the sea
Don't know what for
Why do all my dreams extend
Just around the river bend
Should I choose the smoothest course
Steady as the beating drum
Should I marry Kocoum
Is all my dreaming at an end
Or do you still
Wait for me
Dream giver
Just around the river
Bend
Is that my Pocahontas?
Grandmother Willow,
I need to talk to you.
Good morning, child.
I was hoping you'd visit today.
Oh! Why, your mother's necklace!
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
My father wants me to marry Kocoum.
Kocoum? But he's so serious.
I know. My father thinks it's the right path for me.
But lately, I've been having
this dream and I think it's--
Oh, a dream!
Let's hear all about it.
Quiet!
Now, child, you were saying.
Well, I'm running through the woods...
and then, right there in front of me, is an arrow.
As I look at it, it starts to spin.
A spinning arrow.
How unusual.
Yes. It spins faster and faster and faster
until suddenly it stops.
Hmm. Well, it seems to me...
this spinning arrow is pointing you down your path.
But, Grandmother Willow, what is my path?
How am I ever going to find it?
Your mother asked me the very same question.
She did? What did you tell her?
I told her to listen.
All around you are spirits, child.
They live in the earth, the water, the sky.
If you listen, they will guide you.
- I hear the wind.
- Yes.
What is it telling you?
I don't understand.
You will understand
Listen with your heart
Let it break upon you
Like a wave upon the sand
It's saying something's coming.
Strange clouds?
Listen with your heart
- You will understand
What do you see?
Clouds. Strange clouds.
Look at it, Wiggins.
An entire new world chock full of gold...
just waiting for me.
And scores of adventures waiting for us.
Right, Percy?
- Do you think we'll meet some savages?
- If we do, we shall be sure...
- to give them a proper English greeting.
- Ooh, gift baskets.
Oh, no. And he came so highly recommended.
It's perfect, Governor. The water's deep enough.
We can pull right up to shore.
Hey there, Percy.
- Very well, then. Give the order.
- Already done, sir.
I've got a crew assembled
and they're ready to go.
About the natives, I'm counting on you...
to make sure those filthy heathens
don't disrupt our mission.
Well, if they're anything like the savages
I've fought before, it's nothing I can't handle.
Right. That'll be all, Smith.
There's a good man.
See you, Percy.
The men like Smith, don't they?
- I've never been a popular man.
- I like you.
And don't think I don't know what those
back stabbers at court say about me.
Oh, yes, all that talk about being a pathetic
social climber who's failed at everything...
- He's tried.
- I'm very well aware that this is my last chance for glory.
But mark my words, Wiggins. When King James
sees the gold these peasants unearth...
success will be mine at last.
- Wake up! Shake a leg!
- Top off the yardarm!
- It's incredible!
- And it's all ours. I've never seen anything like it.
It could look like Ratcliffe's
knickers, for all I care...
just as long as I get off  this stinkin' boat.
Come on, men. We didn't come
all this way just to look at it.
Keep it taut, lads.
Keep it taut.
- Steady! Steady!
- Hold up! That's far enough.
All right, now. Tie her off.
Here,John, tie off this end.
John? John?
- What are you doing up there?
- Getting a better look.
Hey!
Well. You're a
strange-looking fellow.
Are you hungry?
Here you go.
Ah, it's a biscuit.
It's food. Well, sort of.
You like it, eh?
Well, try eating it for four months straight.
You got a friend back there?
Hey! Wh-- What? Watch out.
What? Get-- No, get--
Uh, look out.
John, you better get down here.
The governor's coming ashore.
All right. All right.
I'm leaving.
Did you see their skin?
They have hair on their faces like dogs.
My brothers, we must know more
about these visitors.
Kekata, what do you see?
These are not men like us...
but strange beasts with bodies
that shine like the sun...
and weapons that spout fire and thunder.
They prowl the Earth
like ravenous wolves...
consuming everything in their path.
Great Powhatan, I will lead our
warriors to the river and attack.
We will destroy these invaders
the way we destroyed the Massawomecks.
Kocoum, in that battle
we knew how to fight our enemy.
But these pale visitors
are strange to us.
Take some men to the river
to observe them.
Let us hope they do not intend to stay.
I hereby claim this land
and all its riches...
in the name of His Majesty
King James the First...
and do so name this settlement Jamestown.
Bravo! Bravo!
Beautifully spoken, sir.
Hurry now, Percy. We must be all
squeaky clean for the New World.
Captain Smith, it appears I've selected the
perfect location, eh? Not a savage in sight.
Just because we don't see them
doesn't mean they're not out there, sir.
Well, then perhaps you should venture forth
and determine their whereabouts, hmm?
If there are any Indians
out there, I'll find them.
-Now, gentlemen, to work. You men, get the ship unloaded.
-Right, sir.
You men, build the fort.
The rest of you, break out the shovels.
- It's time to start digging.
- Digging?
Why, of course. Let's not forget what the Spanish
found when they came to the New World.
Gold! Mountains of it.
Why, for years they've been
ravaging the New World...
of its most precious resources...
but now...
it's our turn.
The gold of Cortez
The jewels of Pizarro
Will seem like mere trinkets
by this time tomorrow
The gold we find here will dwarf them by far
Oh, with all you got in ya, boys
Dig up Virginia, boys
Mine, boys
Mine every mountain
And dig, boys
Dig 'til you drop
Grab a pick, boys
Quick, boys
Shove in a shovel
Uncover those loverly pebbles that sparkle and shine
lt's gold and it's mine
Mine, mine
Dig and dig and diggety dig
And dig and dig and diggety dig
- Hei, nonny, nonny. Hei, nonny, nonny
- Ooh, how I love it.
- Riches for cheap.
- Hei, nonny, nonny. Ho, nonny, nonny
- There'll be heaps of it.
- And I'll be on top of the heap
- Diggety, diggety, dig
My rivals back home
It's not that I'm bitter
But think how they'll squirm
when they see how I glitter
The ladies at court will be all a-twitter
The king will reward me
He'll knight me
No, lord me
lt's mine, mine
Mine for the taking
lt's mine, boys
Mine me that gold
With those nuggets dug
lt's glory they'll gimme
My dear friend King Jimmy
will parobably build me a shrine
- When all of the gold
- Is mined
- Dig and dig and diggety dig
And dig and dig and diggety dig
All of my life I have searched
for a land like this one
A wilder, more challenging
country I couldn't design
Hundreds of dangers await
and I don't palan to miss one
In a land I can claim
A land I can tame
- The greatest adventure is mine
- Keep on working, lads
- Mine
- Don't be shirking, lads
- Mine, boys, mine
- Find a mother lode. Then mine another load
- Mine me that gold
- Dig, dig and diggety
- Beautiful gold
- Dig, dig for that gold
Make this island my land
- Make the mounds big, boys. I'd help you to dig, boys
- Dig, dig
But I've got this crick in my spine
- This land we behold
- This beauty untold
- A man can be bold
- It all can be sold
- So go for the gold
- The gold
- Is
- All the riches here
- Mine
- From this minute this land
- And what's in it
- Is mine
- And dig and dig and diggety dig
Hey, nonny, nonny
It's mine
No! Wait. Please.
Please!
Don't run off.
It's all right.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Here. Let me help you out of there.
You don't understand a word I'm saying, do you?
It's all right.
Listen with your heart
You will understand
Let it break upon you
Like a wave upon the sand
- Who are you?
- Listen with your heart
You will understand
Pocahontas.
What? What did you say?
My name is Pocahontas.
I'm John Smith.
That's it.
Keep at it, men.
Keep digging. It's got to be here somewhere.
-There's 30 more of them down by the ridge.
-That makes more than a hundred.
- Anything yet?
- Nothing but rocks and dirt, sir.
- Um, how long are we going to
keep digging like this, sir?
- Aye.
We're slaving away, busting our backs
day and night...
- for--
- For king and country. I know, I know.
And I share your fatigue.
Mmm. Wiggins?
- Wiggins?
- Coming!
Dispose of this.
Who's a good doggy, hmm?
Who's a good doggy?
Fetch, boy!
- Savages! It's an ambush! Arm yourselves!
- Run!
Arm yourselves!
Make sure every manhas a musket.
Shoot!
Them, you idiot!
Where's that blasted Smith when I need him?
Namontack!
Back to the village.
Shut up. Shut up, you fools!
They'll be back.
Everyone, back to camp. Get the rest of
the cannons ashore and finish building the fort!
Aye, Governor.
And you.
Learn to use that thing properly.
A man's not a man unless he knows how to shoot.
These beasts invade our shores, and now this.
This wound is strange to me.
We will fight this enemy, but we cannot
do it alone.
Kocoum, send messengers
to every village in our nation.
We will call on our brothers to help us fight.
These white men are dangerous.
No one is to go near them.
- It's called a helmet.
- Helmet.
- So, uh, what river is this?
- Qui-yough-co-hannock.
You have the most unusual names here.
Pocahontas.
You have the most unusual name too.
John Smith.
Hey!
Is this bottomless pit a friend of yours?
Meeko!
Well, how do you do, Meeko?
It's all right. It's just a handshake.
Here, let me show you.
- Nothing's happening.
- Uh, no, no. I need your hand first.
It's how we say hello.
This is how we say hello.
And how we say goodbye.
I like hello better.
Yeah, I remember you.
Flit just doesn't like strangers.
Well, I'm not a stranger any more.
Hmm. Stubborn little fellow, isn't he?
Very stubborn.
Hey!
Meeko, come back here.
Don't worry. He can't hurt it.
Hey! What are you doing? Get--
- Meeko, bring that back!
- N-No, it's all right.
He can keep it. Call it a gift.
- What was that?
- My compass.
- Compass?
- It tells you how to find
your way when you get lost.
But it's all right.
I'll get another one in London.
- London. Is that your village?
- Yes.
- It's a very big village.
- What's it like?
Well, it's got streets filled with carriages,
bridges over the rivers...
and buildings as tall as trees.
- I'd like to see those things.
- You will.
-How?
-We're going to build them here.
We'll show your people how to use this
land properly, how to make the most of it.
- Make the most of it?
- Yes.
- We'll build roads and decent houses and--
- Our houses are fine.
You think that only because
you don't know any better.
W-Wait a minute.
Don't take it tha-- Hey. Hey!
Wait! Wa-Wait!
There's so much we can teach you.
- We've improved the lives of savages
all over the world.
- Savages?
Uh, not that you're a savage.
-Just my people.
- No. Listen. That's not what
I meant. Let me explain, uh--
- Let go!
- No, I'm not letting you leave.
Look, don't do this.
Savage is just a word, uh, you know.
- A term for people who are uncivilized.
- Like me.
Well, when I say uncivilized, what I mean is, is--
What you mean is, not like you.
You think I'm an ignorant savage
And you've been so many palaces
I guess it must be so
But still I cannot see
If the savage one is me
How can there be so much that you don't know
You don't know
You think you own whatever land you land on
The Earth is just a dead thing you can claim
But I know every rock and tree and creature
Has a life, has a spirit
Has a name
You think the only people who are people
Are the people who look
and think like you
But if you walk the footstepas
of a stranger
You'll learn things
you never knew you never knew
Have you ever heard the wolf cry
to the blue corn moon
Or asked the grinning bobcat
why he grinned
Can you sing with all the voices
of the mountain
Can you paint
with all the colours of the wind
with all the colours
Of the wind
Come run the hidden paine trails
of the forest
Come taste the sun sweet berries
of the Earth
Come roll in all the riches
all around you
And for once never wonder
what they're worth
The rainstorm and the river
are my brothers
The heron and the otter
are my friends
And we are all connected
to each other
In a circle
In a hoop that never ends
How high does the sycamore grow
If you cut it down then you'll never know
And you'll never hear the wolf
cry to the blue corn moon
For whether we are white or copapaer-skinned
We need to sing with all the voices of the mountain
We need to paint with all the colours of the wind
You can own the Earth and still
All you'll own is earth until
You can paint
With all the colours
Of the wind
What is it?
The drums.
They mean trouble. I shouldn't be here.
- I want to see you again.
- I can't.
- Please, don't leave.
- I'm sorry.
I have to go.
All right!
This one's ready to hoist!
- Two on each side.
- Ready now. Push!
- Watch it. It's slippery.
- Come on, lads. It's only a little picket fence.
- Steady. Steady.
- There you go.
That'll keep everything out, eh,John?
- Something wrong,John?
- What?
You've been awfully quiet the last few days.
Oh, he's just mad that he missed all the action.
Ah, don't worry,John. You'll get your chance
to deal with the Indians.
Yeah, we'll take care of them like we did
last time, eh, mates?
We shot ourselves an Injun or maybe two or three
All right, you howling nutter, get to work!
Come on, Ben. It's just a little fun.
Oh, sure, we're having loads of fun, right?
Look at us. No gold, no food.
While Ratcliffe sits up in his tent all day,
happy as a clam.
I am doomed!
I should be wallowing in riches by now and I haven't
found as much as a speck!
Think. Think!
It's got to be around here somewhere.
Where could it be?
I've mined the forests and the hills and the swamps.
And nothing!
Why can't I find it?
What am I overlooking?
I-- I--
I made it myself.
Take that silly--
Of course! The Indians.
Wiggins, why do you think those
insolent heathens attacked us?
Because we invaded their land and cut down
their trees and dug up their earth?
It's the gold! They have it and they don't
want us to take it from them.
Well, I'll just have to take it
by force, then, won't I?
You there!
Where's Captain Smith?
Well, he's gone.
Aye. Your singing must have scared them off.
- Well, then go get him, for heaven's sake!
- What if we run into the Indians?
That's what guns are for.
Now arm yourselves and get moving!
Pocahontas.
You should be inside the village.
- We'll be all right.
- We're gathering food for when the warriors arrive.
- Don't go far. Now is not the time to be running off.
- Yes, Father.
When I see you wear that necklace...
you look just like your mother.
- I miss her.
- But she is still with us.
Whenever the wind moves through the trees,
I feel her presence.
Our people looked to her for wisdom and strength.
Someday, they will look to you as well.
I would be honoured by that.
You shouldn't be out here alone.
I'll send for Kocoum.
- All right. What is it?
- What?
- You're hiding something.
- I'm not hiding anything.
Pocahontas, you can tell me.
I promise I won't tell anyone.
Pocahontas, look!
- It's one of them! I'm going to get--
- What are you doing here?
- I had to see you again.
- Huh?
Pocahontas. Pocahontas?
- Please, don't say anything. Quick, this way.
- But--
- Nakoma.
- Huh?
- Where is Pocahontas?
I-- I haven't seen her.
Pocahontas can't keep running off.
It's dangerous out there.
Tell her that. She listens to you.
Huh. Sure she does.
This place is incredible.
And to think we came all this
way just to dig it up for gold.
- Gold?
- Hey, Meeko.
- What's gold?
- You know, it's, uh-- it's, it's yellow.
It comes out of the ground.
It's really valuable.
Oh! Here, we have lots of it.
Gold.
No. Gold is this.
Hmm. There's nothing like that around here.
- No gold.
- Not that I've seen.
All this way for nothing.
Well, those boys are in for a big surprise.
- Will they leave?
- Some of them might.
- Will you go home?
- Well, it's not like I have much of a home to go back to.
I've never really belonged anywhere.
You could belong here.
- What was that?
- Did you see something?
No. No. I just, uh-- I--
I didn't see anything, did I?
Look again.
Let it break upon you
Like a wave upon the sand
Hello, John Smith.
Pocahontas, that tree is talking to me.
Then you should talk back.
Don't be frightened, young man.
My bark is worse than my bite.
- Say something.
- What do you say to a tree?
Anything you want.
- So, uh--
- Come closer,John Smith.
He has a good soul. And he's handsome too.
- Oh, I like her.
- I knew you would.
Smith! Smith!
Where are you, mate?
- We can't let them see us.
- Quick! Over here.
This place gives me the creeps.
Savages could be hiding anywhere.
Aye. Well, if you spot one, don't ask questions.
Just shoot.
- Watch your feet, you big oaf!
- It wasn't me. It was the tree.
Oh, of course! The tree
just felt like lifting its roots and--
Let's get out of here.
- Ow!
- Ow! Run!
- But what about Smith?
- He's a big lad. He can take care of himself.
- I'm glad you're on our side.
- There's still some snap in these old vines.
I'd better get back before
they send the whole camp out after me.
- When will I see you again?
- Meet me tonight. Right here.
Well, I haven't had this much
excitement in 200 years.
What am I doing? I shouldn't be seeing him again.
I mean, I want to see him again.
Who wouldn't?
I want to see him again.
But still, something inside is telling me
it's the right thing.
- Perhaps it's your dream.
- My dream?
Do you think he's the one the
spinning arrow was pointing to?
Hmm.
The warriors are here!
Pocahontas, are you crazy?
What were you doing with one of them?
- There you are.
- Kocoum.
- Look at them.
Now we have enough warriors
to destroy those white demons.
Now that we are joined by our brothers...
we will defeat this enemy.
- Father, I need to speak with you.
- Not now, my daughter.
- The council is gathering.
- We don't have to fight them!
There must be a better way.
Sometimes our paths are chosen for us.
- But maybe we should try talking to them.
- They do not want to talk.
But if one of them did want to talk, you would
listen to him, wouldn't you?
- Pocahontas.
- Wouldn't you?
Of course I would. But it is not that simple.
Nothing is simple any more.
Easy, Thomas. It's me.
Oh,John. I could've killed you.
Not aiming like that, you couldn't.
Keep both eyes open when you shoot.
You'll see twice as well.
- Smith, there you are!
- We were looking all over for you.
Smith! Where have you been?
I was out scouting the terrain, sir.
Excellent. Then you must know
the Indians' whereabouts.
- We'll need that information for the battle.
- What battle?
We will eliminate these savages once and for all.
No! You can't do that.
Oh, can't I?
Look, we don't have to fight them.
- John, what's gotten into you?
- I met one of them.
- You what?
- A savage?
They're not savages.
They can help us.
They know the land.
They know how to navigate the rivers.
- And look. It's food.
- What is it?
- It's better than hardtack and gruel, that's for sure.
- I like gruel.
They don't want to feed us, you ninnies!
They want to kill us, all of us!
They've got our gold, and they'll do anything
to keep it!
- But there is no gold.
- No gold?
And I suppose your little
Indian friend told you this?
- Yes.
- Lies! Lies! All of it!
Murderous thieves!
There's no room for their kind in civilized society.
- But this is their land!
- This is my land! I make the laws here.
And I say anyone who so much
as looks at an Indian...
without killing him on sight
will be tried for treason...
and hanged!
- Pocahontas!
- Nakoma!
Don't go out there.
I lied for you once.
- Don't ask me to do it again.
- I have to do this.
- He's one of them.
- You don't know him.
If you go out there, you'll be turning your back
on your own people.
I'm trying to help my people.
Pocahontas, please.
You're my best friend.
- I don't want you to get hurt.
- I won't.
- I know what I'm doing.
- Pocahontas, no !
Ratcliffe wouldn't take us
halfway around the world for nothin'.
But what if Smith is right?
What if there is no gold?
If you ask me, Ratcliffe's been lying to us
since we left London.
Listen to you, ya bunch of idiots.
Those savages didn't attack us for nothin'.
They're hidin' somethin'.
If they do have the gold,
I reckon we'll have to fight 'em.
- Not me.
- Either too hot or too cool.
I haven't been comfortable since we got here.
Oh, I know.
I've been itching a lot.
- Follow him.
- Yes, Governor.
- I want to know where he's sneaking off to.
- Yes, sir.
And if you happen to see any Indians, shoot them.
Oh, and Thomas, you've been a slipshod sailor and
a poor excuse for a soldier.
Don't disappoint me again.
- Kocoum.
- What is it?
- It's Pocahontas.
- What's wrong? Is she all right?
I think she's in trouble.
The Earth is trembling, child.
What's happened?
- The warriors are here!
- Pocahontas!
John.
Listen to me. My men are
planning to attack your people.
- You've got to warn them.
- Maybe it's not too late to stop this.
You have to come with me
and talk to my father.
Pocahontas, talking isn't
going to do any good.
I already tried talking to my men, but
everything about this land has them spooked.
That's the strangest creature
I've ever seen.
Percy.
- Easy, Percy. Come here!
- Meeko, come back!
You see what I mean?
Once two sides want to fight, nothing can stop them.
- Come-- Come here, both of you!
- It's all right! It's all right! He's a friend!
Bad! Bad dog! Sit!
- What are you doing? Meeko!
- Percy, get back here!
- What are you doing? Stop that!
- All right, that's enough!
It's enough to make your sap boil.
Now then, there's something
I want to show you. Look.
- The ripples.
- What about them?
So small at first, then look how they grow.
But someone has to start them.
They're not going to listen to us.
Young man, sometimes the right
path is not the easiest one.
Don't you see?
Only when the fighting stops can you be together.
All right. Let's go talk to your father.
No!
Kocoum! No!
Kocoum!
Leave him alone!
Kocoum! Stop!
Both eyes open.
Thomas!
- Is he--
- You killed him.
- I thought that--
- Get away from him!
- Pocahontas, it won't help! He was only--
- He killed him!
Thomas, get out of here!
Get out of here!
- Who did this?
- Pocahontas was out in the woods.
Kocoum went to find her
and this white man attacked him.
Your weapons are strong,
but now our anger is stronger.
- At sunrise he will be the first to die.
- But, Father--
I told you to stay in the village.
You disobeyed me. You have shamed your father!
I was only trying to help.
Because of your foolishness,
Kocoum is dead!
Take him away!
Kocoum was just coming to protect me.
Pocahontas, I sent Kocoum after you.
I was worried about you.
I-I thought I was doing the right thing.
All this happened because of me.
And now I'll never see John Smith again.
Come with me.
Pocahontas wants to look into the eyes
of the man who killed Kocoum.
Be quick.
Pocahontas.
- I'm so sorry.
- For what, this?
I've gotten out of worse scrapes than this.
Can't think of any right now, but--
It would've been better if we'd never met.
None of this would've happened.
Pocahontas, look at me.
I'd rather die tomorrow...
than live a hundred years without knowing you.
Pocahontas.
- I can't leave you.
- You never will.
No matter what happens to me,
I'll always be with you. Forever.
Help! Somebody help!
Help! Help!
- Easy, lad. What is it?
- It's Smith! They got him!
- Who got him?
- The savages!
- Savages?
- They captured him, dragged him off!
- Where'd they take him?
- They headed north.
- How many were there?
- I don't know. At least a dozen.
- Filthy beasts!
- Ratcliffe was right!
It's perfect, Wiggins.
I couldn't have planned this better myself.
The gold is as good as mine.
We've got to save him!
He'd do the same for any of us!
- Thomas is right! We've got to do somethin'!
- And so we shall.
- I told you those savages couldn't be trusted.
- That's right!
Smith tried to befriend them,
and look what they've done to him!
- Yeah, that's right.
- But now I say it's time to rescue our courageous comrade.
At daybreak, we attack!
What can you expect from filthy little heathens
- Here's what you get when races are diverse
- That's right.
Their skins are hellish red
They're only good when dead
They're vermin, as I said and worse
- They're savages, savages
- Barely even human
- Savages, savages
- Drive them from our shore
They're not like you and me
which means they must be evil
We must sound the drums of war
They're savages, savages
Dirty shrieking devils
Now we sound the drums of war
This is what we feared
The paleface is a demon
The only thing they feel at all is greed
Beneath that milky hide there's empatiness inside
I wonder if they even bleed
- They're savages, savages
- Barely even human
- Savages, savages
- Killers at the core
They're different from us
which means they can't be trusted
We must sound the drums of war
- They're savages, savages
- First we deal with this one
- Then we sound the drums of war
- Savages, savages
Let's go get a few, men!
- Now it's up to you, men
- Savages
Barely even human
Now we sound the drums
Of
War
- They're going to kill him at sunrise, Grandmother Willow.
- You have to stop them.
- I can't.
- Child, remember your dream.
I was wrong, Grandmother Willow.
I followed the wrong path.
I feel so lost.
The compass?
Spinning arrow.
It's the arrow from your dream.
I was right!
It was pointing to him.
- Sunrise.
- It's not too late, child.
Let the spirits of the Earth guide you.
You know your path, child.
Now follow it!
This will be the day
Let's go, men!
This will be the morning
Bring out the prisoner!
We will see them dying in the dust
I don't know what I can do
Still, I know I've got to try
- Now we make 'em paay
- Eagle, helpa my feet to fly
- Now, without a warning
- Mountain, help my heart be great
Now we leave 'em blood and bone and rust
- Spirits of the Earth and sky
- lt's them or us
- Please don't let it be too late
- They're just a bunch of
- Filthy, stinking savages
- Savages
- Demon
- Devil
- Kill them!
- Savages, savages
- What are we waiting for
Destroy their evil race
until there's not a trace left
- How loud
- We will sound the drums of war
- Are the drums of war
- Now we sound the drums of war
- Now we see what comes of trying to be chums
- Now we sound the drums
- Is the death of all I love carried in the drumming of
- Of
- War
- No!
If you kill him, you'll have to kill me too.
Daughter, stand back.
I won't! I love him, Father.
What?
Look around you.
This is where the path of hatred has brought us.
This is the path I choose,
Father. What will yours be?
My daughter speaks with
a wisdom beyond her years.
We have all come here with anger in our hearts...
but she comes with courage and understanding.
From this day forward,
if there is to be more killing...
it will not start with me.
Release him.
Now's our chance! Fire!
- No!
- What?
- They let him go.
- They don't want to fight.
It's a trick! Don't you see?
Fire!
Fine. I'll settle this myself.
No!
John!
- You shot him!
- He stepped right-- right into it. It's his own fault.
- Smith was right all along.
- We never should've listened to you.
- Get the gun!
- Traitors!
Unhand me, I say!
How dare you!
- Put him in chains!
- I'll see you all hanged for this!
And gag him as well!
- Is he gonna make it, Thomas?
- The sooner he gets back to England, the better.
- Well, let's hope the wind is with him.
- Is the ship ready yet?
Any minute now.Just loadin'
the last bit of cargo.
How dare you!
Untie me at once!
I'll have your heads for this!
And he came so highly recommended.
The ship's almost ready.
We'd better get you on board.
We'll lose the tide.
No, not yet.
- She said she'd be here.
- Look.
Going back is his only chance.
He'll die if he stays here.
Here. It's from Grandmother Willow's bark.
It'll help with the pain.
What pain? I've had worse pain than this.
Can't think of any right now, but--
You are always welcome among our people.
Thank you, my brother.
I thought you didn't like strangers.
My mother's necklace.
See ya, Percy.
Come with me?
You must choose your own path.
I'm needed here.
Then I'll stay with you.
No. You have to go back.
- But I can't leave you.
- You never will.
No matter what happens,
I'll always be with you.
Forever.
- Good luck, lad.
- Godspeed,John.
- The crew a-ready?
- Aye, sir!
Set the mainsails!
Weigh anchor!
- Let go of the topgallants!
- Aye, sir!
lf I never knew you
lf I never felt this love
I would have no inkling of
How precious life can be
And I'm so grateful to you
I'd have lived my whole life through
Lost forever
lf I never knew you
I'd be safe but half as real
Never knowing I could feel
A love so strong and true
- Oh, if I never knew you
- There's no moment I'd regret
- lf I never knew your love
- Since the moment that we met
- I would have no inkling of
- lf our time has gone too fast
- How precious life can be
- I've lived at last
Yeah, yeah
I thought our love would be so beautiful
So beautiful
Somehow we'd make the whole world bright
I thought our love would be so beautiful
We'd turn the darkness into light
And still my heart is saying we were right
We were right
- And if I never knew you
- lf I never knew you
I'd have lived my whole life through
Empty as the sky
Never knowing why
Lost forever
If I never knew
You
Yeah
You think you own whatever land you land on
The earth is just a dead thing you can claim
But I know every rock and tree and creature
Has a life, has a spirit
Has a name
You think the only people
who are people
Are the people who look
and think like you
But if you walk the footsteps of a stranger
You'll learn things you never knew you never knew
Have you ever heard the wolf cry
To the blue corn moon
Or let the eagle tell you where he's been
Can you sing with all the voices of the mountain
Can you paint with all the colours of the wind
How high does the sycamore grow
lf you cut it down
Then you'll never know
And you'll never hear the wolf cry
To the blue corn moon
For whether we are white or copapaer-skinned
We need to sing with all the voices of the mountain
We need to paint with all the colours of the wind
You can own the Earth and still
All you'll own is earth until
You can paint with all the colours
Of
The wind
Subtitles by MAGNO