Hilton security
room, be advised.
Rawhide moving to the cars.
Security room, copy. All
posts, all posts, be advised.
Rawhide moving to the cars.
Shots fired! Shots fired!
Gun! Gun! Gun!
Secure the scene!
We need a car. We need a transport. We
need to get transport over here quickly.
Move it to the car.
Welcome to sports center here on e.S.P.N.
As the preseason draws to a close.
Detroit beat New Orleans,
a closer game, 28-20,
as the start of the new
season approaches.
We saw Philadelphia absolutely
crush Washington last night.
And in other preseason action, we watched
as New York handled Chicago, easily, 42...
Good morning, Jack.
Command post to tomahawk
7. What's your status?
Tomahawk 7, copy.
Sector is all clear.
Okay, seven, break. Tomahawk
8, what's your status?
Command post, from eight.
Eight is clear, all clear.
- Good morning, gentlemen.
- Good morning, Mr. president.
- Your locator, sir.
- Thank you very much.
- Today's brief, sir.
- Thank you.
- Everybody sleep well?
- Mmm. Thank you.
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
Command post, from
a-4. Be advised.
Classic has received his locator
and brief and is up and about.
A- 4, from command
post, Roger that.
Everybody, classic
is up and about.
- Hey, Jack.
- Hey, charl.
Come on, come on. Cough it up.
- Ah, goddamn spread.
- Cough up.
Yeah.
Listen, uh, I want to talk
to you about something.
- Give me a call after work, would you?
- He's a glutton for punishment.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Aziz, good morning. We can talk now.
No, no. I got a theory
I want to float by you.
Everything all right?
Yeah, everything's good.
Everything's good.
All right.
Pete. After work, right?
You know what I'm saying?
Well, if they can get anything
for him, right? He's junk.
Aziz, don't give up soccer, huh?
- Hey, Teddy. Welcome back.
- Hey, thanks.
- Gar.
- Buddy.
How'd the anti terrorist
training go?
Six weeks running around
fort benning in the
rain. I wish I could
do it all over again.
Well, that can be arranged.
- Tom.
- Good morning, Pete.
- Is she in the gym?
- No, uh, phone to Europe.
By the way, you, uh, made time.
It's very fancy.
Ooh, I look good.
Can I get a cup of coffee before we...
What's happening at camp David?
Matt's getting closer with Ben-itzak
on the east Jerusalem proposal...
But it's gonna take your
visit to get him to agree.
What about abu jallal?
If we can work out the water
issues, he'll support it.
But again, we're not
gonna get any firm
commitments until they
have face time on Friday.
I'll be there. I'm just not gonna hang
around, 'cause it loses its effectiveness.
- I understand, sir.
- Thank you, sue. Good morning.
A- 4 to command post.
Classic is in the oval.
So, we will depart the
house at 12:55 p. M...
Arrive at chilton
street school at 1: 10.
There is a diagram of the
school with your paperwork.
- Boss.
- Thank you.
- Kiss ass.
- Uh, speeches and signings...
- Should take under 90 minutes...
- Where's my coffee?
After which classic will return
for meetings in the oval.
- Cincinnati's next move is t.B.D.
- What's the "b" stand for?
Brass ones. Which
you don't have.
Ooh, ouch.
Any other questions?
Let's get to work.
Command post to all units...
Pontiac and raven are in
the yard and ready to go.
Cincinnati's on the move.
Copy that. All
posts, be advised.
Cincinnati moving to the cars.
Break. Montrose, what's your status?
- Jill, we are off to...
- We're off to school.
- Right.
- Classic is moving.
Montrose, command post, copy that.
Break, all posts, all posts...
Be advised, classic
moving to the cars.
Copy, command. Cincinnati
is in the car.
- Classic is in the car.
- One and two back.
Break. Command post, signal departure,
en route. Canvas his location.
We're set.
This is chilton security.
Counter snipers in place.
Ah, damn locator.
School security room, from
es.O.D. 1, be advised...
The sweeps are now complete.
All posts, be advised, full
security now in effect.
- Thanks for doing this with me, hon.
- Hmm.
I think I'll go to the
beach house this afternoon.
All right.
Command post to
apache. Heads up.
- Can I help you?
- Um, agent breckinridge's office.
Thanks.
- Anything else I can help you with?
- No. I'm fine. Thanks.
Agent breckinridge.
Jill marin, sir.
Your secretary said
i could come in.
- Secretary?
- You're late.
It's a minute past.
- Yeah. And that makes you late.
- Right. Sorry.
Hispanic woman. Four
languages. Computer skills.
Second in your class at the academy.
Well, aren't you the recruiting poster.
Resumes don't mean a lot to me, and they
mean absolutely nothing on the street.
Any other supportive advice
before we get to know each other?
As a matter of fact, there is.
If you want a
career here in p.I.D.,
you might want to...
Invest in some more
appropriate clothing.
I was ordered to take you on. That's why
I'm here. You requested me as a t.A. Why?
My field instructor at the academy said
you're the best investigator we have.
- Who is that?
- Pete Garrison.
Right.
Command post, from apache.
Follow up. We have an arrival.
Hi there. Careful now.
All posts, from command post.
Hold all radio for central traffic
only. We have an arrival.
Sorry, folks, no autographs.
Can I see your hands, sir?
At your 6:00,jefferson. Tweed jacket,
halfway up the church steps.
What's the matter, Pete? You see
somebody on the watch list?
He just doesn't look right. Security
room, check out the top view.
- It'll be just another minute, sir.
- All right.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Hi, sir. Could we see
your hands, please?
- Huh? What are...
- Take your hands out of the jacket.
We're clear - all right.
Classic's coming out.
I think we should hold hands.
Fine.
All posts, from chilton
security. We're coming out.
Mr. president, keep
up the good work!
Hey, Mr. president!
- Hi. How are you?
- President ballentine!
How are you? How are
you? Nice to meet you.
All posts, all posts, classic
and cinci moving to hold.
Cincinnati's going
direct to the beach house.
Got it.
Now, I want to introduce
you to someone...
Chilton security to all
posts. Classic wrapping up.
My wife, Sarah.
Thank you.
Dipaola to command. Cincinnati
leaving school for Serenity.
Break. Dipaola to Serenity
security room. Es. T.A. 1800 hours.
How do you think
it went in there?
- Excuse me, ma'am, are you talking to me?
- Yes.
I thought it was, uh,
an excellent speech.
- One to 10?
- Ten, ma'am.
You're not a very
good liar, Pete.
- Seriously?
- Yes. I... I really want to know.
9.5.
Excuse me.
Charlie?
Charlie. Charlie! Oh,
my god. Charlie.
Somebody! Help! Charlie.
Charlie. Somebody help!
I just wanted to say hi. I just want
to let you know what's going on.
I hate you.
I saw you on the news. I got your
message. I know you want me to kill you.
- Excuse me.
- Um, yeah. Sorry.
- So all of these are from last week?
- That's about half of them.
And then there are
the verbal threats.
He's a dead man. I'm gonna
kill him and his whole family.
He's rhinitis country, and
I'm gonna gut him like a fish.
- They sound worse in English.
- Yeah.
We got this guy yesterday.
Did you translate this?
No. But whoever did's
not a native speaker.
How do you know that?
Well, he translated here...
And that literally means "to put
pressure on him, he bit the guy."
As if he was being tortured. But
that's not what it means here.
It's slang. It means
he bribed him.
He didn't bite him.
Good.
We need to talk.
I think you have a little spinach
or something in your teeth.
I want you to route all
calls through to my cell.
You picked a hell of a day
to start your field work.
- Button up your jacket.
- Why? What going on?
Dispatch, this is Charlie
9. Units on scene.
Here comes the secret service.
I really don't need them
breathing down my neck.
What do they know about
investigating murder?
She can breathe down my neck.
But not him.
Agents breckinridge,
marin. Secret service.
- You guys bring lunch?
- Not today.
The way I see it, he
hands over the wallet.
As the guy reaches for it,
merriweather goes for his gun.
Bad guy shoots him first.
- You think this is a street crime?
- In my gut, yeah.
You know my problem
with gut feelings?
Once you have them, the
only evidence you see...
Is the evidence that
reinforces your gut feeling.
Human nature.
There's no money
left in his wallet...
And there's been a series of
robberies here the last two months.
You have some reason to
think it wasn't a robbery?
Well, agent merriweather spent the last 25
years honing his ability to sense danger...
To notice anything outside
of the ordinary...
So for some average street
criminal to get the
drop on him... yeah,
it raises questions.
Not to mention that he's been
shot here twice with a. 45.
I'm gonna take a guess here,
but from your initial
canvassing, I bet you
no one heard anything.
Any homicide cop will tell you that
sort of thing happens all the time.
Yeah, I bet they
would, detective.
Rosario.
Anyone want anything
to eat or drink?
Uh, no, thanks, ma'am.
I think we're fine.
Well, I'm hungry.
Tom, sweep downstairs
and go for dinner. I'll
sweep upstairs, sit post
till the shift change.
You sure? You've been
on as long as me.
You gonna make
me change my mind?
Detective, take a look at the bullet mark
on the doorjamb. The slug didn't penetrate.
It's cedar, which is a soft
wood. It gets brittle with age.
So what are you saying?
Bad guy used a silencer.
That's why nobody heard it.
And that's what slowed down
the velocity of the bullet...
And stopped it from
penetrating the wood...
Which it easily would have done had it been
traveling at its normal rate of speed.
The shooter was
standing right here.
One other thing, detective.
Excuse me. Agent merriweather's
firearm... the safety's still on.
We assumed he just didn't
have time to flick it off.
Agent marin, why don't you explain to
the detectives why that is unlikely.
If he was a police officer, it would make
sense because your academy trains you...
To draw your weapon and flip the
safety in two separate actions...
To avoid accidental shootings.
Our academy trains us to draw
and flip in a single motion.
If he managed to draw his weapon,
his safety should have been off.
A protective agent maybe draws his weapon
once an entire presidential term.
When we draw our weapon,
we intend to use it.
Bottom line... agent
merriweather was assassinated.
I want the murder weapon. I don't
care if you have to drag the potomac.
If this man was one of yours, you would
have treated him with a lot more respect.
Let's get a gurney up here!
It always amazes me
how thorough you are.
Well, we try to do
the best job we can.
Hopefully you sleep
better at night.
And I definitely do.
Garrison, dipaola. We're
good on the perimeter.
- I'm 10-60.
- Uh, Roger, 10-60.
I let dipaola go early,
so, uh, he can...
Get something to eat.
- Hi.
You all right?
I missed you. I
missed you so much.
- Just a second.
- Okay.
- This is outstanding.
- There you go. And enjoy.
I love you, Sarah.
- Garrison, dipaola.
- Where are you?
- Garrison, dipaola, where are you?
- Shit.
Yeah, I'm on my way.
Hi. So what the hell
is going on, or...
Aziz, what are you doing here?
Charlie merriweather
was murdered.
He... he was murdered?
P.I.D. Thinks it might
be connected to work.
Director put us on alert.
I'm sorry. I know
he was your friend.
Was there any kind of
shift in his behavior?
Was he agitated or
worried about anything?
He was a little distant
at breakfast on Sunday.
Did he tell you why?
He just said he had a
couple of tough days at work.
- What'd he say at breakfast?
- Some gossip. Uh, it's kind of personal.
Nancy, I know how difficult
this is for you...
But I need a complete picture if I'm
gonna investigate this properly.
He told me that he thought
Pete Garrison was
having an affair with
someone's wife at work.
- Just gossip. It just...
- Yeah.
Probably not even true.
Look, that's all
we need for now.
- You got the lead on Charlie's murder?
- Screw you.
- What?
- You still got a problem with me?
- Take your hands off of me.
Christ. It doesn't matter
what I say to you.
I don't care if you got
a problem with me...
But you show respect when
you come to this house.
Charlie was one of
my best friends.
If you have information that can
help me, that I want to hear.
- Otherwise, stay out of my way.
- Fine. You're a piece of work.
You know, Nancy did
say one thing.
Charlie was upset about something at work.
You have any idea what that might be?
No.
Then if you figure it out,
you know where to find me.
- Yeah, good. I'll send you a memo.
- Do that.
- Hey. Is everything okay?
- Hey, Jill. Yeah.
- You working with him now?
- Yeah.
Keep your eyes open.
You may learn a lot.
But don't listen to
everything he's got to say.
- Especially about me.
- Okay.
Pete.
There some problem
between you two?
- I thought you were friends.
- We were.
- So what happened?
- It's personal.
Let's go.
No. He can go to hell. I
don't want to talk to him.
Just tell him it wasn't me.
- It wasn't anybody.
- I'm not saying it was.
- I wasn't having an affair!
- Cindy, I know you weren't.
What do you want me to
tell him I haven't already
told him 30 times? This
is why I left him.
He's the most pigheaded
man I've ever met.
You still love him, don't you?
- Hey, Pete. Pete.
- Hey, tom.
You know a guy named
Walter Xavier?
Yeah, sure. He's a snitch I used to use
when I was working in counterfeiting.
Okay. Just fielded a
call from this guy.
I told him you weren't running
informants anymore...
Offered to transfer the
call to w.F.O., p.I.D.
He said you're the only
person he'd talk to.
Thanks.
There he is! Publishers clearing house,
my man! You got something for me?
Did you fill yours out yet?
Every year my mom bugs me to
fill that thing out. I never do.
Long time, no see,
Walter. What's up?
Let's walk.
You got some info on that
Charlie merriweather murder?
That agent who was killed
outside his house on Monday?
Yeah.
Maybe he stumbled into something
he wasn't supposed to, like I did.
- What was that something?
- A plot to kill the president.
Walter, you know, it's a little
more difficult than it sounds.
Not if you got somebody inside.
You saying there's a mole
in the secret service?
That's right.
There's an agent who wants to
help assassinate the president?
That's right.
- Well, what's his name?
- I don't know. I just know he exists.
Well, how? Who... who's
giving you the information?
- I want one million dollars.
- What are you smoking, Walter?
- Now be serious.
- I'm dead serious.
I tell you this stuff, you roll these
guys up, they gonna know I'm the one.
- They'll hunt me down.
- We'll put you in protective custody.
Yeah, and I'll be dead in a day. Listen,
you got a traitor in your organization.
You get me the money,
and I will disappear.
I gotta be honest with you.
I find it pretty far-fetched we got
agents in on an assassination attempt.
Here. Maybe this will
change your mind, okay?
Call signs, code words,
today's encryption keys!
Yeah, whoever this traitor is...
They're either on the president's
detail or in a key liaison position.
Listen, I want a list of everyone
who's got "q" clearance.
And where's the
president right now?
Press conference at his
house. Twenty minutes.
This morning's action demonstrates
our continuing resolve...
To take on the infrastructure
of terrorism...
Wherever we find it
anywhere around the globe.
How reliable is this guy Xavier?
I've built three counterfeiting
cases using his information.
- Against who?
- Mid-level guys, barranquilla cartel.
Sir. That's everyone
with "q" clearance.
Those who actually
commit terrorist acts.
Now let me point out,
this is very important...
Polygraph everyone
on that list...
And stand up a red team
to find the traitor.
Now, I'm going to assume that the hit
on merriweather is connected to this...
So let's fold that
investigation in as well.
And we put breckinridge in
charge of the whole thing.
He's the best we've got?
Yeah.
Pete. He's kind of a protege of yours.
What do you think?
He'll follow the evidence
wherever it leads him.
Then he's the guy.
You can have anybody you want.
From I.D., from the field.
You get crate blanche.
- Not right now.
- Oh, sorry.
I can tell personnel you
need to lose the rookie.
No, I'm gonna keep her.
She hasn't been ruined
by years in the field.
I will blow you up. I come
to bomb this country.
Holy wars.
We have intel that
representatives of al-qaeda...
Have met on at least two occasions
with the barranquilla leadership.
You think it's timed to coincide
with the camp David talks?
Probably. The threat alone
interferes with the process.
We pulled 50 agents
in from the field.
People who haven't worked at the
white house in at least two cycles.
They'll integrate with
both of your teams.
We're all gonna be looking
over each other's
shoulders till we
find this guy, sir.
Well, do what you have to to protect
me, but I want the threat...
The investigation, I want
everything kept classified.
As far as the public is concerned, I'm
just carrying on my normal business.
- Is that clear?
- Mr. president...
We're going to need to get
everyone involved here.
What do you think would happen
to the power of the president...
If people thought I wasn't even
safe from my own secret service?
It took over 200 years to create
the symbol of the presidency...
And I'm not gonna undermine
it with something like this.
Let's circle the wagons, okay?
You all right?
Fine.
Good, let's do that.
How do we proceed?
Bill, you're the guy.
You're the last line of defense.
You can protect him better
than any of us can.
Is there anything else that you can
think of that'll help you do that?
Yeah.
This.
And I promise you, right here and
now, we're gonna win this one.
You can bank on it. Thank
you very much. Good night.
Good night. Thank you.
Heads it's sixth street,
tails it's eighth.
Bravo cars.
- This way, Mr. president.
- Thank you, bill.
Classic is moving to bravo cars.
Copy that. Command to Alpha
cars. You are off the hook.
Sir, could you put
down that knife?
It's not what they wanted to hear.
It's what they needed to hear.
Hello, young lady.
Where'd this guy come from?
He's an old c.I. Of
Garrison's. Nine, 10 years.
- Garrison?
- Mm-hmm.
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
- Are you sure?
- Yes. It's okay.
- How do I find Xavier?
- Um, I don't know where he lives.
He's a fanatic about
not being followed.
You ever tried?
- What?
- Have you ever tried?
He wants a million bucks from us,
Dave. I'm sure he'll contact us.
You better be right.
You get in touch with us
as soon as you find him.
Could be any one of them. It makes
you a little sick, doesn't it?
What percentage of your
people have had a polygraph?
A little over half.
"Over half"? The president's
life is at stake.
Heads up!
I want everybody in this room to have had a
polygraph by 5:00 p. M. This afternoon...
Or don't show up
for work tomorrow.
- Were you born in Morocco?
- No.
- Do you live in Bethesda?
- Were you born in Alabama?
- No.
Have you ever had contact
with child pornography?
Uh, yes. I was involved with an
investigation with the bureau...
- Just yes or no answers, please.
- Okay, Stan. Yes.
Are you up? The
witch hunt is on.
Get your polygraph today.
How did they get these?
Night-vision camera on a boat
stabilized by a gyroscope.
Pretty sophisticated.
I'm so sorry, Sarah.
I'm sorry.
It's gotta be someone
inside the service.
Somebody could have picked it up.
They're good. That's what they do.
Who?
The same agent plotting
to kill John? Who?
141 years there's never been a
traitor in the secret service.
Now, all of a sudden, there's
two? I don't buy that.
Somehow they're connected.
Maybe this is the assassination?
This is a death sentence for John,
a political death sentence.
That's not gonna happen.
Oh, Pete.
Sarah, I promise.
Let's get this goddamn
witch hunt over with.
- Just relax.
- I'm relaxed.
- Were you divorced in 1998?
- No.
Have you received adequate
training for your profession?
No.
But I did stay in a
holiday inn express.
Have you ever violated secret service
protocol in the past 30 days?
No.
Have you done anything
in the past 30 days...
- To violate secret service protocol?
- No.
Are you involved in a plot to kill
the President of the United States?
No.
I could use a few of those.
- Thanks.
- You look exhausted, bill.
You look worse.
I haven't slept since
we went on alert.
Well, I'm back on. It's worse
than going to confession.
Have you done your
polygraph yet?
You know I can't even let
you back on duty unless...
Yeah, I'll go now.
- Is your name Peter Garrison?
- Yes.
Are you involved in a
plot to kill the president?
No.
- Were you divorced in 1998?
- Yes.
Have you violated secret service
protocols in the last 30 days?
No.
Have you done anything
to endanger the life...
Of our president in
the last six months?
- Not that I know of.
- Yes or no answers, please.
No. No.
Welcome to mayflower hotel.
Mayflower hotel, can I help
you? Just a moment, sir.
- Are you Mr. Garrison?
- Yes.
You have a phone call.
You can take it here.
Thank you.
Walk three blocks east
on Massachusetts Avenue.
Take a left on 12th street.
Las palmas coffee shop.
All right.
Now boarding on track 4,
12: 13 acela express...
With stops in Philadelphia,
New York, Boston.
Now boarding, track 4.
F.B.I. Drop it!
- Federal agent! Federal agent!
- F.B.I. Freeze! Put it down!
- The gun is going down!
- All right. Back up now. Back up.
Turn around!
What the hell were you
doing at las palmas?
Having a goddamn
cup of coffee.
What the hell's going on here? Is that
one of your agents I'm following?
Sorry for the crossover.
Pete! I called four times.
Where the hell have you been?
We're not out of
here till tomorrow.
The president decided they should arrive
at the summit together. Where were you?
Oh! Excuse me.
Oh, here we are. Now, Kate, this is
your weekend to catch the trout.
- I don't like worms.
- No, no. This is fly-fishing.
Pete, can I talk
to you a minute?
Yes, sir.
We're really, both of us...
In uncharted territory
here, aren't we?
An assassin inside
the secret service?
Inside my detail?
Now, bill's been briefing
me, of course, but...
This guy's your
informant, right?
- Yes, sir.
- I want to get some of this firsthand...
So let's make time at camp
David to do that, all right?
Yes, sir.
Good afternoon, Mr. president.
Good afternoon. I'll
see you at dinner.
- So, Karen, how do things stand?
- It's time for you to weigh in.
Can I get you in there
now for a few hours?
Absolutely.
Sarah, the wives are
talking about having
tea. If you could stop
by, it would be great.
- Sure.
- Tom, we're gonna walk it.
What's going on, Pete? Why don't
they just tell us what they want?
It's okay. It's gonna be fine.
Nothing about this
feels okay or fine or...
- It will be.
- Has that guy called you?
- What's his name? What's that guy's name?
- Xavier.
- Has he called you?
- Not yet. No.
- Katie, hi.
- Good afternoon, ma'am.
- Hi.
- Would you care for tea?
It's such a beautiful day. Why
don't we have tea outside?
Well, that's a great idea.
How was your flight?
Short.
- You guys all decent?
- Afraid so.
Your informant's on the phone.
- Do you got the money?
- I got $100,000 in cash...
And a legal document guaranteeing you the
rest once the traitor's apprehended.
Yeah, right.
Walter, we haven't
screwed you in the past.
I'm not gonna start now. Otherwise,
all our sources would dry up.
Allenwood mall food
court at 11:00 a. M.
And don't try to bring nobody.
I'll walk if I spot 'em.
I cannot get there
in 20 minutes.
- Drive fast.
- Okay, you heard him. Let's go.
Breckinridge and marin
are already on the way.
All right.
Get the money bag and
a car ready, please.
Okay. Got it.
He knows we're following him. He went
where he can mix up with a crowd.
There's no way we get
surveillance in there.
Hold it. There's no way I'm gonna
let you go without a backup. No.
- Chaminski. Chaminski goes with you.
- Let's go.
At your 1:00.
Watch your 3:00.
Check your 9:00.
Check your 9:00! Check your
9:00! Check your 9:00!
Get down! Secret
service! Get down!
Shots fired. Shots
fired. Agent down.
Copy that. Breckinridge
to command.
We need backup at the
allenwood mall. Agent down.
The shooter has blond hair, dark
jacket. He's on the lower level.
Command, copy that. Available units
en route. Es.T.A. 20 minutes.
They're shooting. They're
right behind the doors.
Heads.
Pete, we're at the north end
of the mall. Lower level.
I'm a hundred yards
south of you.
Unholster your weapon.
Keep it down.
- Work your way towards me.
- Copy that. Stagger off 10 feet.
Get out of here!
Take the point.
I don't have a visual!
Go!
Garrison, Washington command.
Additional agents and medical assist are
en route. Break. All units, be advised.
Shots fired, allenwood mall.
One agent is
down. There are multiple
civilian casualties.
Shooter is male, blond
hair, dark jacket.
Pete. Pete!
You okay?
Do you have any idea why your
informant wanted to have you killed?
No. I'm wondering
the same thing.
You might want to figure
that one out, Pete.
Pete!
Presidential helicopter
just went down.
This is a news center
special report.
The presidential helicopter,
marine one, has crashed.
Marine one, the presidential
helicopter has gone down.
Whether or not the president
was on board has not...
Marine one, the presidential
helicopter has crashed.
It happened just moments ago about
a half mile south of camp David.
The chopper went down in
some densely wooded...
We're now hearing reports the
president was not on board.
Actually, we can now confirm...
That neither the president
or the first lady...
Were on board at the
time of the crash.
The president and
first lady are safe.
If you're just joining us, these are live
pictures just outside camp David...
Where earlier
today, marine one...
Went down shortly after takeoff.
Two hikers who witnessed the crash reported
seeing a contrail or fiery tail...
Just before that
helicopter went down.
That is leading to the possibility,
unconfirmed by authorities...
Our friend was
insufficiently motivated.
That the chopper
was shot down...
Probably by a
shoulder-fired missile.
Now, we want to make
clear, again...
That the president and
first lady are safe.
If you are just joining us, these
are live pictures from the scene...
Just outside of camp
David, where earlier today
marine one went down
just after takeoff.
Sources say marine and secret service
personnel were on that aircraft...
And they were killed
in the crash.
This crash is being investigated by
both the white house and the military.
- You failed.
- I did exactly what I promised.
He wasn't on board.
That is the only thing that matters. That
is the only thing I give a shit a...
Do you understand?
Now, we're gonna meet and
we're gonna discuss this.
Deadly against any
low-altitude aircraft...
Including jets, prop
planes and helicopters.
But that comes from witnesses.
Has not been confirmed
by investigators.
Again, these pictures
coming to us about...
Well, it sure doesn't look like
you're here to bury the hatchet.
You're being investigated
for treason.
- What are you talk...
- Step back.
- Excuse me?
- Hey, Jill.
- Pete.
- Matt.
Sorry for the intrusion, sir.
If I failed the polygraph,
then why am I still on duty?
Director didn't want
to arrest one of the
guys responsible for
saving Reagan's life...
Without a little more evidence.
How long you been working for
the barranquilla cartel?
What are you talking about?
Hugo, can you come
in here, please?
Pete Garrison, special agent
Ortega with the f.B.I.
What were you doing at the
las palmas coffee shop?
I was having a cup of coffee.
Takes you four hours
to have a cup of coffee?
I was killing a few hours at a coffee
shop. Is there a problem with that?
Tom dipaola said he called you four times.
You never returned any of his messages.
And that you almost missed the
marine one flight yesterday.
They moved the flight up two
hours. I was in the coffee shop.
It was noisy. I couldn't
hear my cell phone.
Now, wh-wh-what is this? What the
hell are you doing following me?
Las palmas coffee shop is a dead
drop for the barranquilla cartel.
You screwed up, Pete. You
walked into a stakeout.
I wanna know your number one
go-to guy at the cartel.
And I wanna know how you were gonna
help them kill the president.
Why would I want to kill the
president? What motive do I have?
To be honest with you, I don't care. I
know what the evidence is telling me.
I have given my entire life
to the secret service.
I've gotten up at 4:00 a.
M. Every goddamn morning.
Is that what this is about?
You're bitter after all your years of
service that they didn't make you director?
Oh, no. Don't confuse your own
ambition with mine. Okay, Dave?
Come on, Pete. Think about it.
People would understand that.
Jesus Christ, you took a bullet for
the President of the United States.
And in the 25 years since, you haven't
even made shift supervisor...
On a presidential detail,
and that I know you wanted.
But they don't put guys that bend
the rules, not even a little bit...
In charge of p.P.D., do they?
Even if they did take a
bullet for the old man.
Is that your professional
or personal opinion?
I think this whole thing
is getting personal.
We got you nailed to the wall.
- I didn't have an affair with Cindy.
- Has nothing to do with Cindy.
- You can't accept that.
- We are not talking about that!
We're talking about it all the time,
even when we're not talking about it!
You can't look at me
without thinking about it!
Jesus Christ, Pete,
you better get a grip.
I got a grip.
You think I wrecked your marriage, and
it has completely clouded your judgment.
I am following the evidence
and it is overwhelming.
The polygraph. Las palmas coffee shop.
You had unfettered access to marine one.
It was hit by a missile
for Christ's sake!
because the flares...
And the four other
countermeasures were disengaged!
There was a hundred other
people who had access to it.
Explain to me about
the bank account.
The what? The...
Your signature's all
over the paperwork.
I'm being framed.
- Tell me that's not your signature.
- Think about it!
I'm the guy that initiated
this investigation.
Why would I do that if i
wanted to kill the president?
You initiated this investigation
for a traitor in our department...
So that when the assassination
actually took place...
You'd be at the bottom
of the list of suspects.
I'm being framed! Goddamn
it! Just think about it.
- You take me in, that's the end.
- That guy is out there somewhere!
The director just
rolled up outside.
You better start thinking
about cooperating.
He's in the car.
- What are you doing, Pete?
- Getting a glass of water.
Director's come all the way
down here to see me, huh?
- That's very impressive.
- It's embarrassing for us, sir.
- Want a beer?
- Look, Pete, we're really...
Garrison back door.
Oh, shit.
Pete!
Where is he?
Sorry.
This is breckinridge.
Garrison has escaped
from the rear of the
residence into the alley.
Cordon off the area
and get back to me.
- He got my radio.
- He got my gun too.
He got your gun? And your radio?
What the hell are you
looking at her for?
She's been here two days. How
long have you been here?
Where to, mister?
Just get me out of here.
I know it's hard to believe Pete Garrison
could be involved with something like this.
For most of you he's a
friend, to some, a legend.
But the fact is, the evidence
against him is overwhelming.
So, how do we find him?
To begin with, know this.
He is smarter and more
experienced than all of you.
You've never trained for this. You
are chasing your worst nightmare.
He knows how you think. He knows what
you know. And he knows how you operate.
And he will use
that against you.
He also knows that it's gonna
be very difficult for you...
To pull the trigger if you
have him in your sights.
So I want you to take a
second and visualize that.
Because there is a very good chance that
is exactly how this is going to end.
- Can I have one of these here?
- Yeah, sure. Take it.
Yeah?
Fullback, backstop. Do
you have an arrival?
Backstop, fullback.
We have arrival.
Backstop, go.
Cincinnati wrapping up.
We're Alpha for departure.
I miss the good old days. Do you know
what I mean? I really literally do.
He taps him on the back
and the bear says...
"You didn't come here
to hunt, did ya?"
Get it? The bear.
That's not funny, man.
That joke ain't funny at all.
- Fullback. We're moving.
- Roger that. We're set up.
See you later, okay?
Be right back.
Thank you.
Welke, dipaola.
Cincinnati's coming to you.
Copy that.
Ma'am.
What are you doing here? I heard you
were arrested for the helicopter.
Whatever you hear about me in the next few
days, I want you to know I was framed.
- I had to tell you to your face.
- No, you don't. No, you don't.
- We're gonna get out of this.
- How?
I haven't figured that out yet.
This is out of control.
You've got to turn yourself in.
No, no.
Yes, you do. I'll go to John.
I'll tell him everything.
I can't let you do that.
Pete, they think you're an
assassin. They will kill you.
- You can cover my back.
- How?
The director has got a daily password
for the agents. Find out what it is.
I'm checking through stuff.
Hey, guys. Garrison
just used his cell phone.
He called Chez doucette.
You turned around when
it rang, didn't you?
Yeah, I did.
Ballsy. Very ballsy.
Dipaola said she seemed
completely unfazed.
She came upstairs, waited five
minutes and told him what happened.
Okay.
I'm just trying to understand why he
came here and why she reacted that way.
- This is your post?
- Yeah, it is.
Naturally, the first lady
doesn't want to believe...
The man protecting her for
the last eight months...
Is trying to assassinate
her husband.
That's why Pete came here.
He's looking for an ally.
And the first lady is a
very powerful ally to have.
Great. The idea is to
secure the entire site.
I want you to get every stolen
car report for the entire area.
Start looking for cars that were
taken within walking distance...
Of the restaurant or any of
the nearby Metro stations.
Then within those parameters, i
want you to isolate accords...
Tauruses, camrys
and explorers.
How do you know what kind
of car he's gonna steal?
Those are the four most commonly
registered vehicles in the D.C. area.
Pete knows that. He's
gonna want to blend in.
And the first thing he's gonna
want to do is find his informant.
If he tries to breach our computers, we
can find out where he's connecting from.
He knows we would know
that. He wouldn't do it.
- He could connect to someone else.
- How?
Well, he'd need that
person's password.
But as a supervisor, it wouldn't be hard
to get access to others' passwords.
Why would he do that? Why
would he even risk it?
Because he feels trapped.
We have his credit
cards, his cell phone.
He has no other place to hide.
- Can I help you?
- Oh, yes, ma'am.
My name is Lawson Smith. I'm
looking for a Walter Xavier.
Oh, lovely boy, but he
been gone a long time.
Well, this is the address we
have on his sweepstakes form.
Sweepstakes?
Yes, ma'am. I'm with
publishers clearing house.
He win?
- Well, he's a finalist.
- Million dollars.
- And you must be his mother.
- Uh-huh.
Mrs. Miller. I'm remarried.
Would you have another address or
telephone number where I might reach him?
Oh, I'd love to help ya
get in touch with Walter.
Bet he could use
the money, but...
I don't know where he is.
Walter and me haven't
spoke in three years.
Well, if you do talk to him,
tell him we got in touch.
Thank you, ma'am.
Have a good day.
Leave a message.
Walter, it's mom.
A guy just come by the house
looking for ya. He's a cop.
On a gut level it
doesn't make sense.
The only thing this guy cares
about in life is his job.
And you know this, why?
Because he went out to the academy a few
times and ran your field exercises?
Listen to me. Pete Garrison
was my best friend...
For 10 years... till
he slept with my wife.
So trust me when I tell you, the only thing
Pete Garrison cares about is Pete Garrison.
- Yeah?
- Somebody who's not tom dipaola...
Just signed in to our databases
using dipaola's password.
Pulled up an address in
andrewsboro, Maryland.
I don't believe this.
Get the rest of the
team ready. Let's go.
Walter!
Notify intel we've got a body.
Take the cars around
to the other side!
Pete!
Damn it.
This is breckinridge. I'm in a
salvage boat at the end of the dock.
- Set up a perimeter now. Do you copy?
- Copy that.
- Whoa, whoa.
- Secret service.
Get your men to the
back of the boat.
Pete, don't move!
Pete!
- The traitor is still out there, Dave.
- Fine.
If that's true, come on
in. We'll protect you.
The only reason that I'm alive
is they don't know where I am.
Don't make me do this.
- No way!
- Don't make me do this. Pete!
You want to shoot me?
Forget about the kevlar.
Shoot me in my face!
Dave! My buddy!
Come on! Shoot me!
Come on. Shoot me.
- What happened?
- I took him down with a shot to the vest.
I couldn't take the second shot.
What's the least
contained environment...
The president's going to be
in over the next few days?
G8 summit. Toronto.
It's a nightmare for us.
Canadians are allowing the protestors
all the way up to the three perimeter.
The border's not gonna stop him. It's
3,500 miles long and barely patrolled.
You really think
it's him, don't you?
Pete, you scared me!
Nancy, I'm sorry. I
can explain everything.
What is going on? What the
hell's been happening?
I think Charlie got wind
of an assassination
plot by one of the
other agents...
So I want to check his computer files, see
if there's any indication of evidence.
Is that why there's a
car watching the house?
The maroon Cadillac.
Who are they?
I think they're the
guys that got Charlie.
Nancy, I'm gonna need the keys to your
car, and I want you to call the police.
Not the secret service. The police.
Tell 'em about the Cadillac.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
I was waiting there maybe three
hours. Nobody showed up.
I didn't want to
stay there all day.
She didn't go nowhere. She
didn't go nowhere, so I left.
What do you want me to do?
Come on. Yes, yes, by herself.
Okay. Yeah, yeah. No, no.
What do you want?
I'm not gonna stay there all night.
She's not gonna be a problem.
No, no. No.
Yes, yes, by herself.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Shooting. Shooting.
- Huh? Huh?
- Shooting!
Your name? Your name!
Who sent you? Who sent you!
Come on. Come on.
- Hi, Jill.
- Pete?
Yeah. Look, I just
got into a shootout.
1265 Leslie, northwest.
He's a foreign operative. He's got a
lot of passports and a lot of cash.
He's got full security access to
the g8 summit in Toronto tomorrow.
Okay, Pete. We're on it. But i
really think you should come in.
Yeah.
Pete, we've been through
the entire place, but
you're gonna have to
be straight with me.
- What are you talking about?
- There's no body.
- There's blood all over the goddamn place.
- There's blood all over...
But there's no body, no
passports, no g8 credentials.
Listen. This is not enough to take
back to overbrook and clear you.
Dave, I don't know
what to tell you.
They're gonna hit him
in Toronto, g8 summit.
Pete. Pete?
Sarah?
Listen, I'm leaving
for Toronto tonight.
Montrose wants to move me up there
early for security purposes.
Oh!
California. My sister.
I'll call her back.
Well, this is the speech I'm gonna
give. I'm... I'm reasonably happy.
Maybe you could take a look
at that if you get a chance.
Sure. Then I'll see you tomorrow.
I'll be up after the meeting.
Okay. Thanks.
One new message.
Sarah, I want you to know if i
don't make it, I was doing my job.
I've got to turn this off
before they track me.
I love you.
I want you to get the crime scene
unit out here immediately.
- Rip this place apart.
- Find me something now.
- This is agent breckinridge.
- Agent breckinridge?
Sarah ballentine.
Come in.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Thanks, tom.
- Could I offer you a drink?
- No, thank you, ma'am.
You know, most women
don't like whiskey...
But my mama was from Tennessee.
Pete Garrison and i
are having an affair.
Please have a seat.
And... that's for you.
You know, I don't know all the
evidence you have against him...
But I do know why he failed
the lie detector test.
And I know why he was in that
coffee shop looking for someone.
Hello. U.S. secret
service up for the g8.
I got a priority item for the
duty officer over at the lab.
That'll be that direction
on the eighth floor.
Thank you.
Sign the log, please.
I need any prints that you
can find off this cup.
- Okay.
- Thank you very much.
See you in about 12 minutes.
Sweeps two and three
now complete.
I'm gonna be pushing
post in a few minutes...
- But if you want to grab a coffee...
- Marin.
- Hey, Jill. This is Pete.
- A lot of people are looking for you.
I'm sure they are.
- Did you find any prints at the apartment?
- No. Nothing.
I did. You gotta help me out.
If I e-mail the
prints to you, how long
is it gonna take...
To check them against the
f.B.I. And c.I.A. Databases?
Five minutes after
i receive 'em.
I'll call you five minutes
after I send them. Bye.
I've got a print in here. Could
somebody run it for me, please?
- Yeah, I got it.
- Thank you.
In my experience a guilty man doesn't
break into a police station...
And check fingerprints
for a few hours.
What do you think?
My phone was only on
for five minutes.
I was in the neighborhood.
Dave, I can't explain about the bank
account. The other things I can explain.
- I know about the affair.
- It wasn't with Cindy.
Oh, I know. The first lady.
She told me everything. I
know you're being framed.
She showed me the
blackmail photos.
So where does that leave us?
- We need to find this guy.
- Come here.
Yeah.
You really are an
idiot, you know that?
You honestly thought that
this wouldn't be uncovered?
Dave, I love her.
Well, that's practical.
The prints belong to gennady
Ivanov, former k.G. B...
Now works for the personal security
service for the president of karjastan.
I'm also showing confirmed
intel that this is the guy...
Responsible for the central
Asian pipeline attacks.
Confirmed intel on
what, agent marin?
This is a classified conversation.
We'll be out of here in two minutes.
- Yeah. Whatever.
- Thank you.
These people have the financial and
intelligence resources to pull this off.
All right, let's get going.
We've still gotta find the mole.
We polygraphed every agent
with access to the president.
Yours was the only one
that showed deception.
We need to figure out how the
real traitor passed the test.
Montrose had the list.
You know I never
guaranteed you success.
Security's tighter
than it's ever been.
Routes, modes of transport,
they're all random now.
Yeah, but not random
to you, William.
I mean, if you wanted
him on that helicopter
at camp David, you could
have put him there.
Now, you've been playing
us since the beginning.
All right. Fair enough.
That's not gonna work anymore.
- You did make a deal.
- Yeah.
Twenty years ago with the k.G.B.,
which doesn't even exist anymore.
Do you want out, William?
Then give me... the president.
Just like you agreed.
No.
I don't care.
Expose me.
I don't care if I spend the rest
of my life in prison for treason.
I don't care if you kill me.
- Here you go.
- Have a pint.
Oh. Thank you.
William...
If you don't do this,
we're not gonna kill you.
We are going to kill her.
And we're gonna kill her.
And then we're gonna kill her.
Yes, William, the k.G.B.'S gone.
But we're still here.
William, it's all right.
You do have a way out.
But only one.
When he finishes his speech, you
take him on the primary route...
To the "b" motorcade
under the Plaza...
And you take the radios out.
Then that's it. And
we'll do the rest.
Hey, look.
You can keep those.
I got doubles.
Jill, it's David. I want you to get
in touch with downing and Medina.
Confirm for me which one did montrose's
polygraph and get back to me.
- We're on our way to city hall.
- Got it.
Command post from
apache follow-up.
Arrive Martinez location
1740 hours. Copy.
Summon security, dipaola.
Cincinnati's moving to hold.
All posts, all posts, be
advised. We have an arrival.
Only essential traffic
at this time.
- Everybody ready?
- Yes, sir.
Let's do this.
Yeah, tell me what you got.
- Montrose didn't take the polygraph.
- You're 100% sure?
Positive. Polygraphers have no record
of montrose even being tested.
- Neither one of them.
- Montrose didn't take the polygraph.
Now let there be no mistake. In an
uncertain and an unsafe world...
America must be strong.
But previous administrations...
I also hacked into
merriweather's staff mail.
He was streaming someone's
offshore phone logs.
- The logs are montrose's.
- Give me the phone.
Hi, Jill. It's Pete.
Get a hold of the first lady and tell
her... only her... that it's montrose.
Got it.
Jesus Christ, Pete. The first
lady? What were you thinking?
I never saw it coming, Dave.
Be advised, they just allowed
two armed credentialed...
American agents into the three
perimeter from checkpoint 386.
Be advised, suspect Garrison
has just been let through...
I've got a scope on
subject Garrison.
Ah, Jesus! I got Garrison
through the three.
This resolution cannot function
alone. It is designed...
It's Garrison and Breck.
Holster your weapons.
Holster your weapons!
I'm agent breckinridge. I issued
the warrant on Pete Garrison.
Subject in my sight.
Do I take the shot?
We must ratify the
Kyoto protocol.
We must embrace the ideal
of an African economic union.
Need assistance, over.
- He's a do not admit.
- We have orders.
- I am countermanding your orders!
- You don't control this site.
- Montrose does.
- Don't call him!
- Montrose is the mole!
- Montrose?
What's the procedure for that?
No unauthorized personnel
beyond the two perimeter.
Ma'am.
Something's wrong. My
radio just went dead.
I've lost my radio. I
don't have any radio.
- I'm not hearing any chatter.
- I've got silence on all channels.
- It's going down!
- Agent Garrison called on my line.
He wanted me to tell you
that montrose is the mole.
But I strongly believe that we can
protect our vital interests...
Without causing resentment.
Get your hands in the air!
- Put that down!
- Pete Garrison is not the mole!
- You are a do not admit!
- But at the same time...
- Mr. president.
- Listen to me!
Do not let him move
the president!
This way, Mr. president.
- Do not let montrose move the president!
- Montrose, he's getting away!
Crystal. Crystal
is the password.
We need your help. Tom, get the
first lady to the motorcade.
It's all right.
Freeze!
Password is crystal. Where'd
montrose take the president?
- Motorcade "b."
- Stay with me, ma'am.
This way.
- It's just this way, ma'am.
- Tom, where are we going?
We're going to
motorcade "c," ma'am.
That's a hell of a
way to leave the g8.
What is going on with
these goddamn radios?
Go in twos.
What's next, boss?
What's the next move?
- What's next?
- Bill?
Hold the corridor.
Push 'em back.
Crystal!
Pete, we're cut off
from the "b" motorcade.
You okay?
- I think so.
- Turn off your locator.
What?
Your locator, turn it off. That's how they
know where we are. They're tracking us.
How do you... how do you know?
Oh, no, bill. Oh, god.
Montrose was...
Pete. Pete.
My family. My family. Pete!
Mr. president, you're
gonna have to trust us.
We're gonna get you up
top to an evac car.
Shooter's at 11:00. I'll go
high. You go low. You ready?
- Yeah.
- Go.
Get the president upstairs.
We'll cover you from here.
This way, ma'am. As
quick as you can.
Yes. Garrison.
Need a hard car for the
president at southwest two.
Coming to you, Pete.
Go. Go! Go, go!
Southwest stairs.
Let's go get 'em!
All right, we're gonna
get you out of here.
Give me a perimeter 10
meters, 360 degrees!
President's hard car!
Let's get him in!
Pete, I got him. Mr.
president, you're with me.
The president is away!
Go, go, go, go!
Oh, my god! Oh, my god.
- Secure the first lady!
- We need a hard car, now!
Carl.
Listen, Pete, um...
You take care of yourself.
I'll save you a tee time.
Tom, you did a great job. I
was proud to work with you.
- Thanks.
- Thanks a lot.
I'll see you guys. Good careers.
Take care.
Do well, guys. See you soon.
- Hey, Pete.
- Yeah?
This could be trouble.
I'm gonna walk out of the
white house carrying this?
Thanks, guys.
- Bye-bye. All the best.
- Hey, Pete!
You gonna leave without
saying good-bye?
Well, look who's no
longer a rookie.
Thanks.
So, how about a little
retirement dinner tonight?
I can't. I got a date.
- Something you want to tell me?
- With my wife.
That's great.
- Pete.
- See you around campus, Jill.
- Thanks for everything.
- Pleasure.
Yeah, I'm gonna miss it.
It's gonna miss you too.
Take care.