Mr. Cash?
M... Mr. Cash?
Mr. Cash.
J.R.
J.R., turn it off and get to sleep.
Change it, J.R. Turn it off.
Guess which Carter that is.
- Anita?
- Nope. June.
That was 10-year-old June singing.
What was the name
of that number?
I was gonna sing...
Turn it off.
Do I have to come in there?
Now here's the cut...
Let's get to bed.
It's hot.
It's gonna be hotter tomorrow.
Maybe Daddy will quit us early
and we can go fishing.
We'll go fishing Saturday.
Daddy needs a good day
from us tomorrow, J.R.
I know.
- Jack?
- Mm-hm?
How come you're so good?
I ain't.
- You pick five times more than me.
- Well, I'm bigger than you are.
You know every story in Scripture.
Well, you know every song
in Mama's hymnal.
Songs are easy.
They ain't for me.
There's more words in the Bible
than in Heavenly Highway Hymns.
Look, J.R., if I'm gonna be
a preacher one day...
...I gotta know the Bible
front to back.
I mean, you can't help nobody
if you can't tell them the right story.
They said by noon it's gonna be 104.
Them radio stations say anything
to get them niggers off.
Ray, why don't you let J.R.
Take the babies in?
I told Rollins
we'd have a crop yesterday.
What do I say when he pulls up here
and we're shy?
You ready to unload that piano?
We're not selling Daddy's piano.
And I'm not the one in Bardstown
drinking every Saturday.
Am I a soldier of the cross
A follower of the Lamb
And shall I fear to own His cause
Eh, what's up, doc?
Whoa.
Hey, what did that...? That rooster
say when he was all blown up...
...by TNT and picking his feathers up
outside that henhouse?
"Fortunately, boy, I keep my feathers
numbered for just such an emergency."
I got it. I got it.
Can we go soon?
Mr. Coles gave me a dollar
to cut the whole pile and not half.
Go on ahead, J.R. Catch a fish.
Put a worm on a hook
And drop it in a brook
If things go right
You'll fry some fish tonight
Where you been? Where you been?
Throw that pole down. Get in the car.
In the car.
You hear them, J. R?
Do you hear them angels?
I can hear them, Jack.
They're so beautiful.
They're beautiful.
Jack?
Do something.
You know what that is, J. R?
- You know what that is...?
- Stop it, Ray.
Nothing.
Nothing. That's what that is.
That's what that's worth.
And that's what you are.
Leave him alone, Ray. He didn't do this.
The devil did this.
He took the wrong son.
Stop it, Ray.
He was my best. Now he's gone.
Jack, please don't leave me alone.
Ray.
Quiet!
Stop it...
Quiet! Everybody, quiet!
You're gonna miss your bus.
How come they put "John"
on there, J. R?
Your name's J.R., not John.
Letters don't cut it in the Air Force,
Reba. They told me to pick a name.
Communist troops
have been driven out of Seoul...
... by U.S. Forces,
led by General Douglas MacArth...
Oh. What's that?
- Anybody seen Tommy? Hey.
- He's leaving, Ray. Come on.
Now, don't start crying, Mama.
- Be careful with that rifle, J.R.
- Yeah, I will, Mama.
Last month that Purvis boy
got confused and shot himself.
Ain't gonna be no battles, Carrie.
He's going to Germany.
The war is in Korea.
I love you.
- Love you too.
Take this.
Thanks, Mama.
Take care of yourself, Donzil.
Take care of my sister too.
I will.
Hey, Tommy? Be a good boy.
- You're gonna miss your bus.
- Yeah.
Excuse me. May I?
"Dear Vivian, I really miss you.
Boo hoo hoo."
It don't matter what you write, Cash.
No chassis like that's gonna stay parked
in her daddy's driveway for two years.
Cash.
Write something.
I saw this church in Düsseldorf
made of limestone.
Big as a train station.
We can get married there
and go to Venice.
That's in Italy, Viv. The streets
are made of water. I ain't kidding.
Johnny...
I haven't seen you for two years.
We only dated for a month.
My daddy says there's
something wrong with you.
Well, what do you say, Viv?
I mean, I thought you said
you loved me.
I do. Oh, I do. I...
Well, then don't be scared.
You tell him that.
- You tell him I love you too.
- He says that's impossible.
- He says that you hardly know me.
- I think I know perfect when I meet it.
Let's go, Cash.
Viv...
Listen, baby. You tell your daddy
I'm your man.
Tell him we'll make a family, and I'm
gonna be on the radio because I am.
You tell him we'll have a nice house,
and we'll be happy.
We'll live in Memphis.
Tell him I'll love you forever.
- You promise?
- That's a promise, Viv. You hear me...?
Five minutes was up
five minutes ago.
I am Folsom Prison.
At one time they called me
Bloody Folsom.
And I earned the name.
My own prisoners built me.
Every block of my granite
is cemented by the blood of men.
Is it any wonder a man
sometimes went berserk...
... and fought the hated walls
that shut him in?
Knock it off, you.
Let a guy get some sleep.
This was a common scene
in those old days.
I had so little work for them to do.
I hear the train comin'
Comin' down the line
I can't see no sunshine
From this window of mine
I'm stuck.
When I was just a baby
My momma said to me, "Son"
"Always be a good boy"
"Don't you mess around with guns"
But I killed a man in Reno
Just to watch him die
When I hear that whistle blowin'
I hang my head...
- and cry
You gonna try today, John?
Really try to sell something?
- What does that mean?
- I cleaned out your case last night.
Baby, all I found were peanut bags
and music magazines.
I need you to think
about what my daddy offered.
Viv, I'm trying. I mean,
I'm really trying to sell stuff.
Hello, ma'am. I'm from Home Equipment
Company over on Summer...
...and we have a lot of products...
Enamel colors that you can choose from,
uh, that we can...
Hello, I'm John Cash, and I'm from the
Home Equipment Company on Summer.
Lucretia. Lucretia, who is it?
Hey, you are late.
Well, I woke up this morning
Looked out the door
I can tell that old milk cow
By the way she lowed
Well, if you've seen my milk cow
Please ride her on home
I ain't had no milk and butter
Since that cow's been gone
I've tried to treat you right
Day by day
Get out your little prayer book
Get down on your knees and pray
You're gonna need
You're gonna need your lovin'
Daddy's help someday
Well, then you're gonna be sorry
For treating me this way
Oh, come now!
A little higher.
You're close. Little higher.
A little... Yeah, a little higher.
Now play the chord.
That's good.
Let's hear your E, Marshall.
There's my E.
Loulabelle, time to come in.
Jack. Jack, get in here.
- Let's go.
Jack.
Let's go, John.
There are some people
Say you cannot tell
Whether you are saved or
Whether all is well
They say you only can hope and
Trust that it is so
Well, I was there when it happened
And so I guess I ought to know
Yes, I know when Jesus saved me
- Saved my soul
- The very moment He forgave me
Made me whole
He took away my heavy burdens
Lord, He gave me peace within
- Peace within
- Well, Satan can't make me doubt it
I won't doubt it
I'm gonna shout it...
Viv?
Viv, open the door.
Viv.
Viv, don't embarrass me.
Everyone's out there watching.
I wanna see my daddy.
I wanna go home, John. Please.
He's just got a job sitting in there,
in San Antonio waiting for us.
- It's just sitting there, waiting.
- Viv. The guys are here.
My band is here in Memphis.
Your band? John, your band?
Your band is two mechanics
who can't hardly play.
Oh, baby, can't you hear the difference
between you and that?
You have your wife and your baby
in a dump, John...
...and another one on the way.
And we can't even make rent.
John...
Soon your sugar-daddies will all be gone
You'll wake up some cold day
And find you're alone
You'll call for me
But I'm gonna tell you, "Bye, bye, bye"
When I turn around and walk away
You'll cry, cry, cry
You're gonna cry, cry, cry
And you'll cry alone
When everyone's forgotten
And you're left on your own
You're gonna cry, cry, cry
Hey.
- You hate me?
- No, I don't.
That's a mean song.
Stupid is what it is, Viv.
Yeah.
Vi... Viv, it's just a song.
Excuse me, sir?
You the owner of this place?
- That's me.
- Hello. I'm J.R. Cash.
Sam Phillips.
Good to meet you, Mr. Phillips.
I'm a singer, and I got a band.
We've been working on some songs.
You wanna cut a record, son,
it's $4.
Well, what about the guys there
on the wall in the pictures?
- I mean, they pay $4?
- They're on my label.
Well, how do I get on there?
- You audition.
- Right now?
No...
Call my secretary, Marion,
when she comes back.
She's at the salon. She'll get you
an appointment next month.
- I can't wait that long, Mr. Phillips.
- Excuse me?
I can't wait that long.
- What about this one? I can iron it.
- No.
John, you can't wear that one.
It's black.
It's the only color of shirt we all have.
Nothing wrong with black.
- It looks like you're going to a funeral.
- Well, maybe I am.
Yes, I know when Jesus saved me
Saved my soul
The very moment He forgave me
- Made me whole
He took away my heavy burdens
Lord, He gave me peace within
- Peace within
- Well, Satan can't make me doubt it
I won't doubt it
- It's real and I'm gonna shout it
I'm gonna shout it
Hold on. Hold on.
I hate to interrupt,
but you guys got something else?
I'm sorry. I can't market gospel
no more.
So that's it?
I don't record material
that doesn't sell, Mr. Cash.
And gospel like that doesn't sell.
So is it the gospel
or the way I sing it?
Both.
Well, what's wrong
with the way I sing it?
I don't believe you.
- You saying I don't believe in God?
J.R., come on. Let's go.
No. I wanna understand.
I mean, we come down here...
...we play, and he tells me
I don't believe in God.
You know exactly what I'm telling you.
We've already heard that song.
A hundred times. Just like that.
Just like how you singing it.
- Well, you didn't let us bring it home.
- Bring it...
Bring it home?
All right, let's bring it home.
If you was hit by a truck, and you
was lying out in that gutter dying...
...and you had time to sing
one song, huh?
One song people would remember
before you're dirt...
...one song that would let God know
what you felt about your time...
...here on Earth, one song
that would sum you up...
...you telling me
that's the song you'd sing?
That same Jimmie Davis tune
we hear on the radio all day?
About your peace within
and how it's real...
...and how you're gonna shout it?
Or would you sing
something different?
Something real? Something you felt?
I'm telling you right now,
that's the kind of song...
...people want to hear.
That's the kind of song...
...that truly saves people.
It ain't got nothing to do
with believing in God, Mr. Cash.
It has to do with believing in yourself.
Well, I got a couple songs
I wrote in the Air Force.
You got anything
against the Air Force?
No.
I do.
J.R., whatever you're about
to play, we ain't never heard it.
I hear the train a-comin'
It's rollin' around the bend
And I ain't seen the sunshine
Since I don't know when
I'm stuck in Folsom Prison
And time keeps draggin' on
But that train keeps a-rollin'
On down to San Antone
When I was just a baby
My momma told me, "Son"
"Always be a good boy
Don't ever play with guns"
But I shot a man in Reno
Just to watch him die
When I hear that whistle blowin'
I hang my head and cry
I bet there's rich folks eatin'
In a fancy dining car
They're probably drinkin' coffee
And smokin' big cigars
Well, I know I had it comin'
I know I can't be free
But those people keep a-movin'
And that's what tortures me
Where you been?
Are you drunk?
- What happened?
- He didn't like our gospel.
So I played him some songs
that I wrote.
And we made a record, Viv.
I mean a real, real record.
We did it like six times. I had to sing
the song over and over again.
And I'm playing it, and you should've
seen Marshall, he was so nervous.
But, I mean, we made
a real record of my song.
- Oh, gee.
- I can't believe it. It's still...
Yes, sirree, you're listening
to the Tennessee Farm Hour.
Now, here's a new one
from our girl Patsy.
Good lyrics.
Did you write it?
Yeah, it won a poetry prize
in Stars and Stripes.
That was before...
That was before I set it to music.
Hey, flip that over for me, will you?
This is Bob Neal, and you're listening
to the Tennessee Farm Hour...
...brought to you
by Bronson Seed and Feed.
Mr. Phillips? Oh, man, I broke it.
I broke it, I broke it.
John. John. Broke what?
- The record, man, it's smashed.
Mr. Neal, he asked me to flip it over...
...and when I went to do it,
it slipped out of my hands and it broke.
The worst part is, I think he liked it.
John, I know.
We can do it right now.
- Let's get Luther and Marshall.
- We don't need to record it. Sit down.
- I wanna record it.
- John.
Sit down, John.
You don't have to record another one.
What you broke is the test press.
The factory sends me one of those
before they do a run of a thousand.
He's yanking your chain, Mr. Phillips.
Ain't no way nobody
could be that dumb.
Leave him be, Jerry Lee.
John?
Hmm?
When are we gonna talk about...
...how this tour is gonna work?
Because you're...
...out of town three out of four weeks
for the next three months.
Well...
You wanted it.
- Viv, I don't believe it.
He's playing it again.
Them folks at Sun tell me...
... this boy starts a
four-state tour next week.
Ho-ho! Son of a gun!
We got a baby sleeping. Come on.
Vivian, you hear that?
Hey! Hey, that's my song!
Oh, the baby.
Hear Daddy in the wind?
Cry, cry, cry
I think she really likes it.
My name is Jerry Lee Lewis
Come from Louisiana
Gonna do a little boogie
On this here piano!
Doing mighty fine
Gonna make you shake it
Gonna make you do it
Make you do it till it breaks
Called the Lewis Boogie
In the Lewis way
Lord, I do my little boogie-woogie
Every day
Never seen nobody play like that.
Well, down in New Orleans
The land of dreams
The best doggone place, son
You ever have seen
Yeah, the cats go wild
With a boogie that's hot
And my boogie makes you want to stop
And do the bop
It's called the Lewis Boogie
In the Lewis way
I do my little boogie-woogie
Every day!
Jerry Lee Lewis, ladies and
gentlemen. "The Killer," Jerry Lee Lewis.
Grab yourselves a pine box, boys.
Nobody follows "The Killer."
These next boys have just put out
their first record called "Cry, Cry, Cry."
Oh, shoot. Now I'm late.
Oh, my gosh. Excuse me.
That's my cue. Oh, no, y...
Oh, that's stuck right on my dress.
- Hey, Bill. Hold on, Bill. I'm coming.
- I think...
Oh, my, I think I hear June Carter's
voice, ladies and gentlemen.
I'll be right there, Bill.
I'll be right there.
Reckon when, June?
Well, Bill, I got tangled.
- In what, June bug?
Johnny Cash's guitar strap.
Don't worry, I can keep this funny
for at least two minutes.
And I'll tell you what, Bill.
He's a strapping boy, that Johnny Cash.
And his guitar strap's
pretty strapping too.
Here. I love that "Cry" song,
by the way.
Hey, thanks.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Miss June Carter.
Bill. Bill, I had to come and tell you.
I had to tell you.
I just can't sing tonight.
You best be getting out here.
Yeah.
Bill, I got the laryngitis.
Me too.
June, we just...
- I do. Y'all laughing, but I do.
We all just heard you hollering
up a storm backstage.
Well, I didn't have it then, Bill.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Miss June Carter.
All right, June's gonna be back
to sing later.
Her family's also with us tonight.
But like I was saying, these boys
up next are hotter than a pistol.
They are burning up the radio
with their new hit, "Cry, Cry, Cry."
And I wanna make sure we give them
a big Texarkana welcome.
So here they are, folks. New passengers
on the Sun Rocking Railway...
...Johnny Cash
and the Tennessee Two.
Hello. I'm Johnny Cash.
Hey, get rhythm
When you get the blues
Come on, get rhythm
Get a rock 'n' roll feelin'
In your bones
Get taps on your toes
And get gone
Get rhythm when you get the blues
Little shoeshine boy
Never gets low down
But he's got the dirtiest
Job in town
Bendin' low at the people's feet
On the windy corner of a dirty street
Well, I asked him
While he shined my shoes
How he'd keep
From getting the blues
He grinned as he raised his little head
He popped a shoeshine rag
And then he said
"Get rhythm when you get the blues
Come on, get rhythm
When you get the blues
Yes, a jumpy rhythm
Makes you feel so fine
It'll shake all the trouble
From your worried mind
Get rhythm when you get the blues"
All right.
Well, I sat down to listen
To the shoeshine boy
And I thought I was gonna jump for joy
Slapped on the shoe polish
Left and right
He took a shoeshine rag
And he held it tight
He stopped once
To wipe the sweat away
I said, "You're a mighty little boy
To be a-workin' thataway"
He said, "I like it"
With a big, wide grin
Kept on a-poppin' and he said again
"Get rhythm when you get the blues
Come on and get rhythm
All right!
When you get the blues
It only costs a dime, just a nickel a shoe
It does a million dollars' worth
Of good for you
Get rhythm when you get the blues"
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Well, I love that hair, long and black
Hanging down to the middle of your back
Don't cut it off, whatever you do
I need it to run my fingers through
Viv, I'm telling you, I think this is
the best show we've ever done.
Hell, it might be the best show
I've ever seen, no kidding.
Where are you?
- Texarkana. Baby, I miss you.
Hey, do you hear Orbison doing our
song? He turned it to a two-step. Listen.
- Do you hear that?
- Damn it.
What's the matter?
Damn it. Roseanne just ran
her head into the table.
Roseanne.
Roseanne. Here, talk to Daddy.
Hey, Roseanne? Hey, it's Daddy.
Honey, don't, don't cry.
Daddy's gonna be home real soon.
- John, I have to go.
- Huh?
I have to go, John.
Bye.
Hey, y'all say hi to Johnny Cash.
Dad, he wrote that "Cry, Cry, Cry" song.
Mother Maybelle.
- How you doing, Johnny Cash?
- Good. Heck, I'm great, ma'am.
- Hello, John, I'm Ezra.
- Yeah, I know.
- It was nice to meet you, son.
- Real good to meet you, sir.
I walked into a honky-tonky
Just the other day
I dropped a nickel in a jukebox
Just to hear it play
I didn't have no tune in mind
I didn't wait to choose
Just dropped a nickel in the slot
And played the Jukebox Blues
There's a guy in there
With an old tin horn
And a feller on an old banjo
And the man on the fiddle
He wasn't no slouch
He could really drag that bow
You sounded good tonight, Cash.
Real tight.
Oh, thanks, man.
You want some chili fries?
Oh, no, that's okay.
She's been in the spotlight since
you and me was biting ankles.
They say Maybelle
had a crib at the Ryman...
...so she could pull her out
and let her whoop and holler...
...and pop her back in
and go to sleep.
It must have been a drum
It gave that song a solid beat
Boy, he was goin' some
I walked into a honky-tonky
Just the other day
I dropped a nickel in a jukebox
Just to hear it play
I didn't have no tune in mind
I didn't wait to choose
Just dropped a nickel in the slot
And played the Jukebox Blues
I've played a lot of jukeboxes
Most every one in town
But that's the first tune I ever heard
That could make one dance around
Play the Jukebox Blues
Such a rhythm I never heard
I danced out both of my shoes
- We're leaving in an hour, John.
All right.
Oh, that's a sweet story, honey.
No.
I'm leaving in, like, five minutes.
All right.
Is everything else all right?
I love you too.
- Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
How you doing?
- Coffee?
- Yeah...
...and some toast, please.
- Hey.
- Hey, how are you?
Good. Do you mind?
No, not at all.
- Did you lose your voice?
- I did.
I was just singing my heart out
up there.
I got to ask you how you came up
with that sound.
What sound?
That sound everybody's talking about.
Steady like a train. Sharp like a razor.
Well, we'd play faster if we could.
You know, I guess
it just come out like that.
I gotta close my register.
- Oh, yeah, sure.
Thank you.
Here's a picture of my wife, Viv.
- My baby, Roseanne.
- Oh, look at her. She's beautiful.
Thanks. Got another one on the way.
- I got a little girl too.
- Yeah?
Her name's Carlene. Yeah.
She's about the same age.
When I was in the service,
I used to look at pictures of you.
- You know, in magazines.
- Oh.
No. No, it wasn't like that.
I mean, I...
I liked your music, you know?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I mean, I... You were... Well, you are...
I mean, I... I kept track of you.
Yeah, you and your family, you know.
I listened to your voice my whole life,
you know?
Now, me and my brother, Jack,
we always listened to your songs.
- You know, like "Swallerin' Place."
- Yeah.
Yeah, we liked it
when you'd sing one alone.
Well, you and Jack are the only ones.
- What do you mean?
- I'm not really much of a singer, John.
I mean, I got a lot of personality,
I got sass.
I give it my all, but my sister Anita's
really the one who's got the pipes.
- Well, who said that?
- Everybody.
My mama, my daddy.
That's how come I learned to be funny.
So I'd have something to offer.
Well...
Parents aren't always
the best judge of things...
...you want my opinion.
So how long you on the tour?
Another couple of weeks.
We just got on board...
...but I tell you,
it feels like a lot longer.
I'm sure.
I'm headed off.
I'm going to the Ryman.
Tell your brother Jack to tune in,
I'll sing him something.
What does he like?
Oh, that's... That's sweet.
But he passed.
I'm sorry. Were y'all real close?
Yeah. Yeah, he's, uh...
It's funny, I ain't talked about Jack
in a long time, you know? It's...
After he died, I...
I talked about him all the time...
...but I guess people grew tired of it.
So I just stopped.
John?
You're tired, aren't you?
Yeah.
It'll slow down.
It will.
I better get going.
It was good to talk to you.
- You too.
- Take care.
Hopefully, I'll see you soon.
- You better tune in.
- I'll sing you that "Swallerin' Place."
- I will. I really will.
Okay.
That's fine. That's... That's perfect.
Yes, ma'am.
When was the last time you heard him
moving around in there?
I don't know.
Thought you were gonna
help me today, John.
You head out tomorrow.
- Yeah.
Better start living life here with us
when you come home...
...before you have to leave again.
You know, I was thinking.
You know, maybe I could get Bob
to push my dates.
I'm happy when I'm here.
I like waking up and seeing your face.
John, those bags over there...
Those letters in there
are 10-to-one from girls.
Ten to one. And they're obscene.
Reba's been trying to answer
some of them.
Half of them ain't even 15...
...and they are sending pictures
of themselves in bathing suits.
Pictures for you to look at
while you're doing time at Folsom.
- Oh, Viv.
- This one girl, she sent you her diar...
Viv, don't even read
those letters, they're...
It's just crazy right now, that's all.
You know.
Hell, you should have seen last week.
We was at the fair...
...and this bus full of 4-H girls
pulls up, you know...
...and they come piling out of there.
They go running, screaming
after Carl and Roy. I mean, running.
John. I have a casserole in the oven
and your sister...
...in the kitchen, and I don't want
to talk about the tour.
Well, Viv, you, you're the one
that brought it up.
In fact, that's my new rule.
When you come home...
...I wanna get right down
to talking about regular things.
Viv, don't give me no rules.
All I got are rules.
All I got is to be
at this place at this time.
I'm trying to go there...
...and I'm trying to spend time
with you, the kids.
And write songs through this.
What do you want from me?
I got you your dream house. All of your
things, all the pretty little things.
I got you your car.
What do you want from me?
I want you, John. I want you. And I
want everything that you promised me.
Well, what if I can't do that?
Got your mind on something?
What are you doing up there, man?
I'm building a bomb.
Where are we going again?
Tyler. George Jones' show.
Where was it we just was?
- Have another one, Carl.
Austin, Carl.
That's where y'all picked me up.
Hey, John,
you seen the new charts?
"Cry, Cry, Cry" was 14, I think.
Yeah, I heard that,
but I haven't seen it.
Wherever we've been, I can tell you
where we're going.
Everybody in this car's going to hell.
And what about the car up there?
We're all going to hell
for the songs we sing.
People who listen to them
will go to hell too.
You shut up with that.
God gave us a great big apple, see?
And he said, "Don't touch it."
He didn't say touch it once in a while
or take a nibble when you're hungry.
He said, "Don't touch it."
Don't think about touching it.
Don't sing about touching it.
Don't think about
singing about touching it.
And what about me, Jerry Lee?
Am I going to hell?
No, June. You're beautiful.
Sleepy is what I am.
She's making me fall in love with her.
Feel my heart. Come here. Sincerely.
Feel my heart, baby.
It's just a-beating for you.
- Stop.
Come on, feel it.
- I'm falling for you.
Hey.
- No, you're not. Jerry Lee.
Jerry Lee.
Come on.
Sit your ass down. Just sit down.
The 1957 Chevrolet.
There's new designs...
Looks like we're here.
Oh, thank goodness.
Get me out of this car
and all these boys.
Let's go. Home sweet home, boys.
You can just put those
right there. That'd be great.
Oh, wait. I wanted
to give you that Billboard.
Oh, right.
It's in here somewhere.
You got a library in there, June.
Here it is. I circled it for you.
It's right there.
Yeah, 14.
I can't believe it.
Um, I wanted to give you this.
I just finished it. It's really amazing.
- "The Prophet"?
- Yeah.
Keep it.
- Oh, no. You don't...
- Whenever I finish a book...
...I give it away to somebody.
It just lightens my load.
John.
I just went through a terrible divorce.
And I got a world of judgment
on me right now.
And, um, it's really
none of my business...
...but you seem like you have
a nice family.
I'm sorry. It just happened.
Just happened?
Yeah.
And you wear black because you can't
find anything else to wear?
You found your sound
because you can't play no better?
And you just tried
to kiss me...
...because it just happened?
You should try taking credit
for something every once in a while.
John.
- Hey, Luth.
- Hey, John.
You okay?
I'll let you know in a few minutes.
How you doing?
Okay. That boy Elvis
sure likes to talk poon.
That's all I heard since Lubbock.
- You want some?
- What is it?
They'll make you wanna drive
all the way to Jacksonville...
...and enjoy yourself
once you get there.
Elvis takes them.
Yeah.
Yes, sir.
Try some.
That's a lot. Be careful.
Here comes Marshall with his bomb.
You got your lighter, J. R?
- Yeah.
All right, you help me
get up in there. Grab that fuse.
How long we got us after we light it?
About 30 seconds a foot.
All right.
He light it?
Does your wife know...
...you like to blow stuff up?
Sure she does. That's why
I married her, John.
Well, you light it?
There's a bomb up there...
It'll go.
It didn't work.
Way to go, Johnny boy.
It was around about four
And I thought she would stop
She looked at me
And then she looked at the clock
She said, "Now, wait a minute, Daddy
Now, don't you get sore"
"'Cause all I want to do
Is rock a little bit more"
'Cause she's my rock 'n' roll Ruby
Rock 'n' roll, rock 'n' roll Ruby
Rock 'n' roll
When Ruby starts a-rockin'
It satisfies my soul
One night my Ruby left me all alone
I tried to contact her on the telephone
I finally found her about twelve o'clock
She said, "Leave me 'lone, Daddy
'Cause your Ruby wants to rock"
'Cause she's my rock 'n' roll Ruby
Rock 'n' roll
Rock 'n' roll Ruby, rock 'n' roll
When Ruby starts a-rockin'
Man, it satisfies my soul
Thank you. Thank you very much.
How about them boys, huh?
Johnny Cash
and the Tennessee Three.
- You kicked it good tonight, John.
Thanks, man.
That's right. Kiss his ass.
Hey, Jerry Lee,
your mama know you're out?
She knows.
How about that Johnny Cash,
everybody?
Johnny Cash.
Well, that's all right, Mama
That's all right with you
That's all right, Mama
Just any way you do
Well, that's all right, that's all right
That's all right now, Mama
Any way you do
Well, Mama, she done told me
Papa done told me, too
Said, "Son, that gal you're foolin' with
She ain't no good for you"
Well, that's all right
That's all right
Now, that's all right now, Mama
Any way you do
Okay.
Mr. Cash?
Yeah?
There's a Miss Audrey Parks
here to see you.
Who?
Audrey Parks.
Hey.
Well, that's all right
That's all right
Now, that's all right now, Mama
Any way you do
Oh, get it now!
Ray, why don't you say grace?
Mama, it's J.R.'s table.
Why don't you say grace, J. R?
No, go ahead, Pa.
I go out on a party
And look...
And look for a little fun
I found...
But I find a...
Shit.
But I find a darkened corner
Go out on a party
And look for a little fun
But I find a darkened corner
'Cause I still miss someone
Hi.
- Hi.
You're June Carter, ain't you?
Oh, my. Betsy Purvis.
Hi, Betsy.
So nice to meet you.
- We're coming to the show.
- Wonderful.
- This is my husband, Lloyd.
Hi, Lloyd. So nice to meet you.
You know where
the fishing tackle is?
- Back of them footballs on the corner.
- All right, great.
Enjoy the show. And if you have
any requests, just holler them out.
Good morning.
- Hey.
She's even prettier in person.
Can I help you?
- Oh, I'm looking for some lace.
Oh, the sewing store on Saticoy's
got lace.
Thank you.
You know, your ma and pa...
...are good Christians
in a world gone to pot.
Well, I'll tell them you said that.
I'm surprised they still speak to you.
After that stunt with Carl Smith.
Divorce is an abomination.
Marriage is for life.
I'm sorry I let you down, ma'am.
- Hey.
Hey.
What's funny?
You've been standing in that
spot for about 10 minutes...
...staring at that Polly Pepper book.
Well, I can't... I can't figure which
one Roseanne would like more.
She got brown hair,
which makes me think this one.
- Right.
- But this is "Baby Sisters."
And she got a baby sister, and...
Well, I got that one for Carlene,
and she liked it.
- Mm-hm. I missed her birthday.
- Oh.
So I wanted
to get her something more...
...you know? Like one
of these dollhouses.
But I don't know how
to get it out to her.
Want me to help you?
I think there's a lake right
up around the corner.
- You got a hitch in your giddyup?
- Yeah.
Forgot how much I like this.
Hey, June? I never used one of these
fancy reels before.
Well, what'd you use, a sapling?
Yeah.
Okay, hold on. I'll help you.
It's like there's some kind
of lock on it or...
No. My daddy taught me
how to do this, I'll show you.
Keep your thumb there
on the button.
That loosens the line.
And then you're gonna bring it back.
Then you're gonna throw it out there.
And then when you're ready,
if you got a good spot for it...
...you let go of the button. All right?
- Sidearm?
- Yeah, sidearm.
All right.
See? There you go.
Just around the corner
There's heartache
Down the street that losers use
If you can wade in
Through the teardrops
You'll find me
At the Home of the Blues
Yeah, you're gonna find me at
The Home of the Blues
Hey, folks, what do you say
we get June Carter out here again?
Maybe she'll sing with me.
No, no, no. No.
Oh, come on, June.
I never sing with you.
I got my slippers on,
and I'm not coming out there.
They don't care
if you got your slippers on.
Come on,
it's the shank of the evening.
Folks, let's hear it. June. June.
June, June, June.
- June, June, June.
- Come on, June, prove Elvis wrong.
He says you can't do nothing
that ain't written in your calendar.
June, June, June,
June, June, June.
See, June?
They wanna see us together.
All right. Quit that clutching on me
and I'll sing with you.
But you gotta quit clutching on me.
Hi, folks. How y'all doing again?
I hope y'all don't mind my bare feet.
So, what are we gonna sing, Johnny?
You got me out here.
Is that where your plan ends?
Well, I always liked
that song of yours:
"Time's a-Wastin'."
Let's do that one.
Oh, come on. I don't know about that.
How about your hit song, "Big River"?
That's a good song.
Well, "Big River" ain't a duet.
- Uh, let's do "Time's a-Wastin'."
- I am not gonna sing that song.
It's inappropriate. I recorded it
with my ex-husband. I will not sing it.
No better way to put it behind you.
- I'm not gonna do it.
- June, just sing.
- I've got arms
- And I've got arms
Let's get together and use those arms
Let's go
- Time's a-wastin'
I've got lips
And I've got lips
Let's get together and use those lips
Let's go
- Time's a-wastin'
A cake's no good
If you don't mix the batter
And bake it
And love's just a bubble
If you don't take the trouble
To make it
- So if you're free to go with me
I'll take it quicker than one-two-three
Let's go
- Time's a-wastin'
Don't do that.
Hey, June.
June? Open up.
June, open the door.
Just leave me be, John, all right?
What? What, what did I do?
June, it's a song.
Just please get away from me.
I think I hear Johnny
Cash and the Tennessee Three.
They'll be playing all weekend long
at the Malco.
Matinees and evening shows...
... along with Jerry Lee Lewis,
June Carter and Carl Perkins.
It's the candyman
Well, all you ladies gather round
You know who's comin' to town
And it ain't Santa Claus
It's the candyman
The candyman right there, Luther.
How come you don't never try
this brand of picking, Luther?
What you're looking for, Waylon,
I already found.
The candyman is coming home
Don't get stuck
On the candyman's stick
Well, hey, June.
Hey, Jerry Lee.
How you doing, John?
Uh...
Well, okay, June. How you doing?
I surmise you've never been to bed.
- "Surmise."
We got a show at 2.
- A matinee. You remember?
We were just practicing.
- Sit down. It's slick here.
Practice makes perfect.
- Not today, Jerry Lee.
Why not?
- Because you're drunk.
Uh-oh.
Amen, brother.
Come on, Junie, just come
have a beer with us.
I'm going home tonight
after the show.
I'm not here to look after y'all.
You're not?
You got somebody
to do that for you, John.
You got a wife somewhere.
You remember that?
Well, what if I didn't?
There's too many ifs in that sentence.
Only one, actually.
There's only one if
in that sentence, June.
Good point.
I thought it was a good point.
I mean, there is only one.
- Really?
It's a good point.
Hey.
- Don't talk to me like that.
We surrender. We surrender.
What was I thinking?
I must've been crazy.
Y'all are gonna blow this tour.
You can't walk no line.
June, we ain't blowing the tour.
I am not gonna be that little Dutch boy
with my finger in the dam no more.
You're lying to yourself
if you think this is about a tour.
This isn't about a tour.
This isn't about a song.
I keep a close watch
On this heart of mine
I keep my eyes wide open all the time
I keep the ends out
For the tie that binds
I got his picture.
Because you're mine, I walk the line
As sure as night is dark
And day is light
I keep you on my mind
Both day and night
And happiness I've known
Proves that it's right
John. Honey, I wanna take
your picture. Roseanne, look at Mommy.
Say cheese.
You've got a way
To keep me on your side
You give me cause for love
That I can't hide
For you I know
I'd even try to turn the tide
Because you're mine, I walk the line
What do you think of California?
We like it.
We just bought a house.
I keep a close watch
On this heart of mine
I keep my eyes wide open all the time
I keep the ends out
For the tie that binds
Because you're mine, I walk the line
Lunchtime.
Come on in, everybody.
Hey, Kath? Roseanne?
Hey, girls, look up in the sky.
Hey, girls!
Hurry up, you can't miss it.
Hey. You see that bird up there?
You see that bird? That's a falcon.
Yeah.
Lunchtime.
Come on in, everybody.
This is the topic.
All right, the answer is:
You ought to know that one.
You look at the funnies.
- Shmoos.
What were the shmoos?
Correct. Go on and choose the next.
Let's go with...
What is this?
Hey, I've been looking for that.
That's the letter I wrote
to Bob Dylan on the plane.
That folk singer I told you about.
You wrote it on an
airsickness bag, honey.
So what?
What's so funny?
I was thinking maybe
you ought to try sleeping at night.
Maybe eating. Maybe both.
Hey, Viv, you made
your mind up about tonight?
You coming?
Well, okay. Because you're asking
so nice.
I got it. Got it.
Hello? Hey, Bob.
Hey, can you hold on a second?
One second.
Hello.
So, uh, you tell them awards people
that we're gonna come.
Uh-huh.
Hey, Bob. Do you know,
is June gonna be there?
This year we had a British
invasion, a beautiful girl from Brazil...
...a matchmaker from New York.
We even had a flying nanny.
- In 1964, we covered the globe.
Hey, Johnny.
Hey, Randy, how are you?
- With some incredible acts...
June? Hey.
Hi, John.
- Been a long time.
- Yeah.
- Hi, Vivian. How are you?
- Hello, June.
I saw you got married.
- Uh, yes, I did.
- Congratulations, June.
Thank you. I appreciate that.
- You're welcome.
- So you think this one will stick?
John.
Is this your third?
I'm just asking a question.
Do not do this to me.
John.
- Hey, June, wait. I need to talk to you.
- I don't want to talk to you, John.
Hey, excuse me, fella, do you mind?
You don't look good, John.
Well, you look real nice.
So where's your truck driver?
Stock-car driver.
You'll be happy to know
things aren't working out.
It doesn't make me happy.
Well, a little, it does.
I wanna tour with you again, June.
I miss the tour.
I miss the music.
I got two growing girls, John.
I can't tour.
You're gonna do the comedy
act the rest of your life?
You got a voice, June. Use it.
One week a month. That's all.
All right,
you'll work for me.
You don't have to worry about bookings,
agents, publicists or anything.
And if one of your girls get sick,
you stay home and I pay you anyways.
Oh, he taught me to love him
And promised to love
And to cherish me over
All others above
How my heart is now wondering
No misery can tell
He's left me no warning
No words of farewell
Oh, he taught me to love him
And called me his flower
That was blooming to cheer him
Through life's dreary hour
How I long to see him
And regret the dark hour
He's gone and neglected
This pale wildwood flower
Thank you. That's my
mama's favorite song.
So y'all sit down, squat down or lie
down, but make yourselves at home...
...because here's the one and only...
...Mr. Johnny Cash.
Hello, I'm Johnny Cash.
Go away from my window
Leave at your own chosen speed
I'm not the one you want, babe
I'm not the one you need
- You say you're looking for someone
- Who's never weak but always strong
- To protect you and defend you
- Whether you are right or wrong
- Someone to open each and every door
- But it ain't me, babe
- No, no, no, it ain't me, babe
- It ain't me you're looking for, babe
- Go lightly from the ledge, babe
- Go lightly on the ground
- I'm not the one you want, babe
- I'll only let you down
You say you're looking for someone
Who'll promise never to part
Someone to close his eyes to you
Someone to close his heart
- Someone to die for you and more
- But it ain't me, babe
- No, no, no, it ain't me, babe
- It ain't me you're looking for
Great show.
- Thank you.
We loved it.
- It's all June. It's all June.
- Brilliant, John.
Thank you.
Hi, good to see you.
- Thanks for coming.
- Hello.
What's next?
- We're booked in Vegas.
June?
Yeah?
- I want you to meet my parents.
- That's my mama and my daddy.
- Hi.
How you doing?
- It's so nice to meet you finally.
Hi, I'm June Carter.
- Miss Carter.
- Nice to meet you.
You haven't met my little girls,
have you? This is Roseanne...
Oh, they were sleeping with...
Ain't they sweet?
You girls are all dressed alike.
I love those yellow ribbons.
June.
- Yeah?
Stay clear of my children.
Vivian, I was just saying hello.
- You heard me.
Viv.
- Vivian, please.
- No.
But ifthey'll laugh at you in Jackson
I'll be dancing on a pony keg
They'll lead you 'round town
Like a scolded hound
With your tail tucked
Between your legs
You're going to Jackson
You big-talking man
And I'll be waiting in Jackson
Behind my Japan fan
- Oh, now, we got married in a fever
- We got married in a fever
- Hotter than a pepper sprout
- We've been talking about Jackson
- Ever since the fire went out
- I'm going to Jackson
- And that's a fact
- Yeah, we're going to Jackson
- Ain't never coming back
Oh, wait, catch it.
Come on, y'all.
I got this beef jerky.
You're gonna love it, man.
Nice boots.
High rollers out there?
Say, officer, how do you get
your shirts to stay that way...
...so stiff?
Just starch.
Huh. It's real nice.
What?
- What?
- Are you out of your rabbit-assed mind?
All right, good night.
- Good night, y'all.
- Good night.
Give me two, give me two.
- That was a fun show tonight.
- Yeah, it was.
- This is my room.
- Right.
Hey, you wanna have
one of these with me?
Uh...
I don't know.
Can I have one?
- John.
- All right.
Wait, wait, here.
I'll get a good one.
You know what? You're just mean.
That's what you are, you're mean.
Here, here.
- You're a mean man.
Don't say that.
- And I knew it.
I've known it all along.
Wait a minute. Here.
- Come on. Open your mouth.
- No.
I don't trust you.
- Don't say that.
- I don't trust you.
Yes, you do.
Open your mouth.
You're so evil. Terrible.
Oh...
I suppose I better answer it.
Hello?
Oh, hey, Carlene, what's wrong?
Okay, sweetie, I can't understand what
you're saying, you're crying so hard.
I know, but you gotta
calm down, honey.
All right. But everything's okay?
Yeah, I know, sweetie,
sometimes that happens.
Sweetie, little sisters do
stuff like that sometimes.
You gotta learn
to be patient with her.
Um, okay, well, um...
...tell Linda that Mommy said you can
have pancakes on Saturdays.
- Hey, June, I'm gonna go to my room.
- All right?
Yeah, I know, sweetie.
I'm gonna come home soon.
Yeah, sweetie, please don't cry.
Front desk.
- Hi, could I have June Carter's room?
Certainly. One moment, sir.
June.
It's not wrong, June.
This ain't wrong.
June.
I'm not gonna do this, John.
I'm not gonna do this.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Where's Johnny?
Johnny.
Well, Johnny Cash'll be
out in just a minute.
He's been detained for just a minute.
But we're gonna keep
you entertained till then.
And we're gonna play a wonderful...
Hold on, hold on. Johnny's here.
Yeah.
Here he is, Mr. Johnny Cash.
Hi, folks, I'm Johnny Cash.
What about that June Carter,
ain't she a sweetheart?
"I Got Stripes."
On a Monday, I was arrested
On a Tuesday, they locked me in jail
On a Wednesday, my trial was attested
And on a Thursday, they said, "Guilty"
And the judge's gavel fell
I got stripes
Stripes around my shoulders
I got chains
Chains around my feet
I got stripes
Stripes around my shoulders
And them chains
Them chains
They're about to drag me down
Get it on, man.
Play the fucking thing.
I got my... just got our britches
On a Tuesday, I got my ball and chain
On a Wednesday, my trial
On a Thurs...
They had to knock me down
I got stripes
I'm okay, I'm okay.
Oh, my God. John.
- Close the curtain. John. John.
Get a doctor.
Put the curtain back.
Come on, pull him back.
J.R., you okay?
- Yeah.
J.R., look at me.
John.
"Fortunately, I was keeping my feathers
numbered for just such an emergency."
Let's get some help.
- Junie? June?
Come on, get him some help.
- Yeah?
J. R?
What?
J.R.
The tour's been canceled, John.
Who says?
We got you a ticket home, John.
Tomorrow.
You see where I'm putting it?
Right here by the phone.
Take care of yourself, John.
You're burning up.
Got hotter places than my forehead.
Tell me you don't love me.
I don't love you.
You're a liar.
Well, then I guess you ain't
got no problems, do you?
- Where are my pills?
- Flushed them all.
June... Junie, don't say that.
Now, hold on. I... I... I need those.
I need those pills. Listen, that's just,
baby... Those are my prescriptions.
From the doctor. Okay?
I need... I need those.
Now, I know... I...
It burns...
...burns, burns.
Mommy.
Few more minutes, pal.
There you go.
The taste of love is sweet
And it burns, burns, burns, burns
Then it burns, burns, burns, burns
The ring of fire
Now boarding,
flight 1919. Service to San Jose.
At this time, we'd like
to see a boarding pass.
Final boarding call for flight 57.
Now boarding at gate 7.
Mr. Cash.
You wanna take these strings off,
or do you want us to break it?
There he is.
What kind of trouble is there?
- Your career, Mr. Cash?
Right this way.
Mr. Cash?
Right here.
Come on, John.
Your mama was here. Your daddy too.
What'd he say?
Said now you won't have to work
so hard...
...to make people think
you've been to jail.
- Daddy.
- Hey, baby.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
I'll see you in the morning.
Cindy doesn't like mustard.
The pills were legal, Viv.
You know, I got prescriptions.
You're not supposed to buy them
across the border, that's all.
Other than that, it's fine.
- So the radio's lying?
- Yeah.
- The TV's lying.
- Baby, they'll say anything.
Your lawyer's lying. Luther's lying.
- Marshall's lying. Your manager.
- Viv, I don't wanna fight.
What about June?
Does she think it's fine her
new boy's a drug addict?
She left the tour, Viv. In Vegas.
Well, that explains everything,
doesn't it?
God said to Abraham, "Kill me a son"
- Abe said, "You must be puttin' me on"
- John.
God say, "No"
Abe say, "What?"
God say, "You can do
What you want, Abe
But the next time you see me comin'
You better run"
John, what are you doing?
It's 7 a.m.
The kids are getting ready for school.
Just hanging pictures.
John, please don't hang these.
Viv, they're pictures of my band.
Don't hang these.
- No, don't hang these.
- Let go of the picture.
- I said, please don't hang these, John.
- Viv.
No.
Viv, get back here. Viv.
Viv, get back here.
- Viv, I ain't kidding.
- No.
Vivian, give me the damn picture.
- Viv, give me the pic...
- No.
Hey, Viv, wa... Don't do that.
- Now, stop it. Baby, stop it. All right...
- You. You pathetic excuse for a man.
She will find out, you liar.
She'll find out.
She'll find out, John.
- You liar.
- Stop it.
- No.
- You think you're perfect?
- You think you're perfect? Huh? Huh?
- No. No.
No.
I'm coming.
Shut the door...
Hey, you leave them out of this.
Viv. You leave them out of this.
Girls. Girls. No.
Girls.
I'm a long way from home
And so all alone
Homesick like I never thought I'd be
I'm a long way from home
Everything is wrong
Someone please watch over me
Thirty hours.
You've been asleep for 30 hours, hoss.
Hey, did June call?
Woman won't return my damn calls.
They disconnected it yesterday.
Insufficient "fundilation."
Now, come on, man.
I gave you money for that.
Well, that was last month.
This is this month.
You see, I'm a little
behind right now...
...and I need this to
turn my phone back on.
Because I need to talk to my woman.
You see, I'm in love with a woman and I
need to talk to her, you understand?
I need this to get my
car out of the shop.
And she lives way,
way out on the edge of town.
It's the Bataan Death March
to get there, you see?
So if you'll just go ahead
and cash this.
I'm sorry, Mr. Cash.
- You know who I am.
- Yes, sir.
Okay, then just please
cash my check for me.
The bank puts an automatic
hold on checks like this.
It's a large amount.
If you can't cash it,
then it's just a piece of paper.
- Oh, don't do that. Please...
- Why? You can't cash it.
It ain't nothing.
Just a damn piece of paper.
Mama, Johnny Cash is here.
Hey, girls.
- Hey, Carlene, you look real nice.
- Hey, Johnny.
- Mama, Johnny Cash is here.
- Hi, Mother Maybelle.
Hey, John.
How are you doing?
Doing all right.
Hi, June.
Hi, John.
Hey, girls can you go inside the
living room and clean up that mess?
All right, honey.
- I tried to call, June...
...but I think there's something
wrong with your phone.
Look at you.
Have you looked in a mirror lately?
How are you gonna sing
when you can't even talk?
"I got the laryngitis." Remember?
- Marry me, June.
- Oh, please. Get up off your knees.
You look pathetic. Come on.
I don't want my girls
seeing somebody like this.
- Come on, baby.
- Where's my friend John?
What'd he get, high? Or is he incognito?
Is he gone?
Because I don't like this guy Cash.
I ain't incognito.
I'm right here. You see?
- I'm here.
- Fine. Where's your car?
It's in make up.
- You walked here?
- Yeah.
You walked here all the
way from Nashville?
Yeah, well, walking's good for you.
See, I'm trying to get in shape, June.
It cleans out your system.
Well, it's a spiritual thing.
I'm on a love walk.
- The June Carter love walk. Immemorial.
- You know what?
I am supporting more than
myself right now.
Please do not blow another tour.
Oh, June, love's more
important than a tour.
- Is that right?
- Yes, it is.
Well, then start loving yourself.
So we can go back to work.
All right, June.
Hey, you keep your phone on,
and I will too.
I'll call.
I'll call you.
When you're feeling better, I'll call.
Oh. Oh, come on.
Listen, you know,
times like this, I say to myself...
...I say, "Jack, what would
the baby Jesus do?"
- That's your name? Jack?
- Mm-hm. Jack.
Shit, I need another drink.
Ahh. I am lit up of the spirit.
Yes, sir, Jack needs another drink.
June Carter, June Carter
Would you give me some time?
How much longer will it be till
Till I can call you mine?
When you see Johnny, would you tell him
That you're gonna stick around?
And then Johnny will buy you
A nice white gown
Hey, that's a beautiful house.
Hey, man.
Beautiful place, man.
- Yeah? Thanks.
- Uh-huh.
Hello?
- June?
- Hey, it's John.
- Hi.
Hey. How you doing?
I'm fine, John. How are you?
Uh, doing a lot better than
last time you saw me.
Well, that's good.
I'm glad to hear that.
- You still taking those pills?
- No.
That was, you know... That was
a rough patch there, June.
I just needed to,
you know, get some time.
I'm doing better,
though, now, you know?
I got out of that apartment...
...and got this place out
in Hendersonville on a lake. Big spread.
- I heard that.
- Yeah, I'm...
...trying to get things together.
- Uh-huh.
Are you alone on Thanksgiving, John?
Yeah... My folks are coming
down with Reba and Roseanne...
...and I got this big bird, but I don't
know when to put it in the oven...
...or really what
temperature to set it at or...
Uh-huh.
It is beautiful.
Really lucky.
I'm really proud of you.
- You see? It goes from right up there...
...clear across halfway around the lake.
- Yeah.
What's going on down
there with that tractor?
Uh, I got it stuck. I was trying to pull
this stump, and I come up...
Doing something dangerous.
- Yeah, but...
That's a fine piece of equipment to
leave in that mud.
Is that the way you take care
of your things?
Hey.
Thanksgiving, okay?
Look at this.
Hey.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Here, Carlene.
- Happy Thanksgiving.
Hey, John.
Hi.
- I like this place here.
Oh, thanks. Hey, Rosie.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Thank you.
- Hey.
Let's go and meet John's...
- House is beautiful.
Thanks. Thanks for coming.
- John, how you doing?
Let me help you.
- That's my mama, Carrie.
- Maybelle Carter, Happy Thanksgiving.
- This is my daddy, Ray.
- How you doing?
- Good to meet you.
- My mama, Carrie.
- How do you do?
- Carrie was gonna cook for y'all...
...but J.R., he doesn't have
a pot or a pan, so...
We're happy to share our food.
I just moved in, you know.
Thanks.
- Come inside.
If you gonna get out on big
water like lakes or a river...
...you're gonna need something
you can cast out pretty good.
If you haven't got one,
I'm gonna tell you...
...you need to get you a Zebco 33.
That's about the best
reels you can get.
Don't tangle up much, and you can cast
them about as far as you want.
There in them little farm ponds, you
don't need nothing but a cane pole...
...and a float and maybe some crickets
or worms, if you can dig them up.
That's all we ever had.
The Zebco 33 is probably your best bet.
I bought June one when she was 12.
- Remember that?
- That's right. I caught a lot of fish.
You sure did.
So, what do you think, Daddy?
About what?
About the house.
It's a fine big house, John.
- Thanks.
- It's not as big as Jack Benny's.
What, you been to Jack Benny's, Ray?
Saw it on the TV.
Carrie, I was meaning to ask you,
did you teach the boys to play?
Well, J.R. Always sang pretty, but I
don't think I could take credit for it.
I'll bet you did. I bet you
learned the same way I did.
Oh, out of the hymnals, sure.
I knew you'd say that.
You know, you'd be surprised how many
musicians can't read shape notes.
I can't imagine.
I know.
But my husband's uncle, E.M. Bayes,
he taught me with hymnals too.
Well, how about you, John?
You know how to read shape notes?
John.
Mama asked you a question, John.
I'm really glad y'all
could be here today.
Especially you, Daddy.
Glad he came...
...to dinner,
and Thanksgiving, and all.
Not everybody's here.
Jack's not here, is he?
Huh?
"Where you been?"
That's what you said to me.
Remember?
And I was 12 years old...
...youse got Jack's bloody clothes...
...and you says to me,
"Where you been?"
Well...
...where were you?
Where were you?
I quit drinking a long time ago, J.R.
What about you?
You still taking them pills?
- That'll kill you, you know.
- Yeah, well, so will a car wreck.
You're sitting on a high horse, boy.
I never had talent. I did the
best I could with what I had.
Can you say that?
Mister Big Shot?
Mister Pill-Popping Rock Star?
- Ray.
Who are you to judge?
You ain't got nothing.
Big empty house. Nothing.
Children you don't see. Nothing.
Big old expensive tractor
stuck in the mud.
Nothing.
Come on.
Let's do it. Come on.
You is a son of a bitch, ain't you?
Come on.
Do it, do it.
I'm gonna sit in the middle this time.
Come on, you son of a bitch.
- John?
A fine piece of equipment, huh?
- John.
Come on.
You should go down to him.
Mama.
- He's mixed up.
- I am not going down there.
- If I go down there...
- You already are down there, honey.
Let's do it. Let's do it.
John.
John. John.
- John.
- Aah!
John. John.
- June?
Come on.
You should have left me.
John?
Go on ahead, J.R.
You know what that is?
Just please get away from me.
Daddy?
John?
Hey, John?
Oh, shit. Jesus. Hey...
What...? Hey, John?
Get your ass out of here, boy.
- Hey, John.
Get out.
Take your poison with you.
Okay. I'm leaving. I'm leaving.
Hey.
Mom and I picked
these up down the road.
They're good.
It's good to see you again.
Can I get you something else?
Just stay.
Okay.
You're an angel.
No, I'm not.
You've been here with me.
I had a friend who needed help.
You're my friend.
But I done so many bad things.
You done a few. That's true.
My daddy's right.
Should have been me on that saw.
Jack was so good.
He would have done
so many good things.
What have I done?
Just hurt everybody I know.
I know I've hurt you.
I'm nothing.
You're not nothing.
You are not nothing.
You're a good man.
And God has given you a second
chance to make things right, John.
This is your chance, honey.
This is your chance.
Hi, how are y'all?
Could you...?
It's okay. Come on.
- The evidence of things not seen.
By faith, Abel offered God a better gift...
...than his brother, Cain.
Better by faith.
Cain left God. Cain fell from faith.
He went out from the Lord
and he dwelt in the land of Nod...
...on the east of Eden.
Amen.
Let's all rise.
What about the Tropicana?
What's wrong with the Opry?
He was banned after he
smashed up the footlights.
Well, if he smashes lights at Folsom,
they're gonna keep him there.
Look, Frank, while Johnny was
out recuperating, the world changed.
Dylan's gone electric.
The Byrds are electric, the Beatles are
electric. Hell, everybody's electric.
He needs a fresh sound,
and all he wants to do...
...is cut a live album with
the same old pickers...
...at a maximum security penitentiary.
You can talk to me, you know.
I'm standing right here.
And what's with the black?
It's depressing.
Looks like you're going to a funeral.
Maybe I am.
Your fans are church folk, Johnny.
Christians.
They don't wanna
hear you singing...
...to a bunch of murderers and rapists,
trying to cheer them up.
Well, they're not Christians then.
I'm fine with you doing a live record.
Just not at a prison.
That's my compromise.
January 13th...
...l'll be at Folsom Prison
with June and the boys.
You listen to the tapes.
If you don't like them, toss them.
Mr. Cash?
M... Mr. Cash?
Might I suggest you refrain from
playing any more tunes...
...that remind them, the inmates, that is,
that, well... That they're in prison.
You think they forgot?
Perhaps you and your wife
could do another spiritual.
That's not my wife, warden.
I keep asking her,
and she keeps saying no.
You ever drink this water, warden?
No. No, I'm a Coca-Cola man.
All right.
I wanna remind you we're
recording live here today...
...so you can't say hell or shit
or anything like that.
I gotta tell you, I can't tell you
how many shows we've done...
...but this is the best
audience we ever had.
I wanna thank you for that.
You know, standing back there in
your shop, catching my breath...
...I come to admire you even more.
You see, I never had to
do hard time like you.
Although I have, on occasion...
...got myself busted.
Once in El Paso I had this bag of...
Oh, you heard about that?
You been in El Paso too?
Well, anyways I felt tough,
you know?
Like I'd seen a thing or two,
Well, that was till a moment ago.
Because I gotta tell you,
my hat's off to you now.
Because I ain't never had to drink this
yellow water you got here at Folsom.
This song is for your warden.
Early one mornin'
While makin' the rounds
I took a shot of cocaine
And I shot my woman down
I went right home and I went to bed
I stuck that lovin' forty-four
Beneath my head
Got up next mornin'
And I grabbed that gun
Took a shot of cocaine and away I run
Made a good run but I run too slow
They overtook me
Down in Juárez, Mexico
Late in the hot joint takin' the pills
In walked the sheriff from Jericho Hill
He said, "Willy Lee, your name is not
Jack Brown"
"You're the dirty hack that
Shot your woman down"
I was dressed in black.
When I was arrested
I was dressed in black
They put me on a train
And they took me back
Had no friend for to go my bail
They slapped my dried-up carcass
In the county jail
The judge, he smiled
As he picked up his pen
Ninety-nine years in the Folsom pen
Ninety-nine years underneath that ground
I can't forget the day
I shot that bad bitch down
Come on, you gotta listen unto me
Lay off that whiskey
And let that cocaine be
All right!
In the back.
Hey, June.
June.
What's wrong, John?
I don't know. Bad dreams. Memories.
Well, you need to get
some rest, sweetie.
You did good tonight.
- But we got another show tomorrow.
- Yeah.
Hey, listen.
The thing is, I think it's time now.
You know? I think it's about time.
- Time for what?
- For you and me...
...to get married.
Go to sleep, John.
I don't wanna sleep.
I wanna marry you,
and I'm telling you it's the time.
Well, I am telling you with 100
percent certainty that it is not the time.
It's not about time.
It's not the right time.
It's not even a quarter to the right time.
June.
How do you know when...?
You haven't been clean
even six months.
Except for a honeymoon, you have not
thought about what you're asking me.
Yes, I have.
I have. It's all I've thought about.
Well, how's it gonna work, John?
Where we gonna live?
What about my girls?
What about your girls?
What about your parents, John?
Your daddy won't even look at me.
June, that stuff will
just work itself out.
No, it doesn't work itself out.
People work it out for you,
and you think it works itself out.
- You're scared.
- What?
Scared of being in love.
Scared of losing control.
And you know what, June Carter?
I think you're scared of living
in my big fat shadow.
- That's your problem.
- Oh, really?
- Is that my problem?
- Yeah, it is.
My problem is it's 2 a.m.
My problem is I'm asleep.
I'm on a tour bus with
eight stinking men.
Rule number one:
Don't propose to a girl on a bus.
You got that? Rule number two:
Don't tell her it's because
you had a bad dream.
- June?
- What?
Marry me.
Okay.
Well, that's... That's the last time
I'm asking.
Well, good. I hate reruns.
I got your extra bag.
You don't have to bother...
Hey, June?
June.
June?
What, you're not talking to me?
You are not allowed to speak to me.
After that stunt...
...you're only allowed to
speak to me on-stage.
- Do you understand?
- What'd I do?
Why don't you ask
your big fat shadow?
- Come on, baby.
- "Come on, baby."
Baby, baby, baby, baby, baby.
The taste of love is sweet
When hearts like ours meet
I fell for you like a child
Oh, but the fire went wild
I fell into a burning ring offire
I went down, down, down
And the flames went higher
And it burns, burns, burns
The ring of fire
All right. Thank you.
I don't know if y'all know
who wrote that song...
...but it's this long-legged gal standing
right here, Miss June Carter.
Thanks, y'all. Thank you very much.
So, June, you gonna
stand over there all night...
...or you wanna come over
here and sing with me?
I'll sing with you.
You sure that's what you want?
- Yeah.
- All right. Hold on.
- Well, folks, what do you say?
All right, Johnny.
You wanna hear "Jackson"?
I thought you was gonna wax
poetic a little bit longer.
- Oh, no, I'm done with that, June.
- Okay, good.
- We got married in a fever
- Hotter than a pepper sprout
- We've been talking about Jackson
Ever since the fire went out
I'm going to Jackson
I'm gonna mess around
Yeah, I'm going to Jackson
Look out, Jackson town
Well, go on down to Jackson
Go ahead and wreck your health
Go play your hand, you big-talkin' man
Make a big fool of yourself
You're going to Jackson
Go comb your hair
See if I care
Sorry for the interruption, folks...
...but I gotta ask June here a question
before we finish this song.
What's that, John?
Will you marry me?
Why don't we just sing
the song, John.
No, darling.
Come on, finish the song.
People wanna hear us sing.
Sorry, folks...
...but I just can't do this song anymore
unless she's gonna marry me.
It'd just be like we're lying.
You got these people
all revved up, John.
- Now, come on, let's sing "Jackson."
- You got me all revved up.
I've asked you 40 different ways, it's
time you come up with a fresh answer.
Please sing.
I'm asking you to marry me.
I love you, June.
Now, I know I've said and
done a lot of things...
...that I hurt you. But I promise
I'll never do that again.
I only wanna take care of you.
I will not leave you like that Dutch
boy with your finger in the dam.
You're my best friend.
Marry me.
All right.
Yeah?
In case none of y'all heard,
she said yes.
She finally said yes.
Grandpa, here. Let's talk on this.
- What do you want me to do with it?
- Well, you listen and you talk.
It's a tin-can telephone,
and the sound goes up the string.
Hello, grand girls.
Can you hear us?
- Hello, Roseanne.
- Hello, Carlene.
- You gotta pull it tight, Daddy.
Grandpa, speak.
Talk, Grandpa.
- Tell us a story.
Speak. Grandpa.
- Take it and talk to them.
- They wanna talk to their grandpa.
Well, I don't got no stories.
You got all the stories. You...
Why don't you tell
them about the flood?
About how you made a boat out of the
front door and got us all out of there.
They'll like that.
Tell us.
- Go on, tell them. Pull the string tight.
It was 1937. There was a flood.