- This is Pete.
- Yeah?
We lost him.
He's your brother, Ross. If you can't
find him, we have people who will.
And you're paying for the contract.
Excuse me.
Have you got a message for Mr. Ross?
What room, sir?
I'm not a guest.
- I'll check.
- Thanks.
- That's, Johnny Ross.
- Yes, sir.
Sorry, sir, nothing.
Nothing?
Are you sure?
I'm sure, sir.
Okay, thanks.
Thank you.
Yes, I'm sure it was him.
Sunshine Cab, 6912.
Would you pull up? I want to make a call.
Right.
Yeah?
Delgetti.
What is it?
Work.
Frank, let me in, will you?
What time did you get to bed
this morning, Frank?
About 5:00.
'"Mumps vaccine on the market.
'"The government authorized yesterday...
'"... what officials term the first clearly
effective vaccine to prevent mumps.
'"... announced it has granted
a license for the vaccine...
'"... at 12:45 Wednesday-'"
Why don't you just relax and have
your orange juice, and shut up, Delgetti?
Let's go, Frank.
Lt. Bullitt to see you, Mr. Chalmers.
It was purely unintentional, I assure you.
It wasn't that I was so well-informed,
it was just that he was so ill-informed.
Would you excuse me
for a moment, please?
What do you like about...?
In Orinda, we have all this beautiful
dry sunshine. Absolutely perfect for roses.
I do all my own work.
See my hands? They prove it.
Hello. Lieutenant, how are you?
Thanks for coming over.
Name is Frank, isn't it?
- That's right.
- Please call me Walter.
I have an important job for you.
Captain Bennet suggested that you take it.
As you know, there is a Senate
Subcommittee hearing here Monday.
I have a star witness
who needs protection.
Sam said that you were
the man for the job.
And I can't find a flaw in that statement.
Protection from who?
The Organization.
His name is Ross.
Johnny Ross. From Chicago.
Once and for all, the top men
in law enforcement are united.
We're going to expose the Organization.
I read your speech.
Why San Francisco?
Ross is safer here. That's your province.
Keeping him out of reach for 40 hours.
Where?
The Hotel Daniels.
226 Embarcadero Road. Room 634.
He's there now, expecting you.
Now that you know where my house is...
...I hope that we'll get to see
a lot more of each other.
Particularly in view of the investigation.
A senatorial hearing has a way of...
...catapulting everyone involved
into the public eye...
...with a subsequent effect on one's career.
It will be a pleasure to have you along.
Have him in court on Monday, Frank.
What was that all about?
Pals.
You and Chalmers, huh?
There's a lot of juice?
Hotel Daniels, 226 Embarcadero Road.
State's evidence witness,
and we're babysitting.
Let's go.
- Yeah, who is it?
- Police.
The roof and the exits.
Mr. Chalmers said you'd be here by 5:00.
He guaranteed me that.
Oh, sorry, we got held up in traffic.
Got any firearms?
No, man, I've got nothing on me.
Just my wallet...
...cigarette lighter.
Want to check me out yourself?
No, that's not necessary.
Put that stuff on the bed, will you, please?
How did you...
how did you get here from Chicago?
I flew.
Sure none of the boys were on the plane
with you, or saw you get on?
How would I know? I wouldn't know.
Why did you pick this room to hole up?
I didn't pick it. Chalmers picked it.
Why?
Stay away from those windows!
That's why.
Sit down and relax, Ross.
It's a long wait until Monday morning.
We'd better get a fix on some food.
- What?
- Some food.
I know Chalmers wants you to be happy,
and we'll do the best we can.
Dad, it's for you.
Listen, you're not going. You're not going.
We're going to a movie.
Hold it down. Hold it down.
Now, don't be too late.
- Hello.
- Hello. Captain?
Frank?
We'll see you later, Dad.
I've seen Chalmers.
What do you know about Ross?
Chicago. It could be very big.
He had access to all the records. He ran
the wire services with his brother, Pete.
Did Chalmers ask for me?
Uh-huh.
Do you happen to know why?
Yes, I know why.
He's grooming himself for public office.
You make good copy.
They love you in the papers, Frank.
I see.
Okay. So long, Sam.
Say, who were you talking to about me
on that telephone?
Mr. Chalmers said
this was just between me and him.
Me and him, and that's all.
Delgetti will take the first shift.
Stanton will be on at 12:00.
I'll take the third.
All you have to worry about is
to stay away from the windows.
Especially at night.
You call me before you leave.
Excuse me.
Fire escape and the freeway.
Bad news, right?
Right. Want me to stay?
No. Go on home to your wife.
What shift?
Second.
If we work on the weekend,
we get two days off?
So long.
- Hi.
Is this the new fountain?
Fountain? All the client can afford
is a leaky faucet!
I thought that,
money didn't matter to artists.
It costs money to have a soul.
'"Friction loss of water in feet
per hundred feet. Length of pipe...
'"Formula using constant one-hundred size
of standard pipe in inches. '"
I want to use
600 gallons of water per minute.
Now what's the velocity per second
of a five-inch pipe?
Look to the extreme right.
Now go down the figures
until you find 600.
Got it.
Now go across until you find
the five-inch pipe column.
What does it say?
Nine point eight.
Now I want the loss in feet.
Feet, huh?
Well?
I lost my place. Nobody's perfect.
May I use your phone, please?
Good evening. Right this way.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Yeah?
- Del?
Coffee Cantata. 931-0770.
-931-0770.
- Right.
If a Sergeant Delgetti calls me...
...would you be kind enough
to let me know right away?
- I certainly will.
- Thank you.
Del. I'm coming off now.
Everything okay?
Yeah, sure.
Hey, hold it down, will you?
I'm sorry.
Anything for Stanton?
No, I'll see you tomorrow.
Who was it?
Del.
Something exciting?
Go to sleep.
Meaning you won't tell me anything.
It's not for you, baby.
Anything you do is part of me.
Front desk. Two gentlemen.
Shall I send them up?
What are their names?
Hold on a minute.
Mr. Chalmers and a friend.
Listen, tell them to wait.
And give me 421-7596.
- Frank?
- Yeah.
Chalmers is downstairs and another man.
They want to come up.
Chalmers, at one o'clock in the morning?
No, don't let them in.
I'll be there in five minutes.
Please, away from the door.
Here are the latest baseball scores,just in.
In the National League,
San Francisco Giants...
...beat the Dodgers in both ends
of a double-header.
A 2-0 shutout in the twilighter
and 4-1 win in the nightcap.
No, wait...
Now look.
They told me...
Who is it?
Ross. Two guys got him with a shotgun.
And Stanton?
They got him in the leg.
They're bringing him down.
Stick with Ross.
Soon as the lab men get out of 634, seal it.
- But seal it, Barney.
- Yes, sir.
How bad?
Bad. He's got a bleeder.
Door is not open.
Somebody screwed up.
They screwed up. The door's not open.
Somebody put the bed in.
I know you're hurting.
But I've got to know, now.
The two men.
Do you remember anything?
Caucasian.
The one who fired, about 5 foot 10.
White hair.
Gun, Winchester pump.
All I remember. Came in so fast.
Chain was off. He unlocked the door.
Who unlocked it?
Ross. Like he was expecting someone.
How is my leg?
Hold on, Carl,
we'll be there in a couple of minutes.
Get out of the way.
To the right.
Let's go.
Scissors, Jones.
Somebody get the blood pressure.
Oxygen.
Can I have an ABD pad?
Can you move your hand?
Say, do you want to step out? Your buddy
is all right. His leg should be okay.
Somebody get X-ray.
How's Stanton?
He'll be all right,
but he's busted up. Ross?
I don't know, Frank.
You better call Stanton's wife
and get her over here.
Okay.
Here you go.
What is it?
What's his blood pressure now?
Scissors.
It's down to 90 over 70.
Suture.
Scissors.
- Better let me tie this one.
- Okay.
Get some balm, please.
He's dropping.
Pulse is also going up, now.
What was it pre-op?
BP pre-op was 140 over 90.
Kahn, take this.
Now it's down to 90 over 70.
How much blood do you have?
We have four up here,
and we've ordered four more units.
How much have you given him?
- We're starting the first one right now.
- You'd better bring me another one.
Mayo, please.
- This is the subclavian.
- Here's your wipe, Doctor.
Thank you, Deanne.
What are his chances?
No more than 50-50.
We stopped the hemorrhaging, but they
got some of the major blood vessels.
Thank you, Doctor.
How is he doing?
Holding.
Stanton?
Okay. He's sleeping now.
I want to talk to you.
I got the report back from the lab.
Nothing at the hotel.
How come they got in?
Ross got to the door,
unhooked the chain from the inside.
He let the killers in himself?
Why would he do a thing like that?
I'm waiting to ask him.
What about the setup?
What do you think about that?
Shotgun and a backup man. Professionals.
Yep.
I had to call Chalmers.
And?
It didn't go down too good.
It's the main event for him.
You know,
the Senate Subcommittee hearing.
He can't produce the big surprise
he promised everyone.
He may try to make up some mileage
by laying it on us.
Play it by the book from now on.
Does Chalmers run the case, or do I?
All I'm interested in is results.
Do whatever you think is best.
I'll try to back you up.
Excuse me, sir.
Are you the policeman who hasn't eaten?
Yes, ma'am.
- Thank you.
- Surely.
Where is he?
How is he, Doctor?
As well as can be expected.
He's still under the anesthesia.
I'm Walter Chalmers.
Is there any possibility of my getting
a deposition from Ross before Monday?
That's impossible to say at this time.
He may remain in shock.
I thank you for doing all you can, Doctor.
Get the supervisor.
Now, what went wrong, Lieutenant?
- Who else knew where he was?
- What?
Who else knew where he was?
What are you implying?
They knew where to look for him
and they used your name to get in.
Are you suggesting
I disclosed his whereabouts?
Somebody did.
And it didn't come from us.
That's hardly the issue.
Well, it certainly is.
I've got an officer with a family.
And he's shot up pretty bad.
And I've got a witness who can't talk.
I want to know about Ross.
What was the deal you made with him?
Deal?
Lieutenant, don't try
to evade the responsibility.
In your parlance, you blew it.
You knew the significance
of his testimony.
Yet you failed to take
adequate measures to protect him.
So to you it was a job. No more.
Were it more, and you had the dedication
I was led to believe...
You believe what you want.
You work your side of the street
and I'll work mine.
Lieutenant, I shall personally
officiate at your public crucifixion...
...if Ross doesn't recover
during the course of the hearing...
...so I can at least present his deposition.
And, I assure you, I shall not suffer
the consequence of your incompetence.
And even if there wasn't any...
...I'm rather certain
I can prove negligence on your part.
There may be another attempt on his life.
I'll be back in the morning,
with my people.
Thank you, Doctor.
I'd like to have Dr. Willard replaced.
I think he's too young and inexperienced.
I'd prefer my surgeon.
Inform the administrator.
But Dr. Willard is one of our-
I'd like him replaced, if you don't mind.
- I'll report this to our administrator.
- Thank you very much.
Doctor?
A relative of mine,
he's here with a gunshot wound.
Could you please tell me
where I can find him?
Why don't you try at the reception desk?
There's no one there.
He could be up on the second floor
in the emergency room.
Thanks, Doctor.
Yes?
Oh, Lieutenant. It's for you.
Thank you.
Yes?
Dr. Kenner. This probably isn't important...
...but a man asked me
whether a relative of his...
...with a gunshot wound
was in the hospital.
I thought you should know about it.
Was he about 5 foot 10? Gray hair?
I'm afraid I told him
that he was on the second floor.
Thank you.
Delgetti.
Our man is in the building.
He was tipped where to find Ross.
- You take the ground floor, okay?
- Got it.
Get in Ross's room. Nobody in
except Dr. Willard and the nurses.
There's a man down the stairs!
Polly, call Anesthesia
and bring the crash cart!
Doctor, there's a cardiac arrest in ICU.
Get Delgetti.
You and the patrolman cover the lobby.
Okay.
I can't get a blood pressure.
Go.
Do you want to defibrillate again?
Not now. Not with that complex.
- How much bicarb?
- Fifteen.
Go ahead. Push it in.
- Do you want some lactose?
- Draw some up.
- Any pupillary reaction?
- No. Dilated.
Get some calcium up, too.
What's that now? What's he got?
No activity.
I need some more epinephrin.
Half a milligram, please.
I need your help.
What is it?
I want this kept open.
If Chalmers finds out that Ross died,
he'll fold this up.
- I want the man who killed him!
- I understand.
I don't want your head on a block.
I understand.
His chart could be misplaced.
You filed it. It's missing.
I'll take the responsibility.
All right.
Call the coroner's office.
Tell them to put Ross under a John Doe.
I want a private ambulance,
unmarked, and I want it quiet.
Far as you go, Doctor.
Take it slow.
City morgue.
Let's go.
Fresh today!
See if Dr. Willard is still in the hospital.
Get Lt. Bullitt on the phone.
I'm sorry, Joe.
He's been transferred to another room.
May I have an outside line, please?
May I speak to your supervisor, please?
I'm afraid she's busy at the moment.
I'd be grateful if you would tell her
that Chalmers wishes to see her.
Immediately. It's very urgent.
Yes, Mr. Chalmers.
I'd like to speak with Dr. Willard, please.
Thank you.
Yes? Can I help you?
I wanted the other supervisor.
The night supervisor went off duty
an hour ago.
I'm Mrs. Francis. May I help you?
You may, indeed. There was a patient
here. His name is Johnny Ross.
- And he seems to have disappeared.
- Disappeared?
He was in Intensive Care, but there's no
record of his whereabouts in the hospital.
That's impossible.
May I see his medical chart, please?
I'm sorry but hospital regulations-
It's an official police request.
Is it not, Captain Baker?
Yes, Captain. I'll take care of it.
Excuse me, but Dr. Willard
has gone off duty.
Call him at home.
Are you sure he's not there?
Do you have Dr. Willard's home number?
I'm sorry, but there has been...
...some medical complication
as regard to my witness.
I'm afraid I'll have to forego
that bedside picture...
...as much as it would've compensated
for his inability to testify tomorrow.
But, in all decency,
I can hardly force the issue.
Does this mean your surprise witness
won't be able to make any statement?
The man was near death
when he was brought in here.
In view of the attempt on his life...
...I'm sure you can understand
my reasons for secrecy.
- Yeah, of course.
- Good to see you again.
Can't reach Lt. Bullitt, either.
Keep trying.
I can't find Mr. Ross's medical chart.
It's evidently been misplaced.
- Or appropriated.
- Appropriated?
All right. I'll inform the administrator.
Thank you very much.
I want a complete list of the staff
who might've been involved...
...in helping Bullitt spirit Johnny Ross
out of here.
I'm certain he grabbed my witness
for his personal aggrandizement.
- I'll lay odds on that.
- And find Ross!
I'll get on that right away.
Mr. Chalmers, I have Lt. Bullitt.
Where's my witness?
I've got him.
Where is he?
Are you going to tell me or not?
Well, I can't at the present time.
Captain Baker would like
to have a word with you.
Now, listen to me, Lieutenant.
Nail him. I want him written off.
No problem.
You want some breakfast?
Just coffee.
Thank you.
For what?
- Is it open?
- The door's open, sir.
Now think back to the time the two
of them first came in and you saw them.
Anything you can remember?
Like I said. They hit me
before I got a chance to look at them.
I don't remember nothin' about them.
Nothin'.
Start remembering.
I can't!
And that's the honest truth.
Delgetti, take him downtown.
Lieutenant, give him a chance, will you?
He's trying.
He's not trying hard enough.
It will come to him.
You're wasting your time.
Okay. Come on.
One thing about the guy who hit me...
He had a square face.
There wasn't much light here.
They try to save on electricity.
Like this?
No. Thinner.
That's it.
Now it's coming back.
Let's go to the guy in 634. No luggage?
That's right, sir.
- And he didn't store anything?
- No, sir.
He came in empty, which means
you gave him a good look-over.
Always do.
They're the ones I give the eye to.
Then you saw how he arrived?
Yes, sir. In a cab.
What line?
Sunshine Cab.
Now, the guy who hit you.
How old was he?
Oh, about 50.
What was his hair like?
Gray. Getting bald. Bald on both sides.
That?
No, balder.
Am I helping you, sir?
I never had it so good.
His first stop was the Mark.
How long?
Not long.
Pull over there and wait.
- Hello.
- Eddy?
Dues time. I need some information
on a Johnny Ross. Chicago.
Give me half an hour.
Meet you at Enrico's.
Right.
- Two.
- Two what?
Calls. He called twice.
The second was long distance.
How do you know it was long distance?
He put in a lot of change.
Good morning, Sam.
I don't believe I've had the pleasure.
This is Mr. Chalmers.
My wife, Mrs. Bennet.
My son, Paul. My son, Tony.
Tony, how are you?
Would you mind if I had
just a moment alone with Sam?
No, of course not.
Must be difficult raising children
in the worid of today.
I presume Tony is a college student.
Yes, that's right.
I can well imagine the financial strain...
...of sending a boy to university
on the salary of a captain.
There's no reason why a man
with your potential...
...shouldn't move right up,
given the right support.
My family is waiting for me, Mr. Chalmers.
Bullitt abducted my witness.
He removed him from the hospital.
As his superior officer,
I've given him complete charge of the case.
If he's moving Ross around,
it's for a reason.
So you mean that you would not order
him to reveal where he's keeping Ross?
It's his case, Mr. Chalmers.
Captain, I'm serving you with
a writ of habeas corpus...
...making you responsible
for the delivery of Ross.
Duly observed...
...you have received it.
Now I need that witness
to prove his very existence.
Excuse me, sir. Dad, Mom is waiting.
Would you excuse us
for just another moment, Tony?
I don't choose to have people accuse me
of false promises...
...for the sake of cheap sensationalism...
...or to be compromised
by your lieutenant. Or castrated.
Wait for me. I won't be long.
According to my sources,
the Organization, Chicago branch...
...caught Johnny Ross
with his hands in the till.
They estimate he siphoned off...
...about two million bucks
while operating their wire service.
The story is they tried to get rid of him.
Friday night. Chicago.
Chicago?
He got away unharmed.
They believe he's hiding here in town.
How old is this information, Eddy?
Four hours. They're looking for him
all over town, Frank.
They've staked out the docks, the airport,
to keep him from leaving the country.
Anyone else trying for a hit?
Haven't heard of any such likelihood.
What about his brother, Pete?
In the clear.
Okay, Eddy. Thanks.
Anything I can do for you?
There is something.
Remember Zash-Zhoe?
They gave him three to five.
What is he in for?
Receiving stolen property.
I'll try.
Thanks, Frank.
- Here you go.
- Take care, Lieutenant.
What the hell is going on here?
A high-speed pursuit!
Two men are killed. An officer in the
hospital. A witness almost murdered.
I want to know what's happening.
Let's hear it straight.
Here's the report.
Now, a man like Chalmers could be
a great help to the Department.
He could speak for us where it counts.
He could fight for us in the legislature.
Now, you have got to
turn over his witness.
Where's Ross?
Tell him! That's an order!
He's dead.
Dead?
He died last night.
After you moved him?
Before. I've got him downstairs
under a John Doe.
You are sick.
Smuggling a dead man out of a hospital.
And now two men killed
who may have had nothing to do with it.
The man I was chasing killed Ross.
How do you know? Did you see him?
Yes. He tried to nail me with a shotgun.
A Winchester pump.
The radio report said the two men
were burned beyond recognition.
Now all he's got are two dead men.
It would never hold up in court.
I've got one lead. I want to move on it.
'"Miss Dorothy Simmons.
Thunderbolt Hotel. San Mateo. '"
Ross called her person-to-person
from a phone in Unión Square...
...approximately nine hours
before he was killed.
So he called his girlfriend.
What does that prove?
This is Sunday. I'm going to hold that writ
until we come to work Monday morning.
Frank?
Go on. Get out.
Need a car.
Sorry, Lieutenant, there are no cars left.
Ms. Simmons doesn't answer.
What's her room number?
I'm sorry, we're not allowed to give...
Front. Take this gentleman
to Room 114, please.
Hello, Del?
Yeah. Yeah.
It's a strangulation.
I thought I knew you.
But I'm not so sure anymore.
Do you let anything reach you?
I mean, really reach you?
Or are you so used to it by now
that nothing really touches you?
You're living in a sewer, Frank.
Day after day.
That's where half of it is.
And we can't walk away from it.
I know it's there, but I don't have to
be reminded of the whole thing.
The ugliness around us!
With you, living with violence is a way of
life, violence and death.
How can you be part of it without
becoming more and more callous?
Your worid is so far from the one I know.
What will happen to us in time?
Time starts now.
- What do you got?
- Let's start with the cleaver.
One cleaver, approximately
eight inches in length.
Ms. Simmons' luggage
has just arrived from the airport.
Okay.
Where is it?
- Here you go.
- One pair of gold shoes...
Where is it from?
San Mateo Thunderbolt Hotel.
- And who from?
- Simmons.
And what do we have?
One yellow metal locket.
Yellow metal watch.
Pearl necklace. Put a hold on these.
We got a man here.
Dearborn Travel Agency in Chicago. Rome.
Look at all this literature!
What do you make out of that?
I thought she was alone.
She's got a guy, now.
New purse, still has a price tag in it.
Give me a bag, Tony.
Everything is new.
They weren't even away.
Passport? No passport. No tickets.
Yeah, I can't find any tickets, either.
Bingo!
What've you got?
Great.
'"Albert E. Renick. '"
Then who the hell is Simmons?
Look how much money he's got.
Look at this.
This guy is loaded!
Well, we've got a Renick.
Wonder who Renick is?
Look what I came up with!
'"Dorothy Renick. '"
Okay. Drop it in.
We're getting warm. '"A.R.'"
How does that grab you?
Give me a bag, Tony.
Fingerprints on this stuff.
Let's wrap it up.
- Thanks, Tony.
- Okay.
No tickets, no passport.
Call Immigration in Chicago. Have them
wire Renick's passport applications.
- I'll get a fingerprint check on Ross, huh?
- Okay.
There are multiple gunshot wounds
on the left side of the face...
...the left side of the neck
at about the left upper thorax.
These extend from the lateral extent
of the left eye...
...and a portion of the left orbit
has been lacerated...
...and aqueous humor
protrudes from the laceration.
There have been deep lacerations
in the immediate area.
And these have been approximated
by fine surgical sutures.
There are multiple surgical incisions
about the left side of the face.
There is considerable hemorrhage
in these deep tissues...
...and a number of surgical sutures
are present about this area.
There are entrances into the sinuses...
...and several pellets are found
located within this area.
There are also multiple lacerations
and multiple gunshot entrance wounds...
...about the left side of the neck.
And similar wounds are found
on the left upper thorax.
Would you send up
those prints right away?
There's a soft rubber catheter extending
out through the lateral extent of the...
I understand that Captain Bennet told you,
you had until Monday morning...
...to comply with
my writ of habeas corpus.
However, I want a signed admissión now...
...that Ross died
while he was in your custody.
When I'm ready. Yes?
Your photographs are coming through.
I'll be right up. Thank you.
I demand that signed statement. Now.
Excuse me.
Is that the girl?
Yeah.
Ross.
'"Albert Edward Renick. '"
'"Used car salesman. Chicago. '"
Who is Renick?
He was the man who was shot
in the Hotel Daniels.
You sent us to guard
the wrong man, Mr. Chalmers.
Mrs. Dorothy Renick and Mr. Al Renick...
...have reservations
on the seven o'clock flight to Rome.
Separate tickets. Not confirmed.
And I got this report from Chicago.
Renick has no record of arrests.
He's clean, Frank.
Ross took close to $2,000,000
from the Organization.
And he set Renick up
to get the heat off of him.
Then he killed Renick's wife to shut her up.
San Francisco Homicide.
Do you have a Mr. Renick
on the seven o'clock flight for Rome?
He confirmed his flight a half hour ago.
Did he check in yet?
Not here, but he could do that at the gate.
Shall I call Security?
Call the gate.
Have them recheck all passports.
- Which gate?
- Seventy-three.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
Clipper Flight 110 is now ready
for boarding.
We hope you have a pleasant flight
and thank you for choosing Pan American.
No smoking, please, beyond this point.
Would you please have
your passports available for inspection...
...as you pass through the departure gate?
Pardon me.
And you're with the tour, too, are you?
There are other giris ahead of you.
Step right on through.
Passenger Service.
Can I help you, sir?
Do you have a Renick, an Al E. Renick,
Flight 124 to London?
What?
Thank you. At the last minute,
on a Rome ticket. Flight Control.
Ladies and gentlemen, we have just
been instructed to return to the gate.
For your safety, please remain seated...
...until the aircraft has come
to a complete stop.
We anticipate only a short delay.
However, all passengers are requested
to disembark...
...and remain in the departure lounge.
Thank you.
He's still my witness.
I'll be delighted to let you have him
after he testifies tomorrow.
The Organization.
Several murders.
Could do us both a great deal of good.
Look, Chalmers, let's understand
each other. I don't like you.
Come on now, don't be naive, Lieutenant.
We both know how careers are made.
Integrity is something
you sell to the public.
You sell whatever you want,
but don't sell it here tonight.
Frank, we must all compromise.
Bullshit!
Get the hell out of here. Now!
How long will we be delayed?
Just about 45 minutes.
Won't be long.
Get me the security guard!
Ticket, please.
All right. Get back. Get back.
Wonder who he was? What he did?
I heard the shot all the way down the hall.
He's a cop. That's what he is.
Let's get back. Let's get back.
Let's keep the area clear.
Now, ladies,
you don't want to see this now.
Subtitles by Dakewl