Dario!
A message from Peligro.
Ho!
Mambo, Mambo, Mambo, Mambo
Mambo
Ladies and gentlemen,
a very good evening to you all.
El Tropico,
the most fabulous nightclub in
the world, presents
its latest,
but not late show,
where we are taking you all
to the magical productions
of our Rodney the Great.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are honored tonight
to have in our presence
the world's greatest
living race car driver,
here in Cuba for the first
Havana Grand Prix.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the one and only Fangio
for once, stationary.
Fangio! Fangio!
Fangio!
And now, a special treat
for a very special couple.
Forever newlyweds,
Dona Cecilia, Don Federico,
The Anniversary waltz
by Strauss.
Happy Anniversary.
A toast.
To the most
elegant couple in Havana.
Happy Anniversary.
And to this,
the happiest of families.
May it be that way forever.
Hear, hear. Salud.
Salud.
Dance with me,
as you once did?
You make me
sound like a relic.
My relic.
Donoso, would you
dance with me?
Watch yourself.
Uncle has two left feet now.
His elbow,
it works fine.
I would give an arm
and a leg and an elbow
for just one single waltz.
My kingdom for a cha-cha-cha!
Hear, hear.
Let's go dance.
I'll be right back. Wait here.
What's wrong?
So which one
of those dancers
is your girlfriend
this week?
Who are you
saving yourself for?
No one.
All the good ones
are already spoken for.
Fangio, I want to present to you
my wife Mercedes Fellove.
Come on, let's go.
This meeting was my idea...
because these are very
difficult times, as you know.
Cuba has always
lived in difficult times,
but through them all,
we have been able to survive
because we have
always been united.
But our country
isn't safe anymore,
and it threatens us.
Your uncle and I are all
that remains of our generation.
So, my sons,
you are the future.
The future of our family.
The future of this island.
Yes, and
look at me.
Look at me, because
this is for you, too.
If we want to
change the status quo,
we must go about it
in a democratic way.
You hear?
We must be patriots.
Patriots.
Patriotism is a refuge for scoundrels.
Do you
It is politics
that has become
the practical refuge of
Papi, do not make the mistake
of confusing me for
one of your students.
I'm not. I graduated.
Hey.
Show a little respect.
No, no, no, no.
Let him talk.
This is a democracy.
Oh, this country,
a democracy? Right.
Our family is a democracy.
This country is my family,
and the only way
to truly unite that family
is revolution.
Revolution?
Revolution, yes.
I just can't believe it.
A son of mine
that would support
the random violence
of revolution?
You better start believing it.
What you need is
a little evolution,
not revolution.
Correct.
The poet.
Club owner, poet.
You're lucky you're on
the other side of the room.
I feel lucky,
because it probably
stinks on that side of the room.
Please.
Happy Anniversary.
You are too much.
Did I forget to say that?
Happy Anniversary?
Just watch your mouth.
What? You've been watching it
the whole time.
If I hear one more
word of disrespect
coming out of your mouth,
I'm gonna
deal with it personally.
Do you understand me?
What?
You understand
what I just said to you?
I understand
You listen to your father
when he's speaking to you,
and you show respect!
Calm down, Fico.
No, you calm down!
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
You want me
to come over there?
Okay.
Huh? You want me
to come over there?
Stop it!
Come on.
Stop it.
Four against one, huh?
Sit down.
Is this a democracy?
You got your little show.
Sit down.
Sit down, right? How is it?
Sit down!
Is this a random act
of violence, Papi?
Huh?
They shot Lieutenant Dario.
Did they get
good descriptions this time?
Did he mention Peligro again?
Mm-hmm.
What happened?
I'm not gonna
have this conversation
with you, you, you,
or any of you.
You know what?
You have no idea
what's going on in this country.
It's sad that you're a professor
and you have zero
zero idea of what is going on
in your own classroom.
Then can you enlighten me?
Can you tell me what's going on?
Discontent, anger...
desperation.
That's what's going
on in this country,
everywhere in this country,
and especially
at your university.
Revolution, okay? It happened in France,
it happened in Russia,
and it's happening here,
and it's happening now.
Nobody wants a revolution.
You don't want a revolution.
But like it or not,
it's coming.
The people, they want it.
How do you know?
Has the people of Cuba spoken to you
in your chosen ears?
No. Batista must be eliminated.
And then what?
Freedom. Democracy.
Right, yeah.
Power to the people.
That's easier said than done.
It can be done,
but the first thing
you have to do
is kill that son of a bitch.
Kill, kill, kill, kill, kill.
Have you ever thought
to live for your country?
Yes. Live. I am living!
I live, and I let die.
Let the tyrant die.
A fish is caught by its mouth.
You need the earth
on your hands, not blood.
Take sanctuary at the farm.
My son doesn't need sanctuary.
He just needs
to reform his character,
for a man's character
is his destiny.
What book did you get that from?
Maybe you should read a couple.
Where do you stand, Fico?
Where do you stand?
Right here with my family.
I see that.
You're just a spectator.
You just watch the parade go by.
Let me tell you something, Fico.
Your days of hiding in this cork-lined
palace are numbered.
Pretty soon,
you and you and you
and you are gonna
have to make a decision.
Are you in the parade,
or are you not?
I have made my decision.
That means good night!
Good night in Cuban!
Buenas noches!
Buenas nochesto you all!
Good evening.
That depends.
It usually does, doesn't it?
It was a great show tonight.
Great show.
Do you know a guy named Peligro?
Who?
Peligro.
Is he a percussionist?
Would you know a guy
named Alberto Mora?
Is he a friend of yours?
Someone here to see you.
I had nowhere else to go.
Have you seen him?
All the time.
Next time you see him,
say good-bye.
When I get to the pearly gates,
you know what
I'm gonna ask for, don't you?
A bottle of Bacardi?
No, a case.
Don't forget the Victrola.
You're not going anywhere
without your dance partner.
Okay, I'll stay.
Viejo.
What is he saying?
Uh-oh, the ticking clock.
Fico.
Well, I wanted to say
that in our house,
Sunday dinner is not...
A moveable feast.
Uh-huh. All my sons
are welcome, but not...
Not after6.
And it is 6 and 3 minutes, Fico.
I know, but I thought
he said after6.
Okay. Okay. Now, um...
I want to make a wish.
If change is going
to come to our country,
I wish that our home
remains an island,
and that despite
all of our differences,
we always put family first.
And food second.
Salud.
It's a joke, my brother.
I'm just kidding.
So it's all in the family.
It's all in the family.
I tell you,
I swear to God it is.
Hello, Senator. How are you?
I've been better.
I come to see your father.
No one knows more
about constitutional law.
Am I interrupting?
I mean, he's picking
for compliments, Senator.
Okay, I'm gonna give you one.
Do you think the light
interrupts the day?
Sometimes.
We intend to pass
a resolution
that will remove Batista
through the constitutional
process.
Senator Cossio has asked me
to prepare a speech for him.
This is the opening statement.
Uh, I've made reference to Seneca.
Read it aloud, Senator,
so we can hear how it sounds.
Okay.
Please.
Mr. Speaker,
I must protest...
as Seneca did in ancient Rome,
of the violence of office.
Today, we, the citizens of Cuba,
are being persecuted by a tyrant
and his reign of terror,
meted out to our population
by his police,
and especially by a certain
colonel in the force
whose name has become
synonymous with sudden death.
Seneca was persecuted
by two tyrants,
Caligula and Nero.
In spite of that,
Seneca advocated the return
to the Republic...
unafraid.
Mr. Speaker, Seneca,
not the Neros of this world,
should be an example to us.
Fangio, I am your biggest fan.
Get in the car.
Just get in the car.
Get in.
What do you want? Money?
Publicity.
Fangio freed,
Grand Prix cancelled,
26th of July Movement responsible.
And listen to what Fangio said.
All they wanted from me
is that I help them
further their cause.
But I don't know anything
about causes, only cars.
And when they ask him
how he was treated,
They were quintessential
gentlemen.
Do you think I'm a quintessential
gentleman, Mercedes?
Huh?
What was so funny?
What were you laughing about?
The funnies.
The funnies?
That newspaper has no funnies.
Why don't you try the one
about the kidnappers
who only wanted publicity?
Stop it!
That's funny. That's funny.
Leave him alone! Stop!
Yeah. Come on.
Stop! Let him go!
Please stop!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
Huh?
You want to be tough? Huh?
Wanna play in my city?
Spoiled rich bastard!
You do not want
to disappoint me.
Believe me.
I'm gonna go for a walk.
When I get back,
I want you to tell
me who Peligro is.
I'm back.
Who's Peligro? Huh?
You're not a good listener.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Ooh. No, I'm okay, I'm okay.
I'm gonna go for a walk, okay?
So you better be thinking about
who Peligro is,
'cause you're next.
Let's go for some coffee.
You're here about your brother.
Your little brother's a criminal
a dangerous criminal.
No doubt about that.
I've got his file
if you wanna read it.
No, thank you.
I know my brother,
and no file will ever change that.
Fico, we've known each other
since we were in prep school.
I've always
been straight with you.
That's true.
Have you ever known me
to change my signals?
Not when you were my catcher.
Fico, you're pitching
for your brother now.
You're pitching wild.
He's guilty.
There's no doubt about that.
I know it and you know it.
He's my brother, Braulio.
I need your help.
Okay.
I think you should
get out of Havana,
go to New York or Miami,
and I'm gonna take
care of the tickets.
Fico, Fidel's gonna
take care of me.
I'm leaving for
the Sierra Maestra.
Hey.
Fico, I have no choice.
What about your family?
Everything I do
is for my family.
I love you.
Uh, come in.
Can I help you?
Al sent me.
Who?
Al.
He's a friend of yours, isn't he?
Are you auditioning?
Yes, I am.
What's your line?
I'm a comedian.
I'm a stand-up comedian
who prefers to remain seated.
That's it?
That's your line?
Yeah.
Some jokes for your emcee.
He writes his own jokes.
They're lousy. So are yours.
Touch?
You want some help writing
some of your other material?
Nobody writes anybody's
material around here.
You just improvise?
You can call it that.
Try New York.
Too cold. Too rich.
Too close to home.
Well, I'm afraid
you're going to have to
find another line of work, then.
I can't.
The laughter
you just become addicted to it.
What'd you say your name was?
I didn't.
I said Al sent me.
If you know Al, you know me.
Oh, Al's friend.
Where've you been?
Where haven't I been?
Federico, remember your
appointment.
And don't forget your dancing
shoes.
You're going to need them.
Oh, Rodney?
Maestro?
Oh, never mind.
I think I have
a job for you after all.
Finally, after all these years
of sacrifice and dedication,
a break.
Why can't you tell
me who we're meeting?
It's better that way.
I love surprises.
Just don't say a word
no matter what.
Sit there,
pretend you're my security. That's it.
How's this?
Cozy enough?
Look a little bit more dangerous.
How about this?
More dangerous.
This is my meanest.
Save that.
Can I make a wish?
Be my guest.
I wish for a tall, athletic,
caramel-colored beauty.
Okay.
An open-door policy
is the sign of a great host.
Mr. Lansky, come in.
Welcome.
Should I call you Federico,
Mr. Fellove, or Fico?
Depends on whether
you shake my hand or not.
Call me Fico.
You can call my Meyer.
All my friends do.
Have a seat.
Who is this guy?
Don't mind him,
he's just a comedian.
A blind one?
Mute.
That's funny.
Would you like a drink?
A little seltzer,
unless you happen to, uh...
have an egg cream.
I have eggs and I have cream.
And you have a blind comedian.
Mute.
An egg cream
is neither egg nor cream.
Would you like
to know how to make one?
Well, that would've
been my next question.
Well, let? S see
how this goes first.
A little seltzer for now.
Cuts the humidity.
You hear that, comedian?
You said something on the
phone about a business opportunity.
Well played. Le Chaim.
I propose
a partnership between us.
20% goes to the house,
the rest to me, my associates.
It doesn't have
to be anything big.
I mean, this is very cozy here.
You could have a couple of tables,
craps, you know, blackjack,
a wheel or two.
This is nice.
Mr. Lansky
Call him Meyer.
Or Mr. Lansky.
You want him here?
Meyer, I appreciate the offer,
but, regretfully, I have to pass.
Now, I know this is
a tremendous opportunity for me.
However, El Tropico
is a place of music,
and that's how
I would like it to stay.
Let me rephrase.
We have the beginning
of a mutually
beneficial relationship.
It would be a pity to see it end
before it even began.
Yes, it would.
All right.
I was informed
you were a reasonable man.
I hope I wasn't misinformed.
You weren't.
What I can offer you in return
is what I offer all my friends
an open-door policy.
Consider my club
your home any time.
What, free seltzer?
As much as you want.
You know, in my business,
Mr. Fellove,
we have friends
and we have enemies,
but we don't
have acquaintances.
I hope to hear
some good news very soon.
Is that Meyer Lansky...
Meyer Lansky?
The head of the mob.
I resign.
Are you wearing false eyelashes,
or are you truly bashful?
I never wear false eyelashes.
That's my girl.
Am I?
Whose idea was that?
Rodney's.
Are you gonna be watching?
Always.
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
Luis has another woman.
Another woman?
He hasn't come home in two days,
and before that, we haven't
His mind is elsewhere.
Has he called?
Just to say that he's okay,
and that's all he says.
Fico, help me.
You're the only one
I can turn to.
I'm gonna take care of it.
She's worried about you.
She came to you?
She's always had a...
very special place
in her heart for you.
And you for her.
What's the matter? Talk to me.
I'm not gonna get you involved.
I'm your brother. I'm involved.
What's up?
Is it another woman?
Yes.
Liberty.
You involved with Fidel?
No.
26th of July Movement,
like Ricardo?
No.
Directorio Revolucionario.
We're no longer associated.
We have our own ideas for Cuba.
Pluralism,
the restoration of
the 1940 Constitution.
You know, democracy.
That's what Fidel says he wants.
Sure, that's what he says,
but he can't be trusted.
You think he's a Communist?
A Fidelista.
You have to promise me something.
What?
Anything happens to me...
you'll look after Aurora.
She'll need you.
Here, promise me.
Promise me, Fico.
I need this from you.
I promise you.
But you're gonna promise me
that nothing's gonna
happen to you, right?
Right?
There's no happiness
outside the revolution.
Okay.
Don't do something stupid.
Okay?
Ricardo Fellove,
26th of July Movement.
Fellove.
Are you the dancer?
Because we don't need any dancers.
Okay, get off the horse.
We're hungry.
It's not another woman.
Then why won't he come back?
He doesn't want us involved.
What is it?
The revolution?
He doesn't want us involved.
That's it?
That's it.
Am I supposed to
take that home and be happy?
I'm his wife.
I have the right to be involved.
If something happens to him,
it happens to me.
To all of us.
And then what?
I think it was the Mafia, Meyer Lansky,
but I can't be certain.
Havana is no longer a capital city,
but a capital sin.
This is
not new, of course,
but even Jesus had
to whip the moneylenders
out of the temple.
We're badly in need of a
of a Christ with a whip.
I don't know what to do.
Satyagraha.
Do you know what that is?
No.
It is the Hindu word
For passive resistance.
Gandhi resisted passively,
and he won.
My son, in the sea,
even a shark can drown.
Okay, we all know how to make it
into the Presidential Palace
by heart now?
So let's review one last time.
I will take over the CNQ radio station
and read our statement.
Carbo?
Machado and I will attack with
Peligro through the main gates,
along with Menoyo and his group.
Ignacio, you will
provide sniper protection
and reinforcements.
Any questions?
What do you think, Peligro?
It's time.
Mockingbird Pet Shop.
Can I help you?
The bird is in the cage.
He's in.
Long live a free Cuba.
Mr. President?
What is it, Pizzi?
There are urgent matters
for you to attend to.
I've been signing
edicts all week,
and you know what
I've been thinking, Pizzi?
I'm a fortunate man
for having had to sign
one single death warrant.
Mr. President,
if I might say so myself,
you are a fortunate man,
but also a noble man.
Thank you, Pizzi.
That's very kind of you.
No, no, no, no, no.
It is not kindness.
It is historical justice.
Have I ever told you
how much I appreciate you?
No, sir.
Oh.
Sorry I'm late.
I got stuck in Pinelarillo
what do you want?
I got 450 napkins and tablecloths.
I'm gonna need help
getting it out of here.
I don't have any deliveries
on my list today.
This is the front gate, right?
Yeah, it's the front gate.
They told me 3:00 at the front gate.
Can you check?
Can you
All right.
Stay there.
Is any deliveries on the list today?
No.
Let's go! Let's go!
Go ahead, go in!
Here!
What's that noise?
Come with me! Now!
Let's go!
Fico! The palace is being attacked.
Listen. Manzanita's taken over
the radio station.
People of Cuba, the dictator
Fulgencio Batista
has just met revolutionary justice.
The gunfire that extinguished
the bloody life of the dictator
can still be heard around
the Presidential Palace.
It is we,
The Directorio Revolucionario,
the iron hand of
the Cuban Revolution
who have accomplished the final
blow
against this shameful regime
still twisting in its own agony.
Cubans who can hear me,
he has just been eliminated.
Long live a free Cuba!
Que vive una Cuba libre!
Carbo! Carbo!
Luis! Luis!
Luis!
Pizzi, leave us alone.
With friends or without friends?
As you like.
Pizzi.
Yes, sir?
People of Cuba,
today alien forces
made an attempt on my life.
As you can see,
the news of my demise
is vastly exaggerated.
The President now declares
business as usual in Havana.
I lend a helping hand to
those law-abiding citizens
and our loyal oppositions.
The future of Cuba is safe.
Abuelo!
Our children are safe.
That is all.
Salud.
Life is becoming
a dress rehearsal
for a show nobody'll see.
What's the word on Luis?
He's nowhere to be found.
Are you sure he's alive?
Positive.
He might be abroad.
I'm leaving.
I'm sorry.
There's no news.
Was he part of the attack?
Yes.
Why won't you tell me where he is?
Because I don't know where he is.
Fico, if something happens,
I want to be there...
for him.
So do I.
May I offer a serious thought
from someone who's never serious?
No.
Well, that was it.
Mmm.
It's good.
A man with a purpose.
A man with less of a purpose.
Fellove, come on.
Please join me.
Mmm. Mmm!
In our house,
Sunday dinner is not
a moveable feast.
It is at 6, as usual.
Sorry.
All my sons are welcome, but...
not a minute after6.
You must always chew.
It's good for your health.
You chew and you chew.
Mmm.
And then you chew some more.
See, I'm a man of...
good digestion.
In fact, if I wasn't
such a modest man,
I'd say I'm a man
of great digestion.
That's why I'm still alive.
About our little business...
our business?
Yeah, our business.
My business is El Tropico.
And I would love to continue
going to El Tropico.
So unless that's a prop
for one of your new shows...
I'm asking myself,
what is a song and dance man
because that's what you do, huh?
Just a little song and dance,
and you put on a little show
doing with a.32 caliber
Smith & Wesson?
What? Hey!
What?
What, are you planning
to shoot your piano player?
Do you have a new
cowboy routine
in El Tropico now,
or something?
Any word from Ricardo?
No.
Why were you late
for dinner tonight?
Hmm?
I have enemies.
Cono.
And I have the right
to protect myself.
Cono.
Fellove, am I your enemy?
You weren't my enemy until
you killed my brother.
Luis Fellove, alias Peligro.
Not angel,
not the Virgin Mary
Peligro!
I swear,
I did not kill your brother.
Your brother attacked
the Presidential Palace
with the intent to kill
my President.
He committed suicide.
Believe me, you do not want
to disappoint me.
Trust me on this.
I can see
all you have is thirst for revenge.
Ah, I see.
You know what a zugzwang is?
It's a chess move.
Mm-hmm.
It is a chess move
that is no move at all.
It is actually a position
the position in which each player
will obtain a worse result
if it were his time to move
than if it were not.
Do you follow?
A double-bind.
A reciprocal situation.
All you have to do
is act accordingly.
Which means...
Do not act at all.
Go.
Ho ho ho!
Hey, hey!
Bravissimo, Fellove!
Bravissimo!
A showman to the end!
One more audition.
So just about any
clothes fit you, huh?
She's very lonely.
Ever since she moved in,
she won't go out at all.
Not even with her friends.
The memory of your brother,
and the fact that she
has not been able
to have a family of her own...
I hate to see her so sad.
It breaks my heart.
Why don't you ask her out?
She would like that.
It would do her good.
She needs you, and you need her.
Fico, talk to me.
Please.
You know the last thing
Luis said to me before he died?
What?
He made me promise...
that if anything ever happened to
him,
I would take care of you.
You've grown up in Havana all your
life,
and I bet there's parts of the
city you don't know at all.
I'm sure you know them well.
You know...
Havana's very much like a rose.
It has petals, and it has thorns.
So it depends on how you grab it.
But in the end,
it always grabs you.
Why don't you come out
with me tomorrow?
It'll do you good.
You ever see Beny Mor? Live?
Mmm.
Ah!
Have you been to
the Tropical Beer Gardens?
Ah!
It's good to see you smile.
Thank you.
Why are their handkerchiefs?
The handkerchiefs
are so there's no evidence.
Of what?
Of the intimacy they're sharing.
Beny! Beny!
Beny! Beny! Beny!
Where is he?
He's always late.
Beny! Beny! Beny!
Beny! Beny!
He likes to make an entrance.
There he is.
How many more are in the barracks?
Come on. Come on.
Fellove!
Let's move. Don't waste
any time with that.
Let's move.
You seem troubled, Fellove.
Is it about the captain we shot?
Listen to me very carefully.
In an insurrection,
the end justifies the means.
What is an insurrection?
Huh?
Armed struggle.
What is the end?
Revolution.
Which entails social, economic,
and political transformations.
Like I said?
The end justifies the means.
Hmm?
This is Havana.
Who said a woman
is like a flower?
A poet with a sense of smell.
May I join you?
Yes.
What was your name again?
My name again is no name.
What do you mean?
I don't mean nothing!
Names don't mean, people do.
But you are people, aren't you?
That... nobody can deny.
So what's your name, then?
I have no name.
I already told you that.
Everybody has a name.
Mm-hmm.
Everybody but me.
Why not?
I don't know.
Ask him.
Leave me out of your puns.
You're the strangest man
I ever met.
Thank you.
Okay, Emilio.
Your moneys no good here.
Thank you, Emilio.
I'll see you at the club.
When I grow up,
I wanna be just like him.
Why?
Because...
he never pays.
we interrupt
this program with a special news report.
The University of Havana was
closed by the government today,
as a direct result
of the ongoing riots.
President Fulgencio Batista,
who is under intense pressure
to resign,
declared publicly today
that the government
will not tolerate the disgracing
of the sacred grounds
of the university's Plaza Cadena,
which he claims the professional
agitators were using
for their selfish acts of anarchy.
She wants to talk to you.
It's okay.
El tiempo no estacon ustedes.
What did she say?
Time is not on our side.
Fico! Fico!
Braulio.
Hey!
Happy New Year.
How are you?
Same to you, my friend.
This is Aurora.
This is Captain Castel
and his lovely wife Marie Cristina.
How are you?
The pleasure's mine.
Ah.
You know, this is our year, Fico.
I just got promoted.
Congratulations.
Thanks again.
Well... it wasn't
because he's your brother.
It's because you're
still my favorite pitcher.
Well, you won't regret it.
Well, I hope not.
If you're wrong,
not even your curveball's
gonna save you.
Let's dance.
Okay.
Bye-bye.
Happy New Year.
Senoras y senores,
ladies and gentlemen,
it's almost New Year's
here at El Tropico
and all over the world!
We have ignition.
Engines running.
Countdown!
5, 4...
3, 2...
Happy 1959!
Happy New Year
to you all!
Mm.
Happy New Year.
A new year, a new life,
or so they say.
I certainly hope so.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you the President of Cuba.
Comrades in arms, friends.
Happy New Year's!
Salud!
Why are you so unhappy?
I'm not unhappy. I'm just sad.
Don't be.
It's in my nature.
Hey.
Beauty's your nature.
Sad can be beautiful.
Sad, yes, but not sadness.
Whoa, whoa. Please.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have an urgent announcement.
Batista, President Batista,
has left the country.
He's gone forever.
Let's celebrate a new Cuba!
Music, maestro!
Hold it! Hey!
Hey, hey, come on!
Come on, come on,
come on!
Vive Fidel Castro!
Fidel! Fidel!
Let us be thankful to God
for all he has given us.
For the love we share,
which should never
be taken for granted.
May it flourish
and be fulfilled,
as it is His gift to us.
Amen.
You seem truly happy.
I am.
And you?
Me?
I love you.
And I you.
I had a dream.
What was it about?
Us.
Luis was there.
What did he say?
He said he was okay.
What do you think?
You really love me.
Like I said.
Say it to me.
Say it again.
Like I said?
I love you.
Watch them closely.
I would be the only
person in Havana
man enough to turn
my back on him.
Hey, come on.
A peeping Tom in reverse.
When all the others are
watching the bearded Godiva,
I will avert my eyes.
Look how happy everybody is.
Everyone is alike in jubilation.
Only suffering makes them different.
I'm need to see your cells.
Cells? What cells?
I have a friend in the cells.
Attention!
When a superior officer
approaches you,
you stand at attention.
Is that understood?
Yes, comrade.
At ease.
I need to talk to you.
What's the matter with you?
You've been here all this time,
and you haven't
come see your family?
What do you need?
What do I need?
What?
I can't touch you?
Castel is in here.
He's in a cell. I need to see him.
There are no cells, Fico.
There's only the cage.
Take me to him.
Don't fuck around.
Take me to see him right now.
As you wish.
Brauilo!
Hmm?
Braulio.
Come here. Come here.
Fico.
Fico, Fico.
Oh, you don't look
so tough now.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay. I'm here.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
Get me out of here.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
I'm not...
I'm not an animal.
I deserve...
a proper jail.
Well, you built it, we didn't.
Listen to me. I
I'm not innocent, okay?
But I never killed anybody.
You just like to pull
people's eyes out
and their teeth and fingernails
and piss on them.
He saved your life!
That was to sell you a favor!
That's a lie.
You know it.
He's lying. He's lying.
It's okay.
Let me handle it.
Look at me.
I'm gonna take care of this.
I believe in you.
You came back.
Let's go.
He'll see you now.
So you're the dancer.
Che, I'm here
to inquire about a
My name is Comandante Guevara.
I'm Che only to my comrades.
What can I do for you?
My brother spoke to you
about a friend of mine,
Captain Castel.
Formerly a captain.
What about him?
He's detained here.
No longer.
He's been freed?
In a way.
What do you mean?
You know what
La Rouchefoucauld said about life?
There are two things
in life we cannot face
the sun and death.
Here we give people
a chance to face both.
We shot your friend
early this morning.
Why do you bother with such scum?
Why?
Look, go to your cabaret
and entertain the rich.
Let's go, Fico.
Go.
Cha-cha-cha!
Va.
Va. Muy bien.
Hold it. Hold it.
It's too military.
All right, girls,
lose the rifles.
Very, very unmilitary now.
M? Sica.
1, 2, 3.
Stop the music!
Stop that music!
Who are you?
I am Zoraida Munoz,
a delegate for
the musicians' union.
What authority do you have
to stop my rehearsal?
The government gave me the
authority.
See, you own this beautiful cabaret,
but we own the orchestra.
Really?
Really. If I tell the orchestra
not to play,
they can't play.
Is that so?
Fico, we're in the union.
They control the union.
I see. And under what
grounds do you have
to come here and stop my show?
You just can't use the saxophone
in the orchestra anymore.
Come again?
The saxophone is a instrument
of the imperialists.
The saxophone was invented
by a man named Sax in Belgium!
Do you know what
the Belgian imperialists
are doing in the Congo?
They're a bunch of murderers.
You don't say.
No, I do say!
And I am saying
that if you want
the orchestra to play,
then you have to go
without the saxophone.
Otherwise, I will stop the show.
Great show.
What's wrong with it?
You mean besides the fact
that they executed my friend
in two days without due process?
And now they're threatening
to close down my club
because we can't use
saxophones in the orchestra.
Saxophones!
Besides that?
What about the pigeons?
The pigeon.
Never work with pigeons.
Guano.
Well, at least
we don't have to deal
with the likes
of Meyer Lansky anymore.
Maybe worse.
Here's to a Cuba libre.
Well, what do we do now?
Let's go to Hernando's.
Hernando's Hideaway.
Now, that has a certain ring to it.
I'm going.
I'm going,
which translates
to I'm not going.
Dance with me.
What's wrong?
What's happening?
Viva el suerte de Fidel.
Viva Fidel!
It's Fidel.
The guy we saw performing
with a pigeon once.
Let's go over.
I want to meet him.
Too early in the day
for that.
There are some things
I need to say.
I want to speak with him.
Will you please take me?
What?
There are some things
I need to say.
Would you please take me?
No.
I'll go on my own, then.
Fidel's inviting us
to have breakfast with him.
He invited you, not me.
I don't think it's
proper for me to turn him down.
Well, I don't think
it's proper for me to wait around.
You're jealous.
Of a circus ringmaster?
You don't know me.
I thought
you never paid?
I always pay sooner or later.
Cecilia?
Yes, dear.
Was that Ricardo
at the door?
No, no. They had
the wrong house.
Oh.
Aurora.
Or should I say
companera?
Fidel sends his regard and
admiration.
He regrets that
he couldn't be here
to greet you personally.
He sent me in his place
to offer you something
of great importance.
Good news and bad news.
Somebody I know?
Somebody you don't know.
Aurora Bernal de Fellove,
a widow of a martyr
of the revolution
Luis Fellove, who was killed
in the massacre on Humboldt Street.
After his heroic exploits
during the assault
on the Presidential Palace.
Comrade Aurora has been named
widow of the Revolution
of the Year.
Nice writers they have
down here, huh?
Widow of the Revolution.
Does that mean
she was formerly married
to the revolution,
and now the aforementioned
revolution is dead?
And did that happen
this year, too?
And the copy
even I can write
better than that.
But...
it does suggest...
heads up now
The Merry widow
of the Revolution
some songs,
a little bit of business.
Very nice musical
you could open
right here in Fico's Palace.
I'd like to run
with this one if I could.
I'm gonna go see if I ca
n nail down the rights.
Hello.
Hello, Fico.
You haven't called me.
I had work to do.
You've just disappeared.
I missed you.
Work to do.
Have you seen it
in the papers?
Isn't it wonderful?
Yes, I'm glad to hear it.
Luis should be so proud.
Right.
The reason I called you
is to invite you
to a little celebration in my honor.
Would you please come?
Maybe some other time.
Listen, I have to go.
All right.
Please call me.
I love you.
Once more into the breach.
What can I do for you?
We're closing down
this cabaret
on account of gambling.
Gambling.
Illegal gambling.
What illegal gambling?
We caught two stagehands
playing cards.
And that's illegal.
Oh, it's worse than that.
It is a dangerous
distraction to the masses.
The opium of the people,
Marx said.
I thought Marx said religion
was the opiate of the people.
Marx said that, too.
Karl or Groucho?
Also an illegal gambling game.
The revolutionary government
will decide when, how,
and if this premises
will be functioning again.
You son of a bitch!
How dare you?
I'm an artist!
Puta! Cono!
Likewise.
Hello!
My nephew the hero!
Good to see you.
My goodness.
There's nothing
like an old Victrola.
Mmm-mmm-mmm.
I was just about
to make my rounds.
But first we have a drink, huh?
And then we'll have a walk,
talk, a smoke,
and then...
...we will eat, huh?
Ricardito.
Isn't this beautiful?
It's a little behind, yes,
but it shows great promise.
The day I die...
all of this will be yours.
No, it won't.
Yes, it will, but after I die.
Ha ha.
You don't understand.
It belongs to the revolution.
The revolution will pass, believe
me.
I've seen it all before.
Menocal, Machado, Batista...
where are they now?
Gone.
Fidel Castro will pass, too.
But the land...
the land, it will endure.
Fidel Castro sent me personally
to take vacant
possession of this land.
What are you talking about?
I'm here too evict you.
Would you repeat that to me,
please?
This farm is now
property of the state.
I am here to legally inform you
that you must leave immediately.
What did you just say to me,
nephew?
Godson.
My blood!
How dare you come to my house
and tell me to get out?
Have you no shame?
You really think
I'm going to leave my house?
My land?
I have worked this earth
too hard with my bare hands
to let some fidelistas
take it from me!
Listen, you have to understand,
this is
the future now.
The future?
Yes, the future.
Piss on your future!
I spit on your future!
Let them try and take it.
You just let them try!
Take it easy.
Where is your sense of
ohh! Aah...
ohh...
where is your sense of
Are you okay?
...family?
Help! Help!
Dono, put your head up.
Put your head up.
Put your head
Help me! Help!
Help! Help!
Hello, Father.
Hi, son.
What a great thing to hear.
No one comes to say hello these
days.
Just good-bye.
I'm so sorry.
Yeah, well...
my brother's resting in peace,
and Ricardo, unfortunately...
will have to live with
the consequences of his actions.
And that's very sad.
But, uh...
I would like to talk about you.
I remember what you said
about the moneylenders in the temple.
Yeah.
Well, the self-proclaimed
Christ is here,
and he's all whip.
I know.
Federico.
Yeah.
Your mother and I...
are worried about you.
Now we think you should be
leaving the country.
My place is here with both of you.
Listen to me.
No. I'm not gonna leave,
unless you're gonna come with me.
Listen to me.
In life, you have
to know when to arrive,
but you have to know when to leave.
And you should be leaving to a
place
where you can express yourself
freely,
not like here.
And this will fill
our hearts with hope.
We'll be fine, Fico.
We'll be fine.
I have left you very little, my son.
How can you say that?
You've given me
the wealth of your example.
That's all I need.
Remember that the future of
our familys with you.
You know... in Cuba,
we have always
had plenty of light.
We have never had darkness
at noon before.
You are my pride and my joy.
I'm going to do
something I did to you
when you were a little boy.
This.
Nothing there, huh?
I'm sorry.
How could you?
Look at me!
What has become of you, Ricardo?
You betray your country.
You disgraced your family.
You are lost, my son.
Yes, you are.
Fico
I wish I could go back to the beginning.
Mmm, I love beginnings.
Why's that?
Nothing's happened yet.
Anticipation is
in the air. Optimism.
What about the end?
Well, they don't
call it the end for nothing.
I hate endings...
unless, of course,
your end is your beginning,
which makes
your beginning your end.
Then I would love the end.
Where are we now?
If you don't know where you are,
then you are in the middle.
No doubt about that.
There goes my swing vote.
Friends, I have an important
announcement to make.
There's no dessert.
Food rationing.
Would you mind?
And now a few brief words
from the man with no name?
I'll be brief.
Ladies and gentlemen...
our Federico
Fellove is going away for good.
Being a writer, I stress
the word good
because I think it will
be good for him...
and good for us, too.
Fico is going
to New York City...
the Mecca of show business...
where I'm gonna be headin'
for eventually.
Fico,
I know you're gonna be there
to welcome us with open arms
as you have so many
times in the past.
Ladies and gentlemen...
the writer,
for the first time, speechless.
I'll bail you out.
I'd like to say something.
Please.
I wanna say that this, uh...
this moment here means
a great deal to me...
and I'm gonna treasure this forever.
Salud.
Forever is a very long time, Fico.
It's all right.
He's with me.
Would you like a drink?
No, I'm driving.
I thought you came in a taxi.
I'm driving the taxi.
Very funny.
Most things are these days.
I need to speak to you alone.
I have an exit visa.
I'm leaving.
What did you say?
You heard what I said.
I'm leaving the country.
I want you to come with me.
To go where?
Anywhere but here.
It doesn't matter.
We can start again.
Fico, I have a duty to my country.
It is what Luis died for.
Luis Luis died for Cuba.
He didn't die for Fidel.
For the first time in my life,
I feel I'm part
of something important.
I feel I can make a difference.
We're fighting the just cause.
In a ruthless
and undemocratic manner.
We have to make
our reforms first.
Democracy will come later.
Then why not
the other way around?
I don't want to argue with you.
Never you.
Why don't you give us a chance?
Us? Us as in us?
Or us as in you
and the cause calibre?
Don't be angry with me.
No, anger would be too simple.
You must know that I love you.
That's the complicated part.
I'm sorry, Senora Fellove.
The Commandante Guevara and
the Soviet ambassador want to see you.
It seems urgent.
Please stay.
Why do you have to leave?
Please.
Miss Fellove,
this is the Soviet ambassador.
That is all you're ever gonna get.
What?
It's not included in the deal?
Yes.
Let's go. Come on.
Let's go.
What are you doing?
You're embarrassing me.
This gathering is an embarrassment.
Get your hands off me.
Get you hands off me!
Take your hands off me.
You have something to say?
Comrade...
the dance floor is yours.
To Luis Fellove...
who died for a dream,
a dream of a pluralistic
and democratic Cuba!
Long live a free Cuba.
Let's go.
Fico, wait.
I can't leave.
We must leave before
it's too late to get out.
Try and understand.
Try to understand?
I understand that I'm
lost without you.
This is bigger than us.
There is nothing bigger than us.
Listen to me.
Can't you see what's happening?
You're being taken advantage of.
Is that what you want?
You want to be told what to think
the rest of your life?
Because there's no end to this.
This is madness.
You deserve more.
We deserve more.
If you stay, your life
will not belong to you.
Please.
Come with me.
We're all that's left
of our family.
In time, you'll understand.
There's no more time.
Here's your exit visa.
I'm leaving tomorrow
at 5:00 in the afternoon.
Comrade, companero
I salute you.
On behalf of our maximum leader
and all Communists in Cuba,
welcome! Bienvenido!
Federico Junior.
I want you to have this.
You will need it
on the day where...
when what is left
of our family...
be reunited.
That's for you.
Mother and I
Just don't worry
because well be right here.
We're strong people.
We're gonna be right here...
waiting for you.
We'll have dinner together.
Uh, but what is very important...
At 6, okay?
Sharp.
Not a minute afterwards.
That's my boy.
Yeah. That's it.
There. It fits you
as well as it fits your father.
Are you kidding?
Much better.
Look at him.
I'm gonna send for you
as soon as I can.
Bye.
It's all okay.
God bless you.
I gotta go.
Okay.
We'll be here.
Let's go!
Next.
What's in the bag?
Only what I need.
Open it.
Man of taste.
What's this?
Home movies.
There's my camera.
Open it.
I wanna photograph
the injustice of American life.
Stretch out your arms.
Empty your pockets.
Ring and watch, take them off.
Put it in here.
Sir?
Inside.
Take it off.
This watch belonged to my father.
Belonged is correct.
In here.
What's this?
A memento.
Hmm.
You worms are strange.
Not yet gone, and you're
already carrying souvenirs.
You can't take Cuba
with you, you know.
Free to go.
Next.
This is Willis Conover
of the Voice of America
bringing you The Music of Freedom.
For those of you in limbo
out there, here is the Duke
and saxophone
is Coleman Hawkins
with Limbo Jazz.
Who is it?
Room service.
So when did you leave?
Better ask
when did I escape.
Semantics, my friend,
is made up of antics.
I'm glad to see you.
It can only mean
that you're lonely.
Lonely is the best word.
When a man is truly lonely,
even a light bulb is good company.
Actually, I'm masquerading
as an exile.
Well, your impersonation
is quite good.
I'm still in Cuba.
Where do you think I am,
Jersey City?
Joe DiMaggio.
Minnie Minoso.
He looks in.
Yeah, you latched on that one.
Hmm, where we going?
El Dragon Rojo,
a Cuban-Chinese restaurant
which is neither.
But they are under
the illusion I'm a writer.
Madam.
Oh, madam.
What would you like today?
My usual please.
Beluga caviarto start.
For an entre, pheasant tongues
marinated in vin de sauternes.
Smyrna figs for dessert,
and a bottle of Veuve Cliquot
chilled, not merely cold, please.
Fried rice and bananas for two.
Yes, the special, please,
but bring it right away.
We haven't eaten
since the revolution.
Did you know that Cuba
is half white,
half black, and half Chinese?
That's three halves.
Everything is coming
in threes these days, even halves.
Which half are you?
Half owner.
Should have been
a stand-up comedian.
I may hold you to that.
I can't help you.
I'm just a former cabaret owner.
Once a cabaret owner,
always a cabaret owner.
Or is it once a former
cabaret owner,
always a former cabaret owner?
Fico.
Take a break, chico.
Time to suffer.
Good one.
Thank you.
Ahem.
Look, Fico,
I've been...
I've been thinking.
You know, it bothers me
to see you, Fico Fellove,
working in the kitchen.
Nonsense.
Now, I've told you before
I appreciate the work.
Well, anyway, I was thinking.
What if I set up
a piano in the cafe?
Would you be interested in...
Unfortunately, the pay
would be the same,
but plus tips.
Whatever you need. Hmm?
You know I appreciate it.
Mm.
I'd like to keep this job, too.
I need the extra money.
I'm trying to bring my family.
Enough said.
To free Cuba.
Salud.
The present
you are living in is so thin,
you could squeeze it
underneath a door.
The trouble with exile is exile.
Thank you.
I have a solution.
This pretty lady's torch
is Aladdin's lamp.
Aladdin's lamp.
And it will grant
any wish in your life.
I wish I could relive it.
You can by rebuilding it.
Will you work for me?
Free drinks?
Done.
Gentlemen, time to suffer.
The door was open.
You know, the thing I love
most about New York
is that you're always
running into old friends.
You know why we're friends?
Because we don't believe
in coincidences.
Please sit down.
You may consider me an enemy,
but I've always considered
you a friend, Federico.
I may at times have lost
my patience at times,
but never with a man I respect
and that respects me in kind.
How we doing there, Joe?
Flirting. Good.
Take your hat off.
Ah, she was a beautiful thing,
Havana.
We should have known she was a...
a heartbreaker.
And here we are.
It's bashert
destiny.
Now, listen.
Listen hard.
I didn't bomb your place, kid.
That's not my style.
Okay?
May I have an egg cream?
Chocolate syrup, cold milk.
Spritz the seltzer until
it foams up over the top.
No.
And a bit of rum, yes?
Yeah. An egg cream.
What's your name?
I never thought you'd ask.
My offer's still open.
A new club.
Las Vegas.
Nevada.
No humidity.
Don't answer.
Think about it.
You know?
You know, even in rejection
lead me on a little bit, hmm?
Don't break my heart...
just yet.
You like egg cream.
Yes, I like egg creams.
And I'm not crazy
about humidity, either.
You give my regards
to your family.
You have the ingredients right.
There's an art
with the seltzer spritz.
Your chocolate
goes at the bottom
with milk over it,
and then you spritz straight down,
but then you spritz
around the glass
until it rises to the top.
Always a pleasure, Lansky.
I mean Mr. Meyer.
Love your wieners.
Bueno, Fico.
Good night.
Okay, have a good time.
Keys are in the back.
Have a good time.
Good night, Mrs. Calabash,
wherever you are.
Gentlemen, don't burn
the place down.
Did you ever
have the feeling
that you wanted to go?
Did you ever
have the feeling
that you wanted to stay?
Go, stay, go, stay, go...
ooh.
That's a go, isn't it?
Madam, always a pleasure.
Give my regards
to the pigeons.
Why are you here?
I'm here...
with our dedication
to United Nations.
Do you have time for some coffee?
I'm sorry you left.
There was nothing left
for me in Havana.
Yes, I know.
You lost your club.
No, that's not
what I meant.
You sound bitter.
Not at all.
I have no money...
but I feel...
as though I'm worth more
than I ever was.
Would it do any good
to say I'm sorry?
No, not really.
Try at least to understand me.
I've understood more
than you could explain.
Why don't you come back
to Cuba with me?
Because it's dangerous...
for my soul.
I see you still do not
believe in causes.
Well, I don't have
a loyalty to a lost cause.
But I do have a loyalty
to a lost city.
And that's my cause and my curse.
Please don't hate me, then.
I'll never hate you.
I'll always love you.
Why can't you love me there?
Too big of a price to pay.
Be well.
Stop crying.
You can always love me here.
Remember that.
You're so beautiful.