In the worst-case scenario
you're two weeks ahead of me,
you get a gorgeous little
apartment in the Marais.
What if I don't want
to live in the Marais?
We could live
somewhere else, then.
Yeah?
Yeah.
We could go to Detroit.
Detroit?
Yeah, you could
meet my mom and dad.
You can meet my sister.
She owns a bakery,
and she will
make you fat.
I have six hours before I have
to go back to the hospital.
You want to go
back into bed with me?
I do.
But I got back-to-back
meetings all morning.
Too bad for you.
Yeah, I know.
But I got to get in.
There's probably
already 25 people
lined up outside
the door, waiting.
I love when
you speak French.
Satcom check.
Echo Nine Three
Victor Echo Two.
Ops Center.
This is safe house 7-R.
We're open for business.
Confirmed.
Any reservations?
Nothing in
the registry.
Walk-ins?
Not expected.
Reconfirm in three hours.
Understood.
Matt?
Your cell, really?
Relax, I've got
an encryption packet.
You know me,
I never relax.
Watch the cholesterol,
old man.
You sound like Miriam.
So, what's new
in Cape Town?
Nothing, nothing.
I updated my Surveillance Target Analysis.
It's complete now.
Yeah, that's an exit report.
It's not due until you leave.
Exactly. Exactly.
And when is that?
How long has it been?
Twelve months.
Well, talk to me
in another four.
David, I'm dying here.
What's happening
with the post in Paris?
One slot,
37 applicants.
Every one of them with more
field experience than you.
How am I supposed to
get more experience?
I'm staring at
four walls all day.
I got passed up on Rome,
then Berlin.
You said yourself, my
evaluation was excellent.
Just put it in
front of Whitford.
I know he'll see that I'm
ready to go, I'm all in.
Matt, I know
this has been hard,
but it's the way
the system works.
Look, I'll talk to Whitford about
Paris, but I can't promise anything.
Look, I've got to go.
Don't worry,
I'm looking after you, okay?
Yeah, I know,
I know, I know.
This is not a negotiation.
It's 10 million.
You'll get the file,
and if the money
is not in the account
by 3:00 p.m.
I'll take it
to another buyer.
How do we know
that you won't do that anyway?
You don't.
Here you are, sir.
Alec, how are you?
Petrus, 1972.
You look good.
I do, don't I?
So, how are things
at MI6?
The usual. Same bureaucratic
bullshit and appalling remuneration.
Life of a government man.
Mmm-hmm.
So...
The original file.
Dates,
transactions, names.
A bargain
at triple the price.
Take a look.
Hmm.
I've been waiting
a long time for this.
Tobin...
What's in that box
is going to make
the world
a smaller place for you,
for both of us.
I got your account.
You get your cut
24 hours after transaction.
Some of our old bosses
aren't going to be happy
these files are out
in the open.
Do I make you nervous?
Always.
Good.
You want her?
Please, listen to me.
I had nothing to do
with this.
Stop.
Let's go.
Tobin, you have
to believe me.
I knew nothing
about any of that.
Did you know if
anybody was following you?
No, I don't think
anybody was following me.
I swear on my life,
Tobin, I had absolutely...
Slow down.
We're going by foot.
Head towards the square.
Move! Move! Move!
We're heading west.
Holland Street.
Move, move.
Excuse me, sir.
Thank you.
My name is Tobin Frost.
Link later.
When?
Lock down the consulate.
Get me a team in the Situation
Room in five minutes.
I want everything we got
on Tobin Frost.
Yes, ma'am.
Is it him?
Yep.
Whitford know?
I'm on my way there now.
Sir, place your finger in
there until I tell you to stop.
Thank you.
So how long has he been
playing in your backyard?
We're working to get you
that answer right now.
Meaning you don't know.
No, meaning,
we're looking into it.
The guy goes rogue,
he spends nine years
selling out the Agency
to all takers.
To Russia, China, Iran,
you name it.
The guy is just not
going to prance
into an American consulate
without good reason.
All right, listen up.
Everybody off the phone.
Tobin Frost has
just waltzed his way
into a U.S. Consulate
in Cape Town, South Africa.
Now this man,
without question,
is one of the most notorious
traders that we've got.
Errington, call up
his background profile.
Tobin Frost was
recruited into the Agency in 1984.
He tested off the charts in aptitude
for psychological field work.
His first assignment was in
Lebanon, in January, 1985.
Three months later,
he captured and flipped
a high-ranking
Hezbollah leader.
Over the next
several years,
Frost successfully questioned and
recruited many high-value individuals.
He became known as an expert
manipulator of human assets,
and he literally rewrote Agency
interrogation protocols.
Frost served
in many active theaters,
including Libya
from 1995 to 1998,
Jordan, 1998 to 2000.
During his tenure
in Jordan,
Frost was suspected of leaking
information to Mossad,
but nothing
was confirmed.
Ten years ago, Frost went off
the reservation completely.
He currently
has no allegiances
and is wanted for espionage
on four continents.
His last known sighting
is Hamburg, Germany, in 2011.
You know, Harlan, we should
interrogate Frost now.
Sweat him for
everything he's got.
Once he's stateside,
we have fewer options.
I have an interrogator in Yemen,
can be there in eight hours.
I already have a team in Jo'burg
that can be there in two.
We'll take Frost to the safe
house, interrogate him there.
My people are fully
capable of handling this.
This is Tobin Frost.
We'll go with Jo'burg.
Okay.
You must turn around.
Help. Help.
Accident.
Housekeeping.
We have
a last-minute reservation.
ETA for check-in?
Sometime tonight.
Freeark Insurance.
Got it.
Hello.
Hey.
Hey, where are you?
Parker just handed me
his oversight papers to finish
and his daughter Chloe's got the
measles, can you believe that?
How long are you
going to be out for?
I don't know.
Okay. Well, look,
I'm gonna dive into this,
and then hopefully I can meet
up with you later, okay?
Yeah, that sounds good.
Hey, hey...
I love you.
I love you, too.
Bye.
Extraction team
is in the air, sir.
They should be on the
ground within the hour.
I want that team in and out of
the city in less than 12 hours.
We're not even
supposed to have
a presence in Cape Town.
Yes, sir.
Any communications about Frost's
whereabouts are strictly need-to-know.
Sir, the extraction team is en
route to the consulate now.
Who's reaching out
to 7-R?
Richards, ma'am.
I want
the housekeeper briefed.
High-priority target is coming in.
I want the house quiet.
Under no circumstances
should there be
any communication
until the team has left.
Yes, ma'am.
Yeah?
Do you have a room?
Account?
Daniel Kiefer.
Freeark Insurance.
K- I-E-F-E-R.
Kiefer. Freeark Insurance.
You are a go.
You're good to go.
Hi, I'm Weston.
Guest room?
It's right around the corner.
Two rights and a left.
All the way back.
That's Tobin Frost.
Stay with him. Let's
go download our gear.
Yes, sir.
Linen closet?
Down the hall. Just right
at the end, there.
Kill all the surveillance
cameras in this room.
My name is Daniel Kiefer.
We were at
The Farm together.
Technically,
you were a year ahead.
I'm here to make you
aware of your rights.
You're being held under
a National Security Directive,
which means you have none,
but you know that.
Six-hundreds.
The towels,
you need six-hundreds.
Those are 350,
375-gram weight.
You're gonna
need six-hundreds.
I want to know the reasons
for you being in Cape Town.
I want you to name your
resources, contacts, assets,
everybody you've
done business with,
traded intel with,
sold secrets to,
in the nine years since you
betrayed your country.
Absolutely.
Anything you want, Daniel.
Khalid Sheikh
Mohammed lasted 20 seconds.
They had six-hundreds.
Is this legal?
Bring him down.
Bring him up.
How long was that?
All right,
take him down.
Bring him up!
Get me a knife.
Miller?
Get in there
with Frost.
Sir, all the security cameras
are down.
Reboot. I want to see what's out there
Copy that.
Let's go, boys!
Go! Go! Go!
Let's go, move!
Velez, take this corner.
Ericksson,
get the back elevator.
Pope, what do you got?
Sir, I see approximately 12
heavily armed men in perimeter two.
Okay, gents!
Work fore to aft.
Two-by-twos.
Perimeter two.
Greer?
Sir!
Ericksson?
Yes, sir.
Velez?
I'm good!
Let's go, fellas.
Incoming!
Grenade!
Greer!
Step-slide!
Start walking back!
Velez!
Three-round bursts!
Velez, where's Greer?
He's over there, sir.
Go, son.
This ain't a test.
This is the real thing.
What are you
gonna do?
You don't want
to try me.
Magazine!
Let's go.
Velez, stay there!
Listen to me
stay there!
Son of a bitch!
Miller!
Hey! Get in here!
Hey, hey. Take these.
Go watch him.
Hey, they're here for me,
but they want me alive.
You, they'll kill.
You got one
in the chamber?
It's okay.
I remember my first posting.
Rio de Janeiro.
A house like this.
Beautiful women.
Not one single visitor, but
I remember rule number one.
You are responsible
for your houseguest.
I'm your houseguest.
The clock is ticking.
They gave you the keys.
Do your duty, son.
Shut up. Let me think.
You want to be the guy
that lost Tobin Frost?
Tick-took,
tick-took, tick-took.
Where's Frost?
We're leaving.
Where is he?
Stay here, stay here!
Wait! Don't move!
Hey, hey, hey!
Go!
Get in the trunk.
Are you serious?
Yeah, get in.
The trunk?
Get in the trunk now!
No!
Ops Center.
Echo Three
Victor Echo Nine.
Go ahead.
This is Weston. 7-R's been hit.
Everyone's dead.
I need you to repeat that, please.
Say again.
Kiefer, his team, everyone,
they're all dead.
Stand by.
Transferring.
It's the house.
Linklater.
This is Weston.
The safe house
has been breached.
What's your location?
I'm eastbound
on Albert Road.
I'm just
passing Woodstock.
I want eyes on this.
Real-time sat feed.
And what's
the location of the guest?
We escaped.
Clarify.
Do you have the guest?
Yes, we escaped!
Look, I can make it
to the consulate.
There's no chance
for SDR,
I think I might have
picked up a tail.
We can't have a gun battle
in front of the consulate.
Diplomatic catastrophe.
Where's that
satellite feed?
Denied by National Recon
War theater use only.
Buy us some time.
Do not go
to the consulate.
Follow protocol
Alpha Zero.
Secure the guest
and stay off the grid.
Reconnect at 1800 hours.
I repeat, stay off the grid.
Copy. copy. copy.
All right, Cape Town police
have responded to the house.
Confirmed.
I want the site secured.
I'm hearing nine dead.
Initiating damage control.
I'm on it.
Reaching out to NIA now.
The locals are going to
have that house locked off.
Check all the traffic
cameras, police reports...
Find out why Frost wanted to go
in that consulate to begin with
and who in the hell else
might be after him.
We need to get Weston and
Frost out of South Africa.
Now, do we have any tactical teams?
Anything in play?
Yeah, I have assets in
Egypt, but they're in deep.
If I pull them out, that would
compromise two years' worth of work.
I can scramble a team
from Europe or Asia,
but it's going to
take at least 18 hours.
At this point,
Weston is all we got.
I need to find out who this
Matt Weston is, right now.
Matthew James Weston.
Born 02-24-82 to
Terry and Madeline Weston
in Port Washington,
New York.
An assault arrest,
one month after
both parents and
a younger sister
were killed in
a traffic accident
in which his
father's blood-alcohol
was twice
the legal limit.
Yale, degree in Economics,
recruited out of Yale law.
High marks in analytics
and linguistics at The Farm.
Excellent in
tradecraft skills.
His girlfriend, Ana Moreau,
is a French national.
He reported them as having
"close and continuing contact. "
She's a second year resident in the
oncology department at Groote Schuur.
Get in that car.
She accepted a
position with Hotel-Dieu Hospital
in Paris,
starts in two weeks.
No known political
affiliations. She's clean.
I want you to post a car
outside their apartment.
Use back channels.
And get NSA to cross-check their telephone
records and their e-mails, please.
Yes, ma'am.
You know, it would be easier
if I knew where we were going.
You just drive, all right?
Just drive, middle lane.
All right.
Hey, what are you doing?
Middle lane.
Just drive around.
All right.
I'm driving.
Nice to know who you're talking to.
What's your name?
You crushed my windpipe.
Well, you locked me
in the trunk.
Come on, you're not NOC. You're
here under your real name.
What is it?
Weston, Matt.
All right.
How long you been
a safe house keeper?
Twelve months.
Happy birthday.
Cape Town,
that's low-level detail.
You should have been
out of here by now.
Maybe I requested
the assignment.
Or maybe Langley doesn't trust
you with anything else.
So, what's your plan?
Oh, let me guess.
Follow protocol.
Protocol states that
if your house is crashed,
you do an SDR to make sure
no one's following you.
Activate your GPS in your Go-Bag,
select another safe house.
You think I'm going to
let you just take me in?
I think you need
to shut up.
I think you need to consider how your
house was attacked in the first place.
Have you done that, Matt?
They followed Kiefer. They
followed him from the consulate,
and that's how they
found the safe house.
Come on, you don't really
believe that, do you?
How did they know I was near the
consulate in the first place?
Hmm.
But I like this, you know.
You and me, figuring shit out.
Like the Hardy Boys.
That house was
a secure location.
Whoever crashed it
didn't stop by a gas station and ask for
directions to the nearest safe house.
They were invited. Someone
told them, Matthew.
Think about it.
Someone you know.
So you better ask yourself,
can you trust your landlord?
Go ahead, you're not
going to get in my head.
I already am
in your head.
They're going to
isolate you, Matt.
They're going to be real
nice to you at first.
They're going to put their arm
around you and tell you things like,
"You did a decent job, son.
We'll take it from here. "
That's when you know
you're screwed.
Forget about me. They're
going to focus on you.
They're going to try and make a
connection between you and I.
So that if this
all goes wrong,
they'll have something
to fall back on
in their little
Senate hearings.
I'm not your
only enemy tonight.
So, it's someone in-house.
It's the only way this
thing could've happened.
We were
completely buttoned up.
I want a list of everyone
who knew about this.
Backgrounds, affiliations,
particularly any
connections with Frost.
Every movement right
up until this operation.
Your extraction team, how
long had they been together?
My team had been together
six months. Why?
Well, I'm just trying to
get my head around this.
That will do, thank you.
Hello.
Hey.
Baby, where are you?
I'm all right.
I'm okay.
I'm sorry I didn't call you
back, I saw your missed calls.
You must be worried sick.
Is everything okay?
I'm good.
I'm good. Listen.
This sounds so crazy.
We had some threats against
the clinic last night,
so Parker and I,
we stayed all night
trying to get to
the bottom of it.
And I'm sorry that I didn't cal! you back.
I should have, right away.
I was so worried.
I know.
Can you do me a favor? Can you go
over to the window for a second?
Why?
Can you just take a quick
look out the window?
I want you to see if
there's anyone out there.
Are there any cars
that don't belong?
Anyone hanging
around out front?
There's a police car.
What's going on?
I'm sorry about this.
I know this is a lot,
but we felt like
it would be best
if we didn't go home
as a precaution,
and I agree with him.
I know there's nothing to worry
about, but I agree with him.
I think you should just go to
Dena's for a little while,
just for a few hours, and I'll
call you in a little bit.
And we'll
get together, okay?
Okay, I'll go.
Okay. I love you. I'll talk
to you soon, all right?
Don't worry. Okay, bye.
She know what you do
for a living?
The girl on the phone.
It was a girl, wasn't it?
Maybe it was a guy,
I don't know.
I don't judge.
You can't expect to have a real
relationship in our line of work, Matthew.
Don't worry. She's not
going to leave you.
See, what happens is, you try
to protect her with lies,
and then it starts
to add up.
At the safe house you said that
they'd kill me to get to you.
After awhile,
even the truth...
Why?... starts to
sound like a lie.
You have something. You got something
that they want. What is it?
Is she a local?
Don't worry about her.
What is it?
Oh, it is a girl.
You'll keep covering your
tracks, she'll keep believing.
Because she wants to,
because she needs to.
That's why we exist, you
and me, that's our job.
To take advantage of that.
People's desire
to believe.
To trust.
She's not going to
leave you, Matthew.
You're going
to leave her.
I'm not you.
Correct, sir.
We verified it.
That is your boy.
You take it.
Everybody, stand by.
Matty, it's me.
How are you holding up?
I'm all right.
Matt, we can't get another
team in for at least 12 hours.
Sorry.
We've cleared a new safe house
for you outside the city.
There's a Go-Bag located
at locker number 256, Green Point
Stadium Metrorail station.
The combination
is 2-5-1-22.
2-5-1-22.
Now, the bag's
got a GPS in it.
It'll direct you
to the safe house.
But you got to be careful,
it's an active location.
So, approach
with caution.
Matt?
Do you know how
they found Frost?
Do you know who
led them to us?
We're working on that.
We're counting
on you, Matt.
Get Frost to that safe house and
you can write your own ticket.
I will.
Left at the light.
To the stadium?
Yeah.
Hey, scarf.
How much for a scarf?
Only fifty rand.
Thanks.
Cuff your hands
together.
Together?
Yeah.
Out.
Are you sure you don't
want to just walk away from this?
Can't do that.
Yes, you can.
You should.
Move. Go.
Across the street.
Going to the game.
I like games.
Metrorail,
straight ahead.
Straight ahead.
Right over there.
Let's go.
Help! Help! He's
trying to kidnap me!
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!
He's trying to
kidnap me! Help!
He's got a gun!
He's got a gun! He's
got a gun right there!
I'm undercover.
I'm undercover!
Calm down, sir.
Everybody, calm down!
Get down! Get down!
All right! Okay!
Get him up. Get up.
Ow, ow, ow!
I'm an American citizen. I don't
know what he wanted from me.
Just calm down.
Hey, hey, hey. I'm a police officer.
I'm from America.
I arrested this man.
His name is Tobin Frost.
Where did you take him?
He's in the infirmary.
There, there!
Is that it?
Top left, second screen from the top!
Look, look, the infirmary.
Right. Go back.
Third-tier infirmary,
now! Move!
Third-tier infirmary.
Go, now!
Do you see?
Don't move.
Frost!
Hey!
Stop! Stop!
Get out the way!
Stop!
No! Stop!
Medic!
Drop the gun.
Drop it.
I'm responsible for you.
You're responsible
for yourself.
Get on your knees.
Are you going
to kill me?
I only kill professionals.
Height,
approximately six feet.
Anglo, wearing
a stadium security jacket.
The suspect was last seen entering
Green Point Stadium Metrorail,
stadium concourse.
Sir, we have a thread on what Frost
might be doing in Cape Town.
Can you bring up...
Alec Wade.
Fifteen-year NOC at MI6.
Sabotage, counter-ambush,
counter-IED tactics,
until he blew up an op
in Lisbon four years ago
and was put on a desk,
pushing papers.
Cape Town Police found him
shot through the head,
high-powered rifle, 14
blocks from the consulate.
Witnesses placed someone
fitting Frost's description
in the car at the time
of the shooting.
And we think, what? That
they were working together?
They ran joint operations
in Hamburg in the mid-'80s.
Frost's last sighting
was in Hamburg, 2011.
And what are the Brits
saying about Wade?
Officially,
they're saying nothing.
Unofficially?
He's been the subject of a
five-month internal investigation.
They think he's
been trading intel.
Hmm.
So what the hell
did Wade leak to Frost
that was so important it was
worth killing six of our men?
I want more details from MI6.
Call in every chit you got.
Yes, sir.
David, I want
an internal investigation
into Daniel Kiefer
and his team.
I've got Weston calling in
for David Barlow.
WESTON ON PHONE
Frost?
Yeah, he's gone.
After I picked up the GPS,
he created a diversion,
took out a couple of cops
at the stadium.
Any idea
where he's headed?
Not exactly,
but I will.
This is Linklater. You
said he took out two cops?
Matt, you're on speaker.
Yes, ma'am.
At the Green Point Stadium.
...involvement
in a possible kidnapping.
The suspect is being described
as a white male of medium build.
Stadium police is
reporting you shot a cop.
I returned fire
in self-defense.
The fact of the matter is,
Frost is on the loose.
I've spent the last
14 hours with him.
He might have said or done something
that could lead me to him.
You are to stand down,
proceed to the consulate,
and present yourself for exfil and debrief.
Acknowledge.
By the time I'm debriefed,
Frost will be gone.
I've spent 12
months researching
every square inch
of this town.
I will find Frost
and I'll deliver him.
Weston, this is
Harlan Whitford, son.
Now, you've done a fine job,
but we'll take it from here.
Understood.
Hello.
Sir, I respectfully
request that,
that exchange not
make it onto his files.
He's either incompetent or he's
working with somebody else.
Do not make this
about Weston.
It was your guys
that lost Frost.
It was your team that
folded at the safe house.
I want both of you on an
airplane to Cape Town.
Frost is trying to get out of the country.
Go find his ass.
There you go, baby.
One ticket to Jo'burg.
Thank you.
Police had detained
American NGO worker Matthew Weston
as a possible suspect
in the shooting.
Weston had been
detained earlier today,
but managed to escape while being
questioned by stadium security officials
about his involvement
in the shootings.
The suspect has been described
as a white male of medium build,
possibly wearing
a stadium security outfit.
Baby
Are you all right?
I lied to you.
About everything.
The NGO, Parker.
My job.
My family.
So, who do you work for?
The government.
CIA.
No, I don't...
I don't do anything.
I sit around in an apartment
all day I answer the phone.
I need you to leave.
I need you to do that
for me. Okay?
Here.
This is a ticket
to Jo'burg.
When you get there, you go
straight to the airport.
There's a 6:00 a.m. flight
to Paris.
Take this.
You take this.
If anyone stops you...
If anybody stops you...
Who do you think I am?
Stop, Stop
Fuck you!
Hey, stop. Stop it.
We broke up a week ago. You
haven't seen me since, okay?
I'm sorry.
Just leave. Please?
Do you love me?
Very much.
Go. Go.
Go.
Attention, all passengers,
Platform 20
for Langa Township
departing in five minutes.
Langa Township,
Sir. Someone just logged into our
system using Weston's password
accessing his
stored files.
It's him. What
the hell is he doing?
I'm not sure.
I want to see
what he's looking at.
He's pulled an old report
on surveillance targets living
in the Langa Township area.
It's a profile of Carlos
Villar, a Nicaraguan national.
He's a known
document forger.
Get me a copy
of Weston's report.
Yes, sir.
Logged off, sir.
He's gone.
An Internet cafe
on Long Street.
Like a black
Dorian Gray.
That's right.
How you doing, brother?
Come in.
Yes, sir.
Illana?
Hi.
We have a guest.
illana.
Good to meet you.
Joseph, my daughter.
How are you?
Hello.
My son-in-law.
May I offer you some tea?
No, we're going
upstairs.
I remembered.
You even let it breathe.
"Too long a sacrifice Can
make a stone of the heart
"O when may it suffice?
"That is Heaven's part"
In the old days,
a cheap bottle
of Flor de Cana kept us
happy all night.
Mmm. Tastes change.
People change.
People don't change.
We grow old.
And some of us adapt.
And learn how to enjoy
simple pleasures of life,
like a family, a home.
And for you...
What's in that glass
right now, for you,
is as good as it's
ever going to be.
One day you'll understand.
You got more past
than future, you learn.
What is this?
An intervention?
I thought you were dead.
So, what brings you to my home
in the middle of the night
after all these years?
Ooh.
Papa?
Uh-huh.
We're going.
Okay, be careful.
Okay, Papa
What are you
going to do with this?
Make some money.
Let me borrow
your glasses.
That's it. Listen.
I'm going to need a new passport,
photo ID, driver's license,
the whole shebang.
Can you do that for me?
Yeah.
You sure?
Yes.
Weston never
showed at the consulate.
And he was just
accessing our secure server,
searching for someone
to create an alias package.
He's trying to
leave the country.
Or he's going
after Frost.
Look at what
happened at the soccer stadium.
This guy
let Frost escape.
I think Weston's turned.
I know this boy.
He's been looking for a
chance to prove himself.
He's trying to
bring in Frost.
Come on, David.
You're not
seeing the evidence.
Not my best work.
But given the pressure
of time, it's passable.
It's good.
I'll wire you the money
as soon as
I get out of town.
Tobin, don't do this.
It's different.
You don't need the trouble,
you don't need the money.
You can give it...
Carlos!
Illana!
illana!
Carlos.
Carlos!
Go.
He's on the roof!
Go! Go!
Get in the car!
They think they can
come at me like this.
Have to do it a whole
lot better than that.
Shit!
Matt, how'd you find me?
It wasn't that hard.
Let's go.
Wait, wait, wait.
Who do you work for?
Who sent you?
Who?
Vargas.
Who's Vargas?
You want to die?
Matt.
CIA.
CIA! CIA!
Report?
There was a shootout
in the Langa Township.
Two crime scenes. One at the
residence of Carlos Villar.
He's a document forger.
The other in
a nearby tenement.
And where was
Frost last seen?
Tenement.
Have fun at Villar's.
We'll meet up later.
You were right
about Ana.
That's her name.
Sorry to hear that.
Most case officers get
married three, four times.
You?
Once.
You're falling apart
over here.
Don't kill innocent people,
Matthew.
What?
Air traffic controller,
a tiny airstrip in Bermuda.
George Edwart Cox,
I remember that name.
Edwart, with a
My inside officer said he was
organizing arms shipments,
but he was just an air traffic controller.
He was just a guy.
I put a bullet
in his skull.
Black Ops came in, they replaced
him with one of their own,
and crashed a Gulf stream
in the ocean that night.
The thing was, the family
that was on the plane...
The husband,
he was a whistleblower.
The whole thing was about
stopping him from
testifying about wet works
to a congressional hearing.
Is that why you left?
No.
I went back to work the next day
like nothing ever happened.
You practice anything a long
time, you get good at it.
You tell a hundred lies a day,
it sounds like the truth.
Everyone betrays everyone.
That's a shitty excuse.
Yeah, I used to be
innocent like you.
Wrap myself up
in the flag...
I'm going to take you in.
Good for you.
Barlow.
LINKLATER ON PHONE Witnesses
identified a pair of men
fitting Weston and
Frost's description
leaving this
location together.
So, he pulled it off.
Weston is aiding and
abetting a fugitive.
You're wrong.
If he's with Frost, he's
taking him to the safe house.
That's where we got to be.
Fine. Fine.
Meet me at the crossroads
at Old Malmesbury Road.
Who are you?
You Weston?
Give me the shotgun.
What the hell is this?
Who are you?
I'm Keller.
Safe house keeper.
Authorization Index, Bravo
Four Seven Oscar Whiskey Six.
Inside. Let's go.
To the left.
Slowly.
I don't know who trained you,
man, but this sure as hell
ain't protocol.
Where's the guest room?
That's the thing, we
don't really have one.
In there. In there.
Cuff him.
To the pipe.
Out. Over there.
All right.
Control room.
Whatever you say, man
It's your rodeo.
Call it in.
Let me hear it.
Landlord.
My guest is here.
Account?
Abaresque Limited.
With a guest?
Yeah, package delivered.
Confirmed.
Pickup scheduled.
They're on the way.
Can we at least
put the gun down now?
Thanks, Clayton. Bye.
It's a microchip.
What?
That was
my guy from MI6.
Wade got his hands
on a microchip.
And what was on it?
Only Wade knew,
but I think
it's safe to assume
that's why he
hooked up with Frost.
To sell it.
Let's get moving.
Long day, huh?
I can only imagine.
Tobin Frost.
That man's a legend.
I hope you
picked up something.
You ain't going to
find a better education.
This is the most
excitement I've seen.
You're the first guest
I've had in 10 months.
But you wouldn't know
anything about that, right?
You got a city posting.
Yeah, nightlife, beaches.
Little ladies
running around everywhere.
Yeah.
I'm jealous.
You got coffee?
Yeah, it's in the cupboard.
Where?
Want me to get it?
I got it.
Why are you
in Cape Town?
Tell me now. Why?
What is it?
A dirt list,
laundry list.
Israeli Intelligence, five years
ago, compiled blackmail intel.
Corrupt agents,
German Intelligence, MI6...
CIA?
Yes.
We got to get away.
We got to get out of here.
Ah, shit.
Don't, don't, don't.
No, don't leave me here,
please.
Don't do it.
Matt?
Hey.
How you doing?
I'm proud of you.
And what you pulled off.
You're going to make
a hell of a case officer.
Where's Frost?
He's gone.
Place is a wreck.
Blood everywhere.
Was he injured or...
I guess you know
he killed Keller.
No.
I killed Keller.
Frost killed Keller.
He killed Linklater, too.
Did he talk about anything?
Anything he was after?
Anything he might
have had?
The file.
The file?
The file that you're on.
Along with a lot
of other people.
Important people.
Listen to me.
What would you do
if someone is
watching your every move?
Some maybe
you're not proud of.
And you will have some you're
not proud of, believe me.
And then tries to
use it against you?
You would do
what you have to do.
Where's the file?
Matt, the file.
Where is the file?
You're a dead man.
Yeah, a long time now.
Frost is here.
Let's go.
We got him.
A hell of a job.
You smell that?
Pinotage. It's a good grape.
Great wine.
Local grape.
Pinotage is great...
I don't want you
losing this one.
It's worth a lot
of money.
You're a good boy,
Matty.
You know what you are.
Hey.
I know what you're not.
You're better than me.
No, it's okay,
just be better than me.
You promise me.
Yeah.
Well, let's...
Let's go.
I just got to get up.
I need to get up.
Stay.
Hey...
That's exactly
as it happened.
Obviously,
this situation needs
to be handled with a
certain amount of finesse.
Has anybody else
seen this report?
No, sir. Not yet.
Matt, I'm sure this
comes as no surprise,
but parts of this report are going to
have to be altered for national security.
Which parts, sir?
Well...
David Barlow can't
be held responsible
for what happened
to the safe house.
We just don't
need the scandal.
But, sir, you and I both know
that, that is just not the truth.
People don't want
the truth anymore, Matt.
It's too messy.
Keeps them up nights.
I'll tell you what I am
willing to do, though.
I think the Agency has
grossly underestimated you,
and I'm recommending you for a
senior case officer position.
Provided you still want it.
That's a generous
offer, sir.
There's just one thing you
need to clarify for me.
Of course.
Frost may have been
carrying some vital intel.
A file.
I'm not seeing that
anywhere in this report.
What was
on the file, sir?
Something that, quite frankly,
could be very damaging
to the Agency
and to our allies.
I don't see why Frost would even
mention something like that to me.
No, I suppose he wouldn't,
would he?
You realize, though,
that if that file did leak,
what would happen
to the person responsible?
That person would
be arrested, sir.
He'd be risking
everything.
He'd have enemies in every
intelligence agency in the world.
In the eyes of the CIA he'd
be just like Tobin Frost.
Frost didn't say anything
about a file, sir.
All right, son.
Take a few days off.
We'll get you
started next week.
Thank you.
And think about our
conversation, would you?
Will do.
I'll take it
from here, sir.
...and other media outlets
received a controversial file
from an anonymous source.
The international intelligence
community is still reeling
from the release of so many
highly classified documents
and the revelations of widespread
corruption and criminal activity
at the CIA,
the BND, and MI6.
...is in
an uproar over the lack
of oversight given to
British Intelligence,
demanding accountability
of the rogue agents.
Officials at MI6
are fully cooperating.
Chancellor
Merkel insists that the BND
has already identified
the corrupt agents
and contained
the intelligence breach.
She has ensured her
international counterparts...
Indictments are
now expected within the week,
and Congress has demanded that
Deputy Director Harlan Whitford
testify before
a Senate subcommittee
in an effort to
determine how many people
at the CIA are
involved in this
and just how far up
the corruption reaches.