Welcome to Wichita
Mid-Continent Airport.
Convenient, friendly, affordable.
Fly with us.
Please note, the Kansas Clean Air Act has
designated this airport as non-smoking.
Your attention, please.
Baggage claim is located
on the east side of the terminal.
Hotel and ground transportation
information boards
and public telephones are located
opposite the baggage carousels.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please maintain visual contact
with your personal property at all times.
Please do not leave your baggage
or other items unattended.
Thank you for your cooperation.
-Excuse me.
-Sorry.
So, l'm gonna make it
onto the earlier flight, right?
Are you gonna check that?
No, l'm gonna carry it on.
lt's got valuables in it.
-Here you are.
-Thank you.
-God, excuse me.
-No, l'm sorry.
That bag is wicked heavy, anyhow.
l was looking at my phone.
l hate it when people do that.
You have a little
smudge.
What are these?
Those are two barrel carburetors
for a Pontiac Tri-Power.
Those are exhaust tips for a '74 Z-28.
l restore old cars, so.. .
Hair-dryer.
Oh, my God, l'm so sorry.
-This is getting to be a habit.
-Yeah, it is.
Sorry about that.
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
-Yeah, sure.
-Boston?
-Yeah.
Gate 12.
-Enjoy your flight, Mr. Garcia.
-Thank you.
Hi.
l'm sorry. You're not on this flight.
Well, l just checked in
for this one, like, 10 minutes ago.
That must be some sort of mistake.
l'm sorry,
the computer shows that we're booked.
Listen, Sharry.
Tomorrow my little sister's
getting married. l practically raised her.
l'm sorry, we are completely sold out.
Listen, can you help me out for a second?
She's my little sister.
She's April, l'm June,
she's counting on me
to march her down the aisle tomorrow.
That's very sweet,
but the 1 1 :50 will get you there
tomorrow morning with plenty of time.
Your boarding pass, sir?
Sometimes things happen for a reason.
-Enjoy your flight, Mr. Miller.
-Thank you.
This is the final boarding call
for US Midland Air, flight 77
non-stop service to Boston's
Logan Airport, now boarding at gate 12.
Would all passengers holding
a valid boarding pass, please proceed...
l should've seen it coming, boss.
He went on tilt, he came undone.
Coming undone in our business
means you need a margarita.
lt doesn't mean capping a dozen people
in a government lab and blowing it up.
lt doesn't mean stealing an object
of critical importance.
-Does he have the Zephyr or not?
-We believe so.
You believe so.
-Check it out.
-l don't care what you believe, Fitz.
-l need you to clean your mess up.
-Go back and play it again.
l want the Zephyr.
We'll have it in hand
by the time he lands in Boston.
Find out who and what she is.
Should l have the field office pick her up
in Wichita?
l got a better idea.
Miss Havens? We did find a seat for you.
l'd like to have your attention, please.
We apologize for the delay.
We will be departing
Wichita Airport shortly.
Thanks for your patience.
l know it's policy or whatever
and it's just your job,
-but it's kind of lame.
-Again, l apologize.
Fitz. What did you do?
lt's no wonder these airlines
are going out of business.
We have been cleared onto the runway.
There's nobody on the plane.
The captain has turned on
the ''fasten seatbelt'' sign.
Please remain seated
until the sign has been turned off
and it's safe to move about the cabin.
l'm June, by the way.
l'm Roy Miller.
-Nice to meet you.
-lt's very nice to meet you.
Tequila on the rocks?
Yeah. Just in time, thanks.
So, your sister's
getting married tomorrow?
-Excuse me?
-Your sister.
She's getting married tomorrow.
Congratulations.
Yeah, thanks.
You know, Roy, l'm a bad liar.
l'm sorry, how's that?
April is getting married,
but not till Saturday.
You had me fooled.
Well, l do have a fitting tomorrow.
So, l do, actually, have to go home.
l hope this isn't gonna be a rough flight.
lt might be.
Wichita is a long way to go
for a carburetor.
lt's not just any carburetor.
lt's a triple deuce.
l'm restoring a '66 GTO.
And Kansas has the best scrap.
Really?
My dad had a garage,
and when l was a kid,
he bought this chassis.
He used to take us to yards,
and search for parts, you know?
He died in '98,
and now that April's getting married,
l just figured, why not finish it up,
give it to her sort of as a wedding present?
Kind of like a present
from our dad, too, you know?
That's nice.
-Yeah.
l used to think that
someday, when the last part went in,
l would just climb into that GTO
and start it up.
Just drive and drive and drive,
and just keep driving
until l got to the tip of South America.
-Cape Horn.
-Yeah.
-There's beautiful islands down there.
-Yeah?
Pirate islands.
Yeah, ''someday."
That's a dangerous word.
Dangerous?
lt's really just code for ''never."
l think a lot about things l haven't done.
Dive in the Great Barrier Reef.
Ride the Orient Express.
Live on the Amalfi Coast with nothing
but a motorcycle and a backpack.
Kiss a stranger on the balcony
of the Hotel Du Cap.
Where is that?
South of France.
What about you? What's your list?
Well, yours sounds pretty good.
Wow.
Thanks.
lt's no problem.
l'll just put this up here, if that's all right.
You know what?
l'm gonna go back and use the restroom.
-l'll help you.
-Thanks.
Lots of turbulence, huh?
-l'll be out in a minute.
-Sure
''Kiss a stranger on the balcony
of the Hotel Du Cap''?
l mean, what kind of a line is that?
l mean, it's, like, a really good line.
Ma'am? Ma'am?
Did you see his hands, by any chance?
They just, like, snatched that bag
right out of the air.
Lightning-fast reflexes.
Not cool.
Okay.
This will help.
Enough. lt's over, Roy.
Yeah, l agree. Enough.
Where's the Zephyr?
Why is the girl on the plane? Tell me.
Why did Fitz put her on the plane?
Don't move, Miller.
So what are you gonna do?
What are you gonna do?
You're just gonna
let this opportunity pass you by?
No, of course you're not.
You're gonna walk right through that door,
you're gonna get it right.
lt's not your first rodeo, woman.
Hey.
l decided to join you.
l'm sorry. l.. .
-No, no, don't.. . lt's great.
-l'm sorry.
lt's just, like, the tequila and the altitude
and everything.
There's something l've gotta tell you.
What? Oh, my God,
you're in a relationship. l'm so sorry.
No, no, no. That's not it.
Okay, l'm all ears. What is it?
Are we landing?
No, not yet.
No?
Listen, there's no need to panic. l have
contained the situation.
Situation?
Yeah. We've lost the pilots.
-Where did they go?
-l mean, they're dead.
-The pilots are dead.
-Shot. lt's.. .
Shot?
By who?
Well, me.
Actually, l shot the first pilot.
He shot the second pilot accidentally.
lt's just
one of those things.
Seriously, this is great!
Really, l'm relieved
you are taking this so well.
Where are you going?
l'm just gonna go check on things
and think about landing.
Would you mind
putting your seatbelt on for me?
-That would be great.
-Yeah.
This is weird.
Mayday. Mayday.
This is US Midland Air 77 heavy.
What's happening?
Everybody's dead out there!
Come on in. Sit down.
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
-Everybody's dead in here.
-l'm declaring an emergency.
-Oh, my God! Are we going down?
-l'm sorry?
Are we going down?
No, June, it's just a rapid descent.
Please, sit down.
Please state your emergency, Midland 77.
l'm sorry,
l think l've heard enough of this guy.
Are you a pilot? Who are you?
The shoulder straps.
You can put those over,
and it clicks in right down there.
You wanna click it right there, that's it.
Okay, l got it, l got it. Okay.. .
Gear down, showdown.
Why can't we just land in an airport?
No, no, that wouldn't be a good idea.
-They'll be waiting for us.
-What do you mean? Waiting for us?
-Who?
-l think the less you know, the better.
What?
Okay, we're gonna touch down here.
Oh, God. Oh, my God!
-That's a truck. That's a truck!
-Yeah.
-That's a truck!
-Yup.
That's a truck!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
-That's a curve. That's a curve!
-l see it. l see it.
Oh, my God!
Oh, God!
Okay, this is good.
What's good?
Take a sip of that.
lt'll take the edge off.
-Are you shot?
-Yeah, how about that?
lt's just a scrape. That's good news.
June, we have to
discuss what's gonna happen next.
You need to go to the hospital.
Prison, maybe?
Some people are gonna come
looking for you now. Bad people.
You know, l feel a little weird.
Yeah, that'll pass once you fall asleep,
which should be in a couple of minutes.
-What?
-l need you to listen, June.
Did you drug me?
Yes.
-You drugged me.
-Yeah, it's for your own good.
Now, look. These bad people
who are going to come and see you,
they're gonna ask you about me. Okay?
And you need to tell them
you don't know me.
-June? June?
-Okay.
You need to tell them
you don't remember anything.
And you need to avoid getting in
any vehicle with them at all costs.
Okay, who are ''them''?
Well, they're serious people, June.
They'll probably identify themselves
as federal agents, and they'll DlP you.
Dip me? ln what?
Dis-lnformation Protocol.
They'll tell you a story about me.
About how l'm mentally unstable,
paranoid.
How l'm violent and dangerous,
and it'll all sound very convincing.
l'm already convinced.
There's a few common DlP keywords
to listen for.
Reassuring words.
Words like, ''stabilize,'' ''secure,'' ''safe."
lf they say these words,
particularly with repetition.. .
Okay.
...it means they're going to kill you.
Oh, God!
Or intern you somewhere offshore
for a very long time.
-Okay?
-Okay.
Now, stay with me.
lf they tell you you're safe.. .
lf they tell me l'm safe,
they're gonna kill me.
-Don't get in what?
-Vehicles.
-Any vehicles.
-Okay, any vehicles.
-Just run.
-l'll run.
-Run.
And if they ask you about me.. .
l don't know you. l don't know you at all.
Who are you, Roy?
...a mixing of rain and snow,
good for ski country, but probably...
-Thanks, Andrea.
-You're welcome.
Now, back to our top news story
of the morning.
Here's Bradley Moss,
with an on-the-scene report.
According to FAA sources,
at approximately 7.:30 last night,
all contact was lost with a
Boston-bound commuter jet from Wichita.
The plane was apparently passing through
an area of turbulence
and may have met up with wind shear
or a lightning storm
causing an electrical failure.
Now, this is all conjecture at this point,
as all that's left is a crater
in an lndiana cornfield.
Coming!
Rodney?
Thank God.
l wanted to make sure you were okay.
Yeah, why?
You were on that flight from Kansas, right?
-Yeah.
-l saw on the news about the crash.
What news? What crash?
-Anyway, you're alive.
-l'm alive, yeah.
Sure, that's cool.
Hey, but, June, you know.. .
l told myself that if l found you alive,
that l was gonna ask you to dinner.
How about l call you later, okay?
lt's just another day.
lt's just a normal day. Okay.
She's moving.
Wow!
And gotta love the boots.
Yeah, you know.
l promise l'll wear heels on the day.
-Hey. Can l talk to you for a second?
-Yeah.
So, this weekend,
l was thinking about Dad's GTO.
-Really?
-Yeah, it's just sitting there.
And l was wondering how you would feel
about maybe selling it.
You wanna sell Dad's GTO?
Ben and l, we really want our own place.
Excuse me?
Excuse me. Anyone here belong
to that blue truck parked outside?
-Yeah, why?
-You're about to get a ticket.
-Thought l put enough quarters in there.
-Yeah.
l hate getting tickets.
Excuse me.
Please step inside, miss.
Let me just go grab a few things.
Miss Havens, good afternoon.
Special Agent-in-Charge, Fitzgerald.
Will you join us inside the car
for a moment?
We know you were on the flight
with him last night.
The one that crashed.
Who are you again?
FBl. You do know Mr. Miller.
No, l don't.
Well, we chatted a little bit
before security, but.. .
l see. And once you were on the flight,
what happened then? More chatting?
-ls this funny to you?
-No.
He's dangerous, Miss Havens,
and out of control.
He said that you'd say he was crazy.
So, you did talk to him.
And about me, no less.
No. No, not you, specifically.
About whom, then?
Simon Feck?
l don't know who that is.
Look, this is getting really twisted around,
and l think l should probably call a lawyer.
We're gonna take you to a secure location,
Miss Havens, until Miller is contained.
Someplace safe.
-With you?
-Yes, ma'am.
You wanna tell me where we're going?
-Fellas?
-Don't worry, miss, you're safe.
Excuse me?
You're safe with us.
l wanna know where we're going.
Just a shortcut
till the situation is stabilized.
We'll keep you safe.
You said that already.
Because l meant it.
What is Jackson doing?
Shooter! Shooter! Evade! Evade!
Shooter on the freeway.
The dot's on your back!
Follow me, now!
Are you insane?
l'm not going out that door!
Oh, my God!
Get your foot off.. .
-Oh, my God!
-Hey, June!
-l can't see!
-You are doing great.
-l can't see! Get out of the way!
-Open the door.
-l can't get his foot off the gas.
-Open the door, June.
Open the door, June.
That's a beautiful dress, by the way.
One second.
Oh, my God!
l totally know what you're talking about.
lt's so boring, l can't even stand it. Totally.
Thank you.
Who are you?
Oh, God!
What are you doing?
-Hi, June.
-Move out of the way, l can't see!
Please unlock the door, June.
Unlock the door. That way, l can help you.
-l can't let go!
-You need to let go, June.
-June, door!
-Got it!
Just pull over! Oh, my God!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Yup, come over here.
Right over here.
Just stay down, you're doing good.
Here, hold this. Well, well, well.
Check this out.
Nice.
These guys are loaded for bear.
You're doing well, June.
Excellent driving.
Over a dead guy, no less.
You're a natural.
That's a beautiful dress.
ls that for April's wedding?
-Saturday?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, that will be nice.
Please, stop shooting people, okay?
-Just stop shooting people.
-l understand.
You're in shock.
How about you stay here
while l go have a word
with the guys in the tunnel.
-Okay?
-Okay.
Actually, l'm just gonna go shoot them.
l'll be right back.
By the way,
your timing when you opened that door.. .
-Okay.
-.. was sublime.
You saved us, l hope you know that.
-You saved us.
-Okay.
Hey! Hey!
Oh, shoot.
Hey, wait!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Oh, no.
Excuse me, sorry.
There you are.
June?
-Rodney?
-He's in the gym. Over there.
-Hey!
What are you doing here?
Whoa ! That's a.. .
Hey, guys, say hello to June.
-That's a dress.
-Thanks.
-Everything all right?
-Yeah.
No, it's.. .
lt's complicated.
You know what?
l've been feeling the same way.
You wanna talk?
Maybe over some pie?
My point is.. .
My point is,
that plane crash made me think
about our break-up.
You know, this bulb went off, bing!
''Rodney, why are you giving up?
You're being passive."
''Getting back at her
because she didn't want the ring."
''So June didn't want
to be engaged right now,
''and that freaks your mom out. Big deal!
''What about all the things you
and June wanted to do together, huh?''
Our list, you know?
Like camping in Vermont with my brother
and Sheila in their new Winnie.
Tickets to Blue Man Group,
the battlegrounds tour.
l wanna talk about the plane crash. Okay?
Sure, what about it?
l was on it. l mean, in it.
l mean, l was in it.
So you were in the plane crash?
l wasn't supposed to be on that plane,
but l was on it,
and there was this guy who was some sort
of secret agent or something, and he.. .
He killed everybody on board.
And then he landed the plane.
Next thing you know,
l wake up, l'm in my room.
l have no idea how l got there.
He must've drugged me or something.
Then l go to April's fitting,
because l have to wear
this ridiculous dress.
These other guys, these other agents
come, they snatch me up.
Next thing you know,
l'm in Grand Theft Auto on the l-93.
-Why are you touching my hand?
-Because l'm here for you.
-Jeez, you are so stressed out!
-Well, yeah!
-And l get it.
-Really?
l completely understand. l mean.. .
-Wow, June.
-l know.
-Your little sister's getting married.. .
-lt's like.. .
-.. and that is stressful.
-What are you talking about, Rodney?
You didn't even listen
to what l was talking about.
No, l did. Look, l would probably be
the same way in that situation.
What can l do to help? Setting up?
We can bring the guys over.. .
No, no, no. Okay.
Oh, Christ.
Hi, June. Look, l.. .
l'm sorry if l'm interrupting anything, but.. .
l'm Roy Miller.
Rodney Burris.
Rodney, hi. How are you?
We're running out of time,
and maybe l didn't make it clear enough,
but we're gonna have to stick together
for a little bit, because of our.. .
You know, our situation.
ln case you didn't notice,
Rodney is a fireman, okay?
So he's perfectly capable of handling
any situation that comes up.
Thank you very much,
you can leave us alone.
l have no doubt.
Ever since l was a little kid,
l have great respect for firemen.
-l appreciate it.
-Fact of the matter is,
-l don't think you guys get paid enough.
-Yeah, we don't.
You're in Engine 10.
Yeah, Engine 10.
Yeah. Have you taken
your lieutenant's exam yet?
-l'm working on it.
-Yeah? How's that going?
lt's a bitch.
Did you ever do a tour in that hall,
what is it?
Grove Hall, that's where the action is.
lt's the fastest way up the ladder.
-Rodney!
-House of Flames!
l often thought l.. .
l should have been a fireman.
Rodney, this is the guy.
What?
-This is the guy.
-What? ''This is the guy''?
l'm sorry, who are you?
l'm the guy?
-l'm the guy. This is the guy.
-This is the guy.
-l'm a guy.
-l'm the guy.
-You are a guy.
-l'm a guy.
-He's the guy! He's the guy!
-Rodney, whatever happens.. .
-God.
-Please, for your own safety.. .
-Rodney, whatever happens,
-you should know.. .
-.. .please stay in the booth.
What are you talking about?
Wait!
Everybody! Everybody get down.
Get down, down, down! Everybody down.
Rodney, get down,
or l will blow her head off.
l'll blow her head off.
What did l say?
Rodney, what did l say?
-Just calm down, buddy.
-Answer!
Sorry, l thought you were making a move.
Sorry. lt's all right,
l thought he was making a move.
Making a little pie.
Pies for everybody. Everybody.
Everybody gets pies, okay?
No ice-cream, à la mode.
Weakens the legs, people. Lincoln knew it.
lt's why they got to him.
No one follows us,
or l kill myself and then her.
-Get in the car. Please.
-No.
Watch your head.
We're at 560 Harris.
They're getting into a blue Volvo.
-Rodney! Rodney!
-Rodney?
Oh, my God! Rodney!
lt's okay. Look at me.
-Okay. Look at me, it's okay.
-Shit!
l shot you through and through. No bone,
nowhere near the femoral artery, okay?
All right?
This is gonna be better for you
than Grove Hall. lt's all good.
Okay? You good?
-Good?
-Good.
Good?
There were four security cameras
in that restaurant, June.
Now there is proof you're my hostage.
So we've cleared your name,
with the locals, at least.
You know? lt's a start.
Something to build on.
-You shot Rodney!
-Yeah, l did.
But l asked him to stay in the booth.
You shot Rodney!
lt might be the best thing
that ever happened to him.
Yeah, right, because we all should
get shot every now and then!
Rodney.. . Rodney is a good guy, June.
But not really right for you.
l mean, you know, in my opinion.
But a good guy.
Took a bullet, he's gonna be a hero.
Probably get a promotion.
-Stop the car. Stop the car.
-What?
Stop the car. Stop the car.
Stop the car. Just stop the car!
June, l understand
you want off the carousel.
l do, l wanna get off the carousel.
Please, Roy.
Can you stop the car, please? Right now!
l'm not one of those
''l told you so'' kind of guys,
but l did warn you
to stay off the plane last night.
When?
Well, when l said,
''Sometimes things happen for a reason."
That's not a warning.
That's not a warning, Roy!
That's like a needlepoint expression
or a bumper sticker.
Next time, try, ''June, if you get
on this plane, you will fucking die! ''
You know, Roy, maybe they meant it
when they said that l would be safe.
-You really mean that, June?
-Yeah!
-Did you feel safe with them?
-Safer than l do now!
Okay, okay. All right.
Just so you understand,
right now, out there, on your own,
your life expectancy is like here.
With me, it's here. Without me, here.
With me, without me.
So.. .
l wouldn't advise going home.
But, you know, it's up to you.
So right now l need another car,
keep moving.
Someone else is depending on me.
Someone whose life is in danger.
Someone who trusts me.
Every second l waste chasing you,
l'm letting him down.
Rodney, why did you make this brave call
to leap into action?
Well, l didn't think.
l just did what any man would do
in that situation, you know?
-l leapt into action.
-Thanks.
-Like you said, it's really the job.
-You should be so proud.
-Thanks.
-Good job.
lt really didn't even hurt.
lt was kind of like a bee sting.
What a brave firefighter.
The doctors tell me Rodney is going
to be okay, just a flesh wound.
A true blue Boston hero. Back to you, Don.
This is what it's all about.
That, right there,
is what everybody wants.
A Burger King toy?
Open it up.
lt's warm. What is it?
A battery.
A battery?
lt's code-named Zephyr.
Not your average Duracell.
lt's high output. Never runs out.
What do you mean, ''never''?
That little thing there is the first
perpetual energy source since the sun.
So, what, your flashlight
never runs out of juice?
lt can power a lot more
than a flashlight, June.
Really? How much more?
Small city.
Large submarine.
lt's big.
The guy who invented it
is barely out of high school.
Simon Feck.
l was assigned with another agent to
watch him at a facility, a lab in Wichita.
And the other guy, the agent, is the guy
who picked you up this morning.
Fitzgerald.
A couple of weeks ago, l found out
he was going to sell the battery
and kill Simon.
So l got Simon out of there,
put him someplace safe
and went back for the battery.
And Fitz set me up.
Made it look like l went rogue.
That's when l met you.
So.. .
So, what's next? l mean, what's the plan?
l think we get some rest,
pick up Simon, and get you back
for your sister's wedding.
l'm pretty good at what l do, June.
And tonight, we're safe.
Scout's honor.
Safe and secure?
Good night, Roy.
Were you really a Boy Scout?
Eagle Scout.
l was a Brownie.
That's cool.
Good night, Roy.
Pies for everybody. Everybody.
Everybody gets pies, okay?
No ice-cream...
So, what do you think?
Are we looking at another player?
We're looking at a pawn.
l talked to her, so did he.
She owns a garage, no passport,
gone nowhere, been nowhere.
She's a nobody.
You've been two steps behind
since this began, Fitz.
Are you sure someone
is not taking you to school?
Clean this shit up.
This is a safe-house?
Simon!
Simon?
Stay close.
Hey, Simon, this is no time to play.
What is all this?
Simon. lt's what he does.
l'm late, and he's gone.
Simon.
''Made in Austria."
Who are these people?
Are they Fitzgerald's guys?
No, it's other guys.
Other bad guys?
Worse guys. Hold my mags.
Worse guys?
Now, l need you to listen carefully.
Do exactly as l say.
On three, l'm gonna lay down cover,
then we're gonna run
to those shelves over there.
Okay.
-Okay?
-Yeah.
-You ready?
One.. .
Oh, my God!
Sorry. l panicked.
-What number would you like?
-Let's just stick with three, it's good.
Okay. One.. . Two.. .
Three.
These guys are fancy. Mags.
Could be Antonio Quintana's men.
He's a Spanish arms dealer.
He also wants the battery.
Ready?
-Let's move.
-Okay.
June. June!
How the hell are we gonna get out of here?
And where the hell is Simon?
l don't know yet, but he left a message.
-A message?
-Wait.
What l need you to do right now
is wait here.
-What?
-Yeah. l'm gonna find us a way out.
-l can't wait here!
-l'll be right back.
Wait! Roy!
Just take this.
Roy?
Shit.
June?
June! June! June! June!
June!
Please stop saying my name.
You keep saying my name,
it's freaking me out.
-Okay. l understand.
-Okay.
-Drink this.
-What is it?
Brotine-zero.
They're gonna smoke us with D-5.
Oh, yeah.
Where's yours?
Oh, shit.
-l'm sorry.
-Oh, no.
They're coming.
June.
l know this looks bad,
but we'll be out of here
in a couple of minutes.
l got this.
We gotta go, June. Here, l'll help you.
We've been hit!
But it's okay!
We get through this, we're home free!
Ready, set, go!
We're almost there.
Hey, there, sleepy head.
How long have l been out?
Eighteen hours.
Where am l?
My place.
We're off-grid.
No one's ever found me here.
Shame we can't stay longer.
We got a rendezvous with Simon.
He's fine. l figured out his code.
He's crazy about trains.
He used the passport l gave him
and went to Austria.
You drugged me again, Roy.
Yeah.
You can't do that.
Well, you weren't coping well.
l'm not sure, if you were awake,
if they would've even let you live.
What am l wearing?
A bikini. We're in the tropics.
How did l get in the bikini?
June, l've been trained
to dismantle a bomb in the pitch black
with nothing but a safety pin
and a Junior Mint.
l think l can get you in and out
of some clothes without
looking.
l'm not saying that's what l did, but.. .
Okay. Sorry. Reflex.
l deserved that. Hit me again.
l won't stop you.
June.
June?
June!
...paper clips and Junior Mints.. .
''Not that l'm saying that's what l did."
Shit!
ls this his phone?
Movement alert.
Amapola.
That's a '67 Grand Prix.
l thought we were off the grid.
April.
April?
April! l know! No, l'm okay!
Listen, April.. . April? April?
April, can you hear me? April!
April, can you.. .
l know! No, l'm okay!
Listen, April... April?
April, can you hear me? April!
We don't know, Antonio.
We traced her phone to the Azores.
We're in range now.
Get to them before the agency.
Perfect timing. Lunch is ready.
You must be thirsty.
lt's coconut. lt's loaded with electrolytes.
Just.. . Whoa. Okay?
Okay. Just.. . Whoa.
Yeah?
Yeah!
Hey. You got skills.
-My dad wanted boys.
-Yeah?
-Let me go.
-You can get out anytime you want.
l'll show you.
Hands like Houdini.
Turn your palms down,
and all at once,
throw your hands to the ground
and your hips back.
Nice.
That was good.
Who are you?
Really.
l don't understand.
Follow me.
l don't understand. l came in clean.
My phone is secure. lt's secure.
Unless you made a call.
-And you didn't make a call.
-No, l didn't make a call.
l took a call.
You took a call?
lt was a quick one.
You.. .
Come on.
l thought we were off the grid,
-and then the phone rang.
-lt's okay.
lt was my sister and l had to take the call.
-You know? l didn't want her to worry.
-Watch your step.
No, no, no.. .
l can't get into that.
l just can't get into that thing.
-June.
-Roy.. .
Just, please, knock me out.
Use broton-seven or whatever.
-lt's okay.
-You're grabbing my neck.
You asked me not to drug you.
Okay, good.
Hands like Houdini. Hands.. .
Roy?
-l can't feel my face!
-Okay, time.
Okay, Simon.. .
Roy, the pull on this thing.. .
-We said 10 minutes.
-The traction on this thing.
-lt can pull up to 50,000 metric tons!
-l get it.
lt's a diesel hydraulic!
Don't you wanna see your Zephyr?
Yes.
-Excuse me.
-Guten Morgen, miss.
Can you tell me where we are?
Right now, miss? We are in Austria.
Austria, huh?
Would you like some breakfast, miss?
Yeah, that would be great. Thanks.
Okay, l'm gonna have some pancakes,
scrambled eggs.. .
-Scrambled eggs.
-.. and.. .
With a glass of milk.
And a glass of milk.
-Can l get a Harvey Wallbanger, please?
-Certainly, sir.
You know, statistically, you're a lot
more likely to die riding on a train
than any other form of transportation.
10.3 times more likely
than dying on a plane.
Simon?
Simon Feck?
Yes.
My name is June.
l'm a friend of Roy Miller's.
Have you found him yet?
Have you seen him?
No, not yet.
-Don't you wanna answer that?
-Yeah.
But l can't.
l'm not supposed to.
lt might be Roy.
Yeah, but he told me not to answer the
phone, because the signal can be tracked.
That's right. Of course.
Did Roy happen to tell you
about the plan here?
Are we supposed to meet him here, or.. .
What did you say that drink was?
-A Harvey.. .
-lt's a Harvey Wallbanger.
Do you mind just
ordering me one of those?
Because it looks great.
l'll just be right back.
You just stay here for a second.
l'll be right back.
Something is wrong.
lt's getting hotter, Roy.
She didn't answer her phone.
-l told her not to. That's.. .
-We just got here.
-That's good news.
-l'm sure she'll turn up. Roy.. .
-l left a note posted right there.
-We may have an issue here.
-The temperature.. .
-She's hungry.. . She's hungry.
lt's getting too hot.
We need to cool it down.
Yeah, she went to get something to eat.
Good. Come on, Simon.
-May l help you?
-Yeah.
l'm feeling a little bit train-sick.
ls it okay if l hang out here for a while?
Of course, l will get you some water.
Here you go.
Antonio Quintana wants to know
where is the battery?
Where is the battery?
l'm sorry, l'm looking for ice.
-Roy.
-Bernhard.
Miller.
-Wrong room.
-lt's okay. lt's okay.
-You know him?
-Yeah.
He's an assassin, platinum grade.
He's come to collect Simon.
Oh, my God.
-And to kill you.
-That's Simon?
-Yeah, June, Simon. Simon, June.
-Hi.
Jeez! l'm okay. l got this.
Simon, please move.
You have quite some balls, Fraulein.
Hands like Houdini.
l'm so sorry.
But you were trying to kill me.
That's disgusting.
Oh, my God. Just die!
Oh, shit.
l got to get you guys someplace safe.
-They're not on the train.
-Oh, really?
Cameras at the last station show nothing.
They must have gotten off
between stops.
Locals haven't found anything.
Always the classics, Roy.
Salzburg, Austria. Very nice.
Yes.
No, we just got in.
Well, we're talking now. No, l understand.
Well, it's good to hear your voice,
too, Naomi.
l'll meet you at the caprice.
As soon as you can be there.
lt's a beautiful city, huh?
Yeah.
Never seen anything quite like it.
Neither have l.
l got to go out for a bit.
Okay.
l was thinking about ordering
some room service.
And l thought maybe we could
have dinner or something.
That sounds great.
9:00?
9:00 sounds great.
June?
Could you do me a favor
and just stick around here? lt's better.
Oh, yeah, of course.
Where else am l gonna go?
See you in a bit.
They're not gonna hurt you.
You're too valuable to them.
Now, just breathe, listen to your music.
Here, as a matter of fact,
l got that for you.
l know you like them.
Cool, thanks.
Listen, order as much room service
as you like, but don't leave the room.
Okay.
-We need to talk about the Zephyr later.
-And we will.
You seem different.
Do l?
So, who's your companion?
She's beautiful. The blonde.
She seems capable.
l just met her.
She's a nobody.
Just someone l picked up along the way.
That's a shame.
This is getting boring.
Are we gonna do a deal or not?
Don't speak to me like that.
l will speak to you any way l please, Tony.
We both know you're lucky l'm here.
l have the battery. l'm on a schedule.
The world is full of bad guys
and people are calling.
l understand.
What's your price?
l have a figure in mind.
What's it worth to you?
Are you angry about your island, Roy?
Tick, tick, tick, tick, tick, Tony.
l'm lsabel George, Director
of Counter Espionage at the ClA.
l'm sure you are.
Forgive me, l just.. .
l just don't know exactly what to believe.
Well, that's understandable,
considering that the last five days
you've been fed a steady diet
of misinformation and fantasy
by an agent of ours
who's recently gone rogue.
Well, he said that Fitzgerald was the
one that wanted to steal the battery.
Well, let's examine the facts.
Miller told you that he was protecting the
Zephyr from people wanting to misuse it.
But now he's trying to sell it
to an international arms dealer.
Antonio Quintana.
One of Europe's leading
weapons manufacturers.
Ask yourself, Miss Havens,
has Roy Miller said anything to you
that's proven to be true?
-God, excuse me.
-No, l'm sorry.
Sorry, l was looking at my phone.
l hate it when people do that.
Oh, my God, l'm so sorry.
-This is getting to be a habit.
-Yeah, it is.
He used you as a mule to carry the battery
through security, Miss Havens.
He's been playing you.
He's a spy, that's what he does.
He lies for a living.
Any love, empathy,
we train that right out of them.
What did you imagine?
The two of you would move
into a condo together, get a dog?
You can't have a life with him.
That's fantasy.
But you can have yours back.
She's been gone eight minutes.
We need you to get back to the hotel
before Miller.
-What am l supposed to do?
-All right, then.
This pen is a transmitter.
Once you have confirmation
that Miller has not hidden the Zephyr,
that it's somewhere nearby,
or on his person,
you can confirm this
by simply clicking the top button.
l'm sorry l'm late.
Everything go okay?
Well enough.
lt's getting hotter.
So, did you get your price?
l followed you tonight.
You have nothing to say?
Here's to Wichita
where we first.. .
Bumped into each other.
Do you think that was fate, Roy?
l don't believe in fate.
But l believe in luck.
l don't know what to believe.
That hurt more than l thought it would.
l'm going home.
They promised that if you turned
yourself in, they'd protect you.
l love your optimism.
Never lose it.
Get her out of here.
He's not here, sir.
Did they tell you you're going home?
You've seen the inside
of the honeycomb, June!
You can't go home.
The suspect is on the roof.
Oh, shit.
Director George!
Get her in the car.
He's heading toward the river.
Stand down! He has the battery!
Hey! Hey! Hold it!
Hold your fire!
Stand down!
He has the battery!
Did you secure the kid?
Yeah.
Did they find Roy?
We'll find the body. We have to.
He went down with the Zephyr.
Thank you, guys.
Fitz?
Fitz, l think we just made a wrong turn.
Ramstein is that way, west.
l think we're going south.
You know what? You're right.
Tell him we're back on track.
l don't have the battery,
but no one's gonna get it now.
Yeah, l've got the next best thing.
l'll see you in Spain in two days.
Hey, Wilmer.
-How was the party?
-lt was nice.
-l see the goat is still out there.
-Yeah.
l thought it was a wedding present.
lt was, but,
l think l wanted her to want it
more than she wanted it.
Okay.
...Boston's classic rock station.
Here are the Kingsmen.
This just come in?
G-body Grand Prix.
Longest hood in history.
Gonna be a real beaut.
Ru-pa.. . Fee-pa.. . No, it's.. .
5826 Amapola.
That's like an hour from here.
Maybe it's a safe-house.
Here we go.
Shit!
Who's out there?
l'm not afraid to use this.
Oh, Frank, look at her!
l want to know what she's doing
on my lawn in the middle of the night.
l.. . l have the pistons you ordered.
Pistons?
For the '67 Grand Prix.
Molly, l didn't.. .
You are all wet. Please, come inside.
That Pontiac you have out there, Frank,
is a real classic.
l really love pre-'70s Grand Prixs.
So, you two lived here long?
This old place?
lt's been our home for 40 years.
Sit down, honey. Have a cookie.
Frank thinks we should move,
but you know what? l am comfortable.
And we can afford to stay,
thanks to Publishers Clearing House.
You won Publishers Clearing House?
-Twice.
-Plus, we won two lotto quick picks
-Frank doesn't even remember buying.
-Because l didn't buy them.
Oh, yeah, like you didn't order pistons
off the lnternet.
You don't know what you're typing
into that computer, Frank.
Another couple of minutes
on your clothes, honey.
So,
Roy Miller.
This was one of his safe-houses,
wasn't it?
What in the hell are you talking about?
Honey, what's this all about?
l'm sorry, l just thought, maybe.. .
l must've had this all wrong.
l was just looking for some information
about my friend, Roy.
lf you'd like to change,
there's a powder room right there.
That's our son, Matthew.
We lost him in Kuwait.
There was a chopper crash.
He saved the lives
of two of his crewmen, and.. .
He just always took care of everyone.
He was an Eagle Scout.
This was taken the day
he got that swimming badge.
He could swim clear across Lake Sunapee
with practically one breath.
l just.. .
l've been terribly rude.
l'm June Havens.
Molly Knight.
This is June Havens, and l'm leaving
a message on my own machine
for whoever is listening to this phone call.
l have the Zephyr.
l have the Zephyr,
and l'm ready to make a deal.
l'm sitting on Route 28,
right outside New Hampshire.
And if you want the Zephyr,
you better come and get it.
Hey, fellas.
So,
you want the Zephyr?
l got the Zephyr. lt's right here.
Come and get it.
Come on. Let's go!
Welcome to España.
Today is the festival of San Fermin.
Have you ever seen a bullfight,
Miss Havens?
My name is Antonio Quintana.
l know who you are.
What did he give me?
lt's something we're developing
at my company.
A new kind of truth serum.
Really?
l have a few questions for you
about the battery,
since we both know
what you gave to my men was a joke.
l don't like you very much.
The truth!
Good!
You know, l really like Miller, though.
'Cause, you know, l was totally wrong
about him in Salzburg.
He wanted me to hear that phone call
so that l would follow him.
l'd turn him in,
and then he could get me home safely.
He was trying to protect me.
Shut up.
lt's crazy that l could feel
so powerful and capable around him.. .
-Shut up.
-.. and yet he takes care of me.
Shut up! Where is the battery?
Where is it?
l bet you've never made a girl
an omelet, have you, Antonio?
Don't test me, June.
Or got her to her sister's wedding
on time.
lt's really the little things, honestly.
-But they count so much.
-Enough!
Okay!
Miller is dead!
Roy Miller is dead, he's out.
No.
No, he's not. He can hold his breath
for a really long time.
He is dead!
l'm not gonna ask you again. But if
you don't tell me what l need to know,
-you're gonna die!
-l don't know where the battery is.
Then why did you tell everyone
you had it? Why?
Because l was trying to find Roy.
Well, Antonio, whenever there's bad guys
like you around, Roy's not too far away.
You're gonna die.
Finally!
Nice to meet you, John.
Antonio.
Too bad you couldn't get the battery.
Where is the boy?
You didn't think
l'd just bring the package, did you?
Come on.
Why don't you follow me down
to the river and bring the money?
Okay.
ls this thatching in here? Because l've
never seen anything like that before.
We have really old architecture
in Boston, but nothing like this.
You're really lucky, because this place is.. .
Let me tell you.
You're really lucky, it's beautiful here.
My thoughts are so clear.
ls this all weapons money,
or is this family money?
Gardens! He likes gardens, huh?
Do you guys ever do any gardening?
lt's really relaxing.
lt's amazing how much you can just.. .
This really is a happy place.
Look at these trumpet flowers. They.. .
Okay, Eduardo,
you don't have to pull me around.
You can just tell me
where you want me to go, okay?
-This way, blondie.
-See? Now we're communicating.
l bet you're taking me someplace
safe and secure.
Someplace special.
Antonio's special place.
Antonio has a special place?
That's so nice.
Everyone should have a special place.
-Luis?
-ls there a problem, Eduardo?
-Hi, Roy.
-Hi, June. You're supposed to be home.
-You're supposed to be dead.
-l can explain.
-You don't have to.
-l came here to get Simon.
-l just, you know, caught up with him.
-That's cool.
His name is Eduardo. Eduardo.
l need you to listen,
because when you wake up,
you're gonna call your boss
and you're gonna tell him
that Roy Miller, that's me,
has the battery and escaped with the girl.
-You have the battery?
-Yeah.
You tell him l'm coming for him.
-Yes.
-Okay.
Let's go.
l'm worried about Simon.
l haven't seen him.
My tracker has been spotty.
Life with you is so exciting.
You excite me, Miller.
l took too long to get here.
-7:00.
-What?
7:00.
l think l feel like having sex.
l think we'd have really great sex.
Did they give you something?
You should hydrate.
Roy?
Roy.
June.
June?
You don't seem
very happy to see me, Roy.
What?
Not really.
l am happy.
-So the red dot is us?
-No, we're yellow.
The red dot is Simon.
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
-Air time.
-Air time?
He says his name is Roy Miller.
He says he has the battery.
Miller is here.
There he is!
This way. Follow me!
Bulls?
-There's Fitz!
-l see him.
-Take the guns.
-Okay.
Here.
-What next?
-Let them have it.
June Havens, you've got skills.
Let's go!
Go.
-See you down there.
-Are you sure?
No.
Sorry.
-Get up.
-Okay.
Freeze right there, Roy!
Hey, Simon.
Get down on your knees, now!
-Roy!
-Now! Now!
Put them in the water. ln the water.
l just want the kid, Fitz.
Okay.
Well, l hope you brought what l want,
otherwise l'm gonna have to kill him.
And l swear to you, l'll do it.
l believe you. Just like Wichita.
-l understand.
-Okay.
l'm just gonna get the battery.
-lt's right here.
-Don't give it to him, Roy.
Please don't give it to him. No, no.
Roy, Roy, please don't give it to him.
Put it on the deck.
-Roy, Roy, please don't give it to him !
-Easy, easy.
Simon, it's okay.
Roy, don't give it to him !
-Shut it! Stop it! Shut it!
-Roy!
Okay. Okay, l'll make another one.
-You don't understand.
-Simon, don't talk.
-l'll just make another one.
-Make another one?
Am l dying?
No, you fainted.
-l'm sorry.
-No, that's okay.
No, no. l've been trying to tell you.. .
Why is it hot?
Because it's filled with power.
The battery.. . l messed up.
lt's deteriorating.
l know. lt's unstable.
You're a smart guy, Simon.
l know you'll figure it out.
Oh, my glasses. Thank you.
Roy,
you're shot.
Get help.
Roy.
You're beautiful, June Havens.
Stay with me. Roy, look at me.
Stay with me.
We're here now, Miller.
We got you. We got you.
-Charge at 360.
-June.
Clear!
lt's been a spectacular
couple of weeks, Miller.
lt's good to see you, lsabel.
Hi, guys.
You cleaned house, Roy.
l have to thank you for that.
l trusted the wrong man.
lt happens.
Simon's happy. He's got a new lab.
Where is June?
l sent her home.
She gets it.
She knows you two lead different lives
and she's moving on.
As should you.
You gave up those things.
You let go of who you were.
Family, friends, that's the deal.
Why are we still talking about this?
Because the agency invested a lot in you.
And you're an asset
only as long as you stay focused.
You look good.
Get some rest.
We got to transfer you to a secure facility
tomorrow. For your safety.
Nurse? What.. . What did you give me?
Brotine-zero.
Stay under there, Roy.
You're dead.
Make way, please.
Going to the mortuary.
Don't worry, Roy. l got this.
lt's time for a vacation.
Ride like the wind
And l've got
Such a long way to go
To make it to the border of Mexico
Hey, there, sleepy head.
What day is it?
Someday.
Someday, Roy.
What am l wearing?
A pair of shorts.
How did l get into shorts?
Roy, l've been trained to rebuild
a six-speed transmission
with nothing but a pair of pliers
and a crescent wrench.
l think l can get you into a pair
of shorts without looking.
l'm not saying that's what l did.
You're both the navigator and the DJ.
And we have a long way to go
to Cape Horn.
With me, without me. With me,
without me.
With you.
Put some tunes on the radio, Mr. DJ.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, my God, Frank.
What is this envelope
with tickets to Cape Horn?
What are you talking about?
Did you order tickets to South America?
Molly, l didn't order tickets to anywhere.
You don't know what you're typing
on that computer, Frank.
-Molly.. .
-Then, we must've won them !
-Molly...
-Well, we're going, aren't we?