[Disco ]
[ Crowd Chattering]
[ Chattering Continues ]
- [ Man ] Richard, say, kudos.
- Oh, thank you.
Wow, that was-- You found some
essential truth in that staging.
- Yeah?
- Absolutely. Clearly, it's about Vietnam.
He suffers from
suburban existential--
[ Richard ] It's about whatever
you want it to be about.
- [ Woman ] Richard, we loved the play.
- Thank you.
- You could understand it?
- Perfectly well.
[ Richard]
I'll talk to you later.
[ Chattering Continues ]
You aced it.
This is. uh-- I'm sorry. I
don't know your name. Pam. Pam.
Pam? This is Shelley. my
girlfriend. Hi. Shelley. Hi.
Hi. How are you? I'm
Richard. and I'm thirsty.
So we'll talk to you later.
Bye-bye.
Oh. boy. Look at--
Hi. Dan. How are you?
Kudos. That was a fine. fine
play. really. Absolutely.
I'm afraid I don't know-- Mike
Neeley. Chicago Alternative.
[Richard] Hey, Shelley, I
gotta go talk to this guy, okay,?
What is happening? This
is for you. from all of us.
Hey. Shelley! Oh. thank
you. Shelley. look at this.
Wait a minute.
Did everybody sign this?
- [ Woman ] Yeah, everybody, signed.
- Oh, fabulous. Thank you.
- [Richard] Where'd you sign this?
- Inside.
[ Richard]
Good, I got some news.
There was an agent
in the house tonight.
and he says he thinks this play
might be good enough for Broadway.
[ Cheering ]
Yeah. I know.
Let's keep our fingers crossed.
Let's all have some cake.
[Richard]
Penelope, great!
Okay. Now, I think this thing
that we ought to do here is--
Here you go.
Let me trade you that.
I think we shouldn't cut the
mask. We save those for later.
[ Chattering Stops ]
[ Whispers ]
Come back to me.
[ Shelley ]
Who was she?
I never saw her in my life.
What'd she give you?
[ Gasping ]
Oh. my God.
[ Man ] Is this a party, or
what? Let's have some cake.
How was the play?
Did you enjoy it?
Are you all right?
[ Classical ]
¢[ Stops ]
[Elevator Humming]
Aha!
Aha. what?
Aha. where ya goin'?
I'm going on a trip.
Where?
I have no idea.
What about the play?
Well. it isn't done.
Okay. When will it be done?
I don't know.
Oh my God. Richard. There are people
waiting for that play.
She’ll going with you?
No. I don't think so. We broke up.
[Jazz]
[Radio Announcer] The White
Sox are at home tonight...
for a Comiskey, Park game
against the Yankees.
The Cubs are just beginning
a West Coast swing--
How long will you be
with us? Just tonight.
Fine. If you'll sign
in here. sir.
Sure.
[ Clears Throat ]
Arthur. 313. please.
Have a pleasant stay.
Thank you. Okay. thanks a lot.
Uh. this your first time
here. Mister. uh--
Collier. Yeah. For some reason.
I never got around to coming here.
I always heard how nice it
was though. Oh. when was that?
Oh. About eight years ago. See. I used
to be a student up at Millfield College.
Yeah. The students come here now
and then to enjoy the restaurant...
and the rooms.
[ Chuckles ]
It seems to me. I remember they
had a graduation prom here...
back in. uh. '47.
was it?
Oh. really?
You been here that long?
Why. I've been here
since 1910.
1910?
Uh-huh.
Came here with my parents when I was five
years old. My father was a desk clerk.
I used to drive him crazy
playing ball in the lobby.
He got so mad at me sometimes.
I'm lucky I lived to be six.
Three. George.
Got yourself a nice
view here. Let me see.
Oh. great.
Okay. let's see now.
Here you go. Thank you. Mr. Collier.
If there's anything I can
do for you, just let me know.
My name's Arthur and I live in
the bungalow behind the hotel.
Okay. Thanks a lot.
See ya around. Arthur.
Have we ever met before?
Have we ever me--
No. no. I don't think so.
No. No. I'm sure we haven't.
Have a nice stay. Mr. Collier.
Okay, thanks a lot.
Sir? Uh. yeah. When do you open?
In about 40 minutes. sir.
Forty minutes?
Yes. sir.
Arthur! Hi.
Yes, Mr. Collier.
Arthur. you know.
in the Hall of History.
there's a photograph.
a young woman.
There's no nameplate.
Yes. That's Elise McKenna.
She was a famous actress
in her day.
Starred in a play
in the hotel theater.
I-I'm sorry. D-Did you say
there was a theater here?
Down by the lake.
Really?
When was this play done?
Oh. uh. 1912.
1912?
Hey. Arthur!
Arthur. Hi. Listen.
Could you take my luggage and put it
back in my suite? Great. Thanks a lot.
And can you tell me where the nearest
library is? In town. Right past the church.
Great. Look out.
Thanks. Terrific!
Thanks a lot.
See you around. Arthur.
Yeah.
Yes.
[ Whispers ]
Oh, my God.
[Richard] "One of the most revered
actresses on the American stage,
for many,years, she was the
theater's greatest box office draw. "
"Under the guidance of her
manager, William Fawcett Robinson,
Elise McKenna was the first American actress
to create a mystique in the public's eye. "
"Never seen in public
in her lateryears,
"apparently, without
an offstage life,
the absolute quintessence
of seclusion. "
Excuse me. Do you have
any theater biographies...
that aren't in the racks under
the rare books or magazines?
Well. We do have
some magazines.
but they're in the back.
and I'd have to find them.
And-- Oh. could you
do that for me. Please?
Well. all right.
Thanks. I'm in the back.
Okay.
Great!
Here you are.
Oh. Thank you. Thank you. Mm-hmm.
Yes? Uh. hello. yes. M-Miss Roberts?
Yes. Hi. uh. my name's Richard Collier.
and I just read your book on famous American
actresses. and I really enjoyed it a lot.
What is it you want?
Information about Elise McKenna.
What sort
of information?
Well. I'm a playwright. and I was thinking
about doing a play based on her life.
And. of course. I'd
have to talk-- I'm sorry.
Ma'am. Please.
Please. don't.
This is not for a play.
Miss Roberts.
This is something
very personal.
I don't understand.
Where did you get that?
She gave it to me. ma'am. At the
opening night of a play that I wrote...
at Millfield College
about eight years ago.
That watch was
very precious to her.
She never, never left it
out of her possession.
It disappeared
the night she died.
She died that night?
Won't you come in.
please?
Thank you.
I have some things I've been
saving for the theater collection.
That was a costume from
one of the plays she was in.
Miss Roberts.
what was she like?
When I knew her.
She was kind and thoughtful.
But she was just
too much within herself.
She. she seemed
empty somehow.
Well. She wasn't always
that way. was she?
Oh. no. not at all.
People who knew her
when she was young said...
that she was quick and bright
and full of fun.
strong. willful. not at
all the way she was later.
What made her change?
I don't know,
but the change seems to have
taken place about 1912.
After she performed in a
play, at the Grand Hotel.
That was her manager,
William Robinson.
Was he really as strange as you
seemed to indicate in the book?
There was something strange
about their relationship.
Oh. wow. look at this.
Hey. May I? This is
incredible. Of course.
This guy. Finney. He was my
philosophy teacher at Millfield.
Really,?
Yeah.
She read that book
over and over.
She had that made.
[ Classical]
What is it?
That's my favorite music
in the whole world.
I don't understand
what's happening.
Doctor Finney? You'll have
to walk with me. Young man.
I have another class. What's your
name? Collier, sir. Richard Collier.
Student? Uh, yes I was, nine years ago.
Well. I try to make my classes
Interesting, but nine years?
What can I do for you? I
have a question for you, sir.
Shoot.
Is time travel possible?
That is a question.
Let me tell you something.
Richard, is it? Yes, sir.
I was in Venice
in 1971.
I was staying in
a very old hotel.
But I mean, very old:
The structure, the
furnishings. Everything.
The atmosphere was aged,
If you follow me.
And my room. I felt
as though it was...
a century or more
earlier than 1971.
You understand?
Yes, sir.
So, in other words, then,
the location is very important.
Not all important,
but essential. Mm-hmm.
The rest is here.
One afternoon, I--
I was lying down
in that room.
all the sights around me...
a part of the past.
even the sounds
I heard,
and I conceived a notion.
What, I asked myself,
If I attempt
to hypnothesize my, mind?
Suggest to it
that it isn't 1971,
but 1571.
I closed my, eyes...
and fed a suggestion
into my brain.
It's August. 1571.
I am in
the Hotel Del Vecchio.
I spelled out the details
for myself...
and did it
over and over...
and again and again
and again--
And?
Well. I'll never
really know. Richard.
I've never done it since.
And I'm not sure
I'd want to do it again.
I felt exhausted afterwards.
completely washed out.
And if it really
did happen.
I was only there a fraction
of an instant. Remember.
- A flicker.
- Yes, sir. I understand that. But you were there.
I thought so.
Oh, it wasn't perfect, granted.
How would it be otherwise?
There were objects around me that
were clearly, from the present,
and I knew they, were there.
Oh, if I were going to
try it again--
Mind you.
I have no such intention.
But if I did.
I would disassociate myself
entirely, from the present.
Move everything out of sight that
could possibly, remind me of it.
Then, who knows?
Whoops.
Sorry. Hey.
Hi.
Hi. how do you do?
Listen. do you have 1912 money?
I mean. very specifically. 1912.
[Scissors Clipping]
Aha. That's it.
All right--
[ Murmuring ]
Yeah. not too bad.
Yup. yup. yup. yup.
It's looking all right.
[ Clears Throat ]
Ah, good evening. Miss McKenna.
You don't know me, but you will.
Evening Miss McKenna.
You don't know me.
but you will.
Okay.
It is June 27. 1912.
Oh, boy.
You are lying on your bed
in the Grand Hotel.
and it is 6:00 p.m. in the
evening of June 27. 1912.
Your mind
accepts this absolutely.
It is 6:00p.m.
On June 27, 1912.
Elise McKenna is in this hotel
at this very moment.
Her manager.
William Fawcett Robinson.
is in this hotel
at this very moment.
Now. This moment. Here.
Elise McKenna and you...
[ Whispering ] God. Hhow stupid.
That's not very bright. Both in the
Grand Hotel on this early evening.
on June 27. 1912.
6:00 p.m..
Elise McKenna and you.
Good-bye.
Elise McKenna, now.
in this hotel.
She and her company, who are in
this hotel at this very moment,
even as you lie here on your bed
in the Grand Hotel on June 27, 1912,
6:00 p.m.. June 27. 1912.
[ Murmuring ]
The stage is being set...
for their performance
tomorrow night.
[ Murmuring ] Your mind
accepts this absolutely.
It is 6:00 p.m.
on June 27. 1912.
You have travelled
back in time.
Soon you will open
your eyes.
and you will walk
into the corridor.
and you will go downstairs
and find Elise McKenna.
She is in the hotel
at this very moment.
[ Yells ]
Damn it!
There's no question
in your mind.
Now. now. now. now. It is
6:00p.m. onJ une 27, 1912.
That which you think
becomes your world.
Your mind accepts this
absolutely. It is June 27, 1912.
It has to happen!
[ Murmuring ] You know
that now! You know it.
It has to happen.
There is no question.
You know it.
It has to happen.
Relax. Accept.
Relax and accept.
[ Screams ]
Shut up!
[ Man ] Yeah. not bad. Great.
Hey. Look at these pictures. Oh.
I'll bet they're a hundred
years old, if they're a day. Huh?
[ Woman ] Oh, look at this
furniture. Isn't that nice?
[Man ] What a place, huh? Mm-hmm.
Yeah? You like those?
Oh, it's beautiful.
They're yours. I'll
bet this is all crystal.
[ Man ] You suppose it
is? Yeah, it must be.
Look at the rest of the place.
It has to be.
Look at here,
the original picture, huh?
Yeah, but look how much
they've been-- It's beautiful.
[ Y ells ]
Arthur!
Arthur? Arthur?
Arthur?
Arthur!
Come on. Wake up.
Arthur. I'm really sorry
to wake you up.
but you're the only one
who can help me.
You know those things in the
Hall of History display cases.
Where do they
come from?
I-Is there a storeroom
or something?
Arthur. Please. Where do
those things come from?
The, uh, attic.
Mr. Collier.
[Richard]
Whew.
Oh. Shit.
Come on.
Here we go.
Twelve!
[ Murmuring ]
McKenna.
[ Whispers ]
Yes.
I was there.
It is 6:00 p.m..
June 27. 1912.
There is no question in
your mind. Wait a minute.
It is 6:00 p.m.--
Of course.
[ Whispers ]
Room 416. room 416.
9:18, tomorrow morning.
9:18. 9:18.
tomorrow morning.
[ Murmuring ]
Believe.
[ Whispers ]
1912. 1912. 1912.
1912. 1912.
[Hoofbeats]
[Horse Whinnying]
[Hoofbeats Continue ]
[ Groans ]
[ Whispers ]
I made it.
Oh. brother.
[Laughs]
I made it.
[Door Opens]
[ Woman Humming
"You Made Me Love You"]
[Humming Continues ]
Maude!
[Humming Stops ]
I'm back.
Are you ready yet?
No.
I don't know why you act
in such a manner.
Indeed. I suspect
you do not.
And what am I to make
of that remark?
What you will. Rollo.
What you will.
Are we to have
this maddening exchange...
each and every time I notice the
existence of a female other than yourself?
Notice her existence?
Oh. That scarcely describes your
rapt appraisal of her every inch.
" Rapt appraisal of her--"
You just don't love me anymore.
Oh. Maude.
Oh. Christ.
- I want to lie down a while. -
That's a good idea. - Great idea.
I warn you. I've had enough
of this constant bickering.
That's what you always say, to
everything: "I will not discuss it. "
That's your answer
to everything.
Unless you come
to your senses,
I shall leave
without you.
Excuse me. did you see someone
just trying to get in here?
Yes. some young chap.
ran that way.
I'll be damned.
I'd better report that.
Indeed.
you'd better, sir.
I'd have reported it myself
if I'd known that there was--
Good afternoon. Miss McKenna.
You don't know me.
[ Murmuring ] Good
afternoon. Miss McKenna.
Good afternoon. Miss McKenna.
I've just come 68 years.
May I please speak to you?
Yes?
Yes. monsieur?
Uh. is Miss McKenna here?
No. I'm afraid. she's not.
Could you tell me
where she is?
I'm sorry.
I have no idea. monsieur.
Strike one.
[ Chattering]
Oh. I beg your pardon.
Getting out?
Not inside, Arthur.
Are you Arthur?
Yes, sir.
Here you go.
Arthur,
not inside.
[Actors Shouting Lines,
Indistinct ] [ Piano ]
Oh. I'm sorry.
[ Man ]
I say, I shall have her!
[ Woman ] Not in my,
life, you shall not!
[Actors Continue,
Indistinct ]
[ Man ]
Whatever you desire,
I guarantee you...
satisfaction!
[ Woman Shouting Lines ]
Be out of here within two
hours after the show's over?
That's impossible. The man's
insane. That's what he wants.
You know Robinson. I
wish to God I didn't.
If he's that anxious to get us out of
here. Let him help us tear down the set.
[ Yelling ]
What?
Sorry. Uh. have you seen Miss McKenna?
You have a message for her? Give it
to me. and I'll see it reaches her.
As for our precious
Mr. Robinson--
[ Actors Continue.
Indistinct ]
Madam. I do not so
regard her. Yes. you do.
And you shall not
marry her.
And I say. I shall have her.
Not in my life. you shall not.
Give in. Cecily. It's not
your place to say. Desist!
Good people, this is a
comedy, not King Lear.
Let's not bury the
playwright before his time.
Excuse me!
I'm terribly sorry
to bother you.
I wonder if you know
where Miss McKenna might be.
Very well. very well.
Let us take it again.
From the beginning.
"A yearly, stipend, shall we say, paid
for by, the month. " "Whatever you desire."
Hello.
- Take it again, Madeline.
- "Why, not put her on the scale and sell her by, the pound. "
May I speak to you. please.
Miss McKenna? May I--
May I please speak to--
Miss McKenna. uh. no. no.
Elise. may I--
Whoo. boy.
Miss McKenna.
Good afternoon. Miss McKenna.
[ Grunts ]
Uh. I'm. uh--
Flustered. my sweet?
Qu'est-ce que c'est?
Never seen an actress
en dishabille before?
Uh. I'm. I'm looking
for Miss McKenna. please.
Most likely walking by the
lake. my dear. Thank you.
Oh! Sorry. Excuse me. Watch it. sonny.
Is it you?
Is it?
Yes.
Are you all right? Yes.
yes. quite all right.
I'm sorry if I startled you. You didn't.
I think I did. I'll
take you in to dinner now.
May I speak
to you. please?
Anything the matter?
Who was that young man?
I've no idea.
He gave no name?
There was hardly time.
You were conversing. McKenna. No.
Well. not really.
No. no need to look back.
He's following us.
Uh. keep on walking.
I'll be right along.
Are you a guest here. sir?
You're Robinson.
Are you a guest
of the hotel?
Uh. yes.
Yes. I am.
Then I must ask you to stop
annoying Miss McKenna any further.
If you do not. I shall
see that you're put out.
What did you say to him? Oh. what
I've always said to men of his sort.
That gown of yours
in act two.
I'm not crazy about it.
you know.
It'll have to be redone.
I shall discuss it
with Marie later.
[Man #1 ] Good evening.
Reservations for four under Woods.
[Man # 2 ] Woods. Yes. Monsieur.
what time was the reservation for?
Monsieur, may I help you. please?
I'm dining with Miss McKenna.
Uh. good evening.
How are you. sir?
[Maude ] I told you, we should
have gone to "Poughpeepskie. "
Poughkeepsie.
" Poughpeepskie."
And I just won't
discuss it any further.
It isn't the lines at all.
If only these actors would--
Isn't he the nincompoop who thought
he could do Hamlet last season?
Oh. mon cheri, we
meet again. Yes. hello.
I so admire a man not hidebound
by the dictates of fashion. Ma'am?
That suit. I haven't seen
one like it for a decade.
A decade?
Yes.
Oh, still looking
For Miss McKenna?
Yes. in fact--
Over there.
[ Orchestra Playing
"Oh! You Beautiful Doll"]
- Thank you.
- A bientot.
What do you think you're
doing? Dancing with you.
But we don't
even know each other.
I know everything
about you.
Yes. I'm sure you do.
What do you mean?
If you will excuse me--
N-N-N-No. you don't understand.
I think I do. No. no.
please. don't leave.
You have no idea how far
I've come to be with you.
There's no need to be
afraid of me. you know.
The man's an intruder.
Will you kindly see to it that
he is escorted from the premises?
If you will. sir.
One moment.
I shall go with him.
McKenna.
Are you sure
you want to do this?
Don't worry. William.
I shall return momentarily.
thank you so much.
I was so embarrassed--
Your name. please?
Uh. Richard Collier.
Your place of residence? Chicago.
Your occupation?
I'm a playwright.
A playwright. [ Stuttering ]
Yes. but I'm not here because--
And you say that you know
everything about me. Well. yes--
Which is patently absurd. You couldn't
possibly know everything about me.
We've never met. You're
a complete stranger to me.
But. then. why did you say.
"Is it you"?
I don't
have to answer that.
I know you don't.
I wish you would. though.
What is the matter
with him?
He's just looking out for me
as he has always done.
Why?
Do I look dangerous?
Wait. wait.
When can I see you
again?
I don't know.
[ Orchestra
Continues ]
Guardez la ligne, Marie.
And have it ready by tomorrow
morning. I'll do my best.
[ Knocking ]
Smiling. McKenna?
Seems appropriate.
Rather handsome young man.
if ill-mannered.
I'll keep an eye on
him. I'm sure you will.
Is he the one. William?
Is he?
Only you can tell
for certain.
Now. tomorrow night's
performance.
Remember.
stay ahead of them.
Keep the mystery.
always the mystery.
[ Together ]
" Excess within control."
Sleep well.
McKenna.
[Door Shuts ]
[ Grunts ]
All right.
[ Yawning ]
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Knocking ]
[McKenna Whispering]
Who is it?
Richard Collier.
Good morning.
Um, you sleep all right?
Wonderfully.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't sleep too well either.
Uh. but I was on a porch chair.
So, you know-- Don't
you even have a room?
Uh. yes. I will at 9: 18.
Room 416.
I mean. w-would you like
to go to breakfast?
At 6:00 a.m.?
Oh well. Later?
I don't eat breakfast on performance
days. Oh, no, Of course not.
Um. Lunch?
Mr. Collier!
No. no. no. It's not Mr.
Collier. Isn't that your name?
Yes. that's my
name. but-- Shh! Shh!
What? Marie. She's
sleeping in the other room.
Marie?
My maid.
Ooh. I'm sorry.
[ Whispering ] Well. of
course my name is Mr. Collier.
But I was hoping you'd call
me by my first name. Richard.
Why should I?
I don't know.
Just hoped you would.
[ Laughs ]
When can I
see you today?
I shall be rehearsing all day. All day!
That's crazy! You can't--
Shh! Don't wake her up.
Will you walk with me? Can
you do that much? I can't.
[ Sighs ] Young woman. if you do
not walk with me. I shall go mad.
positively insane. and do crazed
things to myself. Shh! Shh!
[ Sighs ]
Walk with me. Please.
Say. "Richard--" That's me.
"Thank you.
"I would love to walk with you.
talk with you. get to know you...
not be afraid of you
and resolve everything."
Say "Yes."
Yes.
One o'clock.
Mm-hmm.
Outside the hotel.
She's crazy about me.
[People Chattering,
Laughing]
Can I persuade you
to join me?
Where are you from.
Collier?
Chicago. Where
are you from. sir?
I'm given to understand
that you're a playwright.
You understand correctly.
No doubt you dream of
seeing Miss McKenna...
in one of your opera.
That's plural for opus. I presume
you've written more than one?
Mmm.
And seen them produced.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
I'm not entirely unacquainted
with the achievements...
of the American stage
in the past decade.
Perhaps I've seen one? No. I doubt it.
I also doubt very much...
that I shall ever see one
graced by Miss McKenna.
You don't really believe
that's why I'm here. do you?
Why are you here?
Is it money?
I don't think you really
believe that either.
There is a law. Collier.
I warn you. I will not
hesitate to make avail of it.
Oh. yes?
On what charge?
The matter's concluded. sir. No.
Oh. yes.
You may depend on it.
[Rhythmic Thumping]
Good morning. sir.
Good morning.
Uh. excuse me.
Arthur!
[ Clerk ]
Forgive me again, sir.
[ Grunts ]
[ Laughs ]
I'm very sorry. sir.
Ah. that's quite all right.
I'd like a room. please.
Oh. Uh.
don't you have one?
Well. I was rather ill when I arrived
last night. so I stayed with a friend.
Ah. I see.
Mm-hmm.
You do have a room. sir?
Oh. yes. yes.
Thank you.
One single.
$3.00 a day.
Bathroom privileges extra.
Would you care to sign
the register now, sir?
Um. e-excuse me.
I-I'm sorry. Are you sure
this is the right room?
The right room. sir? I-I don't
understand. I'm sorry. Mr. Biehl.
That room is reserved. Forgot
to put a notice in the slot.
[Biehl]
I'm very sorry.
[ Sighs ]
Right. Shall I sign?
Uh. would you. please?
Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm. Excuse me.
Let me just
finish that for you.
[Bell Buzzes ] [ Woman ] Grand Hotel.
Uh. 9: 18. Mm-hmm.
[ Woman ] I'm sorry--
Thank you. sir.
[ Whispers ] Bingo. I beg your pardon?
Oh. nothing.
Uh. w-which room is
your luggage in. sir?
Um. it's no problem.
I can get it later myself.
thank you very much.
See you around. Arthur.
[Richard Humming]
Morning. [Man ] Morning.
Astonishing.
Hello. Hello. You look lovely.
Thank you. Shall we? Certainly.
Sorry I'm late.
Complications.
What did you do to your face? Shaved.
New blade wasn't
quite sharp enough.
I shudder to think what you'd look
like if the blade were any sharper.
Oh. no. I don't
believe it.
Gotta give him credit.
He's like a bulldog.
Would you like me to speak to
him? Wouldn't do a bit of good.
[ Horse Whinnying ] I think
I know what would. though.
[ Horse Snorts ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
Whoa! Wait for me!
[ Both Laughing ]
Mr. Collier.
it isn't easy being
a successful actress.
Over the years. I--
I found it necessary
to protect myself.
So understand.
please understand...
that I'm even
with you today. when--
[ Sighs ]
when we only met last night.
Why did you say.
"Is it you? "
I was expecting--
Me?
Someone.
Who?
Tell me.
I think you'll laugh.
Why? Is it funny?
In a way.
William told me
you were coming.
Robinson?
Yes.
He knows. somehow.
He really does.
He knew a lot of things
before they happened:
my career. my--
He told me that...
one day I would
meet a man who'd...
change my life.
Did he tell you that man would
be someone to be afraid of?
Yes.
And what
do you think now?
Do you--
Do you believe that?
No.
You're obviously not.
[Humming]
¢Ü¢Ü
That's beautiful. Hmm?
What is it?
That's Rachmaninoff.
from the Rhapsody.
Hmm. I saw him with
the philharmonic once.
I love his music. but I've
never heard this piece.
Really? Well. I'll
introduce you to it sometime.
[ Richard ] Sorry we had the
carriage so long. Thank you.
See that guy's face?
[ Laughs ]
They're gonna hang us for
horse-napping. [ Both Laughing ]
[ Sighs ]
Stick out
your tongue.
Huh? Stick out your tongue.
Why? Oh. no.
The most peculiar moment
in my life. Mr. Collier.
I think you'll survive it.
Miss McKenna.
What time
is it now?
Um.
4:30.
Well. I must be getting
back. You have to?
Can't you stay a little longer?
No. I have to rest awhile.
The play. The play. [ Laughs ]
It's lovely.
Where did you get it?
It-It was given to me.
Well. shall we?
So... when's
the company leave?
Tonight.
Where are you going?
Denver.
Oh.
Well-- Well. thank you for
a most pleasant afternoon.
Could we talk
just a little longer?
I really should rest
awhile. I-- Please.
Very well. then.
Just for a moment or so.
What did you want
to talk about?
No.
Oh. my God.
What's happening?
[ Knocking At Door ]
[Robinson ]
McKenna?
[ Knocking ]
Come in.
I think you'd better go. Have you been
waiting all this time for our return?
This is hardly the
time-- Have you?
Yes. Does that
surprise you?
Our relationship is strictly
business. Strictly, business?
I'm involved with you as an
actress. Mr. Robinson. not a doormat.
Do not attempt
to wipe your boots on me.
Richard.
I shall leave a ticket for you
at the theater door.
" Excess within control."
McKenna?
Au revoir.
[Door Slams ]
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
[ Waltz ]
[Applause ]
[Applause Stops ]
Good evening. miss.
Not good at all.
Particularly bad.
I'll not go downstairs
again. Oh. what is it. miss?
[ Sighs ]
I've just been dining...
with the man my father
is determined that I wed.
Ooh. banker Harwell. Banker
Harwell-- yes. all 67 years...
and five-foot-four of height and
several hundred pounds of him!
[ Laughter ] He does
have money. though. miss.
And never lets
a soul forget it.
I'm amazed he has the
least desire to marry.
- He's so happily wedded to his gold.
- [Laughter]
[Maid] He won't be that bad, miss.
There must be something
you like about 'im.
Yes. his absence.
The man of my dreams
has almost faded now.
And what man is that. miss?
The one I have created
in my mind.
The sort of man...
each woman dreams of
in the deepest...
and most secret reaches
of her heart.
I can almost
see him now before me.
What would I say to him...
if he were really here?
"Forgive me. "
I've never known
this feeling.
I've lived without it
all my life.
Is it any wonder, then?
I failed to recognize you?
You've...
brought it to me
for the first time.
Is there any way that--
that I can tell you
how my life has changed?
Any way at all
to let you know...
what sweetness
you have given me?
There is so much to say. I--
I cannot find the words.
except for these:
I love you.
And such would I say to him.
if he were really here.
[Applause ]
[ Applause. Cheering ]
[ Applause Continues ]
What. in God's name. were
you doing? [ Murmuring ]
Nothing. Nothing? Rewriting
the entire first scene?
I got it back on course.
Elise. hold a moment.
We've just got to take that photograph.
Oh!
Very well. Just a moment.
I have to change. Quickly!
A-And
a little flourish.
Yes. yes.
Yes. very pretty.
Very pretty.
Just one moment. Here we go.
I'm just going to focus
on that lovely--
Oh. yes. yes. yes! I'm just
going to put in the plate.
One moment.
There we go.
A little smile. please.
Uh. not-not quite. Uh. perhaps if you
think of something happy or bright.
Yes, that's it.
That's it. Hold it.
[Shutter Clicks ]
Perfect!
Absolutely, perfect.
[Actor] I say, I shall
have her! [ Laughter ]
[Actress ] Not in my,
life, you shall not.
[ Man ] Mr. Collier? I
am the one who loves her!
For you.
[Actress ]
Neither do you.
[Actor #1 ] I can provide
her with life's enrichments,
rather than
the riches of life.
[ Laughter]
[Actor #2 ]
Are you sure?
[Actor #1 ]
An old song says it best.
[ Laughter, Applause ]
Do you have any notion
how many years...
I have been
with Miss McKenna?
Since March of 1903.
March, 1903.
That's correct.
She was 16
at the time.
There she was
on that dingy, stage...
in that pathetic play.
Total radiance.
It only took seconds
for me to realize...
exactly what
she had to be.
Mrs. Robinson?
Do you actually believe...
that I have nurtured her.
cared for her,
moulded, taught,
developed her
for all these years.
merely to groom
a wife?
What, then?
A star.
Only, someone with...
the limited awareness
of your age...
could possibly conceive that my
entire passion for this woman...
is no more than physical!
Are you incapable
Of understanding that...
she has it within herself
to be one of the greatest.
if not the greatest...
actress
of her generation?
I owe you an apology.
What?
I understand you now.
You have nothing but the best
motives in mind for her.
- And you--
- But so do I.
Of course,
she'll continue to act,
she will continue to grow...
and she will become
everything you want her to be.
With you at her side?
Yes.
With me at her side.
Never.
My God.
You really think
you own her. don't you?
Collier. I know
who you are.
Ever since
you came here.
I've known
from the start.
You came
to destroy her.
God. you're
out of your mind.
[ Orchestra ]
[Applause ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Orchestra Finishes ]
[Applause Continues ]
No more.
No more?
One curtain call? The
audience will be furious.
Marie. did you
find him?
No. Miss McKenna.
Did you try his room?
He wasn't there.
Oh!
What did they say at the
desk? They have not seen him.
He left no message?
No. I'm sorry.
[ Sighs ] This makes no sense at all.
What could have happened
to him?
Marie!
Marie. help me
change. Quickly.
[Knocking At Door]
Wait. Marie.
Thank you. Marie.
Your performance
in act one. I--
I must say.
was somewhat eccentric.
Where is he?
What have you done to him?
I've done nothing. McKenna.
Mr. Collier has left.
That's all.
What do you mean?
Gone... from the hotel...
and your life.
I don't believe you.
I must admit.
he was somewhat
more charming...
than others that
we've encountered in the past.
you and I.
A trifle more sincere,
perhaps. Still--
Then he was not
the one you spoke of?
No. Then you were wrong
about him, weren't you?
You were wrong.
I love him.
and he's going
to make me very happy.
Do you understand?
I love him.
What difference... can
that make now? He's gone.
I'll find him. William.
Don't you dare
try to stop me.
Now. If you will excuse me
while I change.
Of course.
May I remind you...
that we leave
within the hour?
[Door Opens,
Footsteps Recede ]
[Door Closes ]
Thank you.
[Horse Snorts ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Moans ]
[Horse Snorts ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunting. Panting ]
[ Glass Shatters ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
Yah!
Elise!
Elise?
[ Sighs ]
Sir?
Are you all right?
The company-- Are they gone?
Company?
The ones who did the play last night.
Are they gone?
They left as soon
as they were packed. sir.
Oh. come along. Arthur.
We'll be late.
Richard!
[ Laughing ]
You all right?
Yes.
I thought I lost you.
Oh. never.
Never. never. never!
Mm-mmm.
You will marry me.
won't you?
[ Splutters ]
[ Laughing ] Sorry. You won't?
[ Murmurs ]
Sure.
I was just laughing at the
way you asked, that's all.
For one moment there... What?
I thought you had a wife and
children back home somewhere.
[ Laughing ]
Oh. Elise.
I want to be
everything to you.
You are.
Tell me more
about yourself. my love.
Well-- What sort of
plays do you write?
Um-- Are there
parts for me?
I could-- I would love to
act in one of your plays.
assuming that I ever want to act
again after tonight. You will.
Oh. Richard.
[ Clears Throat ]
Good plays.
What?
I write good plays.
[ Laughs ] I never
let you answer. did I?
No.
Sorry.
What time do you think
it is? I don't know.
I don't care.
I love you.
Oh. don't look--
Fine.
It's 5:00.
Really?
I don't feel sleepy somehow. do you? No.
The first thing I intend to do
For you-- You've already done.
Well, the second thing, then. What?
Buy you a new suit.
I don't understand.
Nobody seems to like my suit.
Can you blame them? Wait a
minute. I think my suit's terrific.
What's wrong with this? So
what if it's ten years old?
Oh, at least 15.
Fifteen?
Mm-hmm. Well. I think it's fabulous.
[ Laughing ] Let me show you.
It's a really, great suit.
It's in first-class condition.
The sleeves fit.
That's pretty good for me. My
arms are about nine feet long.
And it's got pockets everywhere.
I can pull rabbits outta here.
The best part. This is a special
coin compartment for emerg--
Richard?
Richard!
Richard! Richard!
[Screaming]
Richard!
[Announcer On Radio,
Faint ]
[ Gasping ]
[Announcer Continues,
Faint ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Traffic Noises ]
[ Radio ]
[Announcer On Radio ]
How's traffic?
[Announcer Continues,
Faint ]
[ Woman On Radio ] The road
conditions are pretty, good today.
[ Gasping. Sobbing ]
At the inbound Kennedy, at Jackson, there's
a three-car accident with injuries...
right at the center
of the roadway.
Traffic is backed up
from Ohio to Jackson--
No. No. no!
No!
[ Panting ]
[ Mumbling ]
June 29. 1912.
It's June 29. 1912.
It's J-- Oh. God.
[ Sobbing ]
Please.
June 29. I'm back.
I'm back. Oh. God--
[ Mumbling ]
June 29. 1912.
[ Exhales ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
No!
[ Sobbing ]
[ Knocking At Door ]
[Arthur] Mr. Collier?
[ Knocking Continues ] [Man
] Are you sure he's in there?
Well, the maid says
he's been in there for days.
[Arthur]
Are you all right, sir?
[Man ] Use the passkey.
[Keys Rattling]
Mr. Collier?
Oh, my God!
Let's get him on the
bed. All right. easy.
Careful, careful! I got him.
Better take his legs. All right.
All right,
over here.
Okay.
Easy.
[Phone Dialing]
Operator? Get Dr. Paul
up to Suite 313 right away.
Looks like
he hasn't eaten in a week.
Send for an ambulance. I'll call one.
- What a shame. If I'd only known.
- Operator? Get an ambulance.
[Arthur] He is gonna make
it, isn't he? I don't know.
[Man ] They're on
their way. How is he?
We're gonna need oxygen.
We've got some. I'll get it.
[Arthur] Keep him
warm with this blanket.
Such a fine man.
What a shame.
I wonder what happened.
Gotta keep him goin'
until they get here.
[Arthur] Glady,s, this is Arthur
again in Mr. Collier's suite.
We've got to--
[ Murmuring]