Fuck!
Fucking-shit!
Agh, fucking-fuck!
Watch it, old man!
What the fuck?
You're doing it wrong.
The needle is doing
what the needle does.
What the fuck is that
supposed to mean?
The Irezumi does not hide the skin,
The tattoo reveals the nature of the man
and illuminates the four noble professions
in the Book of Five Rings:
the Warrior, the Artist,
the Merchant, and the farmer.
If there is a conflict between
the needle and the skin,
between the mark and the man,
perhaps the path you have chosen is not
the path for which you are suited.
What did you just say, old man?
Huh?
I know you didn't just
disrespect me, did you?
You that fucking stupid?
You disrespect me, and I'll tattoo
this ceiling with your fucking brains!
No disrespect.
You're lucky.
I can't kill you
until you finish this thing.
Gimme that mirror!
See how it's looking?
Not bad.
Hey, boss.
This just came for you.
What is it?
A letter.
So open it, dumb ass.
What?
What is it?
Looks like sand.
Yup. Sand.
Black Sand.
No...
You know what this is?
Hey, you wanna let us in on the joke?
Years ago,  I watched a man
open an envelope like that one.
There were many with him
and they laughed as you laugh now.
Then it came from the shadows
and their laughter was drowned in blood.
What came out of the shadows?
I cannot say the word.
What word?
That night,
one of their blades struck here.
I should have died,
but for an accident of birth.
My heart is here,
on the other side.
What the fuck is that?
Looks like a Ninja, boss.
A ninja?
Are you kidding me?
That's the word you're afraid to say?
Ninja?
Ninja-Ninja-Ninja!
You old fuck!
You had me going!
Ninja.
That's some good shit.
You wanna fuck with me?
Fuck!
Look...
you don't have to do this!
Whatever they are paying you,
I'll double it!
I'll triple it!
You hear me!
I'll pay you whatever you want!
You cannot bargain with it.
You cannot reason with it because...
it is not a human being
It is a demon sent
straight from the hell.
You shut your face old man!
I'll blow your ...
For fifty-seven-years,
I’ve told your story...
No one ever believed me.
But you are real,
aren’t you?
Is all that for the Delgata case?
This is Delgata.
- And the rest?
- Evidence.
For?
No. Not again.
Mika, please.
What's the problem?
You’ve trusted my research before.
All right, here's a question for you.
Which of these words does not
belong in this sentence:
laptops, space shuttles,
nanotechnology, ninjas.
All I’m asking for is an hour.
That’s all.
Why do I think
I’m going to regret this?
You remember the Eulmi incident?
Korean queen, late eighteen-hundreds.
Killed by one of these ninja clans.
Ozunu.
I think.
Now I’ve been going through
the original transcripts
of the trial of Kunitomo Shigeaki.
The prosecutor questioned Shigeaki
about a payment of 100 pounds of gold.
Shigeaki answered that he didn’t know
what the prosecutor was talking about.
The question was never brought up again.
But what pinged for me was the amount-
the exact same amount
rumored to be paid to the Ozunu Clan
for the Yakuza massacre
that happened last week in Osaka.
So you start to wonder,
in this ever changing world,
if the cost of a man’s life
has remains the same.
Exactly. And I figure these clans
are like what? A thousand years old?
They probably don’t change a lot.
So I started looking at
international wire transfers,
targeting banks in the regions
of several high-profile assassinations
and bingo -
Russian Prime Minister Zhukov.
The day before the assassination
$1,555,999.90 was transferred
from the bank of Shanghai.
That is the exact market equivalent
of one hundred pounds of gold.
Okay you got me.
This is interesting.
The clans are real, Ryan.
They steal children
and turn them into assassins.
Yeah. Look Mika, no one's denying
the historical facts.
But this whole thing just doesn't make
sense anymore in modern world.
They’re real.
I mean you can call them spooks,
or assassins, or whatever you want
if it makes you feel better,
but they are out there
and they are killing people
and nobody is doing
a damn thing to stop them.
Hi. Excuse me.
Would you mind?
If it's not too much trouble,
could you help me with this?
What clan are you from?
What are you doing in Berlin?
I don't understand.
No!
What's going on?
- So you said you found something?
- Yeah.
I was digging around try to see what I
could come up with and I found this.
A report. A friend of mine
in Moscow, tipped me to it.
It was written during
the height of the Cold War
by a high ranking KGB agent
named Aleksei Sabatin.
In it he raises the possibility
that number of political assassinations
were conducted by an ancient
but very sophisticated network
he calls the Nine Clans.
Mind you,
he doesn’t call them ninjas.
What happened to him?
Same thing that’s going to happen to me,
if I hang around with you---
Kicked out of the service
for mental instability.
You believe it now, don’t you?
Ninjas?
You gotta be joking.
Well then, why are you doing all this?
I don't know.
But I can guarantee you
it has nothing to do with the fact
that you’re the most attractive
researcher I have ever worked with.
Oh, Mr. Nan, good, you're back.
We had a heating problem,
and I had to go into your apartment.
- Is it all right?
- It's all fixed.
You keep it very dark and bare in there.
And forgive me but I couldn't
help noticing in your suitcases.
I told you
my father was a very sick man.
Do you have to leave Berlin soon?
Not yet.
But I'm expecting a phone call.
I'm sorry to hear that.
One day death will come for us all.
Wherever you are,
wherever you may go,
you must never forget who you are,
how you came to be.
You are Ozunu.
You are a part of me
as I am part of you.
This is the truth of your lives
and it will remain true after death.
This is my new son.
I have given him the name Raizo.
Welcome him as your brother.
"Welcome Raizo"
The body must obey the will.
Hunger and thirst,
even the blood in your veins,
are the body’s weaknesses.
Master them,
and you master the self.
This is the power of the Ozunu clan.
This is the way of the ninja.
Eat tonight and you work
twice as hard tomorrow.
What is the lesson?
Look at your brother.
Life is combat.
You know this truth.
Abandoned by your parents.
Without a home.
Without people to care for you.
You should have died.
But, instead you fought.
As you did here today.
You fought, and you won.
In combat.
You faced your enemy.
Without doubt.
Without thinking or remorse.
To survive, you must
learn to feel nothing at all.
Pain breeds weakness.
Remember suffering exists
only because weakness exists.
You must hate all weakness.
Hate it in others,
but most of all hate it in yourself.
- Mrs. Sabatin?
- Yeah.
I'm Mika Corretti with Europol.
We spoke on the phone.
You said you read
my husband's report, yes?
Yes.
I understand the report caused some
problems for him within the KGB.
The report caused "problems"
for Alexei's career
the way Moses
caused problems for the Pharaoh.
Very unpleasant.
What happened?
About two years ago,
after the assassination of Zhukov,
the report drew attention.
After that,
everything was different.
Alexei hired men to change all the locks,
and put in more of them.
Locks on the windows, locks on
the doors, locks on the locks.
He put in cameras and motion sensors
and lights.
Everywhere, lights.
"There can be no shadows," he said.
"No shadows."
Then, one day, a man came to the door.
They talked in Alexei’s study for
sometime and then...
the young man left.
My husband was a soldier.
A member of Russian Intelligence.
He wasn't a man to frighten easy.
But when I came to the door,
in his eyes I saw fear.
And then he stood up.
He kissed me and told me
that he loved me very much.
He said...
I should always remember that.
Do you know what they talked about?
No.
He said it was safer that way.
Can I ask how he died?
The lights went out.
You are the first person who has
taken my husband's work seriously.
It would be good to know
that he did not die without cause.
He would want you to have this.
Who are you?
Go!
Did Takeshi's blow hurt you?
You think this is pain?
You are mistaken.
That is true pain.
Here is your test, Raizo.
Survive the night.
Very good, Raizo.
Very good.
Oh you're like a dog with a bone
on that computer, aren't you?
Excuse me?
Agent Zabranski.
Internal Affairs.
Need to ask you
a couple of questions.
You are Mika Coretti, yeah?
Forensic researcher.
You work a lot with an Agent Maslow.
That right?
A few cases.
Yeah.
You have something of
a social relationship.
Excuse me?
You had lunch with him on the 13th
and again on the 18th.
How do you know that?
Isn't it true?
I’m not sure.
We do have lunch together sometimes,
but that's usually when we’re working.
Has Agent Maslow seemed
different to you lately, in any way?
Has he said or done anything
that struck you as unusual?
No, why.
Has Agent Maslow
done something?
Just routine.
The agency cares about
its field operatives.
We monitor for signs of stress,
fatigue, mental exhaustion.
Agent Maslow has
a serious case load.
That much work
can wear on a man, huh?
Zabranski came to my office.
- Yeah. I got a surprise visit too.
He made it real clear, Ryan.
They're watching us.
I don't get full picture quite yet,
but I know warning when I see one.
- But why?
- Why? It's obvious.
If this little fantasy of yours has
any chance of being real,
then these Clans is gonna have some
pretty major juice protecting them.
So what are you going to do?
We are going to tip-toe,
very carefully from here on in.
You understand? You do nothing
without checking with me first.
Got it?
- Uh, huh.
Got it.
The 14th century scroll refers
to one of the oldest of the Nine Clans,
as the clan of Black Sand.
The Islamic explorer Ibn Battuta
journeyed with a group of orphans
that were being taken
to a remote Shido.
hidden amongst snow-capped mountains.
Battuta describes a ceremonial dinner
followed by a display of martial skill.
The combatants were children
neither beyond the age of ten.
His host explains that a man’s life
must be made meaningless
compared to the life of the Clan.
Own the meaning of a man’s life
and you own his heart.
You shouldn't do that.
It's against the rules.
- If they catch you---
- Then they catch me.
They'll put you in the box.
I believe the heart of the tree
knows which way it needs to grow.
Trees don't have hearts.
Everything has a heart.
I don't.
Really?
Let me see.
Hello?
It’s saying hello back.
And that it’s happy to meet me...
but it misses you.
Liar.
I’m not lying.
Listen to mine.
For an entire year, you shall live
without one of your senses,
beginning with the sense
you rely on the most.
You must see with more
than your eyes.
Cut him Kiriko.
All failure must be sown into the flesh.
Cut him!
You know the law.
I told you.
I tried to warn you.
Yes.
You did.
Why Kiriko?
Why?
Why am I in here?
Or why are you out there?
Kiriko!
Why are you doing this?
I have to.
You know the law.
He will cut your heart from your chest.
No.
He can never touch my heart.
Come with me.
Where?
What is out there?
Life.
My life is here.
Fucking Christ, Ryan---
I'm sorry I couldn’t talk earlier, Mika.
They’re watching me. Get in.
Ryan, where have you been?
I've been calling your office all day.
Now I know
how Sabatin must have felt.
What happened?
Right now I've got internal affairs,
Homeland Security, the CIA,
and for all I know the
fucking Martian Military in my office
tearing the place apart.
What are we going to do?
You are going to go home.
Pack your bags and go on holiday.
- No way.
- Don’t argue with me, Mika.
I trusted you.
Now you’ve got to trust me.
I'm sorry. I can’t let you lose
your job because of me, Ryan.
I’m not talking about
losing my job.
Take this. It’s clean.
Untraceable. No serial number
Ryan...
Yeah. I know.
I’ve investigated,
world bank organizations,
drug cartels, arms dealers,
and I’ve never faced this kind of heat.
For ninjas.
Fucking unbelievable!
Excuse me.
- Hey.
- Hi.
So, what's going on?
Power's out. Us, the building behind us,
and that one across the street.
Seems like every few months,
boom, the lights out.
Okay.
Thanks.
Resync and editing by majtjk0ng
More will come.
What?
They won’t stop
until you are dead.
Oh, God.
The gun won’t help you.
Well I don’t have a lot of options, okay.
I once took a Tae Bo class,
but that’s the extent of
my Kung Fu abilities, right?
I can help you
but you have to trust me.
Okay.
Do you know me?
How?
Security camera in New York,
recorded you fighting with one of them.
You know about them?
A little.
Nine Clans.
And apparently they've been supplying
assassins to governments
or anyone who has
a hundred pounds of gold
for the last thousand years.
His name was Jin.
You knew him?
He was not born an “Assassin”.
You’re from his Clan?
Then why did you stop him?
They're coming.
Who?
Run little brother.
Run.
Weakness compels strength.
Betrayal begets blood.
This is the law of the Nine Clans.
We have been betrayed.
A child of mine, my daughter,
betrayed us.
She refused my gifts.
Rejected our clan.
Her shame can only be purged with blood.
You...
You my son who returned her
shall have this honor.
Where are we going?
Doesn't matter.
Do you think they’re following us?
I know they’re following us.
I don’t see anything back there.
They have our scent.
Following our scent?
Like dogs?
No.
Like Wolves.
My name is Mika by the way.
Raizo is the name I was given.
So, you're an orphan?
If it’s okay with you, I’m gonna try
and fill in some of the blanks here.
So you must have been taken by the
Ozunu Clan, trained to be an assassin,
but something happened and
you decided to opt out of the program.
Now I don’t imagine
that went over so well
and since they’re after me for
just peeking through the keyhole,
they must be after you
in like a major way.
But you are also after them
which is why you are in Berlin.
Because Sabatin is one of
the few people pursuing the Clan,
which is why they took him out.
But here’s a question
I can’t answer:
Why did you save me?
Your entire life has brought you
to this moment.
Do not fail yourself.
Do not fail your family.
He is wearing a gold watch.
Bring it to me.
That kinda tickled...
It's gonna take more than
a knitting needle to fuck me up, boy.
Keep it.
It will remind you that
every moment of your life
is a gift that I have given you.
You have made me proud, my son.
Now the time must come for you
to prove you are true Ozunu.
She tried to get away from us.
From her family.
Takeshi caught her
and return her to us.
Weakness compels strength.
Betrayal begets blood.
This is the law of the Nine Clans.
You need protection.
No. I want Ozunu.
And I need your help to get him.
Exit here.
You are a size 36?
What? No! Size 34.
If you leave while I am gone
they will hunt you and kill you.
Do you understand?
Get undressed.
Shower, but do not use soap.
Do you smoke?
Put your clothes in here.
These jeans are a little tight.
You said 34.
Yeah, well it's German sizes.
They must run a little small I guess.
This is for a scent.
Right?
Let's go.
- Yeah?
- Ryan, it’s me.
Mika! For Christ sake
I’ve been calling you for hours!
I know.
I’m in a bit of trouble---
Trouble? Listen, you miss jury
service, you’re in trouble.
You’re in deepest shit
that you've ever been in.
Yeah, well, at least
I’m not down here by myself.
Sabatin's guy?
The one from the tape? Is he with you?
He’s on our side, Ryan. He wants Ozunu,
but he needs the Agency's help.
Be careful, Mika.
I trust him.
All right, look...
I can't make any promises
but if he cooperates
I'll do what I can.
- Can you meet us?
- Where?
How about the usual?
There he is.
It’s all right.
He's a good guy.
- Mika, you're okay?
- Yeah. Thanks to him.
- Why have you done this?
- Done what?
People will die.
Move it.
What the fuck are you doing?
Following orders.
Prisoner is secure sir.
Right.
He sure doesn't like
a killing machine to me, sir
He looks like he belongs in a boy band.
He couldn't have hurt us.
Could he?
- Sir.
Ryan, this is wrong!
I mean it can’t be legal!
What is this place?
Your private Guantanamo?
It’s an old GDR safe house.
Jamison wants this off the grid.
You’re making a huge mistake.
I don’t think so.
I got reports from London, Washington,
and Osaka all tagging your boy.
The only problem we have is
where to extradite him first.
So two weeks ago,
there’s no such thing as a ninja
and now every city in the
world has a warrant for one?
He’s not the enemy.
He’s a killer, Mika. Weren’t you the one
telling me it was our job to stop him.
You’re not even listening to me!
'Cause you’re not saying
anything worth hearing.
Look, you wanna do
the insubordination tango,
let’s go,
but not in front of the children okay?
Boys get out!
Come on! Let's go! Out!
Damn it, Ryan, I'm just trying---
Listen to me,
we don't have much time.
I don't know
what we've stumbled into here,
but somebody is pulling
some major strings inside.
They want him dead.
He’s been fighting them for years.
I believe you.
I've been in this business
too long not to smell a set-up.
But we have to be careful
how we handle this
and I cannot risk you
going AWOL on me again.
Now if you get into trouble...
you switch this on,
and no matter where you are,
I'll find you.
Hey.
You look thirsty.
I’m sorry.
I didn’t know about any of this.
I know.
You do?
The only time you lied to me was
when you told me your size.
How did you know that?
Your heart.
It is special.
Maslow is on our side.
He’s going to try to help you.
It’s too late.
Ryan, can I talk to you?
We have to do this again, Coretti?
I just...
I have reason to believe that a group
of ninja may be on their way here.
Well I think these gentlemen can handle
a few whack-jobs wearing pajamas.
- Am I right?
- "Yes"
- See?
- But the situation we discussed---
I’m working on that.
You have to give me some time.
We don’t have time.
- They’re not here now, aren't they?
- They’ll be here soon.
How soon?
Raizo.
- Mika!
- Go with her! Secure the prisoner!
Team two, we are on
our way down to the holding cell.
What's your 20?
We're just now entering Section 4.
- Occupied!
Good way to get yourself killed, Coretti.
I need that cell open.
We're moving the prisoner.
- Those are not my orders.
- Mika, get out of here!
Not without you.
Then we all die together.
Shit!
- Open that gate!
- I can't do that.
Going infrared boys.
- They are already in the room.
- Oh, Mika, Mika...
- Shhh
I like you more and more.
Okay, fuck it!
Shit!
- Mika hurry!
- Okay.
Mika, I don't want to sound critical...
Look I'm doing the best I can.
We don't have much time.
Let's go.
Wait here.
Let's go!
Get down! Get down!
I got him!
The car is upstairs.
Go.
- Go now.
- Okay.
Little brother.
Come on Raizo.
Raizo, where are you?
Shit!
Oh my God!
No!
xxx
Come on.
Good bye little brother.
Get in.
I can't believe I found you.
I was waiting for you.
Oh God!
You have to go to a hospital.
No.
Not a hospital.
Just keep moving.
- Mika, where are you?
- He told me to keep moving.
- Is he still alive?
- After a fashion.
Listen, I'm going to bring you in.
No, not this time.
Mika listen to me.
They’re too many people involved now.
- It’s just a matter of time.
- Yeah, I don’t think we have much time.
Mika don't ...
Mika?
I know you can’t hear me,
so I’m sure
this doesn’t matter, but ...
I’m going to say it anyway.
I’m just a forensic researcher.
That’s like a fancy way
of saying I’m a librarian.
By myself I can’t
do anything to help you.
I wanted to thank you
for saving my life.
And I hope
you can forgive me for this.
- Agent Maslow?
- Yeah?
- The tracking device.
- You've got a lock?
Triangulating her position now.
Right. I want the international transport
mobilize and ready to go in five minutes.
God damn it.
- You!
- No!
They took him.
Ten minutes ago.
He’s gone.
xxx
You are Ozunu.
You are part of me
as I am part of you.
This is the truth of your lives
and it will remain true after death.
My child.
It is good to see you again.
Do you know
there was a time
when I looked at you
I felt a sense of pride.
No child has shown more promise.
You are the son I was waiting for.
The one to take my place.
And now do you know
what you have done?
How you have shamed my family?
How you have hurt me.
Why do you think I did it?
Get this thing out of my sight.
Tonight we avenge
our brothers and sisters.
Tonight we avenge our honor.
Let his death will be remembered
for a thousand years.
Weakness compels strength.
Betrayal begets blood.
You're getting weak,
old man.
Father...
Go ahead!
Shit!
What took you?
You knew I'd come?
Just because I was asleep
doesn't mean I couldn't hear you.
And I forgive you.
Mika!
Come this way.
You swore to me
you would stay inside the APC.
I thought we were too late.
First team is ready, sir!
- Hit it!
- Go.
Stay here.
You two, with me.
Come, little brother,
let us play like old times.
My turn.
Do you still think about her?
Do you remember the sound
she made when I stuck her?
You remember all I taught you?
You are true Ozunu.
Come beg your father for forgiveness.
Your heart is weak.
Raizo!
All this loss is waste.
Because you put yourself
before your family.
This is not my family.
You're not my father.
And the breath I take
after I kill you
will be the first breath of my life.
Mika! Run!
Where is he?
Where is he!
Get away!
Mika!
No!
Most children are disappointments,
not worth the effort to raise.
Mika!
Jesus Christ what happened?
She saved my life.
Medic!
She will be all right.
Her heart is special.
I need a medic here now!
- She gonna be all right?
- I don’t understand...
She’s got a hole right through
the middle of her heart but...
My heart is over here.
You...
Come with me.
- subs by majortjkong