Yeah, that's it.
I was out there on the road
Life out of control
She became a victim
to my busy schedule
And I know that it's not fair
That don't mean
that I don't care
This one's dedicated
to the girl out there
- Okay. Good job.
- Thank you.
No.
If I shaved right now...
Shave it.
No, I'm not doing this, bro.
But why the mustache?
I wanna feel
I'm grown up, you know.
There's a phase you go
through when you think
that the mustache actually
looks good on you.
But, um...
It's delusional. It's just all...
It's all delusional.
Basically this 'stache
is to make me think
or feel a little bit older.
See, when I can grow a full beard
like that, I'm gonna be rocking.
But this right here,
it's coming.
- So, um...
- You should slate this.
Okay, let's slate it.
When you've reached
a certain point in your life,
there are people out there
who sit waiting,
wanting to see you fall.
But rather than let gravity
take you down,
sometimes you have to take
matters into your own hands...
...and fly.
Let's go!
What's up, Miami?
How you feeling tonight?
If you're ready to believe,
let's make some noise.
You're beautiful, beautiful
you should know it
I think it's time
Think it's time
That you show it
You're beautiful, beautiful
Baby, what you doin'?
Where you at, where you at?
Why you actin' so shy?
Holdin' back, holdin' back
We're not the only ones
Doin' it like that It like that
So DJ bring that Bring that
Bring that Bring that back
'Cause all around the world
people want to be loved
Yeah
'Cause all around the world
Miami! We need you
to put your hands up!
They're no different than us
Right now!
Yeah
'Cause all around the world
People want to be loved
Yeah
'Cause all around the world
They're no different than us
All around the world
What's up, Miami?
You know I've been
all around the world, right?
Well, tonight I wanna take you with me.
You ready?
One, two...
All around the world
People want to be loved
Yeah
'Cause all around the world
They're no different than us
All around the world
People wanna be loved
They're no different than us
All around the world
You...
Beyond all the lights
and, you know, the hype
and all the scrutiny
and the pressure,
at the end of the day,
it comes down to a young man
in a room writing a song.
I don't know about you...
That's where it all starts.
And with Justin, it starts
with a pad of paper and a pen
and a melody in his head that's
probably been there a very long time
and he just needs to get it out.
Music is his therapy.
Music is his release.
If I was your boyfriend...
There?
If I was your boyfriend
I'd never let you go
I can take you places
you ain't never been before
Baby, take a chance
or you'll never ever know
I got money in my hands
that I'd really like to blow
Swag, swag, on you
Chillin' by the fire
while we eatin' fondue
I don't know about me
but I know about you
So say hello to falsetto
in three, two
Let me hear that pass.
If I was your boyfriend
I'd never let you go
I've known him
for four years now.
And when I met him,
he was just a little kid.
Yeah, man,
yeah, man, yeah. Ready?
It'll look like I'm gonna die.
But I'm really not gonna die.
Just watch.
- I'm gonna do it again.
- No, no, no. You gotta shower.
- Get in the shower.
- One more time.
Here, you take this.
I gotta go do something.
It was just us, you know, in a
van going around the country.
And really it started as me,
Ryan, Pattie and Justin.
- Last one. Go.
- Ready?
Fantastic.
Then it went to
the My World  tour.
And in that tour, he went
from being a kid on a stoop
who sang on YouTube to being
a worldwide arena veteran.
I'd like to be
everything you want
Hey, girl, let me talk to you
Man, the trials of
being a teenager, period.
I mean, it's tumultuous, but,
I mean, you just add on top
of being one of the most sought
after young icons of our time.
It's like a Pandora's Box.
Justin feels a lot of pressure,
a lot of unseen pressure,
to keep outdoing himself.
There's a lot of
expectation on him.
You know, part of his childhood
was taken away from him
from working very early on,
and, you know,
he's constantly being judged.
He's in a constant
search for validation
'cause everyone's just waiting.
You know, they're constantly
just waiting for it to stop.
In a weird way
because of doubts,
we keep finding ourselves
the underdog.
Hey, what's the situation?
Whoa
I'm just trying to make
a little conversation
Why the hesitation?
Whoa
Tell me what your name is
For your information
Don't get me wrong
You know you're right
Don't be so cold,
we could be fire
Tomorrow we go
Let's start tonight
You know what it's all about
I can take you out
I can take you home
I can take you, oh...
Where you wanna go
I can pick it up
We could take it slow
I can take you home Oh, oh, oh
I can take you out
I can take you home
I can take you
Where you wanna go
I can pick it up
We could take it slow
I can take you home Oh, oh, oh
I can take you out
I can take you home
I can get you out
I can take you home Oh, oh, oh
Baby, señorita, ma chérie
Please be my little lady
My little lady, yeah
Mi amor, you're the one I adore
Come on, be my little lady
My little lady
I can take you home
I can take you, oh...
Where you wanna go
I can pick it up
We could take it slow
I can take you home Oh, oh, oh
The first time he told me
that he wanted to
name the album "Believe,"
he said, "I just want for
people to believe in me,
"but at the same
time I want them to know
"that they helped
get me here."
I've been supporting him
since day one.
Ever since those videos
on YouTube before  One Time.
That was us.
We were the comments.
I loved him from,
like, the beginning
when he was making
videos on YouTube.
And, oh, my gosh, I don't know.
He's just so amazing.
He's so hot.
The haters are just jealous.
Yeah.
And they don't...
I don't think... They just
don't understand his music.
They don't.
Yeah, they just think,
"Oh, it's Justin Bieber, he's
a guy, we can't like him."
But, like, that's not it. He's
a musician, not just a guy.
I thought he was cute last year,
but, like, as I'm getting older
and as he's getting older,
like, oh, my God,
he's just getting
even more cuter every day.
He's an idol for me
and really talented, so...
- Pull up that acoustic for me, Brent.
- All right.
You know, we have
different relationships
with different producers,
the people that he goes in with
and sees if he vibes with.
Mike Posner, Max Martin...
-  ...Will.i.am.
- Can you feel it in this beat?
Okay.
No, that's my heart, girl.
And Rodney Jerkins.
Working with Justin, he'll
play me 20, 30 ideas and say,
"No, man, I got ideas. I got
ideas I gotta get out of me."
And I thrive off of that
because that just shows me
how much he loves music.
You know, Rodney Jerkins,
that's like Michael Jackson,
that's Mariah Carey.
Like those are,
like, the top of the top.
Like, Rodney Jerkins,
he's a legend.
They start working and
Rodney just has this beat.
And he's hitting the drums
and he's hitting the piano.
He's going back and forth
with the drums and the piano,
and Justin's vibing out
and then Justin starts,
"Can I try something?
Can I try something?"
And Rodney's like,
"Go, go, go."
And then Justin starts trying to
figure out hooks and melodies,
and then Rodney's doing
his hooks and his melodies.
And then it just kept growing
and growing and growing.
We have a responsibility
to our journey.
Even though
you're singing a song
and it's about
your situation in your life,
you're singing it for
everyone else to connect to.
So what you're
going through, tell it,
tell the story,
make it come to life,
'cause that's what it's about.
Just take them
on this crazy journey.
To get them second-guessing
and be like, "I already know
how the song's gonna end,"
then boom, you smack them in
the face with a Filet-O-Fish,
you know what I'm saying,
you get white stuff all up
the side of their head.
So, like, that's what you wanna
do, you know what I'm saying,
'cause they think you're hitting
them with French fries.
A lot of times,
he kinda just starts rapping,
and he'll just start rapping
his verses.
And then the verses will
start coming onto the songs.
Take it slow, girl
'Cause things get...
No, girl
'Cause things get crazy
up on that road
He'll get a track and then
he'll start getting an idea.
He'll write down a little bit
or write it down on his phone
in his notepad.
Hey, you are the one thing
It would be that I just...
And then go into, like...
I... I... I want,
want, want you, you, you
And then he'll
go back on it again
and he'll start putting
more words to it.
I want you, you, you
Okay. I just...
Don't let it get in the way
Let's take it easy
Oh, oh
Don't let it get in the way
You know, it just
naturally kinda happened.
You know, the song
started flowing and...
And the kids have been waiting
for Believe  for so long.
We revved up the first single, and all
they know is the name is "Boyfriend."
- I can just guess how it goes.
- How does it go?
If I was your boyfriend...
That's exactly how it...
Never let you go
That's exactly how it goes.
Ever, ever, ever let you go
That's exactly...
Girl
How did you know that?
I'm just guessing that
that's how it would go.
I worked on
the record Boyfriend,
and originally
the song was gonna be called
"Inside of Your Bedroom,"
and I always hated that.
Then we were in the studio with
Justin and, like, really hit a wall.
Like, what can we say
instead of that?
Finally we came up with,
"If I was your boyfriend."
And I loved that.
I knew that was it.
Let's do this!
And we're just in
full-on countdown mode.
One day, 12 hours,
six hours, 30 minutes,
seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one.
If I was your boyfriend
I'd never let you go
I can take you places
you ain't never been before
Baby, take a chance
or you'll never ever know
I got money in my hands
that I'd really like to blow
Swag, swag, swag, on you
Chillin' by the fire
while we eatin' fondue
I don't know about me
but I know about you
So say hello to falsetto
In three, two...
I'd like to be
everything you want
Hey, girl, let me talk to you
If I was your boyfriend
I'd never let you go
Keep you on my arm, girl
You'd never be alone
I can be a gentleman
- Your new song, that's pretty sexy.
- Oh, you like it?
I tell everybody that you're
not the Biebs anymore, man,
you are Mr. Bieber.
Tell me about picking Boyfriend
as your first single.
I feel like every single that's
dropping is like this...
Right, right.
So I wanted to do
something a little different,
slow it down, something a
little bit more mature.
When the faders are up and you
pull all that music down,
and all you have is that vocal,
if it's a hit then,
then it'll be a hit always.
People absolutely
love the record.
It debuted number one
on the Billboard charts,
and everyone really received
how his voice had matured.
Let me talk to you
If I was your boyfriend
I'd never let you go
Keep you on my arm, girl
You'd never be alone
I can be a gentleman
anything you want
If I was your boyfriend
I'd never let you go
Never let you go
Yeah, girl
If I was your boyfriend
There was so much talk about
what you were going to do next.
I mean, everybody
in the music business,
everybody in the world
had an opinion about it.
Did you listen to all that?
Did you shut the door and say,
"You know what, I'm not
gonna hear any of them,
"I'm just gonna focus
on what's inside of me?"
I'm the only one who can
ultimately make those decisions
because, like, I'm gonna have to live
with my career for the rest of my life,
so I have to make
those decisions,
where I want my career to go.
So she was sleeping and I was
waiting till, like 12:00 a.m.,
like, for when it
was released on iTunes.
And right when it was released,
I called her and I was like,
"We have to buy it.
We have to buy it right now."
So we bought it
and we just listened to it
together on the phone,
like, the whole time.
Justin Bieber's album Believe
scored the number one spot
on the Billboard 200 Chart,
selling 374,000 copies
in the first week.
It was about making music
that was real to him,
but that was also
real to the fans.
You know, it had to
connect emotionally.
We were on the phone together
and we were both crying
listening to  Be Alright,
and we're like,
"This is the best song."
Best song ever.
As Long As You Love Me,
it's definitely the best.
Yeah.
Thought of You, I love that song.
That's a personal favorite.
Oh, my God, that's his bus.
I'm psyched to play it on the radio.
This is a massive, monster hit.
It feels good.
Girl, I'm in love
with the thought of you
The album was out.
It's number one.
But at the end of the day, Justin
wants to be known as an entertainer.
You wanna be one of those artists
that every generation waits
for that concert
to come to town.
And we needed someone that
Justin really trusted creatively
to direct our tour.
That person was
shooting a movie.
One morning I got a call
from Scooter, and he said,
"You know, last time you did a
little enhancement on his show.
"What if this time you got it
from the ground up
"where there is
no show right now
"and you would work with
Justin to create the show?"
And we were going to force him
one way or another
to commit to us.
Justin called me and Scooter
kept calling me and...
Me and Justin had a plan.
And I said, "Hey, me and
Justin are over here,
"we're hanging out,
come over and see us."
I'm, I'm hanging out right now.
And, I have my friend
Nick DeMoura here.
Hello.
And we have
a special announcement.
Um, Tom is back,
our production manager.
And, um, uh... Oh, oh,
this is Justin Bieber.
What's up, everybody?
I'm Justin.
And as soon as he got there, Justin
and I just completely cornered him.
They said, "You're not
leaving this house
"until you agree
to do this show."
And, Justin, we have
a special announcement
- about the  Believe tour.
- What is it?
Well, I think
someone's just joining on
officially to come and help
us creatively direct it.
No, really?
Yeah, yeah,
to creatively direct it.
- No. Who did?
- Who did what?
- Why don't you sit down over there.
- Maybe it's Jon Chu.
- Jonathan M. Chu.
- Hello.
What's up, everybody?
And then Justin was like, "So
are you in or are you not?"
I said, "Well, I don't know yet.
"I gotta figure out my schedule.
"I gotta see
your guys' schedule."
He's like, "Jon, you're not leaving
this until you say you're in."
Jon has a problem
saying no to Justin.
Oh, my God.
Can I open this one now?
What do you got?
She's crying
with tears of joy, right?
Let me see.
Tears of joy.
Oh, my God.
Catherine, let me see.
- Live Justin Bieber tickets.
- What is it?
Say you love me
As much as I love you, yeah
Would you hurt me, baby?
Could you do that to me, yeah?
Would you lie to me, baby?
'Cause the truth hurts
so much more
Would you do the things
that drive me crazy?
Leave my heart
still at the door?
Oh, I can't help it
I'm just selfish
There's no way
that I could share you
That would break
my heart to pieces
Honestly the truth is
If I could just die in your arms
I wouldn't mind
'Cause every time you touch me
I just die in your arms
Ooh, it feels so right
So, baby, baby,
please don't stop, girl
Music is
what brings us together.
I can't tell you how many friends
I've made because of music.
Oh, if there is a reason...
Music is a universal language
that could describe
any moment in life.
I hear a certain song,
it reminds me of my first
heartbreak, first love.
As any human being,
you've heard a song
and it catches you
and it's a visceral reaction.
Your mind isn't doing
any work, but your gut,
your heart, your soul,
whatever you wanna call it,
it feels it.
Oh, I can't help it
I'm just selfish
There's no way
that I could share you
That would break
my heart to pieces
Honestly the truth is
If I could just
die in your arms...
I love music.
I love making music.
I like making music that
travels all around the world.
And people are all in
different countries,
Mexico, London, France,
all over the world
are singing the lyrics.
They might not even
know how to speak English,
but they're singing
those lyrics.
That's what it's about.
If I could die...
Don't stop, baby, no
It's what you do to me
Yeah, yeah
Have you been in love?
Have I been...
Of course I've been in love.
Um, I think being in love is
the most powerful thing ever.
It's an extreme feeling,
being in love.
Have you ever had heartbreak?
Yes, yes, definitely.
That's...
That's even, I would say, it's
about just the same feeling.
As much as it is
to fall in love,
like, in that...
It's that explosiveness,
that fire,
just when you break up from that,
if you give them everything,
and you break up
from that, you're...
It's the same type...
It's like that
clenching feeling like...
Oh, like, when you...
This is my feeling.
Like, "Oh, I love her
so much."
But then that's the same feeling
when we break up, it's like,
"Oh, like, this hurts.
This hurts so deep."
It's just the same emotion,
but, uh, flipped backwards.
I'm here at Justin Bieber's
world tour audition.
This is the first time
he's using girls,
so I feel pretty honored to hopefully
be one of the first to do that.
Over there are a bunch of lovely
ladies fighting for the gig.
And there's limited spots,
so it's pretty nerve-racking
standing next to a good friend
and knowing that one of you may
make it, and one of you may not.
Move, cha, pa, boom, boom, hold!
Move, ba, da, da, hold.
Pop, pop, shoo, pop, pop,
pop, pop, pop, hold.
Let's go!
Five, six... Eight.
Hold... Whoa!
This is something that has
been itching on the inside.
Like, I've never really
been on a tour before.
And this would be
such a dream come true.
I'm getting older
and I feel like
if there's one time to do it,
if there's one moment to have,
it'd be this one here.
Here we go.
Let's get cracking.
Justin just came in. Yeah,
so no pressure, you know.
I just was, like, so in there. I
was like, "I want this so bad."
So I was really nervous,
but I worked so hard
at that audition.
I was fortunate enough
to work with him before
on the promo tour,
and I see how he works
and how dedicated he is
and how involved he
is with his music.
It's not people just
telling him what to do.
It's really coming from him.
So it'd be such an honor
to be a part of his growth
and watch his journey.
Here, brother.
Hey, CJ. It's, uh, Jon Chu.
Most jobs, you don't get a
personal call like that.
So when that happened,
it really, like,
I really feel like
I earned my spot.
I remember your exact words.
You were like...
You got the job.
You're going on the tour.
Are you serious?
I was, like, screaming.
I was like, uh, just tears.
I'm so excited
to work with you, Jon.
- I'm so excited.
- Me, too.
And then that moment that
it became ours, it was,
I mean, yeah,
completely indescribable.
I think he just started crying.
I think he was crying.
We made him cry, yes.
- Make your dreams come true
- True
Miami...
I need you to put
your hands in the air,
right now, hands up!
Show you off
Tonight I wanna show you off
What you got
A billion could've never bought
We gonna party
like it's 3012 tonight
I wanna show you
all the finer things in life
So just forget about the world
We're young tonight
I'm coming for ya
'Cause all I need
Is a beauty and a beat
Who can make my life complete
Once again, Miami,
hands up right now.
Let's go.
It's all about you
Hands up.
When the music makes you move
Baby, do it like you do...
We had about eight or 12 weeks
to put this show together.
We had to build custom sets
and design the costumes
and the music.
In the middle of it all,
Scooter and Justin
came to me, they're like,
"Hey, we're gonna shoot this music
video for  Beauty and A Beat."
"Oh, that's great,
have fun."
Scooter said, "I don't
think you understand.
"We'd really love it if you
were to help Justin direct it."
I said, "What?"
All right.
No peeing in the water.
So five, six, seven, eight.
One more time, sorry.
One, two, three, four.
It's all in his hands
'cause he's the one
who's holding the camera,
shooting the thing,
directing the thing.
And he's dancing
in between all of that.
Yes.
And we have, like, 50 dancers,
synchronized swimmers
on the side,
people flipping into the water.
We gonna party
like it's 3012 tonight
I wanna show you
all the finer things in life
So just forget about the world
We're young tonight
I'm coming for ya
'Cause all...
Nicki Minaj will be there.
We're gonna throw her
in the water.
Uh, I'm just kidding.
I wanna know how Nicki Minaj
is gonna get on that platform.
I feel like there's a lot of things
we haven't thought about yet.
We should probably
harness her in somehow.
- Just lift her.
- Yeah.
When the music makes you move
Baby, do it like you do
In time, ink lines
Bitches couldn't get
on my incline
World tours, it's mine
Ten little letters on a big sign
Justin Bieber, you know
I'mma hit 'em with the ether
Buns out, wiener
But I gotta keep
an eye out for Selena
Beauty, beauty and the beast
Beauty from the east
Beautiful confessions
of the priest
Beast, beauty from the streets
We don't get deceased
Every time a beauty on the beats
Body rock, oh
I wanna feel your body rock
Raise your hands up, let's go.
'Cause all
I need is a beauty and a beat
Who can make my life complete
'Cause...
Here he comes,
here he comes. Yeah.
And everyone's
cheering at the end.
That is true, true joy
because everyone's
so tired and excited
that Justin got to direct
his first music video.
That's awesome.
Justin Bieber.
Yeah!
Oh, my God.
- Hannah?
- Hey, that's enough.
You got me tickets
to Justin Bieber!
Okay. That's enough.
When I start choreographing,
I just try to hear
what the song is about.
I try not to, like, control the
song, what I want it to do.
The song was there before I was,
so I let it move me.
I try to, like, show you what
the song should look like.
This show is crazy.
We rehearsed, you know,
12-hour days, you know, for
about two months straight
with Justin.
Hey, not like that.
- Zoop. Zoop.
- Yeah!
- All right. I'm good.
- Zoop, yeah.
Hoorah, baby.
I think the hardest
part was taking it
from the dance studio
to the actual set,
and the actual toaster lifts
and the actual fly gags
and timing-wise and
transitioning everything,
I think that was
the hardest part.
And I'm going up
while this is playing?
Justin, he had a lot more input.
Here he had his own ideas
he wanted to contribute,
so it's a lot more of him
giving himself to his fans,
um, which makes the show
a lot more personal to him.
Being young and in the industry,
there's a lot of things that
people tell you to say, right?
The music that I'm making now,
it's all creatively
coming from me,
and I wanna do what I want.
Like, if I'm not happy
with what I wanna do
and who I wanna be, then who...
I'm not gonna be happy.
We talked a lot about
what does this album mean.
And he says, "You know what, a
lot of people want me to fail."
But he's like,
"That doesn't bother me.
"'Cause no matter what,
my fans are there
"and they'll make me fly."
And that really triggered,
in my mind, like,
"All right, we're gonna
make you fly."
You're gonna come in
and you're gonna fly.
With the cheers of your audience,
they're gonna keep you up,
and you're gonna fly in on wings made of
instruments because it's your talent.
And instruments,
not just random instruments,
but instruments that you play.
So we have drums.
We have keyboards.
We have all these things
that he plays
built into these wings
to symbolize
that he's built of
many, many parts.
That's what makes him
Justin Bieber.
As long as you love me
We're under pressure
Seven billion people in the
world trying to fit in
Keep it together
Smile on your face even
though your heart is frowning
But hey now, you know, girl
We both know it's a cruel world
But I will take my chances
As long as you love me
We could be starving
We could be homeless
We could be broke
As long as you love me
I'll be your platinum
I'll be your silver
I'll be your gold
As long as you love me
Love me
I'll be your soldier
Fighting every second of the day
For your dreams, girl
I'll be your Hova
You could be my Destiny's Child
On the scene, girl
But don't stress
And don't cry
No, we don't need
no wings to fly
Just take my hand
As long as you love me
We could be starving
We could be homeless
We could be broke
As long as you love me
I'll be your platinum
I'll be your silver
I'll be your gold
As long as you love me
Yo, B-I-G
I don't know if this makes sense
But you're my hallelujah
Give me a time and place,
I'll rendezvous it
I'll fly you to it,
I'll beat you there
Girl, you know I got you
Us, trust...
A couple of things
I can't spell without "u"
Now we are on top of the world
'Cause that's just how we do
Used to tell me sky's the limit
Now the sky's our point of view
We'll be stepping out like, whoa
Cameras point and shoot
Ask me what's my best side
I stand back and point at you
You, you the one
that I argue with
I feel like I need a new
girl to be bothered with
But the grass ain't always
greener on the other side
It's green where you water it
So I know we got issues, baby
True, true, true
But I'd rather work
on this with you
Than to go ahead
and start with someone new
As long as you love me
We could be starving
We could be homeless
We could be broke
As long as you love me
I'll be your platinum
I'll be your silver
I'll be your gold
Miami, make some noise!
As long as you love me
I'll be your platinum
I'll be your silver
I'll be your gold
As long as you...
As long as you love me
We could be starving
We could be homeless
We could be broke
Justin!
Baby, baby, baby, oh
Six-year-old Avalanna Routh
is a huge Justin Bieber fan.
And now there's a Facebook page
dedicated to trying to get her
to meet the pop superstar.
Avalanna had become
Mrs. Bieber at her hospital.
She had a rare disease.
She loved Justin and they got
a cardboard cutout of Justin.
And she had a whole fake
wedding at her hospital
with this cardboard cutout.
And it was
on the news in Boston.
And I was just blown away.
She was adorable.
So I called Justin.
He said, "Let's meet her.
"I'm gonna be
in New York next week.
"Let's bring her
down from Boston."
And, you know, it was supposed
to be a quick meet and greet,
and he ended up
spending hours with her.
I met with her and it wasn't...
It wasn't normal.
It was different.
It wasn't like I was
just meeting another fan.
It was like...
It was so special.
I sat down. I played
board games with her.
I thought she was
super adorable.
It is.
And they got really, really
close like a big brother,
but she called him her husband.
And he called her
Mrs. Bieber.
- Name is?
- She is Mrs. Bieber.
And basically she had
her own little wedding
- at the hospital.
- Yeah.
She was like,
"You're my husband,
"so my mom's
your mother-in-law."
And she's so little and it's
like, "Wow, she's so cute."
Ducks, ducks, ducks.
Quack, quack, quack.
Smooth.
Avalanna put her hands over her
ears and he was singing to her.
And then he goes, "What's
wrong?" And she goes,
"It's so loud in here.
Why are they screaming?
"You're my husband."
What, are they...
Are they just really loud?
They're very loud.
But that's a good thing.
That's a good thing
because that just means
they're really supportive fans.
Yeah.
So, we're gonna get
you back over there to Mom.
But did you have fun up here?
Yeah, I have to wear earphones.
Okay.
Okay. Well, we'll get you another
pair of earphones side stage, okay,
and you can watch
the rest of the show?
Is that gonna be cool?
Yeah?
Wanna give me a hug?
Okay. We'll get you
some earphones, sweetie.
Come on, let's go.
I love him.
That was so cute.
That was adorable.
Oh, my God.
And, uh...
I'm sorry...
Oh, my God.
It's just like...
But... Give a round of
applause for Avalanna.
Then slowly...
...her talking,
her speech...
...started to slow down.
And her eye started
shutting on her left side.
And, um...
It was just...
It was just hard to see.
But...
I miss her, bro.
Our first show, Avalanna unfortunately
died just four days earlier,
and all of us were feeling it.
Tonight's Lonely Girl
is super special
because, um...
This song is dedicated
to, um, to sweet Avalanna.
So, um...
Avalanna, if you're listening,
I love you.
And everyone... Everyone
in here loves you as well.
So, um, this one's for you.
One less lonely girl
And Justin didn't feel like
it was right to sing
to a girl that night 'cause he
had just shared the last time
he performed One Less Lonely
Girl, it was her in the chair.
We took a bunch of pictures. We
put them into a huge montage.
During One Less Lonely Girl,
we put them up on the screen.
How many bags you packed
Just to take them back?
Tell me that
How many either or's?
But no more if you let me
inside of your world
There'll be one
less lonely girl...
And he didn't walk to the chair.
He walked to the top and he
stared and he sang to the screen.
Before I saw you
Now all I see is you
Oh, no, don't need
these other pretty faces
'Cause when you're mine,
in the world...
I think that was
his way of saying goodbye.
There's gonna be
one less lonely girl
One less lonely girl
I'm coming for you
There's gonna be
one less lonely girl
I'm coming for you
I'm gonna put you first
I'll show you what you're worth
If you let me inside
of your world
There's gonna be
one less lonely girl
One less lonely girl
I'm coming for you
There's gonna be
one less lonely girl
She touched all of
us in her short time
on this planet, and, you know,
those are the things
that make the job real.
We'll never forget her.
That's row four,
seat one. Hot seats.
So things have changed since the
last tour and Never Say Never.
It was an amazing experience
and something that
we'll all be proud of
the rest of our lives,
but now we can't go outside.
- You guys need tickets?
- No, no, we've got tickets.
Kenny goes
outside and gets mobbed.
Kenny!
Dan Kanter
We wrote this song for you
We hope you like it
We really do
You know, Allison can't choose the
One Less Lonely Girl  anymore,
so when I go outside now
I have to literally
disguise myself or hide
to navigate the giveback
that we do every show,
'cause we still give
away those tickets.
Can we have a picture with you?
Would you mind if I hug you?
All right.
So here's my problem...
Yeah.
- I don't have enough tickets to take care of everybody.
- Aw.
Who's gonna stay outside out of your six?
You gotta pick one person.
Can we have a minute
to talk about it?
- You wanna have a minute to talk about it?
- Yeah, a minute.
I can't do that.
I want, like, you don't...
I can't.
No, no,
you were like one of the...
What? So you won't go?
All right.
She's gonna stay. Hug her
'cause you guys get to go in.
No, no.
Hey, wait, come here,
come here, come here...
You guys trying to buy tickets?
You have tickets?
You have any?
- Yeah, we did.
- What happened to them?
They're fraud?
And they said they're
fraud at the box office?
- Yeah.
- Are you upset?
Yeah.
- Oh, my God.
- Shh. Shh.
Oh, my God.
I can't breathe.
I'm gonna cry.
Guys?
Yes.
Girls, you have to hurry to get
to your front row tickets.
Front row!
We still go outside and make
sure kids are taken care of.
We still go up to the top
deck and upgrade people.
And there's no better
feeling in the world.
We just gotta be
a little sneakier about it.
You don't owe me anything.
We're good.
Watch the cables
and watch your fingers,
video wall coming in.
Okay. Lock number
one set, everybody.
Being on tour,
we go to city to city to city,
that schedule, it's so draining.
He would just be on the bus
and he'll just be
in a stare, just like...
And I'll just
be like, "Hey."
It's 7:00 a.m., barely slept
anything, just had a show,
three shows in a row,
so exhausted.
You just wanna run in the
hotel and just go to sleep.
This go round is way more
popular than in my world.
There's a lot more
people outside.
There's a lot more people at the
bus, so it's hard to be normal.
We can sneak off and try to
be as normal as possible.
But feeling normal,
I don't think that's possible.
When he's hiding in the trunk of a
car so we can go get ice cream,
sticking his hand out
of the trunk just to feel air
so he doesn't, like,
go crazy of claustrophobia,
and we're doing all of this
just to sneak to go grab
some ice cream.
How can that even
feel halfway normal?
He's gotta go through things with everyone
watching every step that he makes.
Justin, do you love your fans?
Do you love your fans, Justin?
There's somewhat of a gift
and a curse in being popular.
Move out of the way, man.
You gotta move out of the way.
What'd you say?
I'd been chased by those
same people that whole trip,
and they were talking
nonsense the whole time,
like verbally assaulting me.
As a human being,
rage comes out,
and I happened to snap,
and I opened the door
and I was like, "What do you...
"What are you guys..."
I really wanted to hit him.
We ended up peeling off.
I learned from that.
That's what they wanted.
They wanted to get
a reaction out of me
so that they could print that,
so that they could
make me seem like this,
"Oh, I'm out of control."
But really I'm just...
I have a heart
and I have feelings.
And when people...
When people...
...like hurt my heart,
I'm gonna get angry, upset
and lash out sometimes
'cause I'm a human being.
Here we go.
She don't like the flash
Wanna keep us in the dark
She don't like the fame
Hate it when we're miles apart
Here we go.
It's getting to the point
where it's too much for her
Throw us all away
'cause it's too much for her
She can't hide away
'Cause the world
knows who we are
She don't like the lights
She don't, she don't, she don't
Don't wanna share
with no one else
Want me to herself
Don't want no love
in front of the camera
She don't like the lights
She don't, she don't, she don't
Bieber is no stranger
to flipping off photographers,
but is his behavior
becoming more erratic?
He's out of control.
She's giving ultimatums
She don't like this life
She said if I loved her
I'd give it up,
won't think twice
I can't do that
It's getting to the point
where it's too much for her
Wanna throw it all away
'Cause it's too much for her
She don't wanna live this life
-  Oh
- She don't like the lights
She don't, she don't, she don't
She don't like the lights
Don't wanna share
with no one else
Want me to herself
Don't want no love
in front of the camera
She don't like the lights
She don't, she don't, she don't
How can I choose between the two
When all the lights
are all I know?
I wish she could see
how good this can be
I hope that she waits
a little bit longer
'Cause I don't wanna live life
Without her by my side
'Cause she gives
the light that's in me
But she don't know
She don't like the lights
She don't, she don't, she don't
People on the outside
look in at celebrities,
especially people like Lindsay
Lohan, Britney, almost...
They feel sad.
You look at Michael Jackson,
you feel sad
because they're like,
you can't...
- Yes.
- ...escape this.
It is an inevitability that a young
person will become a train wreck.
Do you think about that?
And are you conscious that you
are the perfect candidate
to become a train wreck?
You are.
- We talk about this all the time.
- Um.
What? We talk about
this all the time.
There's no train wreck.
What... I'm living here,
I'm 19, by myself in this...
In this great house, just...
But that's where
the train wreck can start.
- How can... How?
- 'Cause it's safe.
- 'Cause it's a bubble.
- But there's no...
No one can tell you no.
So now what?
Now what are you gonna do
when no one can say no?
No one can say no,
but here's the thing,
for me, I've seen it happen.
I can't...
I'm not gonna be
stupid enough to...
For me to let
that happen to myself
because I have a good
head on my shoulders.
Maybe I might make a few
mistakes, sure, I'm 19.
But I was raised, like,
Sunday school every Sunday,
like, I was the... My mom
broke it down to me,
like, this is who you are,
you're gonna be a good person,
you're gonna help people, you're
gonna be quick to forgive,
you're gonna be a humble,
genuine person.
And if you're not, there's
gonna be consequences.
She doesn't agree with some
of the decisions that I make.
Sometimes... Well, all
moms don't agree with...
But she knows that I got
a good head on my shoulders.
She did what she
had to do to raise me.
And she did a wonderful,
wonderful job.
And I'm super,
super grateful for her.
You know what, I don't like your
attitude, to be quite honest.
You're mad.
Because, you know what,
you're too young
to be peepeeing in buckets
and driving up and down
the highway fast.
I don't think your mom would really
mind if a stranger whipped her son.
You ain't spanking me, man.
Ow! What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Whoo!
So who are you dating now?
So I'm backstage at,
um, my concert.
I just wanted to make this video
because I just saw Justin's VD.
You really inspire me.
I really, like...
You're the reason why I wake up with
a smile on my face every morning.
Yes, I will stay
with you forever.
I just love you so much, Justin,
and hope you're
gonna see this video
'cause otherwise I'm
really gonna look stupid.
Yeah.
Thank you for everything
you've done for us,
for the fans,
for everybody and...
Justin's dedication to his fans
and his fans' dedication to him
is what keeps him alive I think,
because if he gets
too far off track,
they're there to kinda
be that moral compass
that brings him back always.
Oh, my...
Look, how close we are.
Oh, my God.
It all started... It all
stemmed off from my fans
showing up at
each radio station.
My fans posting,
like, video responses
before I was signed.
It all started from the fans, so
it's gotta end up with the fans.
It's all about the fans.
- Thank you, Justin.
- Thank you.
I might cry a little bit 'cause
that was so cute. Oh, my gosh.
Look at that hairdo.
My music is evolving
'cause I'm growing up.
My fans are
gonna grow up with me
and they're gonna like my music
evolving because they're getting older.
And I want them to be a part
of this journey with me.
Songs like
Believe  and Be Alright,
pure acoustic, represent hope
and represent a connection
that a lot of people need.
Hey, Dan, you ready?
Always ready?
All right. Well, I gotta make
sure my safety is first, right?
Safety comes first.
Oh, you guys like safety?
Miami must love safety.
All right.
Across the ocean
Across the sea
Starting to forget the way
you look at me now
Over the mountains
Across the sky
Need to see your face
I need to look in your eyes
Through the storm
and through the clouds
Bumps on the road
and we're upside down
I know it's hard, babe
To sleep at night
Don't you worry
'Cause everything's
gonna be all right
Be all right
My show now is super elaborate,
but my favorite part is literally
just the intimate moments
with the fans when
I'm on that crane
and I'm in the crowd with them
and I can see each
one of their faces,
they're jumping up
and down screaming...
There's nothing
like that feeling.
I have goose bumps
right now thinking about it,
for real.
You know that I care for you
I'll always be there for you
I promise
I'll just stay right here
Yeah
I know that you want me, too
Baby, we can make
it through anything
And everything's
gonna be all right
Be all right
Through the long nights
and the bright lights
Don't you worry
'Cause everything's
gonna be all right
Thank you.
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
Yo, no, close the door.
Close the doors, bro.
Push the front
button down there.
Where's the button?
Back up!
Back up, back up!
Yo, watch out,
watch out, watch out.
Lock the door, yo.
You said you wanted me
But I said no
'Cause all I can say is
Please
We have a journey.
We have a responsibility
to our journey.
We must complete our journey
the best way we know how.
But along the way, we have to
tell the stories of the journey.
'Cause that journey, by the way,
is gonna help someone
make it through their journey.
I need some space
To come around you
Around, around,
around, around, around
You know, if you're an
artist that is after fame,
after money,
and you achieve those things,
then you have no
reason to go forward.
If your goals are
to make great music,
to be a better
and better singer,
to be a better and
better writer every day,
then that's a lifelong journey
and that doesn't end.
It's a weird position to be in
when you've only been winning,
but he doesn't really understand
what the loss looks like.
That's why it's important for
him to just stay humble,
stay on that humble path,
because the minute
something goes wrong,
everybody's gonna
try to tear him apart.
You know, and he has to always
remember what got him there.
You gonna get through
the whole time this time?
I'll try.
All right. Go ahead.
Um, yeah.
If I wasn't scared
that'd be a bad thing.
We've had moments
over the last year
where it's just been
straight yelling, screaming,
tears, hugs.
I mean, we're going like this
and he'll call me and be like,
- "You just need to come here."
- Just come here.
And you need to spend time,
you need to be around me,
and I want you to be
around me 'cause I want...
I want you in my life and I want
you to see what's going on.
And...
No, but it's always
gonna be that way,
and honestly I'm a better man
because he's in my life
and because I'm going through
these struggles with him.
- That's so sweet...
- Thanks, man. Appreciate it.
That's one of the sweetest
things you've ever said.
But, you know, we're gonna
keep going through...
Hey, man. Um...
We're gonna keep going
through these struggles
and it's not
gonna get any easier,
but at the end of the day,
he's worth it.
You guys seem to help.
Believe, believe, believe.
It's our last show.
Time has gone by fast.
I remember thinking about
this day in the rehearsal.
I can remember the first show.
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
Just feeling that energy
that his fans just, like,
give to us for the first time,
that realization that
I'm fulfilling my dream
and I'll never
forget that feeling.
I've always dreamed
to be a choreographer.
Like, from the day
I started dancing
when the first show happened,
I sat down against a wall
and I just, like, really
started crying to myself.
Oh, my gosh, no,
how about the audition?
Yeah, so no pressure, you know.
It was so surreal.
It was something
that we had all been
working really hard towards
and something we
had wanted so badly.
I remember being,
like, 10 years old
and going to concerts and,
like, watching the dancer
and I always knew
that I wanted to do this.
I'm really, really grateful because
I got to dance with him on stage.
It's amazing and I'm so thankful
that I got the opportunity.
Being right now in my home city
where dancing
all started for me,
seeing my mom out
there and, like,
thinking about how
much she sacrificed for me
to do what I love to do,
and I'm here with my boys
and I'm here with one of the best
artists I've ever worked with,
yeah, it's amazing.
It's amazing.
I think that believing
is the most powerful thing
that you can do in this life.
You can come from absolutely
nothing to something,
to be standing right here,
so I think that,
I'm ready to share that with the
world just like Justin does.
And now here we are
doing the last show.
Oh, my gosh.
I might cry tonight.
- Oh, for sure.
- We might cry.
You might see some tears.
- In  Believe.
The music plays until it stops.
And when it does,
what have you learned
and what do you believe?
Do you believe this hype,
or are you creating
something greater,
a deeper passion that will
not only help to articulate
who you are as an artist,
but also help people to be
able to identify with you?
Believe means,
like, be all you wanna be,
do what you wanna do and don't
stop believing in yourself,
just go for it.
I would listen to it when I
was really upset and it was,
like, I don't know, it's
just really helped me, like,
pull through and,
like, not give up.
Justin,
in a lot of our car rides,
he'd be singing in the back
and I'd be
telling him to shut up
because he'd never stop.
But I didn't know this was
gonna happen obviously, right,
so this is his life,
this is what he loves,
nothing's been
given to him and, yeah,
I'm very proud of him.
I was just looking
at him the other day,
and he had such a baby face,
and he's my baby,
and just to look at him now
with, like,
his little chiseled jaw
and his attempts at facial hair.
He's just...
He's growing so much.
And as busy as he is
and as much as he has on him,
he still continues to give back.
And, you know, as a mom and
just seeing his character grow,
I think that's one of the biggest,
um, achievements, in my mind.
But, Justin, I still want you
to pull your pants up.
...of a night that
they can't believe.
I pray that you will be
with everyone on stage,
bless them all, help everyone
just to have the best show...
No matter what religion,
no matter what race,
not matter what you are,
you can always believe.
It's all about positivity,
all about believing
in something great,
believing in a higher power,
believing in yourself,
believing that
you can do anything
if you set your mind to it.
I don't know how I got here
I knew it wouldn't be easy
But your faith in me
was so clear
It didn't matter how many times
I got knocked on the floor
But you knew one day
I would be standing tall
Just look at me now
'Cause everything
starts from something
But something would be nothing
Nothing if your heart
didn't dream with me
Where would I be, oh
Where would I be
If you didn't believe
Would I know how it feels
To touch the sky, yeah
If you didn't believe
Believe, believe
It didn't matter how many times
I got knocked on the floor
But you knew one day
I would be standing tall
Look at us now
'Cause everything
starts from something
But something would be nothing
Nothing if your heart
didn't dream with me
'Cause everything
starts from something
But something would be nothing
Nothing if your heart
didn't dream with me
Where would I be
If you didn't believe
Where would I be, if you, if you
Would I know how it feels
To touch the sky, yeah
If you didn't believe
Believe, believe
Oh
When you've reached
a certain point in your life,
there are people out
there who sit waiting,
wanting to see you fall.
But rather than let
gravity take you down,
sometimes you have to take
matters into your own hands
and fly.
I'm Justin Bieber.
Thank you for believing in me.
'Cause I believe in you.
This was me.
My pants were like this, guys.
- Normal, normal.
- Higher, higher.
And he said...
He said to me, he said,
"You can't let
the pants wear you,
"you got to
wear the pants."
That's when I started sagging.
- That's true. Hey...
- And that's your fault.
No, listen, I will
tell you one thing though,
I've lost a pair of pants,
bro, walking.
- Yeah?
- Lost a pair of pants walking.
No.
And it's not like, you know,
like, you're out at a bookstore
just browsing
the nonfiction section.
- Yeah.
- The nonfiction section.
And your pants are
a little bit low.
I'm just saying that one day,
just be careful, bro,
because I've lost
a pair of pants.
- Okay. I'm just saying...
- The nonfiction section...
- You were the... You were the one...
- ...at Barnes & Noble.
You were the one that said,
"Hey, don't let
the pants wear you,
- "wear the pants."
- That's right.
That's why...
But they... Hey...
- Wear them though.
- Yeah, wear them.
When they're on the ground,
bro, they're off.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Nobody's wearing them.
Oh, no.
Smile big!
One, two! Perfect, yeah.
Don't cry too much.
Told them he's gonna fall.
When I was 13,
I had my first love
There was nobody
that compared to my baby
And nobody came between us
or could ever come above
She had me going crazy
oh, I was star struck
She woke me up daily
don't need no Starbucks
She made my heart pound
It skipped a beat
when I see her in the street
And at school on the playground
But I really wanna
see her on the weekend
She knows she got me dazing
'cause she was so amazing
And now my heart is breaking
but I just keep on saying...
Hi.
Oh!
Does this look like
I'm walking downstairs?
My man, Ludacris, everybody.
Give it up for Ludacris!