September 21, 1945...
That was the night I died.
Damn tramps...
Watch it!
Disgusting!
Is he dead?
The Americans will be
arriving any day now...
It's disgraceful,
having these bums here!
Mama---!
What day is it?
Setsuko...
Another one.
What is
this stuff?
Never mind.
Just dump it!
This one's a goner, too.
You can see
it in their eyes...
HOTARU NO HAKA
~Grave of the Fireflies~
Production Designer/Original Story SATO RYOICHI
Executive Producer NOSAKA AKIYUKI
Character Design KONDO YOSHIFUMI
Art Director YAMAMOTO NIZO
Music MAMIYA MICHIO
Layout MAMOSE YOSHIYUKI
Character Color YASUDA MICHIO
Director of Photography KOYAMA NOBUO
Sound Design URAKAMI YASUO
Producer HARA TORU
Written & Directed by TAKAHATA ISAO
Air raid!
Get to the shelters!
We are in for a big one!
The shelter behind the
firehouse should be safest!
It's hot!
Be a good girl...
Try to be patient.
I'd better get
over to the shelter.
Be careful, and get over
there as soon as you can.
Setsuko, be a good girl
and mind your brother.
Never mind us!
Get to the shelter!
Yes, yes...
Mom, do you have
your medicine?
Right here.
Don't worry.
I hate the shelter!
Well, you will be sorry if you get
blown up by a bomb! Now get on.
My doll!
Air raid!
Seita!
Get down!
Long live the Emperor!
We are safe here.
Don't worry.
Where's Mama?
In the shelter.
The firehouse shelter can take
a hit from a 250 kilo bomb easy.
Don't worry about her.
She will probably go to
Niponmatsu station to find us...
We will meet her there.
Let's just
catch our breath first.
Are you okay,
Setsuko?
I lost one
of my shoes.
I will buy you better ones.
I have money.
Open this.
Wow, you are rich.
Black rain,
from the bombing...
It's all gone!
Look, that was the civic hall.
We ate lunch there, once.
Is our house
gone too?
Probably.
What will we do?
Dad will make them pay for this!
Mother!
Well, it's not like I was the
only one who lost his house.
We are all in the same boat.
At least
we are still alive.
There were two direct hits.
The fires are impossible to put out!
When you try to smother them,
it just spreads the oil around.
It's not her...
She's not down here!
Seita, I have to pee.
All residents of
lchirizuka and Kaminishi!
Please report to the elementary
school for first aid services!
What's wrong?
My eye hurts.
Don't rub it.
We will get it washed
out at the school.
Where's Mama?
She will be
at the school.
School?
Uh-huh. Let's go.
Seita!
Have you seen your mom?
She's hurt. You'd better go.
I will watch your sister.
Wasn't that scary, Setsuko?
Did you cry?
Seita has to go somewhere.
Why don't we wait for him?
Seita. I have been looking for you.
Are you okay?
My mom...?
This way.
This IS your mother's, isn't it?
In here.
She's finally asleep.
She really should be in
a proper hospital.
I think Kaisei hospital in
Nishinomiya wasn't hit.
My mother has heart trouble.
Can she get her medicine?
I will ask.
I will be around if
you need me.
Mom...
You saw her?
It's terrible...
I'm thirsty.
If there's anything
I can do, just ask.
Oh, did you get your
biscuit ration yet?
I will get it for you!
Keep this ring in your purse.
Don't lose it.
Mom's... hurt.
She will get better, though.
Where is she?
In the hospital.
In Nishinomiya.
We will stay here
at the school tonight.
Then tomorrow we will go to our
aunt's place in Nishinomiya.
Okay?
We will all be on the second floor.
Why don't you stop by later?
Thanks a lot. We will.
See you later, Setsuko.
Want some?
I want to see Mama.
Maybe tomorrow.
It's too late now.
Watch me, I'm good at this!
We haven't unbandaged her.
You don't want to see the body.
With this heat we are having...
She will have to go on the truck today.
Where's your sister?
In Nishinomiya.
We have a distant aunt there.
I think she will
take care of us.
I see. Lucky for you.
I'd better get back to work.
Good luck to you.
Mama!
Where is she?
Is she still sick?
Yeah. Still sick...
Welcome back.
How's your mother?
ls she at Kaisei?
Lucky your dad's in the Navy.
You get to have a truck
help move you over here!
I have laid out futons and
mosquito netting in your room.
Thanks.
Doesn't Mama need her ring?
Did she give it to me?
Just be careful
you don't lose it.
Mom's...
When Mom's a little better,
I will take you to see her.
Time for bed. Okay?
Dried bonito... Herring...
Dried potato... Eggs...
Pickled plums...
And I do believe this is butter!
You can't get these for
ANYTHING nowadays.
Soldiers always get the
best at times like these.
Anyway, did you stop by
the hospital?
I'd like to tell your mother
what's been happening.
And I could take Setsuko
along to visit her.
That bad?!
Mom... died while she
was still at the school.
What?! She's dead!
Then why didn't you tell me?
Why were you hiding it?!
I didn't want Setsuko to know.
Dead... How awful!
You'd best write your
father and tell him!
Seita!
Look!
She bought me new shoes!
Good for you,
Setsuko.
Hello there!
You poor dears...
Thanks ma'am.
What's that?
Bullfrogs.
Nothing to be scared of.
Firefly!
Try to catch it.
Whoops! Squashed it.
Ew! It smells!
You squeezed too hard.
There are millions of them!
Setsuko, close your eyes
and say "ah".
Why?
Just do it.
"Ah..."
Fruit drop!
Fruit drop! Fruit drop!
I almost swallowed it.
We are home.
Where were you?
Did you thank
the lady?
Yes ma'am.
That food looked good...
Seita. Shouldn't you be
going to school. Or something?
Yeah, but the steelworks they
had me working in was bombed.
And my school burned down.
There's no place to go.
Well, I hope you have
written to your father.
I already sent a letter
through the Naval Office.
When?
Just after we came here...
About 10 days ago?
That's strange...
There should have been
a reply by now.
Return the scissors when you have
finished with them, Setsuko.
How's the
war effort?
It's starting
to look hopeless.
The more factories we lose,
the harder the others have to work.
We are getting ready for
when they finally invade.
You are right. That's why food's
getting so hard to find.
Our soldiers aren't the
only ones who are suffering.
You work for our country's
defense too, young lady.
You eat up and work as
hard as you can!
Not again...
So you have taken in a couple
of homeless children?
Poor things... To lose their
mother when they are so young.
What's wrong?
Itch?
It's hot.
I hate shelters!
Just hang on. Don't worry,
I'm here for you.
Wanna go to
the beach?
Yeah! Yeah!
Let's go!
It's all
vegetable fields now.
What are they doing?
Making sea salt.
It's because all the salt
and soy sauce is rationed.
Hurry up, Setsuko!
It might be a
little cold...
Cold!
Feels good, right?
You won't itch now.
It's a big bathtub!
HEY!
Come back here!
Grrr, I'm a bear!
I'm gonna eat you!
Snip... Snip... Snip...
What's wrong?
ls he sleeping?
Don't look at that.
When it gets a little warmer,
I will teach you how to swim.
We will swim,
and that will make us hungry.
Seita!
Setsuko! Come on!
You are hungry, aren't you?
There's food here for you.
Mother! Were you waiting long?
It's good to see you again.
Are you all right here?
I'm fine. Don't worry!
They are very nice here.
I'm hungry.
Let's get home before we are
caught in the raid.
I'm tired... Carry me.
Air raid!
Your mother won't be
needing her kimono anymore.
Why don't you trade
them for some rice.
I have been trading off my
things bit by bit for food.
You can probably get a
full bowl of rice for them.
That much?
You need your
nourishment.
You can't be a soldier if
you don't grow up healthy.
A whole bowl of rice?
Your mother would be glad you
didn't let them just go to waste.
Why don't I take them?
NO!
Setsuko.
You are awake?
No! No!
They are Mama's!
Don't take them!
Setsuko...
Let them go!
Setsuko... Setsuko...
Fine rice, isn't it?
We will have a proper rice
dinner tonight, Setsuko.
Here, this is yours.
White rice, Setsuko!
Here you go.
With my daughter and our lodger
working overtime so much...
...l have felt bad not having
rice to give them.
It's great, huh?
Real white rice!
More!
Yes, yes...
You are just gobbling it down
tonight, aren't you Setsuko?
It's good!
What's wrong?
I don't want
rice porridge!
Don't we have any more
pickled plums?
We finished
those off ages ago.
Here's
your lunch.
Thanks. I'd better
get going.
See you.
Bye.
Take care.
We will have rice balls for lunch.
Just hold on till then.
Stop that!
You will have it for lunch too!
You think a lazy
slug like you deserves...
...the same as people who
work for our nation?!
Seita, you are old enough to
know everyone has to cooperate.
You keep saying you want rice,
but do you earn it?
No, you absolutely do not!
I even give you some rice,
and you still complain!
But it's our rice.
Oh, so now I'm
cheating you, am l?
How dare you say that!
After I take you two in!
Fine! We will just make our
OWN dinners from now on!
Seita, you have other
relatives in Tokyo, don't you?
On your mother's
side of the family?
Why not write to them?
WE could be bombed any day!
Problem is,
I don't know their address...
Let's
go home.
Uh-huh. Papa's
waiting for us.
Frogs are singing,
it's time to go home.
Sorry you had to
wait so long.
What's wrong?
I'm hungry.
And I'm thirsty too.
Okay...
Here, have a fruit drop.
Mom has 7000 yen in the bank.
7000... That's enough to
live on, so don't worry.
I'm telling Dad to write back
soon, because you are waiting.
You are in luck.
You can't buy a stove like
this easily nowadays.
It's almost impossible to
find any hardware to sell.
I will take that comb, and...
Do you have an umbrella?
An umbrella... Oh yes!
It's raining, it's raining.
Big brother's coming home
with an umbrella just for me.
Drip-drop, plip-plop.
Down the rain comes!
That's got it!
Be careful
with that fire.
Right...
What are they up to?
They are doing their own cooking.
Good for them! More please.
Mother, did you scold them again?
Yes, but they refuse to apologize.
And that boy even bought a
stove. Just to spite me!
Finished!
Bad manners, Seita.
Doesn't matter.
We can sit any way we want.
Rice for two.
That's it?
Next ration will be in July.
Let me!
Like it?
It's all different tastes!
Grape, strawberry, melon, mint.
All in there.
Drink it all.
All gone.
Great...
Left the dishes for me to do.
So selfish...
Honestly! Those brats are
two of the worst!
Not again!
Mama!
Seita, my daughter and that
man work for our nation!
We can't have her crying
keep them awake.
We have enough trouble getting
sleep with the air raids!
Report from Central
Military Division.
Several waves of enemy
bombers are approaching.
Going to the
shelter again, Seita?
You are old enough to help
fight the fires, aren't you?
I want to go home.
I hate living with her!
We don't have
a house to go back to.
With a great big streamer
shaped like a carp...
...and longer than a house.
The big one's the Papa,
the little ones the kids.
Stop it! Don't you realize
there's a war going on?!
You two are nothing
but trouble for me!
A couple of pests,
that's what you are!
You are no help
at all during the raids.
You could just go and LIVE in
that shelter for all I care!
That's it.
We will live here.
No one uses it. It's sturdy.
We can live like we want!
Can we really live here?!
We have bothered you long enough.
We are leaving now.
Leaving...? For where?
Haven't really decided yet.
Well, take care of yourselves.
Bye-bye, Setsuko!
This will be the kitchen!
This will be the front door!
Where's the bathroom?
That can be anywhere.
Wanna go somewhere with me?
Thanks for
the wagon.
Just leave
it there.
Do you think you can sell
us some food and straw?
I guess.
Not much left, though.
My mouth's
watering!
Man, am I
hungry.
Well, we can always eat frogs.
Frogs?
They are great.
You'd better get under
the mosquito net.
What's wrong?
I forgot my
toothbrush.
One night without it
won't matter.
It's getting buggy.
You'd better get under the net.
It's dark in there.
I'm scared.
I have to take a leak.
How about you?
A kamikaze.
It looks like
a firefly.
Yeah...
Let's catch some.
Okay, get in.
I can see you!
I can see you, too.
A hair clip.
Okay, let's get
as many as we can!
I went to a naval review, once.
Before you were born.
Naval review...?
Uh-huh. Dad's cruiser, the "Maya",
was in formation with the fleet.
Mighty fortresses
floating on the seas...
Defending our homeland from
invaders near and far.
Enemy plane!
I wonder where
Dad is fighting now...
Get off me, Seita!
What are you doing?
Making a grave.
Mama's in a grave too.
Auntie told me.
She said Mama died,
and she's in a grave now.
We will visit her grave sometime.
Do you remember the graveyard,
the one near Nunobiki?
That's where she is.
Under a big camphor tree...
Why do fireflies
have to die so soon?
Hey, it looks like
some body's living here.
Probably lost
their house.
Maybe it's some
crazy hermit.
It's a swing.
A kid lives here.
What's this?
Rest in Peace!
Wish it was real food.
It says
"Setsuko".
Look!
Dried frogs!
Who'd wanna eat that?!
Nobody I know would
ever eat this stuff!
Ground soybeans! And I thought
the food I got was bad!
A ghost!
I have traded everything for
rice. Even my Mom's kimono.
There's nothing left to trade.
Please, I can pay you
money for the rice...
Sorry. I can't trade or
sell anything to you.
I'm a farmer, but even I
don't have any rice to share.
Don't you have
other relatives?
I can't
contact them.
Then take my advice and
go back to that woman.
Every thing's rationed now.
You can't survive
outside of the system.
Just swallow your pride
and apologize to her.
Thanks anyway.
I will ask someone else.
You are a navy man's son, right?
Try to be brave.
Should we?
Uh-oh!
It doesn't matter if you like
it or not. You have to eat!
You need to,
so you can grow up!
Seita...
I- I feel funny.
Are you cold?
I have been having diarrhea...
Why you-- !
I'm sorry!
Sir, forgive me!
I didn't mean to.
My sister's sick. I just
wanted to get her some sugar!
Yeah, sure! Stealing food's
a serious crime in wartime!
You god damned-- !
Come back here!
What the hell...?!
Potatoes too?!
So YOU'RE the one who's
been stealing around here!
Seita!
I'm sorry! I will never
do it again, I swear!
Tell it to the cops!
I will take you there myself!
Now walk!
I hope they lock you up!
Please, she's sick!
She needs me!
Seita!
SEITA!
Seita...
The nature of the crime
is fairly clear, I think.
Thank you, I will handle this.
You may go.
But officer...
You have knocked this
poor kid around enough.
I'm even tempted to call it...
ASSAULT!
I... er...
Thank you officer!
They hit Fukui tonight.
Would you like
a glass of water?
Setsuko...
Seita!
Seita...
Where does it hurt?
Should I get a doctor?
Setsuko!
Seita, I have to
go to the bathroom.
Can it wait?
Hop on.
Brother's gone to the mountain
to bring back some firewood...
Setsuko. Dinner.
This pumpkin's great.
Tastes just like sweet bean jelly.
Don't like that stuff.
Look, if you don't eat,
Dad will blame ME for it.
Come on, I will even help you.
Now cheer up and eat!
Once you get better, I will take
you to the beach again.
Now I will really get you
something good to eat, Setsuko!
Seita...
These were your mother's?
Don't make me laugh!
Don't try to pawn off
this garbage on me!
Setsuko...
Setsuko!
Seita... Water...
Breathe in.
And out.
She's been having
diarrhea for a while now.
Prickly heat... Rashes...
And salt water hurts her skin.
Weakening from malnutrition.
Probably due to the diarrhea.
Next?
Can you give her
medicine? A shot?
Don't wanna
shot.
Please doctor, help her!
Medicine...
All this child needs is food.
Food...
What's wrong?
Where do
I GET food?!
Boy am I hungry.
What do you want to eat?
Tempura... Sashimi...
Jelly...
Anything else?
Ice cream... And also...
I want fruit drops...
Drops... Okay!
I will withdraw the money and
buy you all the food you need.
Don't want anything...
You can have it...
Don't go! Stay with me!
Don't leave me alone!
Don't worry, Setsuko.
I will buy you some good,
nourishing food.
And I will never leave you again.
Never, ever again.
I promise.
3000 yen.
There's a
typhoon coming?
Great, we get our "divine wind"
AFTER we surrender. Figures...
Surrender...?
We have lost the war?!
Haven't you heard?
Japan's lost?
The Great Japanese Empire?
Yeah...
Surrendered unconditionally.
What about
the fleet?
All gone.
Sent to the bottom.
Not one left afloat.
WHAT?!
Was my Dad's ship sunk too?!
ls that why he hasn't written?!
How should I know?
Crazy kid...
Damn him!
I'm so hungry...
Dad...
Now Dad's gone too...
He's dead too...
Dad...
Sorry I'm so late.
I will make you some rice.
Up they go...
And down again...
Oh... Firefly's stopped...
I bought us
some chicken and eggs.
And also...
Setsuko, what's in your mouth?!
This is a marble.
It isn't a drop!
I brought you something
I know you like.
Seita... Have one...
Setsuko... What's...?
Rice balls...
I made them for you...
Here... Have one...
You don't want them...?
Setsuko!
Look, it's a watermelon.
I didn't steal it, either.
Here, eat it.
It's good...
Hold on, I will make you some
rice gruel with eggs.
I will leave the
melon here for you.
Okay?
Seita... Thank you...
She never woke up.
There.
Charcoal for the cremation.
Since it's a child,
you should do it at a temple.
The body should be lightly dressed.
Use beanstalks for a good fire.
Beautiful day,
in spite of it all.
It hasn't changed a bit.
It's good to be home!
Look! The old phonograph...
I have missed this view.
Come back soon!
The next morning, I put some
of Setsuko's ashes into...
...the candy tin, and then
climbed down the hill.
I never went back to the shelter.
Seita...
Time for bed. Okay?