(SCREAMING)
(BEEPING)
(BEEPING FASTER)
(BEEPING RAPlDLY)
(SHOUTING)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(CRACKING BONE)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Don't.
Calm down.
Hey, fuck you.
Fuck you.
ROYCE: Looks like
his chute didn't open.
(PANTING)
Single shooter.
How do you know?
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Please stop doing that.
You're shooting at
the wrong people.
How do I know?
Because otherwise,
we wouldn't be having
this conversation.
All right.
You wanna show me
the right ones?
Nikolai.
I mean, l'm Nikolai.
What's the last thing
you remember, Nikolai?
War. Yeah.
I was with the Chechnya.
And there was a light.
And then I. . .
Then I woke up
and I was. . .
Falling.
Yeah, same thing.
I was in Baja.
And then
there was a light.
And then ch ingao.
Where are we?
Maybe she knows.
NIKOLAI: Shit.
You wanna
lower the weapon?
I've never seen
this jungle.
And I've seen most.
All right, you think
this is Asia?
Maybe Africa?
Too hot for
this time of year.
And the topography
is all wrong.
Amazon, maybe.
I saw more parachutes.
Which way?
Why?
So I can figure out
who threw me out of
a fucking airplane.
Fuck.
Where's he going?
(MUTTERING)
All right, let's hit
the fucking road.
(MUMBLING IN RUSSIAN)
Fuck.
(SQUELCHING)
You remember a plane?
I woke up in freefall.
You?
Same.
You're IDF?
Yeah.
Are you in
the service?
Not exactly.
(SHOUTS)
You motherfucker.
Come on,
you motherfucker.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
You with him?
No.
(GRUNTING)
Then why don't you mind
your own fucking business?
We have
bigger problems
right now.
Okay, boss.
Whatever you say.
I will finish
what you started.
Strength in numbers, huh?
Something like that.
STANS: Yeah?
Maybe we should
get that guy
hanging in the tree?
Help me!
Fuck!
Help me! Somebody!
Fuck. Help!
EDWIN: Hello?
I'm trapped in a parachute
in a fucking tree.
Hey, man,
why don't you
shut the fuck up?
Oh. Thank God.
I think I can. . .
Stop moving.
You're breaking
the branch.
You have anything
to cut yourself
down with?
Why would I. . .
No, I don't.
Look, if we get rope
from one of the chutes. . .
Do something.
EDWIN: Help!
It was taking too long.
Help!
Who the hell are you?
I'm a doctor.
I was on
my way to work.
(STUTTERING)
Can someone please
just tell me, uh,
what the fuck
is going on here?
Your ass is awesome.
Look.
Goddamn.
Who the hell
is this guy?
STANS: What the hell
is that?
Who would do this?
Whoever they are,
they take trophies.
In my culture
the warrior with
the greatest trophies
commands
the most respect.
Whatever.
It's a test.
To see how we do
under pressure.
If this were a test,
you'd all be military.
Total strangers.
Live rounds.
This is something else.
CUCHILLO:
Maybe it's ransom.
Back in Tijuana,
we kidnap you,
put you in
an oil drum.
The ransom's not paid,
we light you on fire.
STANS:
I hear these stories
about these experiments
they run on cons.
They stick drugs
in your food
and they sit back
and watch what happens.
Well, it's not drugs.
If it was
a psychotropic compound,
we'd be feeling
the residual side effects.
Loss of motor skills,
blurry vision.
And if it was
a behavioral experiment. . .
I mean, there. . .
There'd be a point.
What if we are dead?
I was going to be
executed in two days.
And I was in combat.
So was I.
This is hell.
Last time I looked,
you didn't need
a parachute to get there.
It doesn't matter
what happened, or why.
We're here.
Only question is,
how do we get out?
Where you going?
To high ground.
We need to
stick together.
Then you should
follow me.
Uh, yeah,
I wouldn't do that.
Yep.
Archaefructus
liaoningensis.
That is really,
really poisonous.
Wouldn't take more
than one scratch
to cause
total paralysis.
Thank you.
I'll watch for you
out here.
You made a buddy.
ISABELLE: Hey.
We need to rest.
So rest.
You look like
you could use it, too.
You got a name?
Look.
I'm sorry.
You want to play
scout leader, great.
All right? You wanna
follow me, fine.
But I'm not doing this.
I'm better on my own.
Wanna see
something fucked up?
Well, between that
and the sun,
I'd say we have
a real problem.
What about the sun?
Hasn't moved
since we got here.
What do you think
is really going on?
What do I think?
Spetsnaz.
Alpha Group.
Los Zetas,
cartel enforcer.
RUF.
It's a death squad
from Sierra Leone.
Yakuza, Inagawa-kai.
And the FBI's
Most Wanted.
And him.
They're all
heavy-hitters.
He doesn't belong.
Belong to what?
I'd say we were chosen.
What about you?
What about me?
You know the jungle.
Know the players.
I'm guessing ex-military.
Black ops.
Probably a mercenary.
You got a problem
with that?
Not at the moment.
Good.
(GUN CLICKING)
Something was
dropped here.
Same as us.
Not the same as us.
ISABELLE: You said
we were chosen.
Chosen for what?
Oh, shit.
Looking good there, boss.
(ROPE SLIDING)
(TRAPS SPRINGING)
STANS: Look out!
Down !
(YELLING)
Shit!
(SHOUTS)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
ISABELLE: Help!
Shit.
(GRUNTING)
Damn it.
(GRUNTS)
12 o'clock.
110 meters.
Take him. Take him.
I don't have to.
Don't have to.
We triggered
a dead man's trap.
It's two weeks, judging from
the rate of decomposition.
He took up
a position here.
Shooting in all directions.
This was a last stand.
United States
Special Forces.
This is strange.
He is supposed
to be deployed
in Afghanistan.
What's he doing here,
setting traps for us?
They weren't meant for us.
He was hunting
something else.
Something a lot bigger.
Bigger?
The trunk was a deadfall.
Rule of thumb
with a deadfall
is you set the weight
five times that of
the target animal.
Whatever it was,
it got through
the trip wires.
And it did this.
ROYCE: Let's move.
What is it?
PREDATOR: What is it?
Nothing.
Nothing. Nothing.
We're gonna need
a new plan.
Hey, where are we going?
Someone put us
on this rock.
There's got to be
a way off it.
(EXCLAIMS)
What the fuck?
(SWOOPING)
You know what?
Fuck this.
This is bullshit, man.
I want a gun.
Come on, man,
you got two
motherfucking guns, man.
Somebody give me a gun.
Come on, Russian.
You got a big fucking gun.
Come on, man.
Give me a gun.
Give me your gun.
Right now.
(COCKING GUN)
Give me your gun.
(GRUNTS)
I'm ready to die.
Are you?
(GROWLING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROWLING)
(STANS SHOUTING)
Oh.
EDWIN: Help!
(GROWLING)
Oh, shit!
Oh.
Shit! Fuck!
(GROWLING)
(EDWIN SHOUTS)
(NIKOLAI SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
(SHOUTING)
Help!
(GRUNTING)
Fuck you ! Fuck you !
(GROWLING)
Looking good there, boss.
(PANTING)
(GROWLING)
(SHOUTING)
Go! Go!
Come on. Come on.
(GRUNTING)
(GUN CLICKS)
Oh, shit!
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
Come on !
No!
(HIGH-PITCHED WHISTLING)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
(WHISTLING CONTINUES)
(GROWLING SOFTLY)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
MOMBASA:
As bad as you are,
those things are worse.
(MUTTERING)
So they. . .
They just,
what, left?
ISABELLE: No.
The whistle.
They were called.
All right, listen up.
Everybody do
a shell count.
We got to
conserve ammunition.
Reload. Do it now.
Excuse me.
Just what the hell
is going on here?
We're being hunted.
The cages.
The soldier.
All of us.
All brought here
for the same purpose.
This planet is
a game preserve.
And we're the game.
In case you didn't notice,
we just got flushed out.
They sent the dogs in,
just like you would
if you were stalking boar
or shooting quail.
They split us apart
and they watched.
Testing us.
How do you know this?
Because
that's what I would do.
Fantastic.
Wait.
There are only
seven of us.
CUCHILLO: Help me!
Help!
(WEAKLY) Help.
Wait.
What?
It's a trap.
CUCHILLO: Help me.
Fuck me.
CUCHILLO: Help.
MOMBASA: Wound one man.
Make him suffer.
Make him bleed.
Make him
call out for help,
and set a trap
and kill those
who come.
I know because
I have done this.
So we're gonna
leave him here,
right?
Come on,
look at him.
He's done.
There's nothing else
we can do, right?
Right?
We leave him.
I can't.
Then, that's on you.
CUCHILLO: Help me.
PREDATOR:
(IMITATING CUCHILLO)
Help me.
PREDATOR:
Help me. Help me.
(VOICE FLUCTUATING)
It's a trap. It's a trap.
It's a trap.
What are we gonna do?
We should go to
higher ground.
Really?
We're trapped on
an alien hunting planet.
You really think
the solution is
to walk more?
(SNIFFING)
It wants us to run.
That's how it hunts.
This is its jungle.
Its game.
Its rules.
We run,
we die.
ISABELLE: What's
the alternative?
We need to know
who we're dealing with.
Dog tracks go that way.
We go after it.
ROYCE: Well?
No movement.
(GASPS)
(WINGS FLUTTERING)
STANS: It looks like
we're not the only
things being hunted.
(ROARING)
Holy shit!
STANS: What the fuck?
What the fuck
is that thing?
This is a mistake.
We have to leave. Now.
Where is
the tough guy?
ISABELLE: He left us.
He's here.
(SHOT FIRING)
(SCREAMING)
Run!
(SHOUTING)
(PREDATOR ROARING)
(GURGLING)
(SCREAMING)
(YELLING)
(ROARING)
(GASPS)
(YELLING)
ROYCE: Run ! Run ! Run !
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
(SNARLING)
(ALL PANTING)
(GROANING)
You set us up.
He led us into
that death camp,
then hid and waited
for that thing to strike.
We were bait.
I needed to know
who we were up against.
Now I do.
A man is dead
because of that.
This morning you were
ready to kill him.
It ain't this
goddamn morning, is it?
At least he didn't
die in vain.
Why? So we could
find out firsthand
what it feels like
to have our asses kicked?
No. We found out
that there's more
than one of them.
That they use projectile
and energy-based weapons.
That they have some sort
of cloaking device.
That they're bigger than us,
stronger,
but also heavier.
You put us at risk
for yourself.
You want to be
on your own,
you got it.
Why don't you tell
them the truth?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You know what
I'm talking about.
The way you
looked at that thing
that was strung up,
the way you reacted.
She knows what it is.
Don't you?
We don't have
a name for them.
'87, Guatemala.
A spec ops team
went into the jungle.
High end.
Six men plus
a CIA liaison.
Only one made it out.
In his debrief,
he said
they came in contact
with something.
He gave a detailed
description.
The thing
on the totem.
It wore some kind of
camouflage that adjusted
to ambient light.
Made it nearly invisible
in our spectrum.
It could see
in infrared.
Heat signatures.
He used mud
to block his.
That's how
he beat it.
It hunted and
killed his team,
one by one.
Whatever it is,
wherever they're from,
we're going to
kill them all.
We set up
a defensive perimeter.
Make it look like
we are holing up.
That'll bring them to us.
We force them into
a choke point.
We get them in
overlapping fields
of fire.
It can be done.
I can't do it alone.
You know, man,
if we ever
make it home,
I'm gonna do so much
fucking cocaine.
I'm gonna rape
so many fine bitches.
I'll be like,
"What time is it?
5:00?
"Damn.
"Time to go rape me
some fine bitches."
You know what
I'm saying?
Oh, yeah. Totally.
Like, 5:00,
it's bitch-raping time.
Mmm.
Yeah.
You should
stay away from him.
Yeah.
You still pissed?
Fuck you.
(CHUCKLING)
You know what the difference
between you and me is?
We both do
the same thing.
You just do it
for a country,
so you don't
have to admit
you like it.
What happened to you?
What made you
so fucked up?
"There is no hunting
like the hunting of a man.
"And those who've hunted
armed men long enough,
"and like it,
"never really care
for anything else
thereafter."
That's pretty poetic.
Did you come up with
that all by yourself?
No, actually.
That was Hemingway.
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
(WHISPERS) Fuck.
Why isn't it coming?
They see our traps.
Hey, Doc.
Hey.
I think I just
figured out a way
you can be useful.
Shit. Shit.
I hate this.
Oh!
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Oh, shit!
Come on. Come on.
Fucking shoot!
Shoot already!
Fuck
all of you !
Is he dead? Why ain't
you smiling? Oh, shit.
NIKOLAI: The thing
from the cages.
Maybe it thought
we're the ones
who dropped it here.
ROYCE:
Good shot, though.
I missed.
MAN: (WHISPERING)
Over here.
(GASPING)
(WEAPON ACTIVATING)
Turn around.
What the fuck are you?
I'm alive.
(GASPS)
You talk too loud.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Smelled you
since you got here.
If I can smell you,
if I can hear you,
they can, too.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Storm coming soon.
This way.
ISABELLE: Wait.
Who are you?
(IN SING-SONG VOICE)
Noland,
run away,
live to fight
another day.
I'm the one
that got away.
The one you
don't fuck with.
Come on.
Feel the vibe
of this place.
ISABELLE:
Where are we?
NOLAND: It's a drill
somebody left behind.
The machine is dead,
but the power source ain't.
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
(GRUNTING)
STANS: Wow,
what a shithole.
You live here?
Oh, no. No.
This is my summer home.
I winter in the Riviera.
The schools are
so much nicer there.
And the men. . .
Ooh, la, la!
By the way,
you're welcome.
How have you survived?
Salvaging what I can,
when I can,
from whatever I can.
Oh.
Noland, Ronald.
Air Cav.
They. . . (CHUCKLING)
They drop you
all in, too?
Yeah.
Hmm. (CHUCKLING)
What a rush.
(HUMMING RIDE OF
THE VALKYRIES)
Hey.
Yeah, I'll tell him.
Hey, Agent Orange,
you wanna put that down?
Certain people
around here
are particular
about other people
messing with their shit.
Very important, though.
Disrupts the
heat signature.
You motherfuckers.
So, you killed one?
Uh-uh.
I killed two.
Maybe three.
I can't remember. Anyway,
there's two different types
of them out there.
Hmm? Now they're similar,
but they're different.
It's kind of like
the difference between
dogs and wolves.
The ones that
are running things
up there,
the larger ones,
hunt the smaller ones.
It's some kind of
blood feud, I guess.
Been going on
for a long time.
(MUMBLING)
They do this
just for sport?
Oh, yeah,
they bring in fresh meat
season after season.
I mean, shit you
wouldn't believe.
Bring it in,
and hunt it
and kill it.
In that order.
How long you
been here, man?
Uh. . .
Seven seasons, I think.
What? Ten?
Damn.
Anyway, every once
in a while, one of us
kills one of them.
And, let me tell you,
that's when they get
real interested.
See, they learn quick.
They adapt.
They develop
a whole new set
of skills.
They come back
the next season in threes,
always in threes.
Their armor
might've changed,
or their weapons
have changed,
or their tactics
have changed.
It's amazing.
So, it's like evolution.
They're trying
to make themselves
into better killers.
Mmm-hmm.
You said they come back.
How?
They got a ship.
A ship?
Yeah.
It's 30 yards
from their camp.
(CHUCKLING)
I told you
they wouldn't see it.
they wouldn't.
You were there.
You could've helped us.
How do we kill them?
However you can.
They must have
a weakness.
Not many.
You want to survive?
You dig in deep.
You stay hid.
Yeah, well,
we're gonna go with
door number two.
How do we get out
of this valley?
Oh.
Ten seasons.
First two seasons. . .
No, three seasons
I was here,
I was walking
in the same direction,
trying to reach
the edge of
the preserve.
(LAUGHING)
Let me tell you something,
there ain't no edge
of the preserve.
Maybe you and your friend
wanna tell me about that ship?
Let's see.
That's a brilliant idea.
Brilliant.
The whole time
I've been here,
it never occurred to me
to commandeer
the alien spacecraft.
But I wouldn't know
how to fly it.
He would.
Of course,
you know how to fly.
I'll give it a shot.
(NOLAND LAUGHING)
Well. . .
I'm gonna get
some sleep.
No noise.
They're out there.
They're always
out there.
Water in there.
Help yourself.
All of you.
Who's that?
My kids.
Big one, Ilya.
And that's Sascha.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Uh. . .
(GRUNTING)
This is, uh, Candy Lee.
Tits like howitzers.
Is that your girlfriend?
No. It's my sister.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
This is old.
Very old.
They've been doing this
for a long time.
You speak English.
Yes.
Why don't you
say more?
Because I talk too much.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
(GRUNTS)
Thanks.
Do you know
what I was doing
when I was taken?
Isaac, my spotter.
He was caught.
I could have
done something,
but then I would have been
slaughtered along with him.
So, I hid.
I watched him die.
I wish I pulled
that trigger.
You do what you have to,
to survive.
You said we were chosen.
I asked, "For what?"
I should've asked why.
It's because
we are predators.
Just like them.
We're the monsters
of our own world.
It's probably better
that we're never
going back.
I am going back.
I'm going
after that ship.
You learn how to
fly it in the last hour
and not tell me?
No.
That thing strung up
at the camp might know.
My guess is,
it'd do just about
anything to get free.
Enemy of my enemy.
That doesn't
make it a friend.
So what
do I call you?
(SNIFFING)
Smoke.
Hey, smoke.
Fuck.
(EXCLAIMS)
Where's Noland?
(COUGHING)
He's a scavenger.
He wants what we have.
ISABELLE: Come on !
There must be a way out!
ROYCE: Damn it.
ISABELLE: Do it!
You see the shit
you've gotten us
into, man?
NOLAND: I told you that.
You never listen
to me, though.
Six more. Six more fucking
mouths to feed.
I can barely stand
living with you.
How am I gonna
live with them, too?
ISABELLE: Damn it!
What?
Say goodbye to
your little friend.
You're in my house,
motherfucker!
Get down.
Yeah, that didn't
open up shit.
Wasn't meant to, asshole.
I'm calling in
the cavalry.
(GROWLING)
STANS: How the fuck
can we get out of here?
Open up,
you hanky fucker.
ISABELLE: Come on !
(PREDATOR GROWLING)
Oh.
(WEAPON POWERING UP)
Finally found me,
huh, big dog?
Well, what took
you so long?
STANS:
It's not gonna open !
(STANS SHOUTING)
God damn it!
(POUNDING AT DOOR)
(YELLS)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(AIR HISSING)
It's toying with us.
EDWIN: Guys?
Oh, shit.
Hey!
(PREDATOR GROWLING)
(PREDATOR SNARLING)
This way.
Hey!
(STAMMERING)
I lost you guys!
(GASPING)
You got to get me
out of here, man.
Come on. Come on.
ROYCE: Let's move.
(EXHALES)
(CLANGING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(PREDATOR SNARLING)
(EXCLAIMING) Oh. . .
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(PREDATOR BELLOWING)
(NIKOLAI SHOUTS
IN RUSSIAN)
Oh !
(YELLS)
(ROARING)
(SPITS)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(BEEPING)
(PREDATOR GROWLING)
(ALL GASPING)
(YELLING)
We killed it.
(STANS EXCLAIMING)
We killed it!
We fucking. . .
(LAUGHING)
We fucking killed it.
We killed it. Whoo!
Huh?
Who's your daddy now,
motherfucker?
Hunt my dick, bitch !
Die, you space faggot!
Who do you think
you're dealing with, hoss?
Is that all you've got?
Go! Go!
(GRUNTING)
(PREDATOR SNARLS)
(LAUGHING)
Come on.
Come on !
(GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
(GASPING)
Let's get to
that ship.
(SNARLS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(SHOUTING IN
JAPANESE)
(SCREAMING)
(SHOUTING IN
JAPANESE)
(GROWLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTING)
We're close. Come on.
Ow! Shit!
(GASPING)
Shit.
(WHIMPERING)
Fuck!
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
Another inch,
it would've hit
my tibial artery.
I guess this
is my lucky day.
It isn't. That trap
wasn't meant to kill.
It was meant to maim.
He's dead weight.
Come on.
Uh, um. . .
(STAMMERING)
No, I can still walk.
(SCREAMS) Oh !
Shit. God.
No, he can't. Look.
He's done.
You're gonna beg us
to slow down.
No, no, no.
To carry you.
You can't leave me here.
You can't.
I have a family.
I got kids.
I'm sorry.
(EXCLAIMS SOFTLY)
ROYCE: We need to go.
No. No!
You are taking me
with you !
Look, you and I
can still make it.
We use him.
We booby-trap him.
No.
They'll go to him
to take trophies.
This is our last chance.
This isn't right.
He's one of us!
He is.
That's what
they're counting on.
They want you
to feel something
for this man.
To be human.
And what are you?
Alive.
What's that worth?
(CRYING)
You can't. Please.
Please,
I'm begging you.
Please.
You should go.
(SOFTLY) Shit.
(MURMURING)
You should've
gone with him.
I know.
Hey.
(GROWLING)
I want off this planet.
You understand me?
I'll cut you down.
You take me
to the ship.
Ship.
(GROWLS)
You understand me,
don't you?
(GROWLS)
Huh?
(GASPING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
I'm sorry.
We're not dead yet.
(SHOUTING)
Shit.
(GASPING)
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(POWERING UP)
(BEEPING)
(EDWIN GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
(POWERING UP)
(ROARING)
(PANTING)
(ROARS)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
I guess he made it.
If you could
do it over again,
would you make
the same choice?
Yes.
Thank you.
When the time comes,
I'll do us both.
I promise
it'll be quick.
No.
It won't.
(GASPING)
Cool.
That's right.
(IN DISTORTED VOICE)
It's a neurotoxin.
There's so many
to choose from
around here.
But don't worry.
It's not fatal.
You'll be able to
experience everything.
(GASPING)
(BUTTONS BEEPING)
I guess now you realize
why they chose me.
I was right in front of
you guys the whole time.
Just watching you.
Earning your trust.
You couldn't see me
for what I really am.
You see, back home,
I'm a murderer.
I'm a freak.
But here,
among the monsters,
I'm normal.
I like it here.
I wanna stay.
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
Oh ! You came back.
I missed my ride.
Oh, thank God.
Help us get out of here.
(GRUNTING)
She's paralyzed.
It gave her something.
I don't know what,
but it paralyzed her.
Come on.
You're so busy
taking care of others,
you forgot
to look out
for yourself.
We're getting
out of here.
You just hang
tight, okay?
I didn't think
you'd come back.
But she,
she never lost
faith in you.
I guess I owe you
an apology.
(GASPING)
You are a good man
after all.
No.
I'm not.
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
But I'm fast.
Come here.
Please don't kill me.
I won't.
(GROWLING)
(GASPING)
Help me.
I'm one of you.
(GROWLING)
Yes.
Come on. Come on.
PREDATOR: Come on.
Come on. Do it.
I'm here. Kill me.
Come on.
Do it now. Kill me!
(ROARING)
(SHOUTS)
(PANTING)
(GROWLING)
(SNARLING)
Oh, shit.
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
(COUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(GROWLS)
(YELLING)
(GROWLING)
(GASPING)
Did you get it?
Yeah.
(SIGHING)
I'm Royce.
Nice to meet you, Royce.
I'm Isabelle.
Now,
let's find a way off
this fucking planet.
(GROWLING)
(LONG TALL SALLY PLAYING)
Don't tell Aunt Mary
about Uncle John
He claims he has the music
But he has a lot of fun
Oh, baby, yeah, baby
Ooh, baby, having me
some fun tonight, yeah
Well, long, tall Sally
She's built sweet
She's got everything
that Uncle John needs
Oh, baby, yeah, baby
Ooh, baby, having me
some fun tonight, yeah
Well, I saw Uncle John
with bald-head Sally
He saw Aunt Mary coming and
he ducked back in the alley
Oh, baby, yeah, baby
Oh, baby, having me
some fun tonight, yeah
Ahhh!
Well, long, tall Sally
She's built sweet
She's got everything
that Uncle John needs
Oh, baby, yeah, baby
Ooh, baby, having me
some fun tonight
Have some fun
Having me some fun tonight