Jessica McDowell.
Cognis Chemicals.
When do you leave Kuala Lumpur, Ms.
Macdowall?
I fly to Taiwan Tuesday then back
to Dusseldorf.
Mr Tabir is very busy this morning.
Oh I can imagine.
Seeing’s we’re waiting..
..Why don’t you practice your
little pitch on me?
Actually. If it’s all the same-
I know all my uncle’s business. He
trusts me. Begin.
Well. I’m sure you’re aware that recently,
your subsidiary, developed an organic, ester based
lubricant derived from Kernel oil, that makes...
You American?
Canadian. Actually.
From Toronto.
You a Maple Leafs fan?
Uh. No. Not really.
You must be the only person from
Toronto’s not a hockey fan.
Oh I’m a fan. Dad’s from Vancouver,
so I’m a Canuck.
Between us, the Maple Leaves suck.
They should never have signed Mark Bell. Guy’s
a liability, on an off the ice.
So
who’s your team?
I don’t like hockey.
Unfortunately, Mr Tabir has no
window this morning.
He extends invitation
to private reception at his residence.
Well, if that's ok?
I don’t wanna intrude.
Come...
to the party.
Why are we stopping?
Ms. Macdowall, my uncle believes
that trust is something you earn.
And he doesn’t trust anyone until
he knows them very, very well..
But he trusts you, Hafiz..
How do you know my name?
Your car was swept an hour ago.
Do not get out. If you get out of
this car I can’t protect you.
Who are you?
Let go of my arm Hafiz. NOW.
Your uncle is in business with Abu Domar Khan.
Khan has made contact with a terror organisation,
via an aid agency in Pakistan.
They are seeking materials to build a weapon.
That’s bullshit.
We need information about your uncle.
Contacts. Shipments.
If you help us, we help you.
If you don’t, your brother dies and
tomorrow you’re sitting with your uncle
Right now, you have no idea what we can and cannot do.
You will get a call at 8am.
You’ll be asked if you need a cleaner.
You want her to come three mornings per week.
Do you understand?
I said,
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
- FAIR GAME -
I swear to god, he can’t turn, slow down,
for like four hundred yards.
And yet I’m incredible in bed.
Listen, Steve and I
are not going on the same plane together.
We are not even gonna take the same train together.
It only takes one to fly
plane into a nuclear power plant.
Disneyworld.
A sarin attack on Disneyworld.
- Yeah, but whatever they’re telling us,
we’re totally vulnerable.
I mean who’s protecting us.
Would you risk taking your
kids to Disneyworld right now?
Would you do that?
Absolutely not.
I'd be terrified,
exposing my children to what adds up,
to clearing house for crappy merchandise
and disaapointing rides.
Joe thinks Disneyland is Vegas for kids.
So... Valerie,
what do you do?
I work in Venture Capital.
Brewster Jennings, here in Georgetown.
Cool. So like net startups..?
Exactly. Retail and consumer.
We create pooled investment vehicles..
It's actually, pretty boring.
You get on a plane, two
guys with turbans,
seats one A and one B.
They look nervous. They’re
sweating, they are sweaty... they are saying prayers..
What do you do?
Steve, you have a kid right?
You’re off that plane. You’re calling the cops.
I think if we’re honest we all are.
Joe? You know you are.
I mean come on, you see these guys.
Two guys, On a plane. Turbans. Sweating. Prayers.
The whole thing. What do you say?
What’s the call?
Well Jeff..
He started.
Yeah,
Everytime.
Every time we go out.
He asked me a question,
and I gave a him a full and considerate response.
He’s drunk Joe.
Everybody’s had a hard day.
They’re just trying to let off steam-
By invoking quasi-racist connundra?
The guy’s a parent.
Is he telling his four year old to fear all men in turbans?
It’s Diana’s birthday.
Jeff’s her oldest friend.
So?
So, you can’t call him a racist pussy.
It's not funny, Joe.
Oh its not funny.
Its a very serious subject.
If my not keeping quite while someone spouts obnoxious crap
makes you an asshole.
Then I’m an asshole.
And you knew that when you married me.
How was your trip?
Valerie, Where's Kim?
Oh, she can't come here,
untile after lunch, Didn't I tell you?
O-kay, that sounded like I'll be working
at home this morning.
Is that okay?
Yeah, Me ‘n Spongebob are on it.
Break it up. Trevor don’t hit
your sister.
Listen, the Mitchells wanna have dinner on Tuesday.
But if you wanna skip it...
I promise to behave.
See. Everyone's on their best behavior.
I love you.
Bye
- Bye Mommy!
- Byeee.
- You guys wanna watch television?
- Yeah.
Counter Proliferation tracks and thwarts nuclear and WMD acquisition
by rogue nations and non-state actors.
We’re the fastest growing division
in the Agency,
which sounds cool
but you may have to share a desk.
Hafiz hired a cleaner.
Gotta go.
Kuala Lumpur just wentlive.
- What time did he call this in?
- 11 hundred hours Zulu time.
We keep the transaction live. Trace
it all the way to the end user.
The shipment arrives in Joburg on
the 21st. It’s put in an unmarked container
and shipped to the free
trade zone in Dubai.
Dr Forster and his team at Los Alamos have altered the impedence
timings of the spark gaps by a fraction of a nanosecond.
Val. The chief wants to see you.
Now, shut it down.
Why? We have everything.
We are ready to go.
We have actual intel on the buyer.
Manucher Vaziri. Syrian National,
Based out of Karachi.
On a wire picked up in Cairo
he talks about nuclear componentry
from a known source in Pakistan
he’s moving to an unnamed Gulf state..
Vaziri’s devoutly Shia.
Iraq’s controlled by the Sunni.
Saddam’s Sunni.
There’s no way this is Iraq.
Seventh floor have issued a directive
for a Joint Task Force on Iraq.
I want you to head up operations.
Congratulations, Valerie.
Thank you.
You can pick your team.
This is top priority.
I need 24 hours to brief managment.
From monday, I need your both eyes on Iraq.
Yes sir.
This is coming from across the river.
Down the line D.F.U
D.F.U?
Don't Fuck Up.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
You can put it there.
Hey!
Don’t you have a home to go to?
I thought this went away.
DIA released the report Tuesday. WINPAC aren’t buying and State
kicked it back, but it’s still making waves in the VP's Office.
You think Joe could do it?
Well, he's qualified.
He’s been there hundreds of times.
Knows the arena inside out.
Great, we could put his credentials in memo,
gonna kick it up the ladder.
You don't look over joyed.
He’s been working hard to build hisbusiness.
Then there’s the twins. Money’s kinda tight right now.
He's helped us before.
Couldn't you ask him to come in?
Hey Joe.
Hey. Nice place you got here. Cosy.
I need to get you cleared.
You work in the basement?
Actually. I work in Georgetown for Brewster Jennings.
We’re a small firm of Venture Capitalists.
That must be interesting work.
It pays the rent.
Joe, this is Jack, the Deputy Chief of CPD.
Mr Wilson, what can you tell us
about Yellowcake?
Yellowcake Uranium?
I believe it’s a concentrate made from uranium ore used to
create fissile material for weapons programs. But I’m not a scientist.
What about Niger?
The UN Human Development Index
rates the Least Liveable country in the world. I
I started my foreign service there.
I visited many times,
As Ambassador to Gabon,
and then again,
as director of Africa policy for President Clinton, within NSC.
I often met with Prime Minister Mayaki. I know the former
foreign minister. I know the Minister of Mines.
I know the country very well.
The Office of the Vice President has received a report,
concerning a memorandum of sale
between the governments of Niger and Iraq;
For the purchase of five hundred tons of
Yellowcake Uranium ore..
I don’t have to tell you how
serious this allegation is.
No Sir, you don’t.
This is a request from the Vice President's office.
Can you help us?
What do you have in mind?
So tell me. How can Niger help
its old friend, America?
“In summer 2001
Iraq sought to purchase 60,000 high alloy 7075
- T6 aluminum tubes
Manufactured in China.
The high spec of these tubes led us to conclude
they were intended for the enrichment of uranium.
And as such, provides proof that
Suddam is buildinga nuclear bomb.
In August 2001 J. Turner..That’s me..
Flew to Vienna.
To meet with IAEA scientists.
I produced this report,
aspects of which represents the CIA’s present position.
I’m happy to take questions.
The INR concluded late last year
that these tubes were probably for artillery use,
and the DOE agreed they exactly matched
those used by Iraq for artillery rockets.
Where are the tubes?
WINPAC has them. We’ve examined them.
This is my point.
None of youguys has even seen the tubes.
I’ve seen them.
And when was that?
When I let the covert team,
that intercepted them at Jordan,
bought back samples and delivered
them to you guys at WINPAC.
And I take it you’re not a nuclear expert.
These tubes are an EXACT match for those developed by
German scientist Gernot Zippe in the 50s.
You’re right. I’m no nuclear expert.
But Dr. Houston Wood,
at Virginia U atomic facility is.
He also knows Dr Zippe.
And he told him that the wall thickness of the
Iraqi tubes was three or four times the thickness of his design.
Right, He also said that the length
of the tubes is twice that of Zippe’s design.
In fact, the only thing that was similarity
between his tubes and the alumumium tubes
was that they’re made of aluminium.
And that old metal that hasn’t been used in
gas centrifuges since 1952.
I went to Vienna, okay?
Canada ..
And i've been working on this for months.
They’re centrifuges. Fact.
So basically,
they’re your tubes...
and if we don’t let you win you’re going home.
That’s pathetic.
Joe. No one is saying you’re wrong here.
But if you’re right, it’s huge.
So we ask the question.
Right?
We have to ask the question.
Niger has two Uranium mines in the
Sahara desert.
One’s flooded.
The other’s run by COGEMA, a French
subsidiary, jointly controlled by the Japanese and Germans.
500 tons of Yellowcake is not an
off the books size transaction,
represents a 40 % production increase
in the nation’s annual output of uranium.
A sale that size
would leave a huge paper trail.
Any documentation would by law have
to be signed by the Prime Minister,
Foreign minister, and the Minister
of the mines... But say it was an off the books deal..
How do you hide the transportationof 500 tons of anything,
let alone lightly refined uranium?
You’re talking fifty semi tractor
trucks on one road
through villages where nothing passed for months
except maybe one bush taxi.
It will be the biggest event for months.
To say they forgot,
it’s like kids forgetting Christmas.
The droughts of the 80s and 90s
were met by millions of dollars of U.S Aid,
which continues to this day. It just doesn’t make sense
Niger would compromise this lifeline.
For that reason,
and for all the
reasons that I’ve been telling you.
It’s my opinion
that the sale couldn’t happen.
So? What happens next?
Well, they write a report.
Give it to the analysts.
It’ll be re-written,
then kicked upstairs where it’ll be
thrown in with whoever else’s report they got-
What?
I just think, it's ludicrous.
They’re gonna send somebody all the way out there
to spend all that money for the same conclusion.
Well, You can’t compile Intelligence
from a single source?
That’s not Intelligence.
That’s an opinion.
Trust me.
Its a fact.
Says who?
Says me.
You're just a teeny weeney tiny
cart in a giant machine.
You did your job..
You should feel good.
That's why they'll pay you.
I’m not feeling very 007'ish.
Maybe, I can get the kids to make you a
medal for you.
Us double oh’s are more about the
gratuitous sex.
Maybe, I can ...
do something about that.
Angola is holding them in round of bidding
on their deep water offshore blocks
End of the year
Chevron and Exxon are interested.
It’s an honor to meet you at last
Dr. Harper.
I was unable to attend your String-
Gravity seminar at MIT
but I read a transcript.
Truly groundbreaking work.
Did you read my latest paper on quarks?
Dr.Harper, I cite your 1995 essay more than once.
Dr Harper is in Cambridge, Massachusetts.
She received a call yesterday,
requesting she stay home for 48 hours.
I don’t understand.
Who are you?
I’m sorry for misleading you.
But I’m here to ask you the same question.
Because you are not Professor Badawi.
Your name is Doctor Harif Al Fallari.
You were born in Basra.
You were lead engineer at the Osirak
nuclear facility until you fled the rock and arrived here in Cairo.
I need names of your colleagues
in the weapons programmes.
The lives of hundreds of thousands
of your people may depend upon it.
This is absurd.
You weren’t tortured. Broken.
You didn’t finally escape and arrive
here in Cairo with nothing.
No, my name is Bakra Badawi.
I've never been to Basra.
Dr. Al Fallari had two daughters.
They were taken by Uday Hussein’s private guard.
They were never seen again.
I need names of your colleagues
in the weapons programmes.
Why is the OVP here?
The Vice President’s men are here.
What?
My name is Scooter Libby.
I’m theChief of Staff to The Vice President.
You are?
Dave. I’m an analyst.
In non-proliferation.
What can you tell the Vice
President about aluminium tubes?
I didn't realise that's
what we are going to talk about here.
Relax, will you.
The Veep’s just dotting the i’s.
Oh C'mon Jim. The only time a Vice
President comes to Langley is to cut a ribbon.
Cheney doesn’t trust us.
This shit with Dick goes back thirty years.
It’ll blow over.
Hey Val, Where are we on Iraq?
We need to find sources we can rely on.
We need to get in close.
Jim. Val thinks she can get us
inside the weapons program.
How?
Dr. Hassan?
Is there somewhere we could talk?
How long is it since you saw your brother?
Before that, in ‘83, he came here for an
engineering conference.
Twice in twenty five years.
We try to stay in contact.
It’s difficult.
Would you like to go back and see him?
You want me to become a spy.
We need to ask Sa’ad some questions.
Do you think he would answer them?
I’m a doctor. I work hard.
I’m also a mother.
I have a small girl and I’m all she has.
We can help your brother.
Right nowhe is extremely valuable to us.
And to Saddam.
The Mukbarat watch him night and day.
He could come here. He’s an expert physicist.
He’d have a job,
his children, his family would be safe.
You, your daughter could see
him whever you want.
Can you help us?
I won’t do anything to help you.
I don’t know you.
Don't you care about Iraq?
About your country?
My country is America now.
Trust me, if there's another way to do this.
- I don't trust you.
I don't trust you, at all.
We are going to war. And your brother
is going to be right in the middle of it.
"If the Iraqi regime wishes peace.
It will immediately and unconditionally,
forswear, disclose, remove or destroy...
Weapons of Mass Destructions."
"If Iraq's regime, defy this again.
The world must move deliberately,
decisively, to hold Iraq to account".
Don’t make jokes.
He thinks I don’t know how serious it is..
Weeks and weeks of fifteen hour days,
we’ve been back over this and over this!
Alright, that's it.
I'm gonna handle this.
We’ve been over this
data with you now five, six times..now.
And... we don’t really know how you
want us to play this..
Let me level with you here Paul.
I don’t know what these tubes are for.
There could be something to this,
from everything you’re saying, but very likely not, right?
- Exactly!
- May I ask a question?
When you say we don’t really know how to play this,
what do you mean?
I’m just saying I don’t know how to
say it any other way than that-
So you and the others have discussed how to “play” these
briefings. Why does the CIA feel the need to play these briefings?
No. I mean that.. Ok. I didn’t mean
what I just said.
Which part. The last part.
Or other things too.
I’m a getting a little confused-
You want me to come back?
No. GOD no.
You don’t know why I’m here do you?
In 1991 the United States invaded Iraq,
and afterwards weapons inspectors discovered
Saddam was six months off
enriching uranium to sufficiently
high specification to make a nuclear bomb.
He had fissile material.
And not a single person at the CIA,
had the slightest clue that such a program even existed.
So... now!
One decade on, are you telling me that you’re 100 % sure
these tubes are not intended to create nuclear weapons?
1. With intelligence,
nothing’s 100 percent.
So. What? Are you.. Ninety nine
percent sure? Ninety eight?
You can’t put an exact figure.
You can’t be that precise.
But if you had to say, could you
say you’re ninety seven percent sure?
Is there a three percent
chance you’ve got this wrong?
Or four? Or five?
Still pretty good odds.
You like those odds Paul?
You willing to put your name to that.
Are you ready to make that call?
- Actually, I don’t make the call, Sir-.
- Yes you do Paul.
Each time you interpret a piece of data.
Each time you choose a “maybe”
over a “perhaps” you make a call.
A decision. And right now you’re
making lots of little decisions adding up to a big decision
But what if there’s a one
percent chance you’re wrong.
Can you say for sure you’ll take that
chance and state, as a fact,
that this equipment is not intended for
a nuclear weapons programme?
Do you know...
what one percent of the population of this country is?
It’s three million, two hundred
and forty thousand souls.
Sir. We’re not machines.
We look at the evidence, we game it
out. And believe it or not, Not everyone agrees all the time.
It’s a process.
- It’s a process.
- Yes.
And not everyone agrees.
Exactly.
Who doesn't agree?
What the hell is Joe Turner doing next to the DCI?
Didn’t you hear?
Friday the DCI took him to the White House.
He briefed the President on Aluminium tubes.
You’re gotta kidding me.
That guy's a tool.
Its a dead end.
So we’ve got a list of Iraqi Scientists.
How do you suggest we get to them?
Mukhbarat watch the scientists night and day there.
Their houses are bugged.
Their friends are followed.
Say we sent in a light weight tac
team from the north.
You get through the checkpoints and roadblocks.
You show up in my bedroom in the dead of the night
asking me to help out Uncle Sam?
I’m going to react unpredictably.
Even if we get to them,
they won't come out alone
They wanna bring their family,
their children, kids..
Once we are outside Basra,
We'll ask for Jordan's help.
Give me two months,
I'll give you two or three.
No. I have 29 names. I want to
get to them all.
The wall’s too high Val.
What are you going to do.
Train a mouse?
- Maybe.
Hey, did I wake you up?
It’s three forty five.. In the morning.
I gotta be at the airport in forty five minutes.
How long this time?
Do we need childcare for tomorrow-
I left it all in the post-it.
Of course, it's on the post-it.
I didn’t want to wake you.
All we’ve been leaving post-its for
each other for months now..
That fridge is like a dead letter drop.
I sound like
an old... Some old..
I don’t know where you go.
I don’t know who you meet.
If you’re in some jail,
or lying in some ditch in Jordan, Beirut.
And if you go missing,
I can’t tell anyone because you were never there.
I don’t know where you go.
I’m going to Cleveland.
It’s on the Post-It.
Have a good day.
The ink in this pen is visible for 10 seconds.
Only when given the the
correct chemical fixative can it be read.
If the Mukhbarat find any of this they
will do things to me you cannot imagine.
Tell me what you need to know.
I will memorise it
Ma’am, we have 50 very specific
questions, some extremely technical.
You have 206 different bones in your body.
Do you want their names
in english, latin or arabic?
How do you feel?
If anyone stops you
If anyone asks you anything,
stay calm.. You’re just visiting your brother.
Keep it simple.
How do you do it?
Lie to someone to their face?
Huh?
You have to know,
know why you're lying
And never forget the truth.
It’s time.
You're ready?
Based on the New York Times today, How close is Saddam
Hussein's govt. To developing a nuclear capabilities?
We do get different estimates about,
precisely how close he is.
We do know that That
there have been shipments into Iraq
for instance aluminum tubes that are only really suited for
nuclear weapons programs, centrifuge programs..
There will always be some uncertainty,
But we don't want the smoking gun
to be a mushroom cloud.
:..Equipments, needed would give
an enrichment capability.
Specifically aluminum tubes.
There’s a story in The New York Times this morning.
I want to attribute The Times.
I don’t want to talk about specific intelligenc...
- It’s a coordinated leak..
- I'm coming home.
I always close the doors.
I always roll up the window.
Yeah but you can still smell it.
What would you have me do? You want me to roll up a wet towel?
Like a teenager smoking, Maybe sandbag my study?
Just go out on the deck?
It’s minus ten degrees, out there.
Steve, Help me.
You are missing the whole point of a cigar
to get a little Winston Churchill vibe goin’.
Slippers.
A crackling fire.
Musty books, like a faithful dog.
You don't wanna be outside, GOOSEDOWN
freezing your balls off, alone in the dark.
Don’t think Churchill.
Think Scott of the Antarctic.
Can I ask a dumb question.
What is an aluminum tube?
They’re for centifuges.
For enriching uranium.
Oh, that really clears it up.
Have you read about this Valerie?
I was away last week on business.
I missed it.
Basically Saddam bought all these tubes.
And we’ve nailed him.
We have them.
They’re packed with uranium.
They’re not packed with uranium.
So, they’re for purifying. The bomb comes later.
It’s how you boil it up it to make the big one. Right?
Says who?
It’s a bunch of tubes.
Joe you know about this stuff,
These tubes. What’s your hunch on this?
I don’t know anything
about these tubes. I’m not qualified.
It’s a pretext!
50 % of Americans
think Saddam blew up the Towers-
You can’t tell me
he’s not a threat.
He’s mad. Like Hitler. If we’d
stopped Hitler in the thirties-
He’s not Hitler.
He’s Saddam.
Have you met him? Fred.
Have you met Saddam?
Has Saddam looked you in the eye?
Has he threaten to kill you?
You don’t know what you’re talking about.
We have a rule in our house.
No politicsat the table.
It always ends in a squabble.
I mean, nobody knows what’s going on over there.
At the end of the day, who really knows?
That's right Sue.
Nobody knows?
They’ve given me questions for you.
What questions?
How close is your program to a warhead?
When and where is the first test scheduled?
How much 235-
grade uranium do you have?
Identify other scientists in the program.
Who in the military controls the
program? Which of the-
What is it?
They do not know?
What Ahmad?
The program was destroyed in 90's.
The Americans destroyed it, they
know this.
My god..what else?
How advanced is the centrifuge facility?
Which method are you
using to separate fissile isotopes?
This is insane.
We don’t have spare
parts to keep a tank on the road.
I have to work at a plant which
develops fertilizer. And They know.
The inspectors are back.
They know this.
They must know.
You need to see this..
We need to get Jack to see this.
And Bill.
Ambassador Wilson is the last
American diplomat to meet with Saddam Hussein.
It was 1990, and
it was a pretty scary time.
Saddam threatened to execute
anybody sheltering people, He called, 'foreigners'
Ambassador Wilson, called a press conference
wearing a noose around his neck,
And he said,
The press reports:
“If the choice is to allow Americans
to be taken hostage or be executed,
I will bring my own fucking rope."
Saddam backed down
and Ambassador Wilson
helped thousands get safely home.
When he himself came home to the united states,
he was warmly greeted by our President.
Who took him to the Oval Office,
and introduced him to the War Cabinet,
as an American hero.
That’s not quite true.
It was the Roosevelt Room.
Not the oval office.
In the middle please...
Does Saddam pose
an imminent threath to National Security?
Zahara's brother worked with five
hundred scientists at the Safa factory.
In ‘91 it was blanket bombed by B52s.
Hussein Kamel,
kept the scientists together,
threatening to
kill them if they tried to leave.
But sanctions destroyed the economy,
and when Kamel was executed in ‘95, the team just drifted apart.
They’re all say the same thing Mike.
Everyone.
There's no weapons programme.
So you got thirty nuclear scientists interrogated by Iraqis,
inside Iraq, who are all saying the same thing.
Jim, these people took a great risk-
To bring us what? I could have
saved us the air-fare-
The White House is getting
STOVEPIPED.
Someone is cherry picking
raw dataand serving it up to the press as fact.
And then they look to us to confirm it.
It’s bullshit.
One of Saddam's minister asked him,
"Why he had executed a certain official
who had been a loyal supporter"?
Saddam said...
"I would rather kill a friend in error
than allow an enemy to live."
For me, that is the mark of a monster.
Vice President Cheney, Members of Congress,
distinguished citizens, fellow citizens:
Every year, by law and by custom,
we meet here to consider the state of the union.
- Thank you, so much.
- You're Welcome.
Oh wait, We’d like you to have this coffee mug.
And some Pennants. For your kids.
Thank you so much for coming and speaking to us.
- Thank you, thank you.
From three Iraqi defectors we know that
Iraq, in the late 1990s, had several mobile biological weapons labs.
Saddam Hussein had an advanced nuclear weapons
development program,
Had a design for a nuclear weapon.
And was working on five different methods
of enriching uranium for a bomb.
The British government has learned that Saddam
Hussein recently sought significant quantities of uranium from Africa.
Our intelligence sources tell us
that he has attempted to purchase high-strength aluminum tubes
suitable for nuclear weapons production
his nation fights reluctantly,
because we know the cost,
and we dread the days of mourning that always come.
We seek peace.
We strive for peace.
And sometimes peace must be defended.
Bill. Wait up.
Every Team is combing
the desert looking for WMD. I can’t-
All I need’s a couple units to bring these men and thei
families into Camp Lima and on an air transport into Annandale.
Say we extract these guys.
Bring ‘em home. Put ‘em on CNN.
What are they going to tell us
that the White House wants to hear?
“Thank you oh and by the way there was no
nuclear programme. There’s no WMD.
PS you all knew that.”
Think about it, you want me to go to the DCI,
ask him to sign off on his own funeral?
Bill, I gave my word.
That’s not my problem.
I got biggerproblems.
It’s like, if there was a baby on
the ledge up on seventh,
no-one would get up and save it in case
the White House wanted it there.
Bill’s right.
This is just one snafu in a thousand we got right
now. The scientists are-
These scientists are the WMD.
If we can’t protect them,
they’ll run to the first country who can.
And they’ll put them to work.
I never said this.
If anyone asks,
I deny any knowledge.
How quietly can you do this?
Listen Pete. I have a question. And
it’s real important.
Is the President be referring to
another African country... and not Niger?
I’ve seen the INR. It’s Niger.
He’s referring specifically to
Yellowcake from Niger. Why?
I'm the 'source'
I went to Niger, It's wrong.
Its not true.
I see...
What exactly are you proposing to do?
I don’t know what I am gonna do.
You want my advice? Do nothing.
You already did your job. You did your best.
You came home. End of story.
We were talking about Niger Pete.
Yellowcake from Niger.
Look. I don’t have to go all the way to Africa
to know something’s messed up here.
Three months and
what have we found? No centrifuges.
No yellowcake. No bio. No WMDs.
You think something’s up here. Join the line stretches
all the way from State to the Pentagon and back.
So why has no one’s stepped forward?
Why you think Joe? We went to war.
Listen.
As your friend, now.
Just. Be smart.
You have a wife and a family.
We are talking about
President. Of the United States.
The WHITE HOUSE.
Now go take a long
look in the mirror and say that again.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm just tired.
Are the kids asleep.
Yeah. They’re asleep?
OK. Good.
I’m gonna go up.
There are some who feel like that,
the conditions are such that
they can attack us there.
My answer is bring 'em on..
We got the force necessary
to deal with security situation.
“What I Didn’t Find in Africa”.
Look. There’s zero, nada, nothing, new here.
The President's statement
in the State of the Union was much broader
than the Niger question.
Is the President's statement
correct?
Yes, I see nothing that goes broader
that would indicate that
there was no basis to the President's broader statement.
But specifically on the yellow cake,
the yellow cake for Niger,
we've acknowledged that that information
did turn out to be a forgery.
So you believe the British report
is true?
I'm sorry?
- The British report?
Mark, Clear my morning.
So, it was wrong then?
Let me do this, David.
On your specific question I'm going to come back to you.
Fleischer ploughed the briefing-
I saw.
- CBS know Yellowcake was pulled
from Cincinnatti ten weeks ago at the CIAs request.
They also have
that Gerson wrote both speeches.
Karl is looking for you.
He’s unhappy-
I want a transcript of everything across networks,
blogs and print citing Ambassador Wilson, Niger or Yellowcake.
And tell Karl I’ll be in
my office straight after I’m done.
This has become a trust issue for
the President.
We can’t get behind this.
We need to change the story.
Who is Joe Wilson?
David, If someone works for the CIA,
and sends their spouse on a trip.
Would there be a paper-trail?
No.
Any such request will require
the approval of the chain of command.
From the request stored
right up the director of Operation.
Yes, a paper work would normally be generated.
Does the President
has the power to de-classify Information?
Valerie.
What?
The CIA's decision to send retired
diplomat Joseph C. Wilson to Africa-
Further down.
Wilson never worked for the CIA,
but his wife, Valerie Plame..
“Is an agency operative on weapons
of mass destruction.”
They just went ahead and did it.
Does this run overseas?
Novak’s column.
Is he syndicated overseas?
Its everywhere.
We need a matrix of everyone you've come into
contact with in a covert capacity.
I’ve already started a list.
- Good.
We need to get an idea..fast,
of how much this thing bleeds.
Sir, I have several live ops at
crucial stages,
people in the field
in critical windows of operation-
One thing at time.
Make a list. Then come back here.
Don’t do anything else.
Why is Internal security here?
To help us.
To help you, and us
conduct this damage assessment.
Miss Plame?
We are going this way.
Jack, I gotta get a message to Baghdad.
I've got fifteen scientists being taken to the border today.
I have to get word to them.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Jack, they are packed and ready to go.
You know what this means.
Sorry, I gotta go.
Val?
A few minutes.
Take a walk.
As of this morning
all CPD operations involving you have been suspended.
Effective immediately you are to have no further
contact with assets or agents in the field.
Any further involvement
in operations is no longer possible.
Bill. I have eight,
nine teams in the field.
We have assets in Kuala
Lumpur.Mumbai. Dubai.
I need to brief my replacement in
the Joint Task Force.
The head of the JTFI’s identity is classified
for reasons of operational security.
I have a critical operation in
Baghdad in a major ongoing-
Val!
I'm sorry.
It's over.
You're a good officer.
But, it's over.
“Two senior administration officials told me that Wilson's
wife suggested sending him to Niger,
to investigate the Italian report."
This comes from a Vice President,
a chief of staff or top advisor..I gotta go.
There’s a 1982 act states it’s a crime for a government
official to intentionally disclose a covert agent.
Comes with a fine of fifty thousand dollars fine
and or up to ten years in jail.
- Don't answer the phone, honey.
- It’s been ringing all day.
Your mom called. And your Uncle.
And Janey called from Chicago. I wrote them down.
And Andrea Mitchell called.
She says White House sources say,
“the real story here is not
the sixteen words but Joe Wilson and his wife”.
Would I care to comment?
Well, I damn well do care to comment.
She's asked me on the show day after tomorrow.
No. You are not going on TV, Joe.
This is clearly designed as a shot across the bow
to those who might step forward,
those unnamed analysts who said they were
pressured by the White House for example,
would think twice about having their own
families names
being dragged
through this particular mud.
I didn't prepare for this moment.
I had no plan for this day.
- When did you joined?
- 85 straight out of college.
- Wow... that's?
- 18 years.
So, did they find you? Or
No, I approached them.
And, did Joe know?
- Yes.
- And your parents?
- Yeah, but that's all.
- So.. You have like lovers all over the world?
- Did they make you kill people?
I can't tell you anything.
So... do you want to go shopping?
Some, mani..pedi?
Hello
Your husband is a communist.
I hope you die you communist whore.
We know where you live.
Ahmad has disappeared.
His wife,
his children are missing.
My uncle in Mansour.
He said they were targeting them.
They were killing them..
Who?
Ahmad’s colleagues.
Dr Habbuck was shot dead in the street.
Dr Falli was murdered in his hallway.
- Listen Zahara...
I know you can’t tell me where he is.
Just tell me you have him... I beg you.
I don’t need to know anything.
Just tell me he’s safe..
We don’t have him.
You said he would be safe.
You said we would help.
You promised-
I trusted you.
The justice department need to establish
whether those in the Highest Office
sought to destroy the career of a public servant to
punish me for speaking the truth.
What are you doing here?
Falli. Habbuck.
Who else?
I don’t know what you’re talking about.
Don't bullshit me.
Who else is dead?
You were right.
It’s all about the scientists.
We made a call.
A call?
We passed your case files to liason.
Mossad were already on the same page.
They’ve been trying to hunt these
guys down since the invasion.
You’ll drive them underground.
They’ll run straight to Iran. Pakistan.
Valerie. It's not your problem ...
How can you sleep when you
know-
I sleep just fine.
Now Carol’s mother is here.
I’m going to have to ask you to leave.
It’s called counter-proliferation, Jack.
Counter!
At the end of the day,
it's of keen interest to me to see whether or not
we can get Karl Rove frog-marched out of White House in handcuffs.
And believe me when I use
that name, I measure my words.
Mr.Wilson?
We came all the way from Portland for this.
My wife and I have never sought publicity.
But I know when I tell her about how much support there
was here today, she’ll be thrilled and humbled.
Valerie, turn on the MSNBC
They've launched the investigation.
The FBI now is conducting a criminal investigation,
into who leaked the name of the CIA...
I'm gonna be back later.
I've got to go over to FOX
They want me to comment on the investigation.
Joe Wilson.
Joe, it's Christ Matthews,
I just spoke to Carl Rowe,
He told me...
"Wilson's wife, Is Fair Game"
Thank you for coming here
I wanted to convey my outrage to
you in person.
I know it’s not easy for you,
but I want you to know how much the agency
appreciates your silence in the light of this matter.
We can’t afford for this knife fight
to go on any longer.
I get death threats every day.
People threatening to kill my husband.
Hurt my children.
I went to the agency and
I requested security to protect my family.
I was declined.
Because quote
“My circumstances fall outside budgetprotocols.”
If this is a knife fight, Sir
- but right now, we’re fighting it alone.
Joe Wilson versus the White House. Huh?
Well, all I can say is Good Luck.
But as a friend, I feel I should
tell you that those men..
Those few men in that building over there,
Are the most powerful men in the history of the world.
How much of a stretch do you think
it would be for them to take on Joe Wilson?
Joe’s out there on his own Valerie.
But I know we can trust you.
Speak to your husband.
Tucker Carlson said yesterday
that Wilson’s wife sent him on a boondoggle.
Said I needed the work.
Who needs to work for free?
It's not like Niger is known for its fine dining
and celebrated Operas.
It reminds me of Paris.
Listen,
someone from Vanity Fair called.
They want to do a piece.
They wanna do a full scale
interview, photographs...
tell the whole story.
What do you think about that?
What do I think?
Do I want my photograph in Vanity Fair?
Is that the question?
Valerie, this is our chance.
To do what?
To tell our side of the story.
It'll mean..
A dozen, maybe fifty TV appearances,
we have to do that.
They are killing us.
On Fox, in the blogs..
They are drowning us out.
We've gotta strike back.
What?
What did I say?
Don't you get it Joe.
I mean where does all this stop.
Our address is on the internet.
A photo of our house.
I changed our phone numbers..what?
Five times now?
My name, my name's everywhere.
My real name, Joe.
Where doe this all tough talks and publicity
and noise and all the bullshit that you're doing.
Where is it getting us?
Andy Karl told the Financial Times
that they’re rolling the earth movers over Joe Wilson. Quote.
Earth Movers.
Well I’m sorry
but they don’t get me without a fight.
Not without one hell of a fight.
It’s the White House Joe.
You seriously think you can pick a
fight with the White House and win.
They’ll bury us.
They’ll bury us if we don’t.
If I’m the White House, and I shout
a million times louder than you
Does that make me right?
They lied Valerie.
They lied.
And that's the truth.
Truth..right?
Well, By the time they’re finished here
you won’t know what that is.
Scooter home?
What’s that?
The senate just finished an investigation.
Findings of the Select Committee on Intelligence.
All five hundred pages and eleven pages of it.
Check out page 39.
What’s that?
That is the Senate Select Committee
on Intelligence.
On page thirty nine...
it says “the former ambassador's
wife offered up his name"
It includes a memorandum written by
Valerie Plame which says quote
"my husband has good relations with
both the prime minister and the former Minister of Mines,
both of whom could possibly
shed light on this sort of activity."
This is exactly what i've been denying..
I've been to every newspaper,
Every television, radio anybody, that'd listen to me.
That 'My wife did not send me on a junket'.
I didn‘t send you.
I didn’t have that power.
You sent an email.
The SSCI found the email.
I write hundreds of emails.
Why didn’t you tell me?
It never occured to you that it's important....
I didn’t make the decision.
I was asked to write a recommendation.
What am I supposed to do.
Not say my husband knows about this.
Well..They have this now.
They will call me a liar.
It will stick.
They have all the power here,
what do I have?
My word.
You've got to speak up, Valerie.
You have to go on record now.
You have to defend us. Now.
So what do you want me to do?
Go to the papers like you did?
Write a piece in the New York
Times?
You know I’d have to submit it to the Agency,
The agency?
Valerie, Where’s your loyalty?
To your husband or the CIA?
It’s to MY FAMILY.
I put my family first. ALWAYS.
Were you putting them first
when you wrote that God damned article?
I’m taking different routes to and from school.
I’m looking in empty rooms..
Under the beds every time I come home.
A home we’re going to lose
because your work has dried up
and your clients are running for cover.
What has all this achieved? Joe?
Maybe you’re right.
Maybe I should
have kept my mouth shut.
Is that what your dad taught you Valerie?
Is that what Colonel Sam Plame say..
A good American just keeps his mouth shut.
A good American looks the other way.
Did you send me to Niger?
“His business is struggling. He’s
on the slide. I'll pull a few string..
How dare you?
You think I’m lying to you.
Could I tell if you were?
Well, I think it's really all about the money.
We're talking about a third-rate CIA agent
who had a government salary,
She could've transferred withing the CIA,
She didn't have to leave.
Probably, the CIA wanted her to leave.
B'cos she'd already been in the press,
without their permission.
It's come out that ...
she was considered kind of a mediocre agent at best
When we were at the “Farm”,
training to be field officers,
they picked four or five of us
and told us we’d stood out.
We were bound, hooded and thrown in
separate cells.
They'd deprive us of slepp.
They beat us.
All you had to do was give up
the name of one of the others.
Just one name.
They push you until they find it.
Til they find the point at which you break.
And one by one,
everybody broke.
Except me.
And that made me feel special.
You can’t break me.
I don’t have a breaking point.
I was wrong.
Can I help you? Excuse me.
Can I help you?
I’m just telling these people that
you sir are a fraud.
OK. This is a private lunch.
Pleaseleave us alone.
This man is a liar and a traitor.He is in the pay of left wing hat
groups, he is a democrat stooge, and he is an anti-war zealot.
He has stabbed our troops the back.
Pallisades.
You OK?
I’m fine.
You’re him. I see you on the TV.
You’re Joe Wilson.
No, I’m not.
Yes brother. I see you on the TV.
That’s somebody else.
No no. I know you.
My name is Joe too.
I am from Sierra Leone.
Freetown. You’ve been there, right.
You like Freetown?
Joe, we both know Freetown’s a shit hole.
That’s the truth. That’s the truth right there, brother.
Yes indeed. Sierra Leone is dying.
There's too much injustice and corruption in Sierra Leone.
WAY too much power.
People can’t see that from here.
Over here it’s a different world.
I wouldn’t be so sure of that.
How can you say that?
Land of theFree, brother.
Home of the Brave.
Can we pull over.
I’m going to walk.
Look keep the change.
How’s is he?
Oh you know. Getting better.
Shakin’ through.
OK. See those birds. Those guys.
Those yellow fellas. See ‘em..
Yeah I see ‘em.
I think my marriage is over, Dad.
Well. I know my little girl doesn’t
say anything til she absolutely has to.
There's gonna be another
Congressional investigation,
He wants me to speak out.
Go on the record.
Like that would suddently make all this go away.
We can't even speak to each other.
I can remember saying exactly the same thing,
July 1972, me and your mom
Were'nt getting along,
were fighting all the time.
I guess she was just plain
had enough of moving house.
Wasn’t ‘til I retired after 25 years in the Air Force,
I realised we never had a home.
Germany, Singapore, Australia, England.
Twenty different chances to introduce yourself.
I can’t see how this comes round.
Not this time.
Not anymore.
What they did was wrong Valerie.
Just plain wrong.
Don't you ever forget that.
Say through some miracle you even get through this thing,
there's no guarantee you and Joe won't fight.
He’s a stubborn son of a
bitch too. He don't give up anymore than you are.
I swear to God, she’s gonna keep at
that until she licks it.
They served up Libby.
He’s taking the fall.
I bet they’ve already struck the deal.
He takes the fall. The deck’s stacked.
He gets pardoned.
I bet this doesn’t even get to a trial.
I don’t care what they say about us.
I don’t care how angry you get.
If they take all this away, I don't care.
They do not get to take my marriage.
I’m so sorry.
You did good.
I did it for me.
I know why you did it.
Thank you.
If I could give it back to you.
If I could give you back who you were-
This is who I am. Right here.
Are you ready to fight?
How many of you know who put the 16
words in the State of the Union address?
How many of you know my wife’name?
How do you know one and not the other?
How did the question move from
“Why are we going to war?” to “Who is that man’s wife”.
I asked the first question.
But somebody else asked the second. It worked.
Because we still don’t know the truth.
The offense wasn’t committed against me.
It was not committed against my wife...
It was committed against you.
All of you.
If that makes you angry.
Or feel misrepresented.
Do something about it.
When Benjamin Franklin left the Independence Hall
just after the second drafting,
He was approached by a women on the street.
The woman said;
"Mr.Franklin, what manner of government
have you bequeathed us?
And Franklin said
'A Republic, madam.'
If you can keep it.'
The responsibilty of a country
Is not in the hands of a privileged few.
We are strong and we are free
from tyranny only
as long as each one of us remember,
his or her duty as a citizen.
Whether its a pothole at the end of your street
or a lie in the State of the Union Address..
Speak up. Ask those questions.
Demand that truth.
Democracy is not a free ride...
Man I’m here to tell you.
But this is where we live.
And if we do our job
this is where our children will live.
God bless America.
Mrs.Wilson,
we are pleased to have you here.
Thank you very much
for coming to our committee today.
Its the practice of this committee,
that all witnesses are administered and announce.
And I'd like you to stand
and rise your right hand.
'Do you promise to tell the truth,
and nothing but the truth'
I do.
Now there's a button on the base of the Mic
You can press it in,
and pull it closely enough..
So you can be heard.
Good morning,
Mr. Chairman and members of the committee.
My name is Valerie Plame Wilson,
and I am honored
to have been invited to testify under oath
before the Committee on Oversight and
Government Reform on the critical issue...
...of safeguarding classified information.
I'm grateful for this opportunity
to set the record straight.
I served the United States loyally and
to the best of my ability as a covert operations
officer for the Central Intelligence Agency.
I worked on behalf of the national security of
our country, on behalf of the people of the United States
until my name and true affiliation were exposed
tothe national media on July 14th, 2003,
after a leak by administration officials.
Today I can tell this committee even more.
In the run-up to the war with Iraq
I worked in the Counter Proliferation
Division of the CIA,
still as a covert officer
whose affiliation with the CIA was classified.
I raced to discover solid intelligence
for senior policy makers on Iraq's
presumed weapons of mass destruction program.
While I helped to manage and run secret
worldwide operations against this WMD target
from CIA headquarters in Washington,
I also traveled to foreign countries on
secret missions to find vital intelligence.
I loved my career
because I love my country.
I was proud of the
serious responsibilitiesentrusted to me
As a CIA Covert operations Officer...