I will now tell you about my brother.
My brother, Jonathan Lionheart.
It's almost like a fairytale,
and yet all of it is true.
But only Jonathan and I knows that.
Everybody in the whole town loved Jonathan.
Jonathan was originally named Lion,
just like mom and me.
My name is Karl.
Jonathan calls me Rusk,
only because he loves rusks so much,
he says.
It was that day when I found out
that i'm about to die.
One of those ladies whom my mom
sows dresses for said it.
- What is it, Rusk? Are you sad?
- Yes...
Jonatan, do you know that i'm about to die?
Yes, I know that.
How can it be so horrible, that some
of us must die before they've turned ten?
Know what, Rusk?
I don't think it's that bad.
It's bad to just lie in the ground,
and be dead, isn't it?
It's just your shell that lies there.
Your soul flies away somewhere else,
far away.
Where to?
- To Nangijala.
- Nangijala...?
Somewhere beyond the stars. It lies
in a time of campfires and fairytales.
There you will experience adventures.
That'll be something else than just lying
here being sick.
In Nangijala, you'll be strong and healthy.
[Mom sings]
"Dör jag på sjön, du ljuva,
kanske en kväll...
...flyger en snövit duva
hem till ditt tjäll...
[Karl coughs]
...flyger en snövit duva
hem till ditt tjäll"
Maybe you'll come flying to visit me
some night... from Nangijala.
And you'll sit there, by the window,
like a snow white pigeon.
Here - have some honeywater, Rusk.
Jonathan, i'm afraid.
I don't want to go to Nangijala.
I want to be here with you.
You'll probably live until your ninety,
and I'll have to wait for you until then!
Yes, but even though I might turn ninety
years old...
...it's only like two days for you.
And you can handle being alone for two days,
can't you?
You'll climb in the trees,
and make a campfire.
You'll do some fishing by the lake.
And suddenly, as you catch that perch,
I'll come flying.
Wouldn't it be great if you were there
before me, and you were the one doing the
fishing...
...and I came flying.
But instead, I might have to live on
earth for ninety years before I get to
see my Rusk again.
Well, that's what we thought,
but it didn't turn out that way.
Jonatan is in Nangijala now.
We jumped.
I made it, Jonathan didn't.
Dear Jonathan Lejon...
...shouldn't your name really have been;
Jonathan Lejonhjärta?
When we read about the brave english
king Richard Lionheart...
I wasn't on Jonathan's funeral,
i was too ill.
His old schoolteacher held a speech
for him.
It was good that she made up that part
about Lionheart, really good.
I'm afraid.
What if Nangijala doesn't exist?
What if it's one of those things that
Jonathan just made up.
"Flyger en snövit duva
hem till ditt tjäll. "
Jonathan...!
Then it is true.
In Nangijala, in Cherry Valley...
Will you sit down by the lake,
when I arrive?
No... I am not afraid anymore.
Send my regards to Nangijala!
I will soon be there!
[Karl coughs]
Jonathan...
Jonathan!
- Jonathan!
- Rusk!
[Laughter]
Jonathan...
Jonathan!
[Screaming and laughter]
- Look! I can swim!
- Of course you can, you're in Nangijala now!
Jonathan, we've got rabbits!
Oh, they're so cute.
Jonathan, can I let one out and
play with it?
Look, we've got horses too!
- Oh, they are so beautiful!
- This is Grim and Fjalar.
- Guess which one's yours.
- Mine?! But I don't even know how to ride a horse!
- Well, you could swim, couldn't you?
- Yes, but do I know how to ride, as well?
- Yes. Guess which one's yours.
- The white one, maybe?
Nope, you guessed wrong.
Grim, is my horse. Fjalar is yours.
My own horse...!
Sophia!
Well, Jonathan. Your brother finally
arrived, didn't he?
- This is Sophia.
- I brought you something to eat.
You'll be at Golden Rooster tonight,
won't you? Bring Karl too.
- So how's Cherry Valley?
- We rode today...
...and I can swim.
Wow, I look great! And you look even better!
You look like a prince!
[Laughter]
You told me that, in Nangijala there
will be adventures from morning 'til
night.
And during the nights as well, do you
remember that? But this place seems
so peaceful.
Yes, but there are adventures here
that shouldn't be, but don't be afraid.
- Remember that your name is Lionheart.
- Rusk Lionheart.
We'll have to call you Karl,
so people won't laugh at you.
- I've never been to an inn before.
- There's nothing to be afraid of.
There are only nice people in here.
[Music]
- Here's Jonathan!
- Yes, here comes Jonathan!
Oh look, here are the Brothers Lionheart,
both of them!
This is my brother, Karl Lionheart,
who's finally arrived.
And you will all be nice to him,
just like you've been to me.
We'll become great friends. My name is
Jossi, but people call me Golden Rooster!
And you can come see me whenever you like!
Don't you forget that, Karl Lionheart!
Now, let's get you some food.
Come!
The message will arrive tomorrow morning.
Will you attend?
- Have you told Hubert?
- Shh!
Well, Karl, did you like your horse?
It's the most beautiful horse in existence.
What's so special about Sophia?
Right. What's so special about Sophia.
I've been wondering about that for
very long.
- Who's that?
- He... his name is Hubert.
And he know god damn well what's so
special about Sophia.
[Singing]
"Sjung du min dal med brinnande röst"
"tyst dina heta sånger"
"Sjung markens gräs
och susa vart träd"
"sakta om dagen som kommer"
"Sjung källa och flod
sjung stenar och jord"
"Ge oss till tröst era sånger"
"O, sjung du min dal
och brinn i din tro"
på frihetens dag som kommer"
How come they're treating Sophia so special?
what's so special about her?
You tell me?
We call her The Pigeon Queen.
The Pigeon Queen?
Jonathan, were you one of Sophia's pigeons,
when you visited me?
Yes, only Sophia's pigeons may fly
through the skies, how far as ever.
And they are the only ones who can
get into Rose Thorn Valley.
It's like this,
Nangijala is divided into two green valleys.
Here lies Cherry Valley,
and over there...
...beyond the mountains, lay Rose Thorn Valley.
Tengil and his riders have conquered it.
The people are his slaves.
But Sophia's pigeons, they fly over mountains
and walls with their messages.
Oh, you're heading to Sophia?
What are you up to?
- I'm her garden helper.
- I know that, Jonathan.
- And you're out hunting?
- I was gonna shoot me a couple of wild rabbits.
Oh, her garden helper, sure...
Why are you looking so sad, Sophia?
I found Violanta dead, with an arrow
in her chest, and the message gone.
Then there is a traitor in Cherry Valley.
Thank god, here comes Paloma!
Are you carrying a happier message for me
this time, Paloma?
- I can't stand bad news again.
- What does it say?
"Orvar was captured yesterday, and is
now kept prisoner in Katla Cave."
"Someone in Cherry Valley betrayed his
whereabouts. Find out who."
It can't be true!
Who could be that foul?
I don't know, not yet. But god help him
when I find out.
...and poor Karl, with that clueless look.
Tell him everything.
He must also know.
Without Orvar, Rose Thorn Valley will
never get its freedom back.
He leads the struggle against Tengil.
But he's been captured and brought to
the Katla Cave in Tengil's land.
Jonathan.
Jonathan!
- Jonathan!
- Yes, what is it?
- Does everyone in Cherry Valley know about this?
- About what?
This about Sophia's pigeons, and the
secret messages, and all?
No, only the one that we deem
trustworthy.
But among them is a traitor.
Rusk, you're gonna have to remain
alone on Rider's Farm for a while.
- I must leave for Rose Thorn Valley.
- What are you saying?! Aren't you ashamed?!
Rusk!
If you're gonna let Tengil catch you,
then I'll come with you!
I'm not waiting around!
Maybe you'll never return!
Rusk...
I can't bring you along for
something that dangerous.
I'm Sophia's closest man.
I must save Orvar.
Why can't Sophia go by herself, then?
We can't afford to lose her.
She leads the struggle. Tengil knows this.
The one who catches her alive will
be rewarded with fifteen white horses.
How many for the one who catches you,
then?
Why do you have to do things that
are that dangerous?
There are things that must be done,
even though they're dangerous.
- Why?
- Otherwise you're no human being...
...but just a small piece of dirt.
Jonathan!
- Are you sure you're coming back?
- Don't be sad. I'm sure.
I don't even know where you're going.
To Rose Thorn Valley, and then to Tengil's
land, to the Mountain of Ages Past.
- No, don't shoot!
- What are you doing this far from home?
I'm out riding.
I see you're out hunting?
That's one way to put it, yes.
Ask Jonathan to stop by the Golden Rooster
some time.
He's in the mountains, hunting wolf.
Sophia!
- Oh Karl, are you out this late?
- Hubert is the traitor!
He tried to shoot one of your pigeons!
Anyone but Hubert.
He fights for freedom, just like us.
- Have you heard anything from Jonathan?
- Neither good, nor evil.
- How are you keeping up?
- I miss Jonathan.
- Help!
- Jonathan!
Yes, Jonathan. I will come.
I'll do it.
I'm no piece of dirt.
Has he been here already?
- He would have waited.
- Well, who was here, then?
We'll get him for sure,
unless he shows up!
What's his use, anyway?
Shooting pigeons...
Time to brand him with the mark of Katla,
so he knows where he belong.
It'll be my pleasure.
Ah, there he is, finally!
- So it's finally time to arrive, is it?
- Jossi...
This is from the pigeon I shot last night.
Lionheart is still at large, we know that!
A hundred men are looking for him, day and night!
Find out where he's hiding.
He's got a little brother, in Cherry Valley,
who he loves dearly.
We'll use him as bait, and we'll be
able to catch both Sophia and Lionheart.
Why haven't you told us earlier?
I don't want you to hurt the boy.
I'm kinda fond of him.
- You haven't forgotten the password, have you?
- "All power to Tengil - our saviour!"
Tengil hasn't forgotten his promise,
has he?
Jossi - Chieftain of Cherry Valley!
Sure sure.
And you'll get the mark of Katla, too!
No!
Ouch!
Now you know that you are one of us,
forever! And a traitor, you are!
That one...
that'll be a swell meal for Katla.
Bring out the horses.
Look, there they are!
[Fjalar neighs]
Fjalar! Shut up!
How long have you been lying here,
spying on us?
Well, where do you belong?
Cherry Valley or Rose Thorn Valley?
Where do you live?!
- Rose Thorn Valley.
- Well, we'll find out about that!
- What were you doing in the mountains?
- I was just watching the moonlight...
- Who are you parents, then?
- My parents...?
- I live with my grandpa.
- What's his name, then?
What his name is?
- Just "grandpa".
- You're kinda stupid, aren't you?
- Where in Rose Thorn Valley does he live, then?
- In a small white house...
This grandpa, and this house,
you're about to show us.
- Password!
- All power to Tengil - our saviour!
- Who's this?
- A silly we found in the mountains.
How did he get out of Rose Thorn Valley
last night?
- Who was on guard last night?
- Step aside, we're passing through!
Ride ahead and show us the way.
Halt!
Search the wagon!
- Where is your grandpa? Is he far off?
- No. Not too far.
Why are you stopping?
Do you recognise this boy?
If we don't find your grandpa soon,
we'll throw you in the Katla Cave.
Help me! Save me! Tell them you're
my grandpa.
What do you mean... what do you mean
by staying out so long?
What have you been up to, with these
soldiers showing up, and all?!
Better watch out for your grandchildren!
He was far away in the mountains.
It is punishable by death to be there.
- Were you?
- He was!
In order to watch the moonlight!
Are you really that mad, boy?
If you don't behave better, you
may soon not have any grandchildren left!
There, there. It's over now.
- I really wish you were my grandpa.
- Well, I'll be your grandpa, alright.
My name is Mattias. What is yours?
My name is... please Mattias, my name
must remain a secret, but you may call me Rusk.
Hey, wake up.
Come, and I will show you something,
Rusk Lionheart.
- I never told you my name is Lionheart.
- No, you didn't.
For that is a name that must not
be said aloud in Rose Thorn Valley.
Well, let's see.
Go down.
Just go down.
Don't be afraid.
Jonathan!
- Do you think it's bad that i'm here?
- No, Rusk.
I've missed you so much.
You yelled... you yelled for help.
Why were you yelling?
I saw Katla.
I saw what Katla did.
Jonathan, I know now who the traitor
of Cherry Valley is. It is Jossi.
Fly, my Bianca, over the mountains
of Nangijala, to Cherry Valley.
Fly to Sophia, with the name of
the traitor!
- What are you doing outside, old man?
- Go to grandpa!
Such a nice weather tonight.
You do know that it is punishable by
death to remain outside after dawn,
don't you?
- By the way, where is the boy?
- The boy...? The boy?
Here he is!
Aren't you gonna head off to the
mountains to watch the moonlight?
What was your name again?
- Rusk...
- Rusk.
Tell your grandpa what happens if you're
not inside before dawn.
- Let's go inside, boy.
- Hey, old man!
- You wouldn't know where Lionheart is, would you?
- I don't know anyone named Lionheart.
Lucky you, for a death sentence awaits
the one who is giving him shelter.
Death sentence here, and death sentence there...
that's the only thing they'll ever say.
[Trumpets]
People of Rose Thorn Valley!
From the Mountains of Ages Past,
over the Lake of Ages Past,
your saviour has come! Tengil
of Karmanjaka has something to say!
Thus spoke our merciful duke:
He is disappointed with the people of
Rose Thorn Valley!
Lionheart is yet to be found!
The people of Rose Thorn Valley
are hiding him.
Our merciful duke's patience is
about to run out.
He will punish Rose Thorn Valley
cruelly and mercilessly!
But our merciful duke will postpone
the punishment!
And listen up, good people,
he will reward you well!
Twenty white horses, to the one
who captures Lionheart for him!
- Then I shall find the bastard.
- Have you no sense?
- No, not too much, anyway.
- Jonathan!
- Are you out of your mind?
- I must see what's going on.
Our merciful duke has yet
another errand!
Every man in Rose Thorn Valley,
who can work, step forward!
- Where are they taking those people?
- They're off to Karmanjaka...
...to drag rocks to Tengil's keep.
The one he's built on the top
of the Mountain of Ages Past.
They'll work until they have no strength
left, and then Katla'll get them.
No, no, no...
Tyrant! One day you will die, too!
Have you ever thought about that?
[Weeping]
- Where does this tunnel end?
- On the other side of the wall.
- When it's done, anyway.
- And then?
Then we'll rescue Orvar from the
Katla Cave.
Jonathan... who is Katla?
[Footsteps above]
Are you out of your mind? Leaving
the hatch open, without anyone keeping
watch?
Get this through your head:
Never let Jonathan be down there...
...without closing the hatch!
Tengil reigns this land.
I'm sorry, we forgot. Here's some
more dirt for you field.
Dark, the night shall be,
in Rose Thorn Valley.
There are many eyes here, who want
to see what they must not see.
What's going on?
- What's going on here?
- You're about to find out!
- Get up!
- Ouch!
There is no Lionheart. It's just an
excuse to turn people's houses upside
down.
Beware, old man, or I'll cut your ears
off, and maybe your nose aswell!
Look, a fire! Are you out of your mind?
...to throw wool in front of a fire!
Silent! Or I'll think of several
ways to keep you quiet.
Aren't you going to clean up?
Why don't you clean up your dump yourself,
old man!
[Entering the stables]
You don't need two horses.
Put your mark on this.
- You're gladly giving Tengil your horses.
- I don't feel any joy.
You do too. We'll send a man to get
the horses tonight.
If you want to live, you'll give
him the badge with your mark on.
Tengil wants proof of you giving
your horses to us freely.
Are one supposed to laugh or cry?
- Why don't you dress up like a soldier?
- That won't help.
There, there.
Don't cry in the soup, little Rusk.
There's already enough water in there.
The password...
If I only had that password!
What password?
You've got to have a password to
pass through the gates.
I heard that from Jossi, while
i was in the cave.
- Do you remember it?
-"All power to Tengil - our saviour."
You know something? I really like you.
Take good care of yourself, Mattias;
Until we meet again.
You too. Take care,
Jonathan Lionheart.
Goodbye then, boy!
Don't forget your grandpa!
I'll never forget you!
Never ever!
- Grandpa, do you think we'll find Orvar?
- I'll keep my fingers crossed.
What if Jonathan isn't waiting for me?
What if he never got out?
[Knocking]
Hey! Old man! The stables are empty!
Where are your horses?
My horses...? You've already
taken them, damn it.
What?!
- Ask the guards by the gate!
- I don't understand.
Is it really my fault that you mess
things up so badly that you don't even
know what you're doing anymore?
Karma Falls.
The river of ages past.
Now we must eat and sleep.
Tomorrow we must continue by foot.
- What about Grim and Fjalar?
- They'll be safe here until we return.
There, on the other side, lies
Karmanjaka. The land of Tengil.
We're sitting by a campfire, you and me.
I've longed for this all my life.
"in a time of campfires and fairytales",
do you remember saying that?
I didn't know back then, that the
fairytales of Nangijala would be
this evil.
- Must it always be that way?
- No.
When the final battle is over...
...the fairytales will be beautiful
again, and life will be easy.
But the final battle, Rusk,
will be a sinister story,
containing only death.
That battle must be led by Orvar.
I can't kill anyone.
I know that.
[Roar]
What was that? There!
Jonathan, i'm afraid.
Don't worry, she can't come here.
She is a monster.
A female dragon, from ages past,
much as cruel as Tengil himself.
When he blows his horn, she'll
do whatever he commands.
She'll come creeping, like a dog.
Up there, lies Tengil's Keep.
- Where is the Katla Cave, then?
- Come.
The Black Keepers are bringing
Katla here tonight!
Tell that pig that this will be
his last supper!
As the saying goes:
Orvar might die, but freedom will never!
Well, we'll see what Katla has
to say about that. Tonight.
- We'll never get through there, right?
- No, not through the copper gate.
The stories speak of another entrance,
just north of the mountains.
Yes, this one. I don't know
what awaits me in there...
but i'm going.
It'll be a long and hard way back.
I probably won't be back for quite
some time.
If you're going, i'm going too.
[A door opens]
Well well, Orvar of Rose Thorn Valley.
The black collectors are on their way.
Tengil decided to allow you to have
a torch with you during your last moments...
...so you'll get used to the light,
and you'll be able to see Katla,
once you meet her.
- Who are you?
-Jonatan and Karl Lionheart.
- We are here to set you free.
- Jonathan! I've heard about you.
I'll get you out of here.
He's gone!
He's fled into the mountain!
The prisoner has escaped!
You! Ride to Tengil's castle
and report this!
Alarm all guards!
Quick! Seal the bridge!
[Orvar laughs]
Thank you! Thank you, Lionheart!
Get their clothes, and we'll pretend
that you're a soldier, and we're your
prisoners.
They bear the stench of hate
and oppression!
We've got to get to Rose Thorn Valley.
Seal all ways out of Karmanjaka!
The prisoner has escaped!
Hurry up!
- Password?
- All power to Tengil - our saviour.
Two prisoners who carry information
concerning weapon stashes in Cherry
Valley.
Go away, you scoundrels. Come on!
What are you doing? None shall pass!
Come on!
I'll jump off behind a creek when
the soldiers can't see, and you'll
ride and catch up with Orvar.
- Are you sure?
- No, but I don't want to be a piece
of dirt..
I'll come get you when Orvar is safe.
[A horse]
- Sophia!
- Oh Karl, what are you doing here?!
- Where is Jonatan?
- He saved Orvar from the Katla Cave.
What? You can't be serious?!
That was the best piece of news we
could ever get.
- Cherry Valley will be alright now.
- Where are you headed?
Jossi's going to show us where
to best break through the wall.
Jossi, yes!
Karl Lionheart... of all the
places.
Sophia, how are the pigeons? Bianca?
She never came back.
Someone must have shot her down.
I realised.
Jossi is the traitor.
- I thought I was the traitor?
- You ought to stop throwing
accusations around.
- I'm sorry, Hubert.
- What about Jossi?
Ask him about the meetings in the
mountains...
Ask him how he betrayed Orvar...
Show us your chest!
That's ridiculous, we're in
a hurry! We've got to go!
Not so fast, Jossi!
Show us your chest!
Traitor! curse you and the things
you've done to Cherry Valley!
No, Hubert! Let him run.
I will punish you, Sophia! When i
become chieftain of Cherry Valley,
i will punish you hard!
Aah!
Poor Jossi. You'll never return
to Cherry Valley!
You'll end up in the Karma Falls,
and nowhere else.
When are they arriving? We can't
keep this a secret for much longer.
The riders have passed through the mountains.
They'll be here this evening, or this night.
- We need everyone from Cherry Valley!
- Everyone who's able to fight is here.
- The people of Rose Thorn Valley are starving.
- Bread and weapons are due to arrive.
The day of battle! The day of freedom!
Free the valley from Tengil's men...
- You mean, to kill?
- Yes, what else could I mean?
No, of course... but I can't kill
anyone, and you know it, Orvar!
If everyone thought like that,
evil would reign forever.
If everyone thought like Jonathan,
then there'd be no evil.
- You've done enough already.
- Your presence would mean a lot.
Just the thought of having Lionheart
among us, should inspire courage!
No, come with me, Rusk.
- It's so great to have a grandpa!
- Of course it is.
It's pretty good to have a Rusk
around, as well.
It is time.
Fly high. You're carrying a message
to all that see you, that the day of
battle is here...
and the day of freedom, I hope.
Forward!
[Battlecries]
I don't want him to die...
- I'll just have to try not to, then.
- Yes...
Jonathan!
Jonathan Lionheart!
You're needed out there!
Fjalar is here!
Then we'll leave.
Victory is ours!
Mattias!
Mattias! They're fleeing!
We're winning!
[Sound of a horn]
[A roar]
Katla's coming! Retreat!
Go! Go!
[Katla roars]
[Blowing the horn]
[Roar]
We are free, but what have we
not sacrificed?
- I'm just gonna visit grandpa.
- But grandpa is... you see, he is...
Rusk, Mattias gave his life for the
freedom of Cherry Valley.
We can't mourn our dead, or celebrate
our freedom as long as Katla exists.
Give me the horn, and I'll shackle Katla
in her cave!
No, I must do it. As long as I've got
this, I have nothing to be afraid of.
- I'll see you all in Cherry Valley.
- We'll see you too, I hope.
Katla has gone this way.
[Blowing the horn]
She's found her way to the Katla Cave.
- The horn!
- What shall we do now?
Come, we must leave.
Katla!
We can't get any further.
Come on!
Don't you touch Rusk, you monster!
Don't you touch him!
Get the torch, Rusk.
There are fairytales here that shouldn't
be... now you know what I meant.
I don't have a grandpa anymore...
- Where do you think Mattias is, right now?
- He's in Nangilima.
- That's where Mattias is, right now.
- Yes.
I know...
He lives on a little farm in Apel Valley.
It's season there now, for picking apples.
We ought to be there to help him.
He's too old to climb ladders.
We could stay at his house...
...on the Mattis Farm...
in Apel Valley...in Nangilima...
...and help him with the apples.
What is it, Jonathan?
It's getting dark.
Build a campfire.
Karl Lionheart...
Rusk... there's something i
need to tell you.
What?
Katla burned me.
I'll soon be completely paralyzed.
I can't move my legs... and soon I
won't be able to move my arms either.
Don't you think it'll pass,
if you just get some rest?
No, Rusk. It'll never pass.
Only if I could get to Nangilima.
If you get to Nangilima,
will you be alright?
Do you remember...
...when the house was burning,
and we jumped?
And I carried you on my back,
and I went to Nangijala.
I'll never forget that.
I was thinking...
...that maybe we should jump
one more time.
You and me...
...from the cliff over there.
Will we get to Nangilima if we do?
Yes...
Think about it,
we can jump all the way to Nangilima.
Mattias will be very surprised.
- What about Grim and Fjalar?
- They're already waiting for us
in Nangilima.
They died of Katla's fire.
Only their shells remain.
Jonathan, I'll carry you on my back.
You did it for me once.
This'll make it fair.
- Will you dare, Rusk Lionheart?
- Yes.
If I may stay with you, until
darkness falls.
I'll dare, otherwise
I'm just a piece of dirt.
Rusk Lionheart... are you afraid?
No...
Yes, but I'll do it anyway. I'll do
it now, and I'll never be afraid anymore.
I see the light! Jonathan!
Nangilima!
I see the light! I see the light!
[Hooves clappering]