RAY: After I killed them,
I dropped the gun
in the Thames,
washed the residue
off me hands in the
bathroom of a Burger King,
and walked home
to await instructions
Shortly thereafter,
the instructions
came through
‘Get the fuck out of London,
youse dumb fucks
‘Get to Bruges’
I didn’t even know
where Bruges fucking was
It’s in Belgium
RAY: Bruges is a shithole
KEN: Bruges is
not a shithole
Bruges is a shithole
Ray, we’ve only
just got off
the fucking train
Could we reserve judgment
on Bruges until we’ve seen
the fucking place?
I know it’s gonna be
a shithole
(EXHALES)
(SOFTLY) Shithole
(BELL DINGS)
I think you have
a couple of rooms booked
under Cranham and Blakely?
Yes No, we have
one room booked
One twin room
Booked for two weeks
Two weeks!
Do you have
another room?
No, I'm afraid
we’re fully booked
With Christmas,
everywhere is fully booked
Okay
(SIGHS)
It’s very pretty
I’m not being funny,
we can’t stay here
We’ve got to stay here
until he rings
Well, what if
he doesn’t ring
for two weeks?
Then we stay here
for two weeks
For two weeks?
In fucking Bruges?
In a room like this?
With you? No way!
Ray, I really don’t
like to say this
You really don’t
like to say what?
Well You know?
Fucking bring that up
Do you think
this is good?
Do I think what’s good?
You know,
going round in a boat,
looking at stuff
Yes, I do
It's called ‘sightseeing’
Oh, look at that
It’s a former hospital
From the 1100s
Bruges is the most
well-preserved
medieval town
in the whole of
Belgium, apparently
Coming up?
What’s up there?
The view
The view of what?
The view of down here?
I can see that from down here
Ray, you’re about
the worst tourist
in the whole world
Ken, I grew up in Dublin
I love Dublin
If I'd grown up on a farm
and was retarded,
Bruges might impress me
But I didn’t,
so it doesn’t
(HUMMING)
Trying to get rid
of me coins
3, 350, 4,
410, 420, 430,
440, 450, 460,
470,
480,
Will you take 490?
Entry is 5 euro
Come on, man,
it’s only 10 cents
Entry is 5 euro
(CASH REGISTER DINGS)
Happy in your work?
Very happy
(SIGHS)
I like it here
(IMITATES GUN FIRING)
MAN: Been to the top
of the tower?
Yeah Yeah, it’s rubbish
It is? The guidebook says
it’s a ‘must-see’
Well, you lot
ain’t going up there
Pardon me? Why?
I mean, it’s all windy stairs
I’m not being funny
What exactly are you
trying to say?
What exactly
am I trying to say?
Youse are a bunch
of fucking elephants!
Right, you
Come on, leave it, fatty
(PANTING)
You know, you’re just
the rudest man
The rudest man!
What’s all that about?
They’re not going up there
Hey, guys,
I wouldn’t go up there
It’s really narrow
Screw you, motherfucker!
Americans, isn’t it?
Now, this is more like it
Proper holidays
One gay beer
for my gay friend,
and one normal beer for me,
because I am normal
(SIGHS)
This is the life
We’re not staying here
getting pissed
We are quietly sightseeing,
like he says,
and awaiting his call
to see what we do next
This is my vote
on what we should do
We give it another day,
two days, max
Then we check
the papers again, and if
there’s still nothing in them,
we phone him and say,
‘Harry, thank you
for the trip to Bruges,
‘it’s been very nice,
all the old buildings
and that,
‘but we’re coming back
to London now, and hide out
in a proper country,
‘where it isn’t all just
fucking chocolates’
My vote would be
we quietly sightsee,
like he says,
and await his call
to see what we do next
You don’t even know
we’re here hiding out
What are you talking about?
You don’t even know
we’re not here on a job
What, on a job?
Yeah
Here in Bruges?
Here in Bruges, on a job?
Yeah
Why? What did he
actually say?
He didn’t actually
say anything
Then why do you think
it might be?
I don’t think anything
But it’s a bit fucking
over-elaborate, isn’t it?
‘Go take him to hide out’
‘Go take him to
hide out where?’
‘Go take him to hide out
in fucking Bruges’
You can hide out
in Croydon
Hmm
Or Coventry
It is a bit
over-elaborate
Hmm
But we haven’t
got any guns
Harry can get guns anywhere
(BELL TOLLING)
He’s not gonna ring tonight
(SIGHS)
Let’s go out
Go out where?
The pub
No!
Let’s go out
and have a look
at some of the
All the old medieval
buildings and that
Because I bet they look
even better at night,
all lit up
Yes!
That there is called
the Gruuthuse Museum
They all have
funny names,
don’t they?
Yes, Flemish
In here it says,
‘The Belgians twice sheltered
fugitive English Kings
‘from being murdered,
1471 and 1651’
I used to hate history,
didn’t you?
It’s all just a load of stuff
that’s already happened
What are they
doing over there?
They’re filming something
They’re filming midgets!
Ray!
MAN: So, on this scene,
you’re supposed to walk like
a little, tiny mouse, yeah?
Okay? Great
Ray, come on, let’s go
My arse, ‘Let’s go’
They’re filming midgets
Oh, my God!
Look at that girl
She’s gorgeous!
Ray, we’re going
right now
Fuck off, are we!
This is the best bit
of Bruges so far
You and your buildings
Hello
Do you speak English?
No
Yes, you do
Everybody does
What are you
filming midgets for?
It’s a Dutch movie
It’s a dream sequence
It’s a pastiche of
Nicholas Roeg's
Don’t Look Now
Not a pastiche, but a
A ‘homage’ is too strong
A ‘nod of the head’?
Wow, your English
is very good
A lot of midgets
tend to kill themselves
A disproportionate amount
Herve Villechaize,
off of Fantasy Island
I think somebody
off The Time Bandits
I suppose they must
get really sad about, like,
being really
little and that
People looking at them
and laughing at them
Calling them names
You know, ‘shortarse’
There’s another famous
midget I’m missing,
but I can’t remember
It’s not the R2-D2 man
No, he’s still going
I hope your midget
doesn’t kill himself Your
dream sequence will be fucked
He doesn’t like
being called a midget
He prefers ‘dwarf’
Well, this is
exactly my point!
People go around calling
you a midget when you
want to be called a dwarf
Of course you’re
gonna blow your head off!
My name’s Ray What’s yours?
Chloe
How did you get past
the security man?
Getting past security men,
it’s sort of my job
You’re a shoplifter?
(CHUCKLES) No,
not a shoplifter
It’s a good joke, though
No
I'll tell you what I am
at dinner tomorrow night
(CHUCKLING)
Fuck
How fucking cool
Mr. Blakely?
Yes No, Mr. Cranham
No Yes Mr. Blakely Yes
You have a message
Shit!
HARRY: Number one,
why aren’t you in when
I fucking told you to be in?
Number two, why doesn’t
this hotel have phones
with fucking voicemail
and not I have to leave
messages with the
fucking receptionist?
Number three, you better
fucking be in tomorrow night
when I fucking call again
or there'll be fucking
Hell to pay, I’m fucking
telling you Harry
(DOOR LOCK TURNING)
Would you turn
the fucking light off!
Sorry, Ken
Keep the fucking
noise down!
Someone’s in a mood
(SOFTLY) You’ll
never guess what
Will you shut your
fucking mouth, please,
and go to sleep?
Oh, sorry
Except I've gotta take me
contact lenses out
Altogether,
I had
five pints of beer
and six bottles
No Six pints of beer
and seven bottles
And you know what?
I’m not even pissed!
You’ll never guess what, Ken
Ken, you’ll never guess what
What?
Got a date for
tomorrow night
I’m very happy for you
With a girl
Can you turn
the light off, please?
Only been in Bruges one day,
got a date with a girl
in the film business,
the Belgian film business
They’re doing a film
about a midget
Miss?
Marie?
Sorry about the message
last night The man who
left it is a bit of a
Well, he’s a bit of a
Cock?
Yes He’s a bit of a cock
Morning
Harry called last night
We missed him
Jeez, he swears a lot,
doesn’t he?
We’re staying in tonight
Whatever happens
Hmm
Except
Except ‘hmm’ what?
Except only one of us
needs to stay in, really
Uh-huh
And which one of us
would that be, now, Ray?
I thought you
didn’t like Bruges
I don’t like Bruges,
it’s a shithole
But I did already say
I had a date with
a Belgian lady
in the Belgian film business,
which I did already
say about before
Just don’t get into
any fucking trouble
We’re keeping a low profile
And this morning,
and this afternoon,
we are doing
what I want to do
Got it?
Of course
Which, I presume,
will involve culture
Oh, we shall strike a balance
between culture and fun
Somehow I believe, Ken,
that the balance shall tip
in the favor of culture
Like a big, fat,
fucking retarded,
fucking black girl
on a seesaw, opposite
a dwarf
(DRAGGING FEET)
(SOFTLY) Ray, did we
or did we not agree
that if I let you
go on your date tonight,
we’d do the things
I wanted to do today?
We are doing the things
that you wanted to do today
And that we’d do them
without you throwing
a fucking moody,
like some 5-year-old
who’s dropped
all his sweets?
I didn’t agree to that
I’ll cheer up
Up there,
the top altar,
is a phial
brought back by
a Flemish knight from the
Crusades in the Holy Land
And that phial,
do you know what
it’s said to contain?
No, what’s it
said to contain?
It’s said to contain
some drops of
Jesus Christ’s blood
Yeah, that’s how
this church got its name
Basilica of the Holy Blood
Yeah Yeah
And this blood, right,
though it’s dried blood,
at different times
over many years, they say
it turned back into liquid
Turned back into liquid
from dried blood
At various times of great
stress
Yeah?
Yeah
So, yeah, I’m gonna go up
in the queue and touch it,
which is what you do
Yeah?
Yeah You coming?
Do I have to?
Do you have to?
Of course you
don’t have to
It’s Jesus’ fucking blood,
isn’t it? Of course you
don’t fucking have to!
Of course you don’t
fucking have to!
You little fucking cunt
(SIGHS)
RAY: Murder, Father
PRIEST: Why did you
murder someone, Raymond?
For money, Father
For money?
You murdered
someone for money?
Yes, Father
Not out of anger,
not out of nothing
For money
(CLEARS THROAT)
Who did you murder
for money, Raymond?
You, Father
I’m sorry?
I said you, Father
What, are you deaf?
Harry Waters says hello
The little boy
RAY: I quite like this one
All the rest were
rubbish by spastics,
but this one’s quite good
What’s that
all about, then?
It’s Judgment Day,
you know?
Oh, yeah
What’s that then?
Well, it’s, you know,
the final day on Earth
When mankind will be
judged for all the crimes
they’ve committed and that
And see who gets
into Heaven and who gets
into Hell and all that?
Yeah
And what’s the other place?
Purgatory
Purgatory?
Purgatory’s kind of like
the in-betweeny one
You weren’t really shit,
but you weren’t
all that great, either
Like Tottenham
Do you believe
in all that stuff, Ken?
About Tottenham?
The Last Judgment
and the afterlife
Guilt and sins and
Hell and all that?
Um
Well
KEN: I don’t know, Ray
I don’t know what I believe
The things you’re
taught as a child, they never
really leave you, do they?
So, like,
I believe in trying
to lead a good life
Like, if there’s an old lady,
carrying her shopping home,
I don’t try and help her
carry her shopping,
I don’t go that far,
but I’ll certainly hold the
door open for her and that,
and let her go out before me
Yeah And anyway,
if you tried to help her
carry her shopping,
she’d probably think
you were just trying
to nick her shopping
Exactly
This is the world
we live in today
At the same time
as trying to lead
a good life,
I have to reconcile myself
with the fact that, yes,
I have killed people
Not many people
Most of them were
not very nice people
Apart from one person
Who’s that?
This fellow,
Danny Aliband's brother
He was just trying
to protect his brother
Like you or I would
He was just a lollipop man
He came at me with a bottle
What are you gonna do?
I shot him down
Hmm
In my book, though,
sorry, someone comes
at you with a bottle,
that is a deadly weapon,
he’s gotta take
the consequences
I know that in my heart
I also know that he was
just trying to protect
his brother, you know?
I know But a bottle,
that can kill you
It’s a case of
it’s you or him
If he’d come at you
with his bare hands,
that’d be different
That wouldn’t
have been fair
Well, technically,
your bare hands
can kill somebody, too
They can be
deadly weapons, too I mean,
what if he knew karate, say?
You said he was
a lollipop man
He was a lollipop man
What’s a lollipop man doing
knowing fucking karate?
I’m just saying
How old was he?
About 50
What’s a 50-year-old
lollipop man doing
knowing fucking karate?
What was he,
a Chinese lollipop man?
Jesus, Ken,
I’m trying to
talk about
I know what you’re
trying to talk about
I killed a little boy
You keep bringing up
fucking lollipop men!
You didn’t mean
to kill a little boy
I know I didn’t mean to
But because of the choices
I made and the course
that I put into action,
a little boy
isn’t here anymore
And he’ll never
be here again
I mean here in the world,
not here in Belgium
Well, he’ll never be
here in Belgium,
either, will he?
I mean, he might have
wanted to come here
when he got older
I don’t know why
(SIGHS)
And that’s all because of me
He’s dead because of me
And I’m trying to
I’m trying to
get me head around it,
but I can’t
I will always have
killed that little boy
That ain’t ever
going away Ever
Unless
Maybe I go away
Don’t even think like that
(EXHALES)
You look good
What’s it matter anyway?
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
So, what do you do, Raymond?
I shoot people for money
(SCOFFS)
What kinds of people?
Priests Children
You know, the usual
Is there a lot of money
to be made in that
line of business?
There is in priests
There isn’t in children
So what is it
you do, Chloe?
I sell cocaine and heroin
to Belgian film crews
Do you?
Do I look like I do?
You do, actually
(CHUCKLING)
Do I look like
I shoot people?
No
Just children
Mmm-hmm
I saw your midget today
Little prick didn’t
even say hello
Well, he’s on
a lot of ketamine
What’s that?
Horse tranquilizer
A horse tranquilizer?
Where’d he get that?
I sold it to him
You can’t sell
horse tranquilizers
to a midget!
This movie,
I think it’s gonna be
a very good one
There’s never been
a classic movie made
in Bruges until now
Of course there hasn’t,
it’s a shithole
Bruges is my hometown, Ray
Well, it’s still a shithole
It’s not a shithole
What? Even midgets have to
take drugs to stick it
Okay
So, you’ve insulted
my hometown
You’re doing
very well, Raymond
Why don’t you tell me
some Belgian jokes
while you’re at it?
I don’t know
any Belgian jokes
And if I did,
I think I’d have
the good sense not to
Hey, hang on Is Belgium
where there were all those
child abuse murders lately?
Then I do know
a Belgian joke
What’s Belgium famous for?
Chocolates and child abuse
And they only invented
the chocolates to
get to the kids
What?
One of the girls
they murdered was
a friend of mine
(SIGHS)
I’m sorry, Chloe
One of the girls
they murdered wasn’t
a friend of mine
I just wanted to
make you feel bad
And it worked
Quite well
Fucking unbelievable
What’s fucking
unbelievable?
Are you talking to me?
(SOFTLY) He pauses,
even though he should
just hit the cunt
And he repeats
Yes, I am talking to you
What’s fucking unbelievable?
Well, I’ll tell you what’s
fucking unbelievable, shall I?
Blowing cigarette smoke
straight into myself
and my girlfriend’s face
That’s fucking unbelievable!
This is the smoking section
I don’t care if it’s
the smoking section
All right?
She directed it
right in my face, man
I don’t wanna die just because
of your fucking arrogance
Uh-huh
Isn’t that what the
Vietnamese used to say?
Vietnamese? What are you
talking about, the Vietnamese?
That statement makes
no fucking sense at all
Yes it does
The Vietnamese!
Well, saying it over
and over ain’t gonna make
any more sense out of it
How does the Vietnamese
have any relevance whatsoever
to myself and my girlfriend
having to breathe
your friend’s
cigarette smoke?
Tell me how saying
That’s for John Lennon,
you Yankee fucking cunt!
A bottle? No, don’t bother
(GROANS)
We’re leaving
I don’t hit women!
I would never
hit a woman, Chloe!
I’d hit a woman
who was trying to
hit me with a bottle!
That’s different
That’s self-defense,
isn’t it?
Or a woman
who could do karate
I’d never hit
a woman generally, Chloe
Don’t think that
God, you’re pretty
I have to make a call
Oh, no
You’ve gone off me, now,
haven’t you? Just because
I hit that fucking cow
(MUSIC PLAYING ON TV)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
HARRY: Where the fuck
were you yesterday?
We just popped out for
some dinner, Harry We only
popped out for half an hour
Yeah? What’d you have?
For dinner?
Yeah
Pizza, at Pizza Hut
Was it nice?
Yeah, it was all right
I don’t know
It was Pizza Hut
The same as in England
Well, that’s globalization,
isn’t it? Is Ray
there with you?
He’s in the toilet
Can he hear?
No
What’s he doing?
What do you mean?
Is he doing a wee or a poo?
I don’t know, Harry,
the door’s closed
Send him out on an errand
for half an hour, but don’t
make it sound suspicious
(SIGHS)
Ray? Why don’t you
go out down to the pub
for half an hour?
Yeah, yeah, I know
I said you couldn’t,
but might as well
enjoy ourselves, eh?
No, I don’t know if
they’ve got bowling anywhere
Could have a look
Yeah, see you
Yeah He’s gone
What’d you say to him?
I said, ‘Why don’t you go
have a drink, you say
you’ve been cooped up?’
What did he say?
Said, yeah, he would
And he might go have
a look to see if there’s
a bowling alley around
Was he just having a wee?
Yeah, I think so
I assume so
Sure he didn’t mind?
No, he was glad
to get out
He’s definitely gone?
Yeah, yeah,
he slammed the door
That don’t mean he’s gone
Go check outside the door
Harry, he’s definitely gone
You realize there are no
bowling alleys in Bruges?
I realize that, Harry
The boy wanted to
have a look anyway
What are they gonna have,
a medieval fucking
bowling alley?
As I say, I think
he was just glad
to get out and about
So, is he having
a nice time, seeing
all the canals and that?
I had a lovely time
when I was there
All the canals and the
old buildings and that
When were you here?
When I was seven
Last happy holiday
I fucking had
Have you been on
a canal trip, yet?
Yeah
Have you been down,
like, all the old
cobbled streets and that?
Yeah
It’s like a fairytale,
isn’t it, that place?
Yeah
With the churches and that
They’re Gothic
Yeah
Is it Gothic?
So he’s having
a really nice time?
Well, I’m having
a really nice time
I’m not sure if it’s
really his cup of tea
What?
You know, I’m not sure
if it’s really his thing
What do you mean,
‘It’s not really his thing’?
What’s that supposed to mean,
What the fuck is that
supposed to mean?
Nothing, Harry
It’s a fairytale
fucking town, isn’t it?
How can a fairytale town
not be somebody’s
fucking thing?
How can all those canals
and bridges and cobbled
streets and those churches,
all that beautiful
fucking fairytale stuff,
how can that not be
somebody’s fucking thing, eh?
What I think
I meant to say was
Is the swan still there?
Yeah, the swan’s
How can fucking swans
not fucking be somebody’s
fucking thing, eh?
How can that be?
What I think
I meant to say was,
when he first arrived,
he wasn’t quite sure about it
You know, there’s that big,
dual carriageway when you
get off the train?
It mightn't have been
here when you were
here last, Harry
Well, as soon as he got into,
like, the old town proper,
and he saw the canals
and the bridges and,
you know, the swans and that,
well, he just
fucking loved it then
Couldn’t get enough of it,
the medieval part of town
It was just that initial,
dual carriageway thing sort of
put him off for a second
Don’t know if I remember
a dual carriageway
Must be recent
Hasn’t spoilt it, has it?
No, no, no,
it’s just that
initial thing
And you know what?
As we were walking
through the streets,
there was this sort of
freezing fog hanging
over everything,
and it made it
look almost like
a fairytale or something
And he turned to me,
do you know what he said?
What’d he say?
He said, ‘Ken, I know
I’m awake, but I feel
like I’m in a dream’
Yeah? He said that?
Yeah
Meaning, like,
in a good dream?
Yeah Of course,
like in a good dream
Oh, good I’m glad
he likes it there
I’m glad we were able
to give him something
Something good and happy
Because he wasn’t
a bad kid, was he?
Huh?
He wasn’t a bad kid,
was he?
Listen, take down
this address
Raamstraat 17
That’s ‘Raam, ‘ like ‘Ram, ‘
but with an extra ‘a’
Raamstraat 17
You got that?
Yes, Raamstraat 17
Good There’ll be a man
there tomorrow morning
at 9:00, his name’s Yuri
Yuri
He'll give you the gun
Ring me on the public phone
at Jimmy Driscoll's
about 3:00 or 4:00 tomorrow,
after it’s done
After what’s done?
Are you being thick?
No
Listen, I like Ray
He was a good bloke,
but when it all comes
down to it, you know,
he blew the head off
a little fucking kid
And you brought him in, Ken
So if the buck
don’t stop with him,
where does it stop?
Ken?
If the buck
don’t stop with him,
where does it stop?
It stops with me, Harry
That’s an easy one
Look, don’t get shirty, Ken
Listen, I’m just glad that
I was able to do something
for the boy before he went
Do what for the boy?
You know, have him
get to see Bruges
I’d like to go to see
Bruges again before I die
What was it he said
again about Yeah,
‘It’s like a dream’
‘I know I’m awake,
but I feel like
I’m in a dream’
Yeah
Give me a call
when he’s dead
(GASPS)
That’s my fucking girlfriend,
you asshole
Eirik, what are you doing?
Where are you from, fucker?
Ireland, originally
And you think it’s okay
to come over to Belgium
and fuck another man’s girl?
Look, I didn’t know
she had a boyfriend,
all right?
And I haven’t fucked her,
anyway Ask her
I’d only put me hand on it
Eirik, put the gun down!
Get down on your knees
and open your mouth
Don’t start being silly
Get down on your
Exactly at what point
was it that all skinheads
suddenly became poofs?
Used to be,
you were a skinhead,
you just went around
beating up
Pakistani 12-year-olds
Now it seems a prerequisite
to be a fucking bum-boy!
That’s not gonna
help you, man
Ray, there’s only
blanks in that gun
Eirik, don’t!
Now who’s the
fucking bum-boy?
You, you fucking bum-boy!
(GROANING)
Chloe, what exactly
is going on here?
I can’t see!
Of course you can’t
fucking see! I just shot
a blank in your fucking eyes!
Is this fella your boyfriend?
No I mean, he used to be
Well, what’s he doing here?
We We rob tourists,
sometimes
I fucking knew
it was too good
to be true!
I knew you’d have never
shagged me, normally
No! That’s not true, I
I called it off tonight
I told him not
to come tonight
Why did you come tonight?
EIRIK: Chloe,
I can’t see,
I swear it!
Stop whingeing
like a big gay baby
I haven’t had
a shag in months!
I can’t see out of this eye,
Chloe! I have to go
to the hospital!
I’ll drive you
Great! Now the whole
night’s ruined!
No!
You can stay if you want
I just don’t know
how long I’ll be
I just knew someone like you
would never like
someone like me
I just knew
What do you mean,
someone like me?
You know, someone nice
Call me Please
EIRIK: Chloe!
Cha-ching!
(MUMBLES)
Have you got some
sort of problem?
No, no problem
Four beers
in 20 minutes
No problem
Fuck off
JIMMY: Beer and a red wine
I’ll be back
How’s the movie going?
It’s a jumped-up
Eurotrash piece of
rip-off fucking bullshit
Like, in a bad way?
Your girlfriend’s
very pretty
She ain’t my girlfriend
She’s a prostitute
I just picked up
Didn’t know there were
any prostitutes in Bruges
You just have to look
in the right places
Brothels are good
Well, you’ve picked up
a very pretty prostitute
Thank you
You from the States?
Yeah
But don’t hold it
against me
I’ll try not to
Just try not to say
anything too loud or crass
Hey-ho Drowning
your sorrows, huh?
What sorrows?
You know, being a sad,
old, ugly little man
One gay beer, please
How’d your date go?
My date involved
two instances of
extreme violence
One instance of her hand
on my cock and my finger
up her thing,
which lasted all too briefly
Isn’t that always the way?
One instance of me
stealing five grams of
her very-high-quality cocaine,
and one instance of me
blinding a poofy
little skinhead
So, all in all,
my evening pretty much
balanced out fine
You got five grams of coke?
I’ve got four grams on me
and one gram in me,
which is why me heart
is going like the clappers,
as if I’m about to
have a heart attack
So if I collapse
any minute now, please
remember to tell the doctors
that it might have something
to do with the coke
Give us a gram, then
I thought you were
laying off, because
it makes you depressed?
You know what?
Right now, I don’t
really give a fuck
Why didn’t you wave
hello to me today when
I waved hello to you today?
I was on a very strong
horse tranquilizer today
I wasn’t waving
hello to anybody,
except maybe to a horse
Huh? What are you
talking about?
Just horseshit
You from America?
Yeah But don’t
hold it against me
Well, that’s for me
to decide, isn’t it?
Are you from America, too?
No, I’m from Amsterdam
(SCOFFS) Amsterdam
Amsterdam is just
a load of bloody
prostitutes, isn’t it?
Yes That’s why
I came to Bruges
I thought I’d get
a better price
for my pussy here
Huh?
You two are weird
Would you like some cocaine?
I’ve also got some
acid and some ecstasy
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Herve Villechaize,
I know, did
The dwarf off, I think,
The Time Bandits, did
Lots of midgets
Dwarves, top themselves
Hmm Shitloads
Would you ever
think about it?
Huh?
Would you ever think about
killing yourself because
you’re a midget?
Fuck, man!
What kind of
question is that?
We’re just chatting,
aren’t we?
See, Ken, this is
the kind of hotel
Harry should have put us in
A five-star,
with prostitutes in
You know, sometimes,
I think Harry doesn’t even
give a shit about us at all
Has he still not called?
No Still hasn’t called
No news is good news, eh?
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
RAY: Hmm
Who’s she?
JIMMY: There’s gonna be
a war, man
I can see it
There’s gonna be a war
between the blacks
and between the whites
You ain’t even gonna need
a uniform no more
This ain’t gonna be a war
where you pick your side
Your side’s already
picked for you
And I know whose side
I’m fighting on
I’m fighting with the blacks
The whites are gonna get
their heads kicked in!
JIMMY: You don’t decide
this shit, man
Well, who are
the half-castes
gonna fight with?
The blacks, man
That’s obvious
But what about
the Pakistanis?
The blacks
What about
Think of a hard one
What about the Vietnamese?
The blacks!
Well, I’m definitely
fighting with the blacks
if they’ve got the Vietnamese
So, hang on
Would all of the
white midgets in
the world be fighting
against all the black
midgets in the world?
Yeah
That would make a good film!
You don’t know how much shit
I’ve had to take off
of black midgets, man
That’s
Undeniably true
See, Jimmy,
my wife was black
And I loved her very much
And in 1976,
she was murdered
by a white man
So, where the fuck
am I supposed to stand
in all this blood and carnage?
Did they get
the guy who did it?
A friend of mine got him
Harry Waters got him
So tell me, Jim,
whose side do I fight
on in this wonderful war?
I think you need to
weigh up all your options
and let your
conscience decide, Ken
Two manky hookers
and a racist dwarf
I think I’m heading home
Yeah I think
I’ll come with you
What’s
Back off, shorty!
You don’t know karate
Don’t say you didn’t
have it coming
Shortarse!
Meeting Yuri
Yes, I’m Yuri
Mr. Waters said
that might be necessary
There are a lot of alcoves
in the Koningin Astrid Park
You use this word,
‘alcoves’?
‘Alcoves’? Yes Sometimes
There are not many
people around in these
alcoves in Christmastime
If I were to murder a man,
I would murder him here
Are you sure this is
the right word, ‘alcoves’?
‘Alcoves,’ yes
It’s kind of like
‘nooks and crannies’
‘Nooks and crannies,’ yes
Perhaps this would be
more accurate
‘Nooks and crannies,’
rather than ‘alcoves’ Yeah
You are going to do it,
aren’t you? Mr. Waters
will be very disappointed
Of course I’m going to
fucking do it
It’s what I do
Your friend was behaving
rather oddly this morning
Oddly? How?
Well, he asked me
about the baby, and if
I wanted a boy or a girl
I said I didn’t mind
as long as it’s
healthy, of course
But then he gave me 200 euros
to give to the baby
I refused, obviously,
but he was quite insistent
Would you give it
back to him when
you see him?
I don’t want to appear
ungrateful, but it seemed
like all the money he had
Do you know where he is now?
He said he was
going to the park
Sorry, Ray
I’m sorry
Ray, don’t!
Fucking hell!
Where the fuck
did you come from?
I was behind the thing
What the fuck are
you doing, Ray?
What the fuck
are you doing?
Nothing
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Oh, my God!
You were gonna kill me
No, I wasn’t
You were gonna
kill yourself!
I’m allowed to
No, you’re not!
What?
I’m not allowed to
and you are?
How’s that fair?
Can we go somewhere
and talk about this, please?
I wasn’t gonna go
through with it, Ray
You fucking looked like
you were gonna go
fucking through with it
Where’d you get that gun?
A friend of Harry’s
Fuck, man
Let me see it
Silencer, too
Nice
Mine’s a bloody girl’s gun
I’m keeping it
Pardon me?
Give me me gun back
You’re not getting it back
You’re a suicide case
And you were
trying to shoot me
in the fucking head
You’re not getting
that gun back
A great day this has
turned out to be
I’m suicidal,
me mate tries
to kill me,
me gun gets nicked
and we’re still
in fucking Bruges
Listen, I’m gonna give you
some money and put you
on a train somewhere
Back to England?
You can’t go back
to England, Ray
You’d be a dead man!
(CRYING) I want
to be a dead man
Have you been
missing something?
You don’t want to be
a dead man, Ray
I killed a little boy!
Then save the
next little boy
Just go away somewhere,
get out of this business
and try to do something good
You’re not gonna
help anybody dead
bring that boy back
But you might save
the next one
What am I gonna be,
a doctor?
You need exams
Do anything, Ray
Do anything
RAY: What a wanker!
He said this whole trip,
this whole being
in Bruges thing,
was just to give you
one last, joyful memory
before you died
In Bruges?
(LAUGHING)
The Bahamas, maybe
Why fucking Bruges?
I suppose it’s cheaper
(WOMAN ANNOUNCING ON PA)
The rest of the acid
and the ecstasy
Can I have me gun
back, please?
What am I gonna do, Ken?
What am I gonna do?
Just keep moving
Keep on moving
Try not to think about it
Learn a new language, maybe?
Sure, I can
hardly do English
That’s one thing
I like about Europe, though
You don’t have to learn
any of their languages
Just forget about
home for a while
See how the land lies
in six years, seven years
Seven years is not that long
It’s longer than
that boy got
Me first fucking job
Great hitman
I turned out to be
Some people just aren’t
cut out for it, Ray
Are you?
When are you
going back to England?
I’ll head back
in a couple of hours
or something
Harry’s not gonna be
mad at you, is he?
For letting me go?
I’ll sort out Harry
Just tell him I’ll have
probably killed meself
in a fortnight, anyway
You won’t, will you, Ray?
Harry? It’s Ken
Listen to this noise
Do you know what that is?
Yeah, I know
you know it’s a train
Do you know what train?
Well, it’s a train that
Ray just got on, and
he’s alive and he’s well,
and he doesn’t know
where he’s going
and neither do I
So if you need to
do your worst,
do your worst
You’ve got the
address of the hotel
I’ll be here waiting
Because I’ve got to quite
like Bruges, now
It’s like a fucking
fairytale or something
(PHONE BANGING)
Harry
Harry!
What?
It’s an inanimate
fucking object
You’re an inanimate
fucking object!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Now, you lot be good
for your mummy
and lmamoto, okay?
‘Cause Daddy’s got to
go away for a few days
Where are you going?
I’ve got to go to Bruges
Bruges? Where’s that?
It’s in Belgium
Why would anybody
have to go to Belgium?
‘Cause I’ve got to
sort something out
Is it something
to do with the phone?
It’s something
to do with Ken
It’s a matter of honor
Well, it ain’t gonna
be dangerous, is it?
Well, of course it’s
gonna be dangerous if it’s
a matter of fucking honor!
You are bringing
the fellas with you?
Tell me you’re bringing
the fellas with you
Harry
I’m sorry for calling you
an inanimate object
I was upset
(TRAIN BRAKES SCREECHING)
You’re Irish?
Yes
What is your name?
Derek Perlurrl
You hit the Canadian
I ‘heet’ the Canadian?
I don’t know what
you’re talking about
That’s him!
That’s the motherfucker
You hit the Canadian, yeah?
Canadian? Shit
(HANDCUFFS CLICKING)
We’re taking you
back to Bruges
Brilliant
Aye aye
YURl: Take your pick,
Mr. Waters
(CHUCKLES) An Uzi?
I’m not from South Central
Los fucking Angeles
I didn’t come here to shoot
20 black 10-year-olds
in a fucking drive-by
I want a normal gun
for a normal person
I knew he wouldn’t
kill the guy
I could see it in his eyes
when I was telling him
about the alcoves
About the what?
The alcoves
The alcoves in the
Koningin Astrid Park
Oh, I also have
some dumdums
You use this word,
‘dumdums’? The bullets
that make the head explode?
Dumdums, yeah
Would you like some
of these dumdums?
I know I shouldn’t,
but I will
Motherfucker
Is he talking to me?
No, Eirik’s
on your side,
Mr. Waters
Your young friend
blinded him last night
Ray did?
I was trying to rob him
and he took my gun from me
And the gun
was full of blanks,
and he shot the blank
into my eye
And now, I cannot see
from this eye ever again,
the doctors say
Well, to be honest,
it sounds like
it was all your fault
What?
I mean, basically, if you’re
robbing a man and you’re
only carrying blanks,
and you allow your gun
to be taken off you,
and you allow yourself
to be shot in the
eye with a blank,
for which I assume
the person has to get
quite close to you, then,
yeah, really,
it’s all your fault
for being such a poof
So why don’t you
stop whingeing
and cheer the fuck up?
YURl: Eirik, I really
wouldn’t respond
I thought you wanted
the guy dead?
I do want the guy dead
I want him fucking crucified
But it don’t change the fact
that he stitched you up like
a blind, little gay boy
Does it?
Thanks for the gun, Yuri
Well?
The boy is suicidal, Harry
He’s a walking dead man
Keeps going on
about Hell and purgatory
When I phoned you
yesterday, did I ask you,
‘Ken, will you do me
a favor and become
Ray’s psychiatrist, please?’
No What I think I asked you
was, ‘Could you go blow
his fucking head off for me?’
‘He’s suicidal’?
I’m suicidal You’re suicidal
Everybody’s fucking suicidal!
We don’t all keep
going on about it!
Has he killed himself yet?
No So he’s not
fucking suicidal, is he?
He put a loaded gun
to his head this morning
I stopped him
He What?
This gets fucking worse!
We were down in the park
Let me get this right
You were down in the park?
What’s that got to do
with fucking anything?
Let me get this right
Not only have you
refused to kill the boy,
you’ve even stopped the boy
from killing himself,
which would have
solved my problem,
solved your problem,
which sounds like
it would’ve solved
the boy’s problem
It wouldn’t have
solved his problem
Ken, if I had
killed a little kid,
accidentally or otherwise,
I wouldn’t have
thought twice
I’d have killed myself
on the fucking spot
On the fucking spot
I’d have stuck
the gun in me mouth
on the fucking spot!
That’s you, Harry
The boy has the
capacity to change
The boy has the capacity
to do something
decent with his life
Excuse me, Ken
I have the capacity
to change
Yeah, you do
You’ve the capacity
to get fucking worse!
Yeah, now I’m
getting down to it!
Harry, let’s face it
And I’m not being funny,
I mean no disrespect,
but you’re a cunt
You’re a cunt now,
you’ve always been a cunt
And the only thing that’s
gonna change is you’re gonna
become an even bigger cunt
Maybe have some
more cunt kids
Leave my kids
fucking out of it
What have they done?
You fucking retract that bit
about my cunt fucking kids!
I retract that bit about
your cunt fucking kids
Insulting my fucking kids!
That’s going overboard, mate!
I retracted it, didn’t I?
Still leaves you
being a cunt
Yeah, I fucking got that
Where’s Ray now?
Oh, right about now,
Ray is in one or other
of the one million towns in
mainland Europe it’s possible
to be in, other than here
(DOOR SHUTS)
I’ll get all the money
back to you soon as I
get through to me friend
It’s not a problem,
Raymond
And I’ll get all your acid
and your ecstasy
back to you, too
English humor!
I’m assuming you’ve
got your gun on you
That Yuri bloke’s
a funny fella, isn’t he?
He does yoga
‘The alcoves’
Was he going on
to you about the alcoves?
(CHUCKLES)
‘The alcoves
in the Koningin Astrid Park’
(SNIFFLES)
Harry, I know you gotta do
what you gotta do
It’s a bit crowded
round here, you know?
Well, I’m not gonna
have a shootout
in the middle of a thousand
fucking Belgians, am I?
Not to mention
the other nationalities,
just on their holidays
Hmm
To see the swans
and the Gothic and all
the fairytale stuff, eh?
Are you trying to
fucking wind me up?
No, Harry
On top of calling me a cunt
and calling me kids cunts
I might just have to
fucking shoot you right here
Christ!
Let’s go up the bell tower
Be quiet up there
this time of evening
Let’s go up there
Yeah Canadians
I feel a bit bad
They didn’t kill
John Lennon, did they?
Anyway, supposed to turn up
to court here in two days
Are you going to turn up?
Don’t know
What have I got to
stay for really?
The most beautiful woman
you’ve ever seen
in all of your stupid life
The tower is closed
this evening
No way It’s supposed
to be open till 7:00
The tower is usually
open until 7:00
Yesterday an American
had a heart attack
up the tower
Today the tower is closed
Here, cranky, here’s
100 for you We’re only
gonna be 20 minutes
The tower is closed
this evening
Understand, Englishman?
(GROANING)
(CHUCKLES)
Jimmy, I’ve been
wanting to say
I’m really sorry for
karate-chopping you
the other night
That was way out of order
You know, Ray, I’d find it
easier to believe and
forgive you, somehow,
if the two of you weren’t
laughing straight
in my fucking face!
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
It’s for the
goddamn movie, man
It is a nice town, Harry
I’m glad I got to see it
I didn’t mean to be
taking the piss out of it
being a fairytale place
It is a fairytale place
It really is
Hmm
It’s just a shame
it’s in Belgium, really
But then you figure
if it wasn’t in Belgium,
if it was somewhere good,
there’d be too many people
coming to see it It would
spoil the whole thing
Well, I’m glad
I got to see it
before I died
What are you doing?
What are you
fucking doing?
I’m not fighting
anymore, Harry
All right, then I’m blowing
your fucking head off
Don’t come over all Gandhi
What are you fucking doing?
Ken, stop messing
about, please
Pick up your gun
I know I’m going
to beat you anyway
‘cause you’re a spaz, but
Harry,
I’m totally in your debt
The things that have
gone between us in the past,
I love you
unreservedly
for all that
What?
For your integrity
For your honor
I love you
The boy had to be let go
The boy had to be
given a chance
And if to do that,
I had to say, ‘Fuck you,
and fuck what I owe you,
‘and fuck everything
that’s gone on between us,’
then that’s what I had to do
But l’m not fighting you
And I accept, totally,
everything you’ve got to do
I accept it Totally
Oh, yeah?
Yeah
Well, you say all that
fucking stuff, I can’t
fucking shoot you now, can I?
Lt’s entirely
up to you, Harry
lt’s entirely your call
All l’m saying is
l’m not fighting
Oh, you fucking cunt!
Look, l’m not gonna
do nothing to you
just ‘cause you’re
standing about like
Robert fucking Powell
Like who?
Like Robert fucking Powell
out of Jesus of
fucking Nazareth!
My fucking leg!
The psycho dwarf
turns out to just be
a loveable little schoolboy,
and it’s all some kind of
Boschian nightmare
Kiss my ass!
I guess at least there
weren’t any black people
involved, eh, Jimmy?
I wasn’t
I wasn’t talking about
There’s gonna be a war
between all the blacks
and all the whites
And all the black midgets
and all the white midgets,
which would actually
be really good
That’s just cocaine
He didn’t even want
the Vietnamese on his side!
That’s just cocaine
Listen, we’re filming
down by the pointy
building tonight
It might actually be
good for once
You guys should come along
We I think we’re just
gonna have a quiet one
tonight, Jimmy
That’s how it is!
In another life
They’re great,
aren’t they?
You didn’t You didn’t!
(GRUNTING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Mr Waters? Mr Waters?
Who’s that?
Lt’s Eirik
The blind boy?
Yeah
Yes
What do you fucking want?
The guy you’re looking for,
the guy Ray,
he’s downstairs
at the bar
(GRUNTING)
L’m sorry, Ken
But you can’t kill
a kid and expect to
get away with it
You just can’t
Where?
To the left when you come out
The bar to the left
(GROANING)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(COINS CLINKING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Ken!
(GASPING)
Ken! Ken!
Harry’s here
What?
Take
my gun
Ken?
Where’s my gun?
L’m gonna die now, I think
Oh, Ken!
Jesus!
(SCREAMING)
Mr Blakely said
you had left
I need the key
to the room right now
Quickly, now!
And you gotta go
home right now lt’s very,
very dangerous here
All right? Go home!
Right now!
Okay
MARIE: No, I won’t let you
up there! Put that
gun away, right now!
HARRY: Lady, get out of
my fucking way, please
No, I won’t I won’t
get out of your way
You’ll have to
go through me
Well, obviously,
l’m not gonna through you,
am I, with a baby and that?
L’m a nice person
But could you just get out
of the fucking way, please?
Marie!
Just let him
come up, it’s okay
Harry, swear not to
start shooting until
she’s left the hotel
I swear not to start shooting
till she’s left the hotel
I totally swear
Well, l’m not
going anywhere
This is my hotel
So you can fuck off!
I suppose you’ve got
a gun up there?
Yeah
Then what are we gonna do?
We can’t stand here all night
Why don’t you both
put your guns down
and go home?
Don’t be stupid
This is the shootout
Harry, l’ve got an idea
What?
My room faces
onto the canal, right?
L’m gonna go back to me room,
jump into the canal,
see if I can swim
to the other side
and escape
Right
If you go outside
and round the corner,
you can shoot at me
from there and try
and get me
That way, we leave this lady
and her baby out of
the whole, entire thing
Do you completely promise
to jump into the canal?
I don’t want to
run out there,
come back in 10 minutes
and find you fucking
hiding in a cupboard
I completely promise, Harry
l’m not gonna risk
having another
little kid die, am I?
So, hang on, I go outside,
then I go which way,
right or left?
You go right,
don’t you?
You can see it
from the doorway!
Lt’s a big fucking canal!
All right Jesus!
L’ve only just
got here, haven’t I?
Okay On a count of
‘one, two, three, go,’ okay?
Okay
What? Who says it?
Oh, you say it
You guys are crazy
Are you ready?
Ready
Set?
Set
One, two, three, go!
Keep driving!
No way You’re way
too far away
(GROANING)
The little boy
That’s right, Ray
Oh
I see
No, Harry
He’s not
You’ve got to stick
to your principles
RAY: There’s a Christmas tree
somewhere in London
with a bunch of presents
underneath it that’II
never be opened
And I thought,
‘If I survive all this,
l’II go to that house,
‘apologize to
the mother there,
‘and accept whatever
punishment she chose for me’
Prison, death,
it didn’t matter
Because at least in prison
and at least in death,
you know,
I wouldn’t be
in fucking Bruges
But then, like a flash,
it came to me, and I realized,
‘Fuck, man, maybe
that’s what Hell is
‘The entire rest of eternity
spent in fucking Bruges!’
And I really, really
hoped I wouldn’t die
I really, really
}}