(TYPING)
(DINGS)
Still got it.
(SHOTGUN PLAYING ON RADIO)
MISERY
(SINGING) I said, Shotgun
Shoot 'em for he runs now
Do the jerk, baby
Do the jerk now
Hey
Put on your red dress
And then you go downtown now
I said buy yourself
a shotgun now
We're gonna break it down
baby now
We're gonna load it up
And then you shoot him
'fore he runs now
I said, Shotgun
Shoot 'em 'fore he runs now
Do the jerk baby
Do the jerk now
Hey
Put on your high-heeled shoes
I said we're goin' down here
Listen to 'em play the blues
We're gonna dig potatoes
We're gonna pick tomatoes
I said, Shotgun
Shoot 'em 'fore he runs now
Do the jerk baby
Do the jerk now
Hey
I said it's Twine Time
(TIRES SCREECHING)
MARCIA: What's that?
An old friend.
I was rummaging
through a closet
and it was just
sitting there.
It's nice, Paul.
It's got character.
When I wrote my
first book, I used to
carry it around in this
while I was looking
for a publisher.
I was a writer then.
You're still a writer.
Haven't been a writer
since I got in
the Misery business.
It's not a bad business.
And it would still
be growing, too.
The first printing
for Misery's Child
was the most ever.
Over a million.
Marcia, please.
Misery Chastain put braces
on your daughter's teeth
and is putting her
through college,
bought you two houses
and floor seats
to the Knicks.
And what thanks
does she get?
You go and kill her!
I never meant for it
to become my life.
And if I hadn't
gotten rid of her now,
I'd have ended up
writing her forever.
Now I'm leaving
for Colorado to try to
finish the new book.
If I can make this work,
I might just have something
I want on my tombstone.
(GASPING)
ANNIE: I'm your
number-one fan.
There's nothing
to worry about.
You're gonna be just fine.
I'll take good care of you.
I'm your number-one fan.
Where...
We're just outside
Silver Creek.
How long?
You've been here two days.
You're gonna be okay.
My name is Annie Wilkes.
My number-one fan.
Yes. That's right.
I'm also a nurse.
Here, take these.
Here.
What are they?
They're called Novril.
They're for your pain.
Thank you.
How come I'm not
in a hospital?
The blizzard was too strong.
I couldn't risk trying
to get you there.
I tried calling,
but the phone lines
are down.
(GROANS)
You mustn't tire yourself.
You've gotta rest.
You almost died.
Open wide.
Your legs just sing
grand opera when you move,
don't they?
It's not gonna
hurt forever, Paul,
I promise you.
Will I be able to walk?
Of course you will.
And your arm
will be fine, too.
Your shoulder was
pretty badly dislocated.
It was a little stubborn,
but I finally
popped it back in.
What I'm most
proud of is the work
I did on those legs.
Considering what
I had around the house,
I don't think there's
a doctor who could've
done any better.
It's not nearly
as bad as it looks.
You have a compound fracture
of the tibia in both legs,
and the fibula
in the right leg
is fractured, too.
I could hear
the bones moving,
so it's best for your legs
to remain immobile.
And as soon as
the roads open,
I'll take you to a hospital.
Meantime, you've got
a lot of recovering to do,
and I consider it an honor
that you'll do it in my home.
This is Marcia Sindell,
I'm calling from
New York City.
I'd like to speak
to the Silver Creek
Chief of Police or Sheriff.
BUSTER: Which one
of them do you want?
Whichever one's not busy.
Well, I'm pretty sure
they're both not busy,
Miss Sindell,
since they're both me.
I also happen to be
president of the Policeman's
Benefit Association,
chairman of the Patrolman's
Retirement Fund,
and if you need
a good fishing guide,
you could do a lot worse.
Call me Buster.
Everybody does.
What can I do for you?
I'm a literary agent,
and I... I feel like
a fool calling you,
but I think one
of my clients,
Paul Sheldon,
might be in some
kind of trouble.
You mean Paul Sheldon
the writer?
He's your client, huh?
Yes, he is.
Everybody sure likes
those Misery books.
I'm sure you know
that Paul's been coming
to the Silver Creek Lodge
for years
to finish his books.
I understand
he's been up here
the last six weeks.
Well, not quite.
I just called there
and they said
he checked out
last Tuesday.
Isn't that
a little strange?
I don't know.
Does he usually phone you
before he checks
out of a hotel?
No, of course not.
It's just that his daughter
hasn't heard from him,
and when he has
a new book coming out,
he usually keeps in touch.
Now when there wasn't
any word from him, I...
You think he might
be missin', huh?
(SIGHING)
I hate that I made this call.
Tell me I'm being silly.
A little overprotective,
maybe, but tell you
what I'll do.
Nothing's been
reported out here,
but I'll put his name
through our system, and
if anything turns up,
I'll call you right back.
I'd appreciate that.
Thanks a lot.
Goodbye, Miss Sindell.
We got a phone call?
Busy morning.
Yeah. Work, work, work.
Virginia,
when was that blizzard?
Last Tuesday. Why?
No reason.
I guess it was
kind of a miracle,
you finding me.
(CHUCKLES)
No, it wasn't
a miracle at all.
In a way,
I was following you.
You were following me?
Well, it wasn't any secret
to me you were staying
at the Silver Creek,
seeing as how I'm your
number-one fan and all.
Some nights I'd just
tool on down there
and sit outside
and look up at
the light in your cabin
and I'd try to imagine
what was goin' on
in the room
of the world's
greatest writer.
Say the last part again,
I didn't hear you.
Don't move now.
I wouldn't want
to hurt this neck.
Well, the other afternoon
I was on my way home,
and there you were,
leavin' the lodge.
And I wondered why
a literary genius
would go for a drive
when there was
a big storm comin'.
I didn't know there was
a big storm coming.
Well, lucky for you, I did.
And lucky for me, too,
'cause now you're alive
and you can write
more books.
Oh, Paul, I've read
everything of yours.
The Misery novels.
I know 'em all by heart.
All eight of 'em.
I love them so.
Well, you're very kind.
And you're very brilliant.
Like a baby. All done.
Thank you.
When do you think
the phone lines'll be up?
I have to call my daughter,
and I'd like to call
my agent in New York
and let her know
I'm still breathing.
It shouldn't be
too much longer now.
Once the roads are open,
the phone lines'll
be up in no time.
If you give me
their numbers, I'll keep
tryin' them for you.
Thank you.
Could I ask you a favor?
I noticed in your case
there's a new
Paul Sheldon book, and
I wondered if maybe...
You want to read it?
Well, if you wouldn't mind.
Well, I do have a very
hard-and-fast rule as to
who reads my stuff
at this early stage.
Only my editor, my agent,
and anybody that saves me
from freezing to death
in a car wreck.
(EXCLAIMS)
You'll never realize
what a rare treat
you've given me.
(GROANS)
Boy, it's like clockwork
the way your pain comes.
I'll get you
your Novril, Paul.
Forgive me for prattling away
and making you feel all oogy.
ANNIE: What's your
new book called?
I don't have a title yet.
What's it about?
I don't know.
I know it sounds crazy,
but I haven't
written anything
but Misery for so long.
Why don't you read it,
and you can tell me
what you think it's about?
Maybe you can
come up with a title.
Like I could do that!
LIBBY: There's nothin'
unusual about Mr. Sheldon's
leaving, Buster.
You can tell
by the champagne.
Maybe you can, Libby.
No, see, he always
orders a bottle
of Dom Pérignon
when he's ready to go.
Then he pays up
and he's out the door.
No long-distance phone calls
or Federal Express packages?
Anything out
of the ordinary?
I don't think
Mr. Sheldon likes
for things to be
out of the ordinary.
Considering who he is
and all, famous and all,
he doesn't put on airs.
Drives up from New York
in the same car each time,
a '65 Mustang.
He says it helps him
to think.
He's always
been a good guest.
Never makes a noise,
never bothers a soul.
I sure hope nothing's
happened to him.
So do I.
I bet that old Mustang
is pulling into
New York right now.
I'm sure you're right.
Thanks, Libby.
My pleasure.
I know I'm only 40 pages
into your book, but...
But what?
Nothing.
What is it?
Well, it's ridiculous.
Who am I
to make a criticism
to someone like you?
It's all right,
I can take it.
Well, it's
brilliantly written.
But then everything
you write is brilliant.
Pretty rough so far?
The swearing, Paul.
There, I said it.
The... The profanity
bothers you?
It has no nobility.
These are slum kids.
I was a slum kid.
Everybody talks like that.
They do not!
What do you think I say
when I go to the feed store
in town?
"Now, Wally, give me a bag
of that F-ing pig feed
"and 10 pounds of that
bitchly cow corn"?
And in the bank,
do I tell Mrs. Bollinger,
"Here's one big bastard
of a check,
"give me some of your
Christing money"?
There! Look there!
See what you made me do?
Paul, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Sometimes I get so worked up.
Can you ever forgive me?
It's fine.
I love you, Paul.
Your mind.
Your creativity.
That's all I meant.
Well, this sure is fun.
Virginia, when
you're in this car
you're not my wife,
you're my deputy.
Well, this deputy'd
rather be home
under the covers
with the sheriff.
Stop. Stop.
What? What?
See that broken limb?
Could've been
the weight of the snow.
Yeah? Could've been
a rotten branch,
could've been the wind,
could've been
a lot of things.
(GRUNTS)
Damn!
Need some help?
No, I'm enjoyin' myself!
Thank you.
You really think
Sheldon's out there?
I hope not.
If he is, he's dead.
Let's go to
the newspaper office.
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
I hope I didn't wake you.
No, that's fine.
Look what I got.
They had it
at the store, Paul.
There was a whole batch
of 'em there,
and as soon as I saw it
I slammed my money down.
I got the first copy.
Then the roads are open.
Well, the one to town is,
but that's about it.
I called the hospital
and I talked to the
head orthopedic surgeon
and I told him
who you were and
what had happened.
He said as long as
there's no infection
you're not in any danger,
and as soon as the road
to the hospital is open,
they'll send
an ambulance for you.
The phone's working?
Well, mine's still out,
but the ones in town
were working just fine.
I called that
agent of yours.
Paul, I peeked at
the very beginning.
What a wonderful
first page.
Just to read the name
Misery Chastain...
My daughter's gotta
be goin' nuts.
It's like a visit
from my oldest,
dearest friend.
I mean,
I'm supposed to be home
for her birthday. It's today.
The agent said
she would tell her
you were okay,
but I'm afraid you'll have
to wait till tomorrow
if you want to talk
to her yourself.
Oh, Paul.
What a poet you are.
I made you my specialty,
scrambled eggs à la Wilkes.
And I'm on Page 75.
I guess that means
it's okay.
No.
No, it isn't, it's...
Pooh. I can't think
of any words.
Would "great" be insulting?
I can live with great.
No. It's not just great,
it's
perfect.
A perfect, perfect thing.
(SNORTING)
I thought it was time
you two should meet.
Paul, say hello
to my favorite beast
in the whole world,
my sow Misery.
Misery?
Yes. I told you I was
your number-one fan.
Yeah, I'm...
I'm starting to
believe you.
This farm was
kind of dreary,
what with just a few cows
and chickens and me.
But when I got
Misery here,
everything changed.
She just makes me smile so.
She's a fine pig,
is what she is.
I'm on Page 300 now, Paul,
and it's better than perfect.
It's divine.
What's the ceiling
that dago painted?
The Sistine Chapel?
Yeah!
That and Misery's Child.
Those are the only
two divine things
ever in this world!
(IMITATING MISERY SNORTING)
When my husband left me,
I wasn't prepared.
It wasn't an easy time.
For a while I thought
I might go crazy.
I know how that can be.
I don't know about you,
but what I did
to get through it
was I dove into work.
Days, nights.
Night shifts can be lonely
at a hospital.
I did a lot of reading.
That was when I first
discovered Misery.
She made me so happy.
She made me forget
all my problems.
Course, I suppose
you had a little something
to do with that, too.
Yeah, well...
I just kept reading
them over and over.
I've only got two chapters
to go on this one,
and I know when I finish
I'll just turn right
to the first page
and start reading it
all over again.
I'm...
Done?
Yeah.
No problem.
Thanks.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not against marriage
per se,
but it'd take
a pretty special guy
to make me
want to walk down
that aisle again.
Yeah, it's not something
you should enter
into lightly.
It boils down to respect.
People just don't respect
the institution of marriage
anymore.
They have no sense
of real commitment.
Well, I'd love to
stay here and chat,
but I'm right at the end,
and I gotta find
out what happens.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR SLAMMING)
You...
You dirty bird.
How could you?
She can't be dead!
Misery Chastain
cannot be dead!
Annie, in 1871,
women often died
in childbirth.
But her spirit
is the important thing,
and Misery's spirit
is still alive.
I don't want her spirit!
I want her!
And you murdered her!
No. I didn't.
Who did?
No one. She died,
she just slipped away.
Slipped away? Slipped away?
She didn't just slip away!
You did it!
You did it! You did it!
You murdered my Misery!
Annie!
I thought
you were good, Paul.
But you're not good.
You're just another
lying old dirty birdie.
And I don't think
I better be around you
for a while.
And don't even
think about anybody
coming for you.
Not the doctors,
not your agent,
not your family,
because I never called them.
Nobody knows you're here.
And you better hope
nothing happens to me.
Because if I die,
you die.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
BUSTER: No, Miss Sindell,
there's no point
in comin' up here now.
Everything that
can be done is.
Yes, we're working close
with the state police
and the FBI's
been informed.
Right. Right. As soon
as we know anything,
we'll let you know.
No bother at all.
Call anytime.
Bye, Miss Sindell.
All right. Well, I sure
appreciate it. Thank you.
According to
the check on Sheldon's
credit charges,
there's nothing
after the Silver Creek.
And no calls about
the article, either.
You poor, dear thing.
What are you doing
on the floor?
It's all my fault.
If I'd had a proper
hospital bed this never
would've happened.
Here, let me
help you back in.
I know this hurts,
but it'll only
take a few seconds.
Upsy-daisy!
(GROANING)
Please, wait.
You're such a crybaby.
There you go. Comfy?
Perfect.
You're such a kidder.
I have a big surprise
for you.
But first there's
something you must do.
You don't suppose
I could have a little snack
while I'm waiting
for the surprise?
I'll get you
everything you want,
but you must listen first.
Sometimes my thinking
is a little muddy,
I accept that.
That's why
I couldn't remember
all the things
they were asking me
on the witness stand
in Denver.
But this time
I thought clearly.
I asked God about you,
and God said,
"I delivered him unto you
"so that you may
show him the way."
Show me the way?
Yes.
When I mentioned a snack,
I was thinking
more along the lines
of cheese and crackers
kind of thing.
Paul, this is
no time for jokes.
You must rid the world
of this filth.
You want me to burn my book?
I know this may be
difficult for you,
but it's for the best.
It's really
not difficult at all.
My agent made
dozens of copies.
There's gonna be
an auction in New York.
Every publishing house
in New York
is reading it now.
So if you want me
to burn my book, fine.
You're not really
ridding the world
of anything.
Then light the match, Paul.
It's no big deal.
So you've indicated. Do it.
I know this is
the only copy, Paul.
When you were 24
you wrote your first book,
and you didn't make a copy
because you didn't think
anybody would
take it seriously.
But they did.
And ever since you've
never made any copies
because you're
superstitious.
It's why you always
come back to the
Silver Creek Lodge.
You told that story
to Merv Griffin
1 years ago.
Merv Griffin.
I'll tell you what.
It doesn't ever
have to be published.
No one ever has to read it.
I'll just keep it for myself.
No one will even
know it exists.
As long as it does exist,
your mind won't ever be free.
I think you should
light the match, Paul.
Can't you see
it's what God wants?
You're so brilliant,
I would think
you'd certainly
be able to see that.
We're put on this earth
to help people, Paul.
Like I'm trying
to help you.
Please. Help me help you.
You're doing the right thing.
My goodness!
Goodness gracious!
Oh, my.
Goodness!
Heavens to Betsy!
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, goodness!
Well, isn't that
an oogy mess?
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
That's the Steadman place
down there.
And that's the Wilkes farm
straight ahead.
That's no '65 Mustang.
There's nothing else
out this way. Let's...
Let's circle back.
I do believe
the winters are getting
shorter and shorter
every year.
People say it has
something to do
with the ozone layer.
What do you think?
I don't know.
Yeah, well, it's a theory.
Here's your Novril.
All right. We're back.
Now, you're gonna
have to remind us
who the audience chose.
They chose Kevin.
Hi, Kevin.
Hi. How you doin', Chuck?
Fine. Make yourself
at home back there,
and Sheree will tell us
about the date.
Okay. First of all,
I picked out
a very classy restaurant.
It was so classy,
and he shows up
without no tie...
(WOMAN CONTINUES CHATTERING)
See, isn't this nice?
Great. I always wanted
to visit the other side
of the room.
And look what
I got for you.
An electric razor,
so you can shave
yourself now.
(WHIRRING)
If I knew this was gonna
be the surprise, I'd have
burned all my books.
Now, don't poke fun!
This is
a very big day
for you, Paul.
You just sit tight
and I'll set
everything up.
Set what up?
That's the
big surprise.
Your new studio.
After all, writers
do need a place to work.
Work? You mean write?
What in the world
do you think I'd write?
Paul, I don't think.
I know.
Now that you've gotten rid
of that nasty manuscript,
you can go back to doing
what you're great at.
You're gonna write
a new novel,
your greatest
achievement ever.
Misery's Return.
Misery's Return?
I know you didn't mean it
when you killed her,
and now
you'll make it right.
It'll be a book
in my honor,
for saving your life
and nursing you
back to health.
Paul, you're gonna
make me the envy
of the whole world!
You just expect me
to whip something off,
is that it?
I expect nothing less
than your masterpiece.
You do understand
that this is not
the ordinary way
in which books get written.
I mean, some people
might actually consider this
an oddball situation.
I have total confidence
in your brilliance.
Besides, the view
will inspire you.
You just inhale that.
I'll be right back.
I guess you
don't get bothered
by neighbors much.
ANNIE: Don't you
worry about that,
you'll have total solitude
so you can concentrate
on your work.
Great.
I got you
this expensive paper
to type on,
and I got a great deal
on this 50-pound clunker,
on account of
its missing an "N."
I told the saleslady
"N" was one of the letters
in my favorite writer's name.
It's two of the letters
in my favorite
nurse's name, A-nn-ie.
You fooler! Did I do good?
You did great.
There is just
one little thing.
I can't work on this paper.
See, it's Corrasable Bond.
It smudges.
So I thought maybe,
if you went back into town,
you could bring me
some white long-grain mimeo.
But mine cost the most,
so I don't see
how it can smudge.
Come here, I'll show you.
(WINDING)
(TYPING)
It does smudge, after all.
Isn't that fascinating.
PAUL: I thought
you'd be interested.
I'd like for you to be
in on everything, Annie.
Not just the finished book,
but how it's written.
Thank you
for thinking of me.
Anything else I can get
while I'm in town?
Any other
crucial requirements
that need satisfying?
Would you like
a tiny tape recorder?
Or how about a handmade set
of writing slippers?
No, just the paper
will be fine.
Are you sure?
'Cause if you want,
I'll bring back
the whole store for you.
Annie, what's the matter?
What's the matter?
I'll tell you
what's the matter!
I go out of my way for you!
I do everything to try
and make you happy!
I feed you,
I clean you, I dress you,
and what thanks do I get?
"You bought
the wrong paper, Annie.
"I can't write on
this paper, Annie!"
Well, I'll get
your stupid paper,
but you just better
start showing me
a little more appreciation
around here, Mister Man!
(GROANING)
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
Shit.
Come on, you've written
about this, now do it.
(UNLOCKING)
What do you know?
It actually works.
(GROANING)
What a surprise.
You crazy bitch.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(LOCKING)
Paul, I've got your paper.
I hope it's enough.
It's three reams
of long-grain mimeo.
Just the kind you asked for.
Paul, you're dripping
with perspiration.
Your color is very hectic.
What have you been doing?
You know damn well
what I've been doing.
I've been
sitting here suffering.
I need my pills.
Poor dear.
Let's get you back in bed
and I'll get them for you.
I want my pills now!
It'll only take a second.
No!
I want my pain
to go away, Annie.
Please, make it go away.
Please, Annie. Please.
It just breaks my heart
to see you like this.
I've done a lot
of thinking on the drive.
Here you go.
And I'm absolutely certain
the main reason I've never
been more popular
is because of my temper.
You must be so mad at me.
The truth, now.
Well... Who doesn't
let off a little steam
every once in a while?
My genius needs his rest
before he writes.
Footsies up.
There you go.
Here. In case you think
of any ideas.
Well, I wouldn't
expect too much.
Don't be silly!
You'll be brilliant.
Think of me as
your inspiration.
I have faith in you,
my darling.
Catch this.
"My darling."
The presumption
must now be that
Paul Sheldon is dead.
We know that he somehow
managed to crawl
outside his vehicle,
but we have been unable
to find his body
anywhere in the vicinity
of the accident.
We also know that
if anyone had found him
they would have taken him
to an area hospital.
Undoubtedly he is buried
somewhere out there
in the snow.
We'll find him
after the first thaw.
That is, unless
the animals didn't
get to him first,
which is
a distinct possibility.
MAN: Local papers...
That was a statement
from Colorado Police Chief
Sherman Douglas.
The whereabouts
of famed novelist
Paul Sheldon is...
We will be updating
you with the latest...
(REPORTERS CHATTERING)
You don't think
he's dead, do you?
Well, he might well be,
but not the way they say.
He never crawled
out of that car
by himself.
You can see the dents
on the door there.
Someone pulled him out.
(MAN CHATTERING ON TV)
I'm sorry, Paul.
This is all wrong.
What?
You'll have to
do it over again.
It's not worthy of you.
Throw it all out.
Except for that part
of naming the gravedigger
after me.
You can leave that in.
I really value
your criticism,
but maybe we're being
a little hasty here.
Paul, what you've written
just isn't fair.
Not fair?
That's right.
When I was growing
up in Bakersfield,
my favorite thing
in all the world
was to go to the movies
on Saturday afternoons
for the chapter plays.
Cliffhangers.
I know that, Mister Man!
They also call them serials.
I'm not stupid, you know!
Anyway, my favorite
was Rocketman,
and once it was
a no-brakes chapter,
and the bad guys stuck him
in a car on a mountain road,
and knocked him out
and welded the doors shut
and tore out the brakes
and started him to his death.
And he woke up
and tried to steer
and tried to get out,
but the car went off
a cliff before
he could escape,
and it crashed and burned
and I was so upset
and excited!
And the next week,
you better believe
I was first in line.
And they always
start with the end
of the last week,
and there was Rocketman,
trying to get out,
and here comes the cliff,
and just before the car
went off the cliff
he jumped free,
and all the kids cheered!
But I didn't cheer.
I stood right up
and started shouting,
"This isn't what
happened last week!
Have you all got amnesia?
"They just cheated us!
This isn't fair!
"He didn't get out
of the cockadoodie car!"
They always
cheated like that
in chapter plays.
But not you.
Not with my Misery.
Remember Ian did ride
for Dr. Cleary
at the end of the last book,
but his horse fell
jumping that fence,
and Ian broke his shoulder
and his ribs and lay
all night in the ditch
and he never reached
the doctor,
so there couldn't have
been any experimental
blood transfusion
that saved her life.
Misery was buried
in the ground
at the end, Paul,
so you'll have
to start there.
Is it fair?
Should I continue?
You better!
Oh, Paul!
When Ian realized that
the reason they'd
buried Misery alive
was because the bee sting
had put her in
that temporary coma!
And when Gravedigger Wilkes
remembered how
30 years earlier
the same thing had happened
to Lady Evelyn-Hyde!
And then old Dr. Cleary
deduced that Misery
must be Lady Evelyn-Hyde's
long-lost daughter
because of the rarity
of deadly bee stings,
my heart just leapt!
I've known from
the very first book
that Misery had to
be born of nobility
and I was right!
Yeah.
Paul,
can I read each chapter
when you're finished?
I can fill in the "N's."
Will she be her old self
now that Ian has dug her out,
or will she have amnesia?
Have to wait.
Will she still love him
with that special,
perfect love?
You'll have to wait.
Not even a hint?
Uh-uh.
(EXCLAIMING)
Misery's alive,
Misery's alive!
It's so romantic!
This whole house
is gonna be filled
with romance!
I'm gonna put on
my Liberace records!
You do like Liberace,
don't you?
Whenever he played
Radio City,
who do you think
was right there
in the front row?
I'm gonna play my records
all day long, to inspire you.
He's my all-time favorite.
Annie.
Would you have
dinner with me tonight?
To celebrate Misery's Return.
I couldn't have
done it without you.
Paul.
It would be an honor.
No, he's not here.
I don't know where he is.
He never tells me
anything anymore.
He's probably out
havin' an affair somewhere.
Wait a minute.
He's comin' in now.
It's Jim Taylor.
He wants to know
who you're havin'
an affair with.
Hello, Jim.
What's doin'?
Jim, we've been
through this before.
If you're gonna have
benches out in front
of your store,
people are gonna want
to sit on 'em.
Well, I don't like him,
either,
but I'm not gonna
come over there
and tell him to move.
Give my best to
Denise. Bye.
Well, whoever she is,
she sure likes to read a lot.
Virginia, I'm flattered
that you think I've got
that much energy.
I figured that if
I can't find Paul Sheldon,
at least I can find out
what he wrote about.
What do you expect to find?
A story about a guy
who drove his car
off a cliff in a snowstorm?
You see, it's just
that kind of sarcasm
that's given our marriage
real spice.
(I'LL BE SEEING YOU PLAYING)
(SINGING) I'll be seeing you
In all the old
familiar places
I hope you like it.
It looks wonderful.
So do you.
(GIGGLING)
I've never had
meatloaf this good.
What do you do to it?
My secret is I only
use fresh tomatoes,
never canned.
And to give it
that little extra zip,
I mix in some Spam
with the ground beef.
Can't get this
in a restaurant
in New York.
Let's have a toast.
A toast?
Yes. To Misery.
Let me pour you some wine.
(EXCLAIMS)
To Misery.
Wait. Let's do this right.
Do you have any candles?
(EXCLAIMS)
I don't know.
I think so.
I'll go look.
Did you study decorating
or do you just have a flair?
Oh, you!
I just picked things up
over the years.
Well,
it certainly says you.
You really think so?
Absolutely.
Listen, if you can't
find any, it's okay.
I just thought it'd be nice.
Are you kidding?
If anyone had ever
told me that one day
I'd be having
a candlelit dinner
with Paul Sheldon
in my own house,
I would have checked
both legs
to see which one
was bein' pulled!
Will this do?
It's perfect.
To Misery and to Annie Wilkes,
who brought her back to life.
Paul, I get goose bumps
every time I think about it!
(EXCLAIMING)
My God, what have I done?
I'm so sorry, Paul!
I ruined your
beautiful toast!
Will you ever forgive me?
Here, let me
pour another one.
Can we pretend
this never happened?
To Misery.
(TYPING)
Paul, this is positively
the best Misery
you've ever written.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Here's your pills.
Annie?
Annie, what is it?
The rain.
Sometimes it
gives me the blues.
When you first came here,
I only loved
the writer part
of Paul Sheldon.
But now I know I love
the rest of him, too.
I know you don't love me.
Don't say you do.
You're a beautiful,
brilliant, famous man
of the world
and I'm not
a movie-star type.
You'll never know the fear
of losing someone like you,
if you're someone like me.
Why would you lose me?
The book's almost finished.
Your legs are getting better.
Soon you'll be
wanting to leave.
Why would I leave?
I like it here.
That's very kind of you,
but I'll bet it's
not altogether true.
I have this gun.
(COCKING)
Sometimes I think
about using it.
I better go now.
I might put bullets in it.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
"There is a justice
higher than that of man.
"I will be judged by Him."
What?
They're haulin'
Misery into court.
That's nice.
There is a justice
higher than that of man.
I will be judged by Him.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CAR APPROACHING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(MAN CHATTERING ON TV)
See you in the morning.
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
(GRUNTS)
(DOOR CLOSING)
MAN ON TV: I'm supposed
to lead to the finale
of my show right now,
but I'm having
such a wonderful time
that I have...
ANNIE: Paul.
Hmm?
I know you've been out.
What?
You've been out of your room.
No, I haven't.
Paul, my little
ceramic penguin
in the study
always faces due south.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Ceramic penguin?
Is this what
you're looking for?
I know you've
been out twice, Paul.
At first I couldn't
figure out how you did it,
but last night
I found your key.
I know I left
my scrapbook out.
I can imagine
what you might
be thinking of me.
But you see, Paul,
it's all okay.
Last night it came so clear.
I realize you just
need more time.
Eventually
you'll come to accept
the idea of being here.
Paul, do you know
about the early days
at the Kimberley
diamond mines?
Do you know what they did
to the native workers
who stole diamonds?
Don't worry.
They didn't kill them.
That would be like
junking a Mercedes
just because it had
a broken spring.
No, if they caught them
they had to make sure
they could go on working,
but they also
had to make sure
they could never run away.
The operation
was called "hobbling."
Annie, whatever you're
thinking about doing,
please don't do it.
Annie, for God's...
(SHUSHING)
Darling. Trust me.
God's sake!
It's for the best.
Annie, please!
(SCREAMING)
Almost done.
Just one more.
God, I love you.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CAR HORN HONKING)
You cockadoodie!
Turn on this!
You poop!
Just leave it, all right?
I like that tone!
How many times
do I have to
tell you?
I have a system here!
Where the hell
is that thing?
What thing?
The thing!
Here it is,
right where it's
supposed to be.
What is it?
I'm not sure.
Maybe nothin'.
Well, I'm glad you found it.
There's that spice again.
ANNIE: Come on, Misie.
Come on.
Hi, pumpkin.
(BELL RINGING)
Such a kidder!
Come on, Misery.
Hey, Pete.
Buster.
Answer me a couple things.
If I can.
Do you have any new
Paul Sheldon books?
Well, we had a batch.
Sold 'em all out
in three days.
You wouldn't happen to know
if Miss Wilkes bought
one of them, would you?
Are you kiddin'?
Every time that fella
writes a new book,
she has me set aside
the first copy.
Has she been buyin'
anything odd lately?
Miss Wilkes?
Same old stuff.
Lest you call paper odd.
Newspaper?
No. The typin' kind.
That kind.
Nothin' odd about that.
Miss Wilkes done somethin'?
Not a thing.
(CAR APPROACHING)
(SCREAMS)
I don't think
I'll ever understand you.
I cook your meals,
I tend to you practically
24 hours a day,
and you continue
to fight me.
When are we going to
develop a sense of trust?
Oh, my.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean
to startle you,
but you didn't give me
a chance to knock.
I guess you can tell
from my reaction
I'm not all that used
to visitors out here.
What can I do for you?
Well, I was wonderin',
do you happen
to know anything
about Paul Sheldon?
What do you want to know?
Well, anything you
could tell me might help.
Well, he was born
in Worcester, Massachusetts,
45 years ago,
the only child of Franklin
and Helene Sheldon,
mediocre student,
majored in History...
Well that...
That isn't exactly the kind
of information I'm after.
You see, he's been missin'
for quite some time now...
I know. It's so upsetting.
I'm his number-one fan.
I've got all his books.
Every sentence
he ever put down.
I'm so proud of my
Paul Sheldon collection.
Well, here I am,
prattling on,
and my manners
have just flown away.
I haven't invited you in.
Please.
Thank you.
Of course, you must know
all about that
horrible accident.
Mind if I take a look around?
Of course not.
That accident almost
killed me, too.
I prayed when
I heard the news.
I got down on my knees
and I begged for it
not to be true.
You're gonna laugh
at what I'm about to say,
but go ahead,
I don't care.
When I was praying,
God told me to get ready.
Get ready
for what?
To be his replacement.
He gave so much pleasure
to so many people,
and there's a shortage
of pleasure on the planet
these days,
in case you
hadn't noticed.
God told me,
since I was his
number-one fan,
that I should make up
new stories as if
I was Paul Sheldon.
So I went to town,
and I bought
a typewriter,
and paper to type on,
the same kind
Paul Sheldon used.
And I turned
the guest bedroom
into a writing studio.
Would you like to see it?
Sure.
It's right this way.
I know how he wrote.
The kinds of words
he used,
the wonderful stories
he told.
I've spent the last
four weeks
trying to write
like Paul Sheldon,
but I can't do it right.
I try and I try,
and I know all the words,
but it's just not the same.
Well, maybe
it takes a while
to get the hang of it.
I could give you a couple
of hundred pages of mine
and you could tell
me what you think.
I'm not much of a critic.
Well, I just thought...
Oh, look at me.
You'd think I'd never
had a guest before!
Would you like a nice
hot cup of cocoa?
No, really, I don't...
It's no trouble.
There's some already made.
Must get lonely,
livin' out here
all by yourself.
Well, I always say,
if you can't enjoy
your own company,
you're not fit company
for anyone else.
Well, you've got
a point there.
(CHUCKLING)
Here you are.
Well, thanks, Miss Wilkes,
but I don't want to take up
any more of your time.
I best be goin'.
But you didn't even
taste your cocoa.
I'm sure it's wonderful,
but I really should
be gettin' back.
If you wouldn't mind,
perhaps I could
pay you another
visit sometime.
I'd be delighted,
now that you know the way.
(CLATTERING)
Miss Wilkes?
Miss Wilkes,
are you all right?
PAUL: Here!
Here! I'm down here!
I'm down here!
Mr. Sheldon?
Don't feel bad, Paul.
It was bound to happen
sooner or later.
It's a sign.
You see,
I've known for some time
why I was chosen to save you.
You and I were meant
to be together forever.
But now our time
in this world must end.
But don't worry, Paul.
I've prepared
for what must be done.
I put two bullets in my gun,
one for you and one for me.
Darling,
it'll be so beautiful.
Now don't be afraid.
I love you.
I love you, too.
And you're right.
We are meant to be together.
And I know we must die.
But it must be
so that Misery can live.
We have the power
to give Misery eternal life.
We must finish the book.
But the time is now.
Soon others will come.
It's almost finished.
By dawn
we'll be able to give Misery
back to the world.
I'll fix you
something to eat.
Paul, I'm dying!
Does she wind up
with Ian or Windthorne?
You'll know very soon.
I've just started
the last chapter.
You know, when I finish,
I'd like everything
to be perfect.
I'll need three things.
What things?
You mean you don't know?
(LAUGHING)
I was foolin', silly.
You need a cigarette,
because you used to smoke
but you quit,
except when you
finish a book,
and you have just one.
And the match
is to light it,
and you need
one glass of champagne,
Dom Perignon.
Dom Perignon it is.
Annie, Annie?
Yes, Paul?
I'm almost done.
Oh, Paul,
this is so romantic!
Ian and Windthorne
dueling for the right
to Misery's hand.
Does Ian win?
Don't tell me.
It's Windthorne, right?
You'll know everything
in a minute.
Get the champagne.
(EXCLAIMS)
Did I do good?
You did perfect.
Except for one thing.
This time we'll need
two glasses.
Oh, Paul.
Remember how,
for all those years,
nobody knew who
Misery's real father was?
Or if they'd
ever be reunited?
It's all right here.
Does she finally marry Ian,
or will it be Windthorne?
It's all right here.
Paul, you can't!
Why not?
I learned it from you.
No, no, no!
Not Misery!
Not my Misery!
No! Not my Misery!
(PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
I'm gonna kill you,
you lying cocksucker!
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
Here, you want it?
You want it? Eat it!
Eat it till you choke,
you sick, twisted fuck!
(GROANING)
(SIGHS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
MARCIA: This is it.
The very first copy.
The word I'm getting is
the Times review is
gonna be a love letter.
That'll be a first.
And my contacts at
Time and Newsweek
tell me they're both raves.
And don't laugh,
but for the first time
I think you've got
a shot at some prizes.
Great.
I thought you'd be thrilled.
You're being taken seriously.
I'm delighted
the critics are liking it
and I hope the people
like it, too.
But I wrote it for me.
Now, don't think
I'm completely nuts, but...
In some way, Annie Wilkes,
that whole experience,
helped me.
Paul, since you
brought her up,
I have to ask you this
or I'll be drummed out
of the agents' union.
How would you feel
about a non-fiction book
about what went on
in that house?
Gee, Marcia,
if I didn't know you better,
I'd think you were suggesting
I dredge up the worst
horror of my life
just so we can make
a few bucks.
MARCIA: I thought you
were over it.
I don't know if anyone
could ever totally get over
something like that.
It's weird.
Even though I know
she's dead,
I still think about
her once in a while.
Excuse me.
I don't mean to bother you,
but are you Paul Sheldon?
Yes.
I just want to tell you
I'm your number-one fan.
That's very sweet of you.
(SINGING) I'll be seeing you
In all the old familiar places
That this heart
of mine embraces
All day through
In that small cafe
The park across the way
The children's carousel
The chestnut trees
The wishin' well
I'll be seeing you
In every
lovely summer's day
In every thing
that's light and gay
I'll always think
of you that way
I'll find you
In the morning sun
And when the night is new
I'll be looking at the moon
But I'll be seeing you
I'll be seeing you
In every lovely summer's day
in every thing
that's light and gay
I'll always
think of you that way
I'll find you
In the morning sun
And when the night is new
I'll be looking at the moon
But I'll be seeing you