Come on, champ. You ain't so bad!
Come on!
You're out!
We made a deal.
I know, but this is extremely crazy.
Yeah, it's mentally irregular.
But it makes sense.
You owe me a favor.
I know, but when did you think of this?
About three years ago
This is very crazy, Apollo
Look, Stallion
you won that last fight by one second
You beat me by one second.
That's very hard for a man of my intelligence to handle
Is it? Didn't you say afterwards
you learned how to live with it?
I lied.You lied
So now you have to prove it to yourself?
Just for myself. No TV or newspapers,
just you and me.
Nothing. Just you and me.
Age before beautyAnything you say, son.
I do all the work.
You better go slow.
You ain't as young as springtime no more.
I'm still young enough to whip your butt.
Yeah? How will you do that?
You taught me everything you know.
Almost everything
Remember, you fight great
but I'm a great fighter, you ready
Absolutely.All right.
You know, Stallion.
It's too bad we have to get old, yeah?
Just keep punching, Apollo.
Want to ring the bell?
All right.
Come on!
You really move good for an older guy.
Look at him fly.Look out.
No, you don't want any of this.
Maybe I'm in here with the wrong guy.
Dad, you're late.
Mom's going to yell at you.
How you doing? Fine.
Don't you think that's a little bright? A little bit.
Where'd you get that hat?
A friend gave it to me. Like it?
Who punched you in the eye?
Same friend.
That's weird. Better hurry, Dad
You know, you're developing a very loud personality.
Don't go too fast or you'll get out of focus
Really?
Yo.
Yo, It's about time.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Why don't you get ready to eat, ok?
You're here. Now stop calling him name
You been calling me names?
We wait any longer, it will be my next birthday
Where have you been?
Out getting punched.
Bring the cake in here,
and let's get the celebration underway.
I'm hungry.
Babe, get the cake. He'll love it.
We have a great surprise for you.
You'll love this cake, ok?
You'll love your present, Uncle Paulie.
Where is it?
Let me set the mood here. I have to turn the lights down.
Watch this
It's parked in the driveway?
Just be patient, would you?
I'm so excited, I'm sweating.
I feel like I'm going into a big fight.
Happy birthday, Paulie.
What the hell is this?
Your present.
I wanted a sports car for my birthday.
not a walking trash can.
Come on, he looks great here.
This is extremely psycho.
Since you don't have any friends, we thought you'd like it.
Yeah. Pretend you're happy. It'll keep you company when you're all alone.
That's a great-looking guy.
Please make a wish
It's creepy! That thing talks!
Creepy? These things are great! I wish I had one when I was growing up.
Make a wish, like he said.
I wish I wasn't in this nightmare.
A very classy wish.
What do you think?
Very good.
Want to help me put out this forest fire?
Sure.
On the count of three. One
Two
Three
They're out.
You drowned me!
Don't worry.
I'll clean it up for you, Paulie.
Rocky.
Yeah, you noticed.
What are you doing with that cake?
The party ain't over yet.
Still got to celebrate.
It's a special night.
Yeah, it's Wednesday.
It's definitely Wednesday.
but in case you forgot.
it's almost been nine years since you married me.
so here's your prize.
But our anniversary's a week away.
That's true. But why wait?
Has it been that rough? No.
It's been excellent.
Open your prize. Go on.
All right.
Do you like it?
It's beautiful.All right.
I was so nervous. I didn't know.
I hope you like it.
The guy I bought it from says.
even if it looks like a snake, don't worry.
It won't bite you.
It's beautiful.
You know what's amazing?
After all these years.
everything still seems kind of new.
You remember a long time ago I told you that
you ain't never getting rid of me.
remember that?
You're not.
You're never getting rid of me.
Happy almost anniversary.
Can you answer a few questions?
How long you here for?
We talk later, please.
When are you fighting, Drago?
We talk it later.
Is it definite the Soviet Union
will enter professional boxing?
Please, no more talk now.
We will talk at press conference.
Do you know where it will be held?
We talk it later.
Today may have proved to be a landmark in sports history.
After unraveling years of red tape,
Russia will now throw its hat into the ring.
The prize ring, that is.
The introductions were made by his wife Ludmilla Vobet Drago.
She was the double gold medalist in swimming.
Today the Soviet Union has officially entered professional boxing.
My husband and great undefeated heavyweight world amateur champion
Captain Ivan Drago.
has come with his trainers to America
to compete as an international sportsman and ambassador of goodwill.
Has Drago ever boxed against a real professional?
From having been trained in Russia by great boxing coach, Manuel Vega
and now by Sergei Rimsky, we hope he's qualified to do so.
Hope?
Well, I know he is, but I don't want to sound too confident.
If possible, we would like to
have an exhibition bout with your famous champion Rocky Balboa.
What makes you think he can fight someone as seasoned as Balboa?
No one can match his strength, his endurance
or his aggressiveness.
You sound like he's indestructible.
Yes, he is.
Well. Can this mammoth Russian,
already nicknamed the Siberian Express,
wreak havoc among the professional heavyweight ranks?
Whoever he fights first,
it'll be one hot ticket.
We'll be right back with a check on today's pro football scoreboard.
Dad, when can I learn to fight?
I can't hear you. What?
I want to learn to fight.
Could you turn your robot down?
You see I fight,
so you don't have to fight.
I want you to use your head for something
instead of a punching bag like I do.
Your head doesn't look like a punching bag.
That's nice. Thanks a lot.
It looks like a catcher's mitt.
A wise guy.
Mr. Balboa, Mr. Creed's on the phone.
Yeah? I'll be right there.
You can get it right here.
I hope it's not another rematch.
Don't worry about it.
Hello? Yeah, Apollo.
Turn that down. How are you doing?
Yeah? You're coming out?
That's great. What am I doing?
I'm just getting dizzy.
My husband and I thank you for coming to our training quarters today.
As you can see, it is highly advanced
and we wish to show the American press a small portion
of the advances our country's made
in the technology of human performance.
Coach Rimsky, what does all this do to enhance performance?
Well...If I may answer.
It makes a man a better man
a great athlete a super athlete by harnessing all his strength.
Though most of the world is ignorant in body chemistry,
we wish to educate your country.
There have been rumors of doping
and distribution of anabolic steroids in the Soviet Union.
Has Drago partaken in any such experiments?
No, Ivan in naturally trained.
Then how do you explain his freakish strength?
Like your Popeye, he ate his spinach every day.
Shall we have a demonstration?
Please do.Thank you.
A normal heavyweight
averages 700 pounds of pressure per square inch.
Drago averages 1850 pounds.
So the result is quite obvious.
What results are those?
Whatever he hits, he destroys.
He's big and he's strong, but he's clumsy.
I know I can beat him.
Why do you want to fight again?
It's something I believe in.
You can do your homework.
Okay. Later, Dad.
Later, Uncle Paulie, Apollo.
Later, big man.See you later, kiddo.
Don't you think people are expecting to see Rocky whack this bum out first?
Yeah, and he will when it's for real.
This is just an exhibition bout. It's kid stuff.
What's the purpose?
What's worth getting hurt for?
What the hell is that?
That's my girl.
Thanks, honey.You're welcome.
Nice song.
It's my favorite. You're the greatest.
See you, sport.
See you.
Paulie, who taught it to talk like that?
She loves me.
Like I was saying,
I don't want this chump to come here with all that hype
trying to make us look bad.
They try every other way.
With Rock's help, we can get great media coverage,
We can make them look bad
I think it's wrong.
It's never been more right.
You're a great fighter,
but you've been retired for five years.
Don't you think it's time to think about something else?
How much can you take?
Either of you.
I'll get the coffee.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to.
I just care about you both.
You ever try these comics?
No.
Keeps your fertility.
Paulie.
This was a great fight.
Great? I'm getting punchy just watching.
What you using for a chin there, Stallion?
I should have slipped that one.
Yeah, You definitely should have slipped.
It's crazy how people care about you when you're in that ring bleeding,
but once you step out of that ring, you're ancient history.
You ain't ancient history.
Nobody's asking for autographs.
Apollo, Can I ask you something?
What?
You know this fight you're having against the Russian.
Do you think maybe it ain't against him?
If it's not him, then who is it against?
Do you think maybe it's like you against you?
No, I think you really are getting brain damaged.
That's what I think.
Yeah, maybe, but
I'm speaking the truth, Apollo.
Are you? Yeah.
I don't think I want to hear this.
Come on, Apollo.
you're a great fighter. No doubt about that.
But we have to face the facts too.
You don't want to believe it, but maybe the show is over.
That's easy for you to say. You're still on top.
What happens when you're not on top? Then what?
Where do we go? We sure can't be born again.
I know we can't be born again, but we have to change sometime.
I don't want to change! I like who I am!
I like who you are too, but look at that.
You don't want to believe this, but that ain't us no more.
We can't do that the way we did before.
We're changing. We're turning into regular people.
No, maybe you think you're changing.
but you can't change what you really are.
Forget all this money and stuff around you. It don't change a thing.
You and me don't even have a choice.
We're born with a killer instinct,
you can't turn off and on like a radio.
We have to be in the middle of the action because we're warriors.
Without some challenge, without some war to fight
then the warrior may as well be dead.
So I'm asking you,
as a friend,
stand by my side this one last time.
You're a great talker, Apollo.
All right, but when this is over.
You know me, Stallion.
I always think of something else.
That's what I'm afraid of.
All right, you have a deal.
I feel sorry for that guy.
Apollo, what made you decide to put on an exhibition with Drago?
Call it a sense of responsibility.
Responsibility, how?
I have to teach this young fellow how to box American style.
Isn't Drago a little inexperienced to be in the same ring?
Some folks have to learn the hard way.
No knockout prediction?
I'm not angry with him.
I just want to show the world
Russia doesn't have all the best athletes.
How do you think Apollo should fight Drago?
Personally, the first thing you need is a ladder.
How does it feel to spar with the great former champion?
The man's tongue didn't come through customs.
My husband is very happy to have this opportunity.
It's his dream.
Dream. How do you mean?
In our country, Apollo Creed is well-known and very respected.
It could be a good victory.
Wait a minute. Win?
You don't really think you're going to whip me, do you?
He didn't come here to lose.
You hold on, little lady.
Lose and lose royally he will do.
How can you be so sure?
I've been with best, I've beaten the best.
I've retired more men than Social Security.
Excuse, please.
You are not very realistic.
Where did you come from?
What are you talking about?
You can box, yes,
but you are far too old to think you can win over Drago.
Is that a fact?
Yes, and it could be a painful one.
You put that heavy bag without balls in the ring with me
and you'll see the meaning of pain!
Why do you insult us?
You just hold on here.
Don't make me out as the bad guy.
I came to talk about a friendly exhibition bout till you started up.
come right the big mouth body
You are the aggressor! This is obvious!
I wish to say to the press in all fairness,
Drago should not even fight this man,
He is a has-been!
You get that big chump in the ring right now!
Bring it on. I don't want to hear her.
Just let that chump go.
All right
I said what I feel.
We'll finish this in the ring.
You understand? Whatever you like.
You and all your puppets just shut up!
You are history, chump.
How did I do?
A little loud for my taste.
But good? Yeah, very good.
Welcome one and all to the city of lights
Las Vegas,
and one of the most unusual events in years
East meets West.
Age versus youth in a goodwill exhibition match
as the former champion Apollo Creed
takes on a mountain of muscle from the Soviet Union
Ivan Drago.
Come on.Patience is a virtue.
I'm ready to rock and roll.
I understand, but you need your equipment. There you go.
Now you look like a mummy.
I feel like a mummy.Does it feel okay?
It feels great. I could eat nails.
I never tried them things.
What?
I never had snails.
I seen them in the garden, but I never wanted to eat them.
I didn't say anything about snails. I said, "nails,"
Nail. Stallion. Yeah
You look pretty good
but do me a favor when you go up there
Try not to wear yourself out
Yeah, wear myself out
It's just that you haven't been in the ring for five years
I just want you to maintain a bit
You sound like I'm an old man
I'm in the best shape of my life. I'm stronger. I'm quicker
I'm not saying you're not ready
but, personally, if it were me
I wouldn't mind postponing it a couple weeks
Postpone? Yeah
Come on, we don't really know anything about this guy you're fighting
Let's say I postpone.
I pull out, somebody else steps in and whips this chump
Where does that leave me? What do you mean?
It's just some exhibition fight.
This don't mean nothing
No, that's where you're wrong
This is not just an exhibition that doesn't mean anything
This is us against them. Come on
Stallion
maybe you don't know
what I'm talking about now
but you will when it's over
Believe me, you will when it's over!
Drago
Good luck.
I hope after we can be friend.
I hope so
Of course.
They're sportsmen, not soldiers.
Enjoy the fight
Good evening, everyone.
Along with Warner Wolf, I'm Stu Nahan
We welcome you to a most unusual event
For the first time,
West against East in professional sports.
Thanks for getting me here.
I owe you one.
No, we're even
God, I feel born again
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome
I would like to announce the presence of a true fighting champion
that defines the word courage
The Italian Stallion, Rocky Balboa
Excuse me, would you
Certainly
Rocky
Tonight's special event features
two great athletes
In the blue corner weighing 221 pounds
the former heavyweight champion of the world
the Dancing Destroyer
the King of Sting
the Count of Monte Fisto
You think you have enough names?
Be patient. We're almost done
The Master of Disaster, the one and only
Apollo Creed!
The crowd anticipating a great fight.
Apollo is playing to the crowd.
In the red corner
weighing an even 261 pounds
gold medalist and undefeated world amateur champion
from the Soviet Union
the Siberian Bull
Ivan Drago!
I want you!
The two fighters come to the center of the ring
for the instructions from referee Lou Filippo.
You boys know the rules
Watch your low blows, kidney punches, rabbit punches
In case of a knockdown,
you go to the corner I tell you
and you stay there until I tell you to come out
Shake hands and let's have a good fight
It's time to go to school, son
Get your hands up.
Do you need an interpreter?
It's time to go to school
You will lose
All right
The bad blood between these two
can be felt all over this arena.
I can't get over the size of this Russian
It's show time!
Excuse me.
Didn't you forget something?
Come on
Apollo seems to be in great spirits tonight
He's really putting on a show for this capacity crowd
Be back in a minute
Round one
Creed dancing around Creed backpedaling now
He's been away five years
Don't wait him, get out first.
Come on
Neither fighter ready to throw a punch
A left jab there.
A left jab once again by Creed.
A slip by Creed
This is bizarre
Creed is over the hill,
and the Russian hasn't fought anybody.
Keep moving! Stick him! Apollo.
Drago moving in again
A left hand by Creed and another. Drago moves away
Come on
Get your hands up!
Another left hand by Creed!
Drago waiting, cocking that right hand.
Get out there!
Get out of there!
And a left hand!
He's taking some punishment now!
Drago moves him against the ropes!
Tie him up now!
Now the Russian throws Creed across the ring!
Move!
It is Drago with the upper hand!
Drago with a left to the midsection!
Get out of that corner!
Another right and another right!
Another right, another right!
Creed is against the ropes!
They step in and stop it!
What are you guys doing?
This is supposed to be an exhibition! You understand?
Just an exhibition!
A tremendous end to the first round by the Russian
And a very bloody Apollo Creed
The Soviet's strength is incredible!
Champ, I have to stop you
This fight's finished. I have to call it
Champ, you can't do no more out there
I'm here to fight
He's killing you. I have to stop this thing.
I'm here to fight.
Promise me you won't stop this fight.
That was a pulverizing round for the ex-champion
Ivan Drago is definitely for real.
Don't stop this fight no matter what
no matter what
Creed comes out for round two, dancing around.
The legs appear to be still a little rubbery
Get your hands up
Now it is the Russian just standing there.
The Russian trying to intimidate Creed.
The Russian throws a right hand and staggers Creed!
Another right to the jaw!
A left to the head!
Creed is being pounded without mercy!
Stop the fight!
The referee tries to step in
and he's thrown across the ring!
Throw the towel!
No
I have never seen Apollo take so much punishment!
Throw the damn towel!
No
My God!
Creed is down!
Apollo could be badly hurt
Let him breathe!
Get move back.Get these guys out of here!
The winner: Ivan Drago
Let me through! Apollo!
I cannot be defeated
Is he okay? Somebody get a doctor!
There is no movement by Creed
Get that light off him!
I defeat all men
Is he dead? Get out of here!
It's absolute pandemonium!
Stand back
Let him breathe!
You can do it
Soon
I defeat real champion
Where's the stretcher?
Let him breathe!
What started out as a joke has turned out to be a disaster
Creed appears to be in very serious condition
Is the man alive?
You can make it, Apollo.
If he dies, he dies.
There's a lot I could say about this man
I don't know if it matters now
I guess what matters is
what he stood for
what he lived for
and what he died for
You always did everything
the way you wanted it
I didn't understand that, but
now I understand
I'll never forget you, Apollo
You're the best
Rocky, is the decision final?
Yes.
Are you the first to give up his crown?
I don't know about that
Doesn the title mean anything to you anymore?
Not until this is over.
Coach Rimsky, considering Rocky's known punching power.
do you still think this will be an easy fight?
Yes, of course. It's a matter of size
and evolution. Isn't it, gentlemen?
Drago is the most perfectly trained athlete ever.
This other man has not the size or the endurance
or the genetics to win.
It's physically impossible for this little man to win.
Drago is a look at the future.
There's been no mention yet, but how much are you making for this fight?
No money.
It's not about money.
Has the fight date been set yet?
December 25
Why Christmas?
That's what I was told.Where?
It's in Russia.
Are you nuts?
What's going on?
Why did you agree to this?
We fight in Soviet Union or we fight nowhere.
Why don't you ask Drago's wife why she is afraid?
Tell them, please.
I'm afraid for my husband's life.
We have threats of violence everywhere.
We are not in politics.
All I want is for my husband to be safe, to be treated fairly.
You call him a killer.
He's a professional fighter, not a killer.
You have this belief that you are better than us.
You have this belief that this country is so very good
and we are so very bad.
You have this belief that you are so fair
and we are so cruel.
It's all lies and false propaganda.
to support this antagonistic and violent government!
"Violent"?
We don't keep our people behind a wall with machine guns.
Who are you? Who am I?
I'm the unsilent majority, big mouth!
Good!
Yes, insult us!
It's more typical rude behavior toward visiting foreigners
But perhaps this simple defeat of this little so-called champion
will be a perfect example
of how pathetic and weak your society has become!
We go!
Mrs. Balboa!
How do you feel about going to Russia?
How does it feel to be part of such a controversial decision?
Did Creed's death make up your husband's mind?
I don't know what you're talking about!
why will fight in Christmas?
Is it his decision?
When will you go to Russia?
I'm not going to Russia. I don't know what you're talking about.
or what you people are doing here.
You all right?
Yeah
Fine
Why did you do it?
I just have to do what I have to do.
You don't have to do anything
No, Adrian, I do.
I have to leave this place too.
So where are you going?
They said they would let me train in Russia.
I just want to go someplace where
I won't think of nothing except him
Rocky, give it some time.
Don't do this.
A lot of people live with hurt.
Adrian, a lot of people don't have the choice.
I do.
And for that you're willing to lose everything?
This ain't everything
This house and the stuff we have
ain't everything
There's a lot more than this
Before, there were reasons to fight
I could understand.
but I don't understand this
Even if you win, what have you won?
Apollo is still gone.
Why can't you change your thinking?
Everybody else does!
Because I'm a fighter
That's the way I'm made
That's what you married
We can't change what we are
Yes, you can.
You can't change anything.
All we can do is just go with what we are.
You cann't go with what we are.
Have you read the papers?
Do you know what everybody says?
Everybody says it's suicide!
You've seen him. You know how strong he is
You can't win!
Adrian always tells the truth
Maybe I can't win
Maybe the only thing I can do
is just take everything he's got
But to beat me
he'll have to kill me
And to kill me
he'll have to have the heart to stand in front of me
And to do that
he has to be willing to die himself
I don't know if he's ready to do that
I don't know
I don't know.
Be careful with the plaid ones.
They belong to the boss.
Did you pack your toothbrush?
You know how tobacco stains your teeth.
If I've told you once, I've told you a thousand times.
Stop busting my chops
I'll have her wires tied when I get back
When will you be back?
Pretty soon
Are you scared?
No.Yes, you are
A little maybe?
Wouldn't you be?
If a big giant man wanted to beat me up,
I'd be real scared.
The truth is, sometimes
I do get a little scared
When I'm in that ring really getting hit
and my arms hurt so much I can't lift them
I'm thinking, "God,
I wish this guy would hit me on the chin,
so I don't feel nothing anymore."
Then there's another side that comes out
that isn't so scared.
It's another side
that wants to take more
that wants to go that one more round
because by going that one more roundwhen
you don't think you can
That's what makes all the difference in your life
You know what I mean?
Can you remember one more thing?
Remember that
Daddy thinks you're the best boy in the world
And Daddy loves you, no matter what
I have to go now
Will you take care of everything
Don't forget to feed your robot
Bye, babe
Good luck
Thanks
Come on! The meter's running!
What a horrendous flight
This is Russia? Don't look so tough
Mr. Balboa
We take you to quarters now
When does the sun come up?
This is detrimental to my sinuses.
Weather changes hour to hour.
Get used to it.
Get in car now
We have very long trip.
He sounds like Dracula's cousin.
Come on, Paulie.
Like you requested, yes?
You requested this dumb location? Yeah
Why? You planning to grow reindeer or something?
I just wanted to get away from things
The equipment you requested
is in barn
Who are they? "They"?
They are assigned to you
Official chaperones.
Where you go, they go
I have a bad dream here
It's okay.It's okay?
This is below human standards.
There's no antennas. You have to complain.
We'll crack out here
You have everything I have been instructed to provide
We are finished, yes?
No sparring?
I don't think I need it anymore
No sparring? No TV? Nothing?
How the heck is he supposed to train around here?
No TV. What about the Rose Bowl game?
No room service, I bet.
I hope they got my comics here.
What a depressing vacation
Goddamn
Checkmate, friend
Champ, can I come up? Sure
How you doing?
Pretty good
Some kind of weather we're having
It's pretty rough
But for what you have to do it's good
Toughen you up
I guess so
You'll have to do almost everything alone
but I'll be with you.Yeah, I know
Apollo was like my son
I raised him
When he died
part of me died
But now
you're the one
You're the one that's
going to keep his spirit alive.You're the one
that's going to make sure he didn't die for nothing
You'll have to go through hell
worse than any nightmare you ever dreamed
But in the end
I know you'll be the one standing
I'll try
You know what you have to do
Do it
Thanks, Duke
I couldn't stay away any more
I missed you
I'm with you no matter what
"No matter what"?
No matter what
No pain
Drago
Hello, everybody, and Merry Christmas from a very unusual place
We're in Moscow in the Soviet Union
I'm Barry Tompkins along with Al Bandiero
This promises to be the most-watched event in boxing history
The iron horse from America, Rocky Balboa
Drago
Since that tragedy in Las Vegas and the death of Apollo Creed
Drago has been nicknamed Death From Above.
The General Secretary of the Soviet
and other members of the Politburo
have made their way to their seats high above the ring here in Moscow
I know you're busy just now
but I want to tell you some things
I never told you
I know sometimes I act stupid
and say stupid things
But you kept me around when others would have said, "Drop that bum."
You give me respect
It's hard for me to say these things
because that ain't my way
but if I could just be someone else
I'd want to be you
You're all heart, man.
Thanks, Paulio
Now blast this guy's teeth out!
I'll try
One of the fighters is starting to make his way toward the ring
Listen to this crowd!
This borders on pure hatred.
Rocky's face absolutely like stone
He is the picture of concentration.
The booing crowd here does not seem to bother him one bit
The champ has a look tonight that can burn through lead
The booing crowd has absolutely no effect on the man.
His concentration seems to be like stone
That's my dad
We know.We're not nerds.
Listen to this crowd. It sounds insane.
Now the entrance of the Russian national champion
Ivan Drago, a man with an entire country in his corner.
Look at the expression on the face of Ivan Drago
He seems impervious to the madness of the crowd.
He's like a volcano just waiting to erupt
The Russian champion is amazingly cool as he acknowledges his premier.
I'd like to point out again this is a non-sanctioned fight
This is not for the title
The American boxing commission has not sanctioned this bout
Ladies and gentlemen
It's unbelievable.
I've never seen such a hostile crowd.
It's an unbelievable sight to see.
They're toe-to-toe.
The Russian towers above the American It's a true case of
David and Goliath.
The condition of both men is unbelievable
I must break you
Remember what I said back there about wanting to be you?
Forget it
Thanks, Paulio
Take it straight to him and be a rock for me. Understand?
Be strong!
All right? Take it to him.
No pain.No pain
Do it!
There's the opening round bell.
Rocky comes into the center of the ring
The Russian way back into Balboa's corner now
Get out of there! Let's go!
Once more, it's Drago backing up Rocky with a jab.
Balboa is not staying on balance
because of the Russian's long jab
Brace yourself!
Hands up!
Charge him! Now!
He can't seem to touch the Russian!
Rocky pounding away at the midsection of the Russian!
He hit him with everything he's got!
Drago just smiled at him.
Keep chopping away! Chop him down!
Come on, Rocky
Rocky Balboa is in serious trouble!
They might have to stop this one before somebody gets killed.
Break his rhythm!
Rocky's hurt. He woke the sleeping giant.
Now he's paying the price
A solid hand from Drago sends Rocky Balboa 15 feet across the ring!
And the champ is down!
Rocky, get up!
Hand up
Drago continuing to punish Rocky Balboa!
Hejust will not let him out of that corner!
Rocky Balboa is just trying to get through this first round.
The Russian just threw Balboa into his own corner like a rag doll
A tough first three minutes for Rocky.
He's not only fighting what appears to be an invincible opponenthe's
also fighting a very hostile crowd
The Russian Premier and most of the Politburo are looking on
What's happening out there?
He's winning
I see three of him out there
Get the one in the middle.
Right, hit the one in the middle.
Take his heart. If you hurt him, you'll take his heart
No pain.No pain.
Take his heart
Keep working!
There's the bell for round two. It's been a one-sided fight so far
It will take more than luck for Rocky to survive this round.
Rocky's been hit with bombs.
Slip and hook!
Balboa trying to stay in the middle of the ring against the big Russian
Move the head!
Do you get to do. Stay with him!
No pain!
Rocky!
Balboa goes down again! Bounces right back up!
He's getting killed!
Rocky Balboa has taken Ivan Drago's best punches so far.
He's cut and bleeding,
but he's on his feet and on the run.
He's cut!
He dead!
The Russian's cut! It's a bad cut!
Now it's Rocky Balboa coming after Ivan Drago!
Incredible! Get him!
The Russian wants to go on!
He grabs Balboa by the throat!
Balboa picks up the Russian
and throws him to the ground like a wrestler!
It's a gutter war!
No holds barred in Moscow!
Rocky may be on the receiving end so far,
but he's here to fight!
This is shaping up to be a personal war.
Right now,
it's anybody's boxing match
You're doing good.
I couldn't do better myself
You got him hurt bad.Yeah
Now he's worried. You cut him!
You hurt him! You hurt him!
You see? You see?
He's not a machine! He's a man!
You want it more than he does!
No pain! No pain!
Okay, Take it to him!
A big right hand by Rocky Balboa!
You're doing great.
You've come a long way.
Charge him! Now!
Punch him!
Come on!
A few cheers now for Balboa
Suddenly Moscow is pro Rocky!
No pain.
Keep taking it to him.
Al, this place is ready to explode
Lethal punch after punch!
Amazing willpower!
Neither man backing off
Rocky Balboa's determination
is actually winning over the once-hostile crowd.
This is incredible
What round is it?
Fifteenth. One more round.
There's no stopping us now.
This is our round
No stopping now!
You start, and you don't stop!
All your strength!
All your power! All your love!
Everything you've got!
To win, you have to knock him out!
Punch till you can't punch no more!
This is your whole life here!
Knock him out
Do it now!
There's the bell. The war is on.
This is the last round.
To the end
Which one of these fighters
will be standing at the end of this round?
Drago snaps out a stiff jab
and another
Go on
Rocky taking punishment,
trying to get inside!
He's completely exhausted
Come on, cut him
What are you waiting for?
Hit him!
Come on, fight!
Balboa is chopping the Russian down!
Drago's hard right hand stuns Rocky Balboa
Don't go down!
Don't go down.Go away.
Forget technique. Forget strategy.
This is just a street fight.
It's a question
of who wants it most.
What is he doing? He's winning!
To the body!
Come on!
Rocky
knock his head off!
Rocky, knock his head off!
Come on! Finish him!
Don't stop
You're gonna do it!
Four
Six!
Rocky Balboa has done the impossible
and these people love it!
It is absolute pandemonium!
Thank you
I came here tonight
and I didn't know what to expect
I've seen a lot of people hating me
and I didn't knowwhat to feel about that
so I guess I didn't like you much either
During this fight
I seen a lot of changing
the way you felt about me
and the way I felt about you
In here, there were two guys
killing each other
But I guess that's better than 20 million
What I'm trying to say is
if I can change
and you can change
everybody can change!
I just want to say one thing to my kid
who should be home sleeping. Merry Christmas, kid!
I love you!