2306, please.
Hello, honey.
How you doing?
Good.
What did he say?
Uh-huh. Is he still there?
How long ago did he leave?
Uh-huh. I'm stopping here,
then I got a little meeting,
and then I'll...
I would if I could.
As soon as I can.
Let me get off and I...
let me get off and I prom...
I promise you it'll be okay.
A bunch of bullshit.
Waste a good man's time.
Hi, could I speak
to Dr. Lowenstein, please?
It's rather important.
Could you get him for me?
Bunch of bullshit trying to make
a living on these deadbeat leads.
I swear to God, Shel,
I'm on a sit today...
Hello, Mrs. Swoboda,
this is Dave Moss.
Yeah, we spoke yesterday.
Now on the Rio Rancho Estates,
we've had a situation just come up.
The president of our company
is in town just one day,
- and he has certain parcels...
- Doctor...
well, could you get...
what do you mean?
He's not there?
I have to speak to him.
Yes, it is fairly urgent.
Mr. Levene.
No, I can't be reached.
I'll get back to him.
He has certain parcels...
certain choice parcels
which he's given me
a hold on for the next 48 hours.
What would be the best time to get
you and your husband together?
Say, tonight, at 10:00,
or tomorrow at 8:00?
Okay.
Okay, what would be
the best time to do that?
Look, you sent in the...
no, no, listen to me now...
I've got 48 hours
to make you a lot of money.
Well, when will he be home?
Fine, I'll call you back in 10 minutes.
They don't give you the leads,
they don't give you the support,
- they don't give you dick.
- Yeah.
Then they're yanking us in
on some sales conference.
When's the last time anybody
learned a goddamn thing?
All it does is some jerk
shoots his mouth off.
I swear to God, Shel, I got half a mind
to go across the street.
I got half a mind to go
with you if they'd take me.
You never know... I was talking
to Jerry Graff last week.
I got to call
these deadbeats back.
I can't make a goddamn
dollar with these leads,
and you're killing my ass
on the street.
- I'm sorry you aren't happy here.
- That's cute,
but you're running this office
like a bunch of bullshit.
You're on an override...
you make money, we make money.
- I'd like you to make more money.
- Then don't go waste my time.
- A sales conference?
- The strategy comes from downtown.
Oh, the strategy?
The strategy?
- Well, I think I'll pass.
- I wouldn't.
- Why is that?
- When you come, then you'll see.
- Shelly.
- John.
Are you ready
to do or die tonight?
Oh yeah,
always ready, John.
Always ready, John.
Now, one thing...
we were talking about the leads.
We got some new ones?
That's what we're going
to talk about at the meeting.
We are? Because I'm running
into a bit of a snag.
Yes, I've seen
your sales figures.
That's the leads.
You give me a better lead...
That's what we're going
to be talking about.
I'm in a bind...
personal problems.
- I could use a leg up.
- After the meeting.
- I hear the new Glengarry leads...
- After the meeting, Shel.
- Hey, Ricky.
- Hello, John.
- Wet out there tonight.
- Huh?
- Uh-huh.
- Maybe it'll break the heat.
- Yeah.
Al, give me a quick J&B, huh?
Double.
Cutty, Al.
- They say...
- Huh?
they say it was so hot
downtown this afternoon,
grown men on the street corner
were going up to cops
begging the cops
to shoot them.
They say you should not drink
alcohol when it's so hot.
- Who says that?
- Something I read.
For they say
it dehydrates you.
They say
you should drink water,
but I subscribe to the law
of contrary public opinion.
If everyone thinks one thing,
then I say bet the other way.
Added to which,
you know they're wrong.
That's what I'm saying.
- Slow tonight.
- Oh, yeah.
Well, I guess
everybody's staying home.
If my daughter calls,
anybody calls,
I'm over at the office.
Thanks.
I had a woman
in White Plains on the hook...
five units, Mountain View...
what happens?
She has to check
with her lawyer.
- You let her check with her lawyer?
- What could I do?
- I dunno.
- Shelly.
- Huh?
- Who's the guy?
Couldn't tell you.
I don't like the whole thing,
because all I need is a lead.
- They won't give out...
- Uh-huh.
The rich get richer,
that's the law of the land.
Who belongs
to the BM?
It is 7:30.
So who is that?
And where is
Mr. Roma?
Well, I'm not a leash,
so I don't know, do I?
Let me have
your attention for a moment.
You're talking about what?
You're talking about...
bitching about
that sale you shot,
some son of a bitch
don't want to buy land,
somebody don't want
what you're selling,
some broad you're
trying to screw, so forth.
Let's talk
about something important.
- Are they all here?
- All but one.
I'm going anyway.
Let's talk
about something important.
Put that coffee down.
Coffee's for closers only.
You think
I'm fucking with you?
I am not fucking with you.
I'm here from downtown.
I'm here
from Mitch and Murray.
And I'm here
on a mission of mercy.
- Your name's Levene?
- Yeah.
You call yourself a salesman,
you son of a bitch?
I don't got to listen
to this shit.
You certainly don't, 'cause
the good news is, you're fired.
The bad news is you've got...
all of you've got...
just one week
to regain your jobs,
starting with tonight...
starting with tonight's sit.
Oh, have I got
your attention now?
Good...
'cause we're adding
a little something
to this month's
sales contest.
As you all know, first prize
is a Cadillac Eldorado.
Anybody want to see
second prize?
Second prize is
a set of steak knives.
Third prize is you're fired.
Do you get the picture?
Are you laughing now?
You got leads. Mitch and Murray
paid good money.
Get their names
to sell them.
You can't close
the leads you're given,
you can't close shit,
you are shit!
Hit the bricks, pal, and beat it,
'cause you are going out!
- The leads are weak.
- The leads are weak?
The fucking leads are weak?
You're weak.
I've been
in this business 15 years.
- What's your name?
- Fuck you...
that's my name!
You know why, mister?
Because you drove a Hyundai
to get here tonight,
I drove an $80,000 BMW.
That's my name.
And your name
is "You're wanting."
You can't play in the man's game?
You can't close them?
Then go home and tell your wife
your troubles.
Because only one thing
counts in this life...
get them to sign
on the line which is dotted!
You hear me,
you fucking faggots?
"A-B-C."
A... Always,
B... Be, C... Closing.
Always Be Closing.
"Always Be Closing."
"A-I-D-A."
"Attention, Interest,
Decision, Action."
Attention...
Do I have your attention?
Interest...
Are you interested?
I know you are,
because it's fuck or walk.
You close
or you hit the bricks.
Decision... Have you made
your decision for Christ?
And Action.
"A-I-D-A."
Get out there...
you got the prospects coming in.
You think they came in
to get out of the rain?
A guy don't walk on the lot
lest he wants to buy.
They're sitting out there
waiting to give you their money.
Are you gonna take it?
Are you man enough
to take it?
Crap.
What's the problem, pal?
You... Moss.
You're such a hero,
you're so rich,
how come you're here wasting
your time with a bunch of bums?
You see this watch?
- You see this watch?
- Yeah.
That watch costs
more than your car.
I made $970,000 last year.
How much you make?
You see, pal... that's who I am,
and you're nothing.
Nice guy?
I don't give a shit.
Good father? Fuck you...
go home and play with your kids.
You want to work here...
close!
You think this is abuse?
You think this is abuse,
you cocksucker?
You can't take this, how can you
take the abuse you get on a sit?
You don't like it, leave.
I can go out there tonight...
the materials you got...
make myself $15,000.
Tonight... in two hours!
Can you?
Go and do likewise.
"A-I-D-A."
Get mad, you son of a bitches.
Get mad!
You know what it takes
to sell real estate?
It takes brass balls
to sell real estate.
Go and do likewise,
gents.
The money's out there...
you pick it up, it's yours,
you don't,
I got no sympathy for you.
You want to go out
on those sits tonight and close...
close... it's yours.
Not, you're gonna be
shining my shoes.
And you know
what you'll be saying.
Bunch of losers
sitting around in a bar,
"Oh yeah, I used to be a salesman.
It's a tough racket."
These are the new leads.
These are
the Glengarry leads.
And to you, they're gold.
And you don't get them.
Why?
Because to give them to you
is just throwing them away.
They're for closers.
I'd wish you good luck,
but you wouldn't know what
to do with it if you got it.
And to answer your question, pal...
"Why am I here?"
I came here because
Mitch and Murray asked me to.
They asked me for a favor.
I said, "The real favor...
follow my advice
and fire your fucking ass,
because a loser
is a loser."
Bunch of fucking nonsense...
treat people like that.
The fuck is he going
to get off?
- Mickey Mouse sales conference.
- He didn't mean it.
I'm sure he didn't mean it about
trimming down the sales quota.
Where is Roma?
Where the hell is Mr. Ricky Roma?
All the while we got to sit here,
eat this nonsense?
Hello? Mr. Levene.
How's she doing?
Uh-huh, yeah.
Is she awake?
Oh, the doctor came by.
What did he say?
Uh-huh.
I can't come in tonight.
I think... I know she is.
I know that she is.
I've gotta go out. Will you please
tell her when she wakes?
I've got to go out.
Tell her I'll call her from the road.
Thank you.
Gentlemen,
you heard the man.
What is this in aid of?
- As of tonight...
- What is this? Excuse me.
What it's in aid of
is that Mitch and Murray...
Fuck Mitch and Murray!
I'm doing my job,
I got to put up
with this childishness?
I don't make the rules.
I'm paid to run the office.
You don't like the rules, Dave?
There's the door!
Two lead cards for tonight,
two lead cards for tomorrow.
As you heard,
end of the month,
top salesman on the board
gets the Eldorado.
- Next man down the...
- What about the good leads?
- The leads I've given you.
- But these leads are shit.
They're old...
I've seen that name 100 times.
- The leads are assigned randomly.
- What about the new leads?
The new leads...
the Glengarry leads.
I've got them.
I'm going to hang onto them.
And they'll be
assigned to closers,
based on the sales volume,
first to Roma.
- Where is Roma?
- Don't worry about Roma.
He'll get his leads,
you've got yours.
He's top name on the board,
so he don't have to be here?
That's correct!
And as the hour is waning,
I suggest you... those of you
who are interested
in a continuing job with
this organization, get to work.
That's garbage.
Bullshit.
- Thank you for your attention.
- Bullshit!
How am I supposed to close these?
Look at this.
I've had this guy before.
I've been to his house twice.
I... I can't...
I can't close this stuff.
Shelly, how am I
supposed to...
They're going
to bounce me out of a job.
Hello, Mr. Palermo?
I'm sorry.
Mr. Speice?
Mr. Robert Speice?
Yeah,
this is George Aaronow.
I'm with Rio.
I spoke with your wife earlier.
I'm the vice president of Rio Rancho
Properties in Furman, Arizona.
Yes. I'm calling from the airport,
and consulting my map,
I see that you and your wife
live near the airport.
I have some rather...
rather unusual,
rather good information
on the property...
Hello? Hello, this is
Sheldon Levene.
Please listen closely...
I only have a moment or so.
I can speak only
to a Mrs. Nyborg.
Oh, this is Mrs. Nyborg.
Please listen closely, Mrs. Nyborg.
I'm calling from Consolidated
Properties of Arizona.
Our computer has chosen you
from all of the many thousands
who write in requesting
information on our properties.
Now by federal law,
as you probably know,
the prize must be awarded to you
even if you are not engaged
in our land
development plan.
The only stipulation, of course,
is that you and your husband
must sign at the same time
for the receipt of your prize.
Now, I will be in the area
tonight, possibly tomorrow.
What do you think might be
a convenient time to meet
with both you
and your husband?
Of course I'll hold.
- Bunch of fucking nonsense, huh?
- I can't close them.
- Nobody can close 'em.
- They're old.
They're ancient...
a bunch of fucking nonsense.
Get some jerk
to come in here...
Sometimes I think,
"I wonder if I belong in this business."
Send a guy out there...
no support, no confidence.
Then I say,
"Nobody can close 'em."
- Then I look at Roma.
- Roma... fuck Roma.
Had a freak...
a little run of luck.
The leads are garbage.
Then I say,
"Why give him the good leads?
- He doesn't need 'em."
- You going out?
Yeah. I have to go out.
I can't make a sit.
- Have you tried?
- Yeah. Something's wrong with me.
What is it?
I can't push through.
Get your coat on.
You're coming out with me.
- Something in me.
- Forget it.
- I try, I try.
- I said forget it, come on.
I can't close 'em.
Life.
I swear to God,
you work all your life...
- Forget it, George.
- Roma, so on...
- so gifted.
- Gifted, my ass!
- The guy gets a string of luck.
- No, no, no.
The thing of it is,
money's tight.
When times are tight,
it don't do no good
to throw around,
"Just go out and sell."
Threaten a man all you want,
you can't whip a dead horse.
- Nope.
- All this garbage...
"Sell 10,000,
you win a Cadillac;
you lose, we're gonna fire
your ass"? It's medieval.
- Yes.
- It's wrong.
- Yes it is,
and you know
who's responsible?
- Who?
- You know who it is.
It's Mitch and Murray,
'cause it don't have to be this way.
- No.
- Look at Jerry Graff.
He's clean, he's doing
business for himself,
he's got that list...
with the nurses?
You see? That's thinking.
Why take a 10% sales commission?
Why are we giving the rest away?
What are we giving 90% for?
For nothing.
For some jerk in the office,
telling us, "Get out there and close,
go win a Cadillac."
Graff goes out and buys.
He pays top dollar.
- You see?
- Yes.
For the leads... that's thinking.
Now, he's got the leads,
he goes in business for himself.
That's what? That's thinking.
Who... who's got
a steady job,
a regular job,
a couple of bucks nobody's touched?
Nurses.
Graff goes and buys
a fucking list of nurses. One grand...
he paid two, I'll eat my hat.
4,000 or 5,000 nurses.
- He's going wild.
- He is?
- Yeah, he's doing very well.
- I heard they were running cold.
- The nurses?
- Yeah.
You hear a lot of things.
He's doing very well.
- With River Oaks?
- River Oaks, Brook Farms.
All that shit. Somebody told me...
you know what he's clearing, himself?
- 14, 15 grand a week.
- Himself?
That's what I'm saying.
Why? He's got the leads.
He's got the good leads.
What are we?
We're sitting
in the shit here. Why?
Because we got to go to them
to get them.
90% of our sales we're paying
to the office for the leads.
There's our leads, there's overhead,
phones, a lot of stuff.
What do you need?
A telephone?
Some broad to say, "Good morning"?
Nothing. It's the leads.
The whole thing is the leads,
you understand me?
You can't sell to a void...
you got to get a goddamn person.
You get a lead, you get
a person... I'll go sell 'em.
Otherwise, what do they want
from my life?
Hello, Danny?
Dan, it's Shel Levene.
Yeah, we spoke...
last May I called you.
I was in town from my estate
in Rio Rancho, and...
Arizona.
I wish we could have
gotten together at that time.
Danny, that piece of property I had
for you has increased in value...
Grace, Grace,
what was that figure? $76,000.
Oh, Danny, I wish you could have
been in on it with me.
Look, I'm here overnight...
I have to go home tomorrow,
and I thought, after the interest
you showed on the last trip, that...
Hold it, Grace. Danny,
I know that you're serious,
and because of that, I am going
to shove my appointments around
and make sure...
oh, gee, I wish that...
All right, Danny.
Yeah, all right.
Going out tonight,
Shelly?
What is this bullshit
with the sales promotion?
It isn't bullshit.
It's the way it is.
You're going to fire
the bottom men on the list?
That's the way it is
and I don't make the rules.
- The rules come from downtown.
- I got a problem here, John.
- I'm closing up the office.
- Come have a drink with me.
- I've got to get home.
- Do me the courtesy... five minutes?
I am trying to get home
for two hours.
I got to go home, grab one hour
with my kids, come back here,
see if any of you closed
a contract, take the contract...
- How about one minute?
- What is it?
- I can't close these leads.
- Then move on.
Don't jump! Don't jump out
of your manager bag a second.
It's just two guys talking,
am I right? We're just talking.
You got the new leads.
If you would give me... just hold on.
The Glengarry leads are to be
assigned only to closers.
Hold on a second.
If you give me the good leads...
You blew the last good one
I gave you.
No, no... hold on,
will you?
I did not blow 'em.
One kicked out. One, I closed.
- You didn't close it.
- Would you listen to me?
I closed that cocksucker!
His ex! John, his ex!
I didn't even know he was married.
The judge invalidated it.
Shelly...
What was that job, huh?
Bad luck. That's all it was.
I pray you never find it...
it runs in streaks.
That's what it's doing,
that's all it does... streaks.
I pray that it misses you
and that's all I have to say.
Shit, I've got to eat.
Williamson...
look at the sheets.
Look at the sheets.
1987, '88, '89...
six months in '89... who's on top?
- Roma.
- Under him?
- Moss.
- Oh, bullshit, John!
April to September it's me...
it's no fucking Moss.
Due respect,
he's an order-taker.
Talk... talks a good game,
but look on the board, it's me.
- Not lately it isn't.
- Not late...
Well, lately...
kiss my ass "lately."
You call Murray and you call Mitch...
when we were on Peterson,
who do you think bought the new car?
Call Mitch. The Seville?
He came in here...
"You bought that for me, fella."
And out of what? Hey, look at me!
Out of what? Nothing!
Cold calling.
You want to talk about a sale?
You are really
beginning to burn my ass, kid.
I can't get a lead, you...
it was skill, John.
It could be working for you...
you want to throw it away.
- It isn't me.
- It's not you...
I wonder who it is.
Who the fuck am I talking to?
- I need the leads to sell.
- After the contest. After the 30th.
Bullshit,
"After the contest."
If I'm not on that board by the 30th,
they're going to can my ass.
I need those leads
and I need 'em now or I'm out.
You're going to miss me.
I swear to you, you will miss me.
Let me tell you
something, Shelly.
I do what I'm hired to do...
you might do the same.
- Jesus.
- Now wait a second!
I'm hired to watch the leads,
to marshal my sales force.
I'm given a policy.
My job is to do that.
Marshal your sales force?
Anybody falls below
a certain mark, I'm directed.
I'm not permitted
to give them the premium leads.
How do they rise
above that mark? With dreck?
With this toilet paper
you're giving me?
You give me
one premium lead...
Do you know what
the premium leads cost?
Do I know what
Yeah,
I know what they cost.
I generated the sufficient
dollar revenue to buy them.
But I cannot sell shit!
Jesus. And I've seen
these before, you know.
Christ, I saw these back...
Homestead...
1985, we pitched
these cocksuckers Baywater.
They couldn't buy a fucking toaster.
They're broke. They're deadbeats.
Just give me some leads that don't
come out of a phone book.
You give me something hotter
than that and I can close it.
It's just a streak.
I'm gonna turn it around.
Hey, I need your help.
I can't do it,
Shelly.
John...
I'll give you 10%.
- Of what?
- My end... what I close.
You give me the premium leads,
you're in for 10%, what I close.
- And what if you don't close?
- I will.
- What if you don't close?
- I will close.
What if you don't,
you understand?
Then I'm fucked. You think you're
the only guy with a family?
- You see what I'm saying?
- John...
I step out and you don't close,
then it's my job.
- Then I'm fucked.
- I will close!
Now, 10% John...
I can get hot, you know that.
- Not lately you can't.
- That's defeatist... fuck it!
Go with me. Get on my side
and let's do something.
You want to run this office?
You heard what the man said...
"Attack."
Let's do something.
- Huh?
- 20%.
- All right.
- And 50 bucks a lead.
- No?
- Oh!
Oh, shit.
Listen...
I got to talk to you.
Permit me to do this a second.
I'm older than you.
A man acquires a reputation
on the street.
What he does when he's up,
what he does at other times...
I said, "10," you said, "No."
You said, "20," I said, "Fine."
Now you want to throw
this 50-buck thing in.
John, a good deal... has got to be
one where both parties...
Okay, okay, okay, fine...
20%, 50 bucks a lead. It's done.
Let's go out.
We make some money.
I got bills to pay.
I want two sits tonight
and I want the good leads...
the Glengarry leads... two.
Two, John, because
I am going to close 'em both.
It's a long road
with no turning, pally.
Huh? Okay.
Now, let's go.
I've got to go back
to the office to get 'em.
Go on, let's go.
This is what I was saying, John.
All you need, a little boost,
you turn a streak around.
Am I right? Good, huh?
Huh, good?
What?
- What?
- Two leads, 100 bucks.
- Now?
- Now, yes. When?
- Shit, John.
- I wish I could.
You fucking asshole.
I don't have it...
I don't...
I'll bring it in the office
in the morning.
- I'll be coming with the sales.
- Nope.
I can't fucking
believe this.
All right, here's...
20... 30, and...
Jesus, here's the 30.
I'll bring the rest in tomorrow.
We got to do this, huh, pal?
For Christ's sake!
No.
- My daughter...
- I can't do it, Shelly.
I got to tell you something.
It wasn't so long ago,
I'd pick up the phone
and call Murray... I got your job.
"Murray, the kid is burning my ass."
"Shelly, he's gone."
You are gone before
I'm back from lunch.
Bought him a trip
to Bermuda once.
- I've got to go.
- All right, hey.
Give me... I'll take two more
of the old leads.
- I gave you two today.
- One is a bust-out, John!
- The other ain't home!
- Shelly...
I promise you,
I've been on the phone... I know.
No more leads today...
two per day. You've got yours.
All right.
- All right?
- Sure.
We will do that...
other thing.
I guess I left
my wallet in my room.
Deadbeats.
Deadbeats, all of 'em.
My mistake.
I shouldn't have took the leads.
- You had to.
- Yeah? Why?
- To get on the...
- To get on the board, yeah.
How am I gonna get on the board
trying to sell a doctor?
Two regular,
two chocolate donuts.
Give me the same thing to go.
And don't try and sell an Indian.
I will never try to sell
an Indian.
These names come up...
you ever get 'em..."Patel"?
- You ever get 'em?
- I think I had one once.
You had one,
you'd know it..."Patel."
They keep coming up.
I don't know.
They like to talk to salesmen.
They're lonely.
They like to feel superior...
never bought a fucking thing.
I don't know.
Come down the line...
doctors, lawyers, Indians...
times are tight. It's tight.
Pressure's just too great.
Man can't work all of 'em.
You go in the door... I got to close
this fucker or I don't eat lunch,
or I don't win a Cadillac.
We work too hard, George.
Remember when we were... when we
were selling Glen Ross Farms?
Didn't we sell
a bunch of that?
- They came in...
- They fucked it up.
- They did.
- They killed the goose. And now...
- We're stuck with this...
- Stuck with this fucking shit.
- This shit.
- It's too...
- It is.
- You get a bad month...
they put you on this board.
Some contest board.
- It's not right.
- It's not right to the customers.
I know, it's... hey. What did I learn
as a kid on Western?
Don't sell a guy one car.
Sell him five cars over 15 years.
- That's right.
- You're goddamn right, it's right.
Guys come in..."Oh, the blah,
blah, blah. I know what I'll do.
I'll go out and rob everybody
blind and go to Argentina
'cause nobody ever
thought of this before."
So they kill the goose
and the man's worked all his life...
- That's right.
- He's got to cower in his boots...
Boots, yes...
For some fucking "Sell 10,000,
win the steak knives."
- What do you do?
- What can you do?
What can you do
if you don't have the leads?
If you do not
have the goddamn leads!
Mr. Spannel?
Sheldon Levene.
I was speaking
to your wife earlier?
Come in.
- "Cats and dogs," huh?
- Yeah.
Oh, "cats and dogs."
Oh, I see you're
interested in fishing.
- Yeah.
- I've fished myself... many years.
Muskee, Wisconsin.
Ooh, a beauty.
- Where's the missus?
- Out at the PTA.
- Ahh.
- What was this in reference?
I spoke to your wife
earlier on the phone.
I called, I'm in town
with Rio Rancho.
Yes, I'm sorry. She said you had
some sort of award?
Yes, I was speaking to the people
in my sales organization...
my representatives in this area...
and Mr. Spannel...
your name is Larry.
Mind if I call you Larry?
All right, Larry.
We had a consultant,
and he made me...
he made me an offer.
He offered me $230,000
to promote a sales plan...
to present investment opportunities
in Rio Rancho to the public.
Well, I said, "Hell,
let me save you the 230,
and pass the savings
along to the investor."
My people immediately said,
"Whoa, how do you do that?
How can you present
investment opportunities
without television,
without magazine ads?"
I said, "You take
something this good,
you go to a man...
has invested in the past...
you go to him direct and offer
the money to him... rebate.
And don't give it
to this expert."
So you're here
to sell me some land?
No, I wouldn't try
to sell you...
I leave that to the salesmen
and people who want to own land.
I think something
has to be fed,
watered and painted,
but don't invest in it.
That motto has stood me
in good stead.
- Mister...
- Just call me Shelly.
I have never
been afraid of familiarity.
I'm walking out the door.
I've got to pick up my wife at the...
Let's take my car.
We'll pick her up together.
Spoke to the little woman
on the phone... can't wait to meet her.
No, we're going
over to our relatives'.
- She didn't say anything about that.
- I'm sure she forgot.
- I'm on a plane to Florida...
- I'm sorry if we put you out.
You didn't put me out.
I'm just trying to think, Larry.
You know, that's the only parcel
that I've got.
You know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna go back to the computer,
I'm gonna pull another one, and we're
gonna speak to your relatives, too.
- No, no, no.
- C'mon, you're a busy man, so am I.
My God, I'm in the act
of giving a gift away.
Look, I don't want to buy land.
I don't want to invest in land.
I have nothing. She took the call
without my knowledge.
I have no business
that I wish to transact.
I don't want to tell you
how to handle your wife.
My wife filled in a form, and we
have been plagued for the last year...
That's the situation
I'm trying to alleviate, Larry.
No, no.
Do you understand?
Thank you. No.
- Roma, man... he don't care.
- He don't care.
He's sitting on top of the world.
He's got good leads, good prospects.
- Sales, sales.
- Sales contests.
- That's what I'm saying.
- Times turn hard, they bounce you out.
If they bounce you with no
confidence...
That's what I'm saying.
That's what I'm saying to you.
If they get you
on a bad beat...
and you got to go out there,
get a new job...
- With no...
- With no confidence...
Yes.
I'll tell you what the hard part is...
to stop thinking like a goddamn slave.
You say the Nazis
in Europe...
"If they came in my door"...
bullshit, the time is now.
What do you do now?
Some guy pissing in your face.
Cocksucker...
wants to break your rice bowl.
Mitch and Murray, fuck you.
What I say... fuck you!
Sitting on the good leads.
George, we're men here.
Yes.
And I'll tell you...
I'll tell you what the hard part is.
- What?
- Starting up.
Standing up.
Breaking free of this bullshit,
this enslavement to some guy,
'cause he's got the upper hand.
This is the difference...
listen to me, George.
Now Jerry Graff went
into business for himself.
He said, "I'm going on my own."
And he was free, you understand me?
I'll tell you... I'll tell you
what somebody should do.
What?
Somebody should stand up
and strike back.
Somebody should do something
to them.
- What?
- Something to pay them back.
Someone should hurt them,
Mitch and Murray.
- Somebody should hurt them?
- Yeah.
- How?
- Someone should do something
- to hurt them where they live.
- What?
Someone should rob the office.
That's what I'm saying.
If we were that kind of guy
to hold up the joint and trash it,
it looks like robbery,
we take the leads out of the files
and we go to Jerry Graff.
And we take the fucking
Glengarry leads! Huh?
Yeah, Mr. Nyborg? Ah, Mr. Nyborg,
Sheldon Levene.
I was speaking to your wife earlier.
That's right.
I'd like to speak to you
about awarding you your prize.
We're coming to the end
of our fiscal year,
I'd really like to get it
off the books before...
yes, the prize
for Consolidated Properties.
The information you requested
on Rio Rancho.
Now, I'm in town only for...
well, let me see.
I suppose I could
swing by tonight. Yes. Uh-huh.
When do you think
it might be more convenient?
As I said,
I could swing by tonight...
well, of course,
you speak to your wife.
Grace, I'm gonna need
a first-class seat,
passport, 10,000 in cash,
put that with the negotiable
papers, if you would.
And put me
on the telex hookup... yes?
Well, when do you think
Mrs. Nyborg might be back?
All train compartments
smell vaguely of shit.
It gets so you don't
mind it.
That's the worst thing
that I can confess.
You know how long it took me
to get there? A long time.
When you die you're gonna regret
the things you don't do.
You think you're queer?
I'm gonna tell you something.
We're all queer.
You think you're a thief? So what?
You get befuddled
by a middle-class morality?
Get shut of it.
Shut it out.
You cheat on your wife,
you did it. Live with it.
You fuck little girls,
so be it.
There's an absolute morality?
Maybe.
And then what?
If you think there is,
go ahead, be that thing.
Bad people go to hell?
I don't think so.
You think that,
act that way.
A hell exists on earth?
Yes. I won't live in it.
That's me.
Did you ever take a dump, made you
feel like you slept for 12 hours?
- Did I?
- Yes.
- I don't know.
- Or a piss?
Great meals fade
in reflection.
Everything else gains.
Do you know why?
'Cause it's only food.
This shit we put in us,
keeps us going...
it's only food.
The great fucks
you may have had,
what do you remember
about them?
- What do I remember?
- Yeah.
I don't know.
For me,
I'm saying what it is,
it's probably not the orgasm.
Some broad's forearm
on your neck,
something her eyes did.
There was this sound she made.
Or it's me in the...
I'm telling you...
I'm in bed the next day,
she brought me caf au lait,
gives me a cigarette,
my balls feel like concrete.
Eh?
What I'm saying,
what is our life?
Our life is looking forward
or it's looking back.
That's it.
That's our life.
Where's the moment?
And what is it
we're so afraid of?
Loss. What else?
The bank closes, we get sick,
my wife died on a plane?
The stock market collapsed?
What of these things happen?
None of them.
We worry anyway. Why?
What could we get
for them?
- For them?
- For the leads.
What could we get
for the leads?
I don't know. 10 bucks a throw.
15 maybe. I don't know.
For the leads, you're saying?
Say somebody took them,
- went to Jerry Graff?
- Yeah. How many leads do we have?
The Glengarry?
The premium leads?
I've got to think they've got 500.
Say 500 leads.
You're saying a fella could take
those leads and sell them to Graff?
The leads to Graff.
Yes. I was saying... yeah.
A guy could take...
like anything else, it seems to me,
that is negotiable,
a guy could sell them.
- How do you know he'd buy them?
- Because I worked for him.
- You didn't talk to him?
- No. What do you mean?
- Did I talk to him about this?
- Yeah.
Are you just talking about this,
or are we just talking about it?
- Just speaking about it.
- Speaking about it as an idea?
- Yes.
- We're not actually talking about it.
- No.
- Talking about it as a robbery.
As a robbery? No.
- Well...
- Hey.
So all this...
you didn't actually call Graff?
- You didn't talk to him?
- Not actually, no.
- You didn't?
- No, not actually.
- Did you?
- What did I say?
- What did you say?
- I said, "Not actually."
Fuck you care, George?
We're just talking.
- We are?
- Yes.
- Because it's a crime.
- Robbery. That's right.
It is a crime.
- It's also very safe.
- You're actually talking about this.
- That's right.
- You're going to steal the leads.
- Have I said that?
- Are you?
- Did I say that?
- Did you talk to Graff?
- What did I say?
- What did he say?
What did he say?
He'd buy them.
You're gonna steal...
you're gonna steal the Glengarry
leads and sell them to Graff?
- Yes.
- What's he gonna pay?
He figures there's 500 leads,
let's say 10 bucks apiece,
- that's $2,500 each.
- Each?
- "Each"?
- That's right, George.
- You're saying me?
- No, you and me.
Yeah. That's exactly
what I'm saying. $2,500 apiece.
You and me for one night's work,
and a job with Graff
- working the premium leads.
- A job with Graff?
- Is that what I said?
- He'd give me a job?
He could take you on.
Yes.
Hello?
I was dialing the direct line
to my daughter's room.
Sheldon Levene.
She's in...
well, yeah, I'm sure she's asleep.
But... where's the duty nurse?
They canceled her...
well, let me talk...
who am I speaking to?
I'll have the money there
tomorrow.
It's a big decision,
George.
At times a guy
has got to make one.
It's a big decision
and it's a big reward.
$2,500 and a job, it's a big reward
for one night's work.
Yes.
Sometimes a guy...
sometimes, a man
if he wants a reward...
That's absolutely right.
He'll do one thing,
one thing on one night.
That's absolutely right.
The thing is, it's got to be tonight.
What?
What, what?
The leads ain't going to leave?
They bring those leads up,
wave them under your nose,
tomorrow they take them downtown,
parcel them out.
A guy wants those leads,
he's gonna have to get them tonight.
Tonight is the thing.
Talk about a chance.
It's when a chance
presents itself.
You got to go
in there tonight.
- You.
- I'm sorry?
- Me?
You have to go in.
You have to get the leads.
- I do?
- It's not something for nothing.
I took you in on this.
You have to go. It's your thing.
I've made a deal with Graff.
I can't go in.
I've spoken out on this too much.
I've got a big mouth.
"The fucking leads," et cetera,
"the tight-ass company," blah, blah.
- They'll know when you go to Graff.
- What will they know?
That I stole the leads?
I didn't steal the leads.
I'm gonna go to the movies.
Then I'm gonna have a late drink
- at the Como Inn with a friend.
- Dave.
Yes?
You want me to break into the office
tonight and steal the leads?
- Yes.
- No.
- Oh, yes, George.
- What does that mean?
Listen to this. I have an alibi.
I'm going to the Como Inn.
Why? Why?
The place gets robbed,
they're going to come looking for me.
Why? Because I probably did it.
Let me ask you this...
are you going to turn me in?
What if you don't get caught?
They come to you,
are you going to turn me in?
- Why would they come to me?
- They're going to come to everybody.
- Why would I do it?
- You wouldn't, George.
That's why I'm talking to you now.
They come to you,
- are you going to turn me in?
- No.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
Uh-huh. George...
when they come to me,
if I have to go in there,
and if I get caught...
- they come to me...
- You don't have to go in.
I have to go in, see?
That's something I have to do.
- Why?
Are you going to give me $7,500?
75? I thought we were
splitting five grand.
I lied, all right? Your end is 25,
my end is my own concern.
Now, stick with me here.
If they come to me,
I'm caught, they're going to ask me
who were accomplices.
- Me.
- Absolutely.
That's ridiculous.
To the law, you're
an accessory before the fact.
- I didn't ask to be.
- Tough luck, because you are.
- Because you told me about it?
- That's right.
Why are you doing this
to me, Dave?
Why are you talking this way to me?
I don't understand.
- Why are you doing this at all?
- None of your fucking business.
Just in or out?
You tell me.
You're out,
you take the consequences.
- I do?
- That's right.
- And why is that?
- Because you listened.
Well, when will
Mrs. Nyborg be back?
You know, I hate to keep
calling you this late, Bruce,
but I feel a responsibility,
I must say. When you have...
You know, they say,
"You don't buy it, you rent it."
- Huh?
- The thing.
You really...
what do you keep?
I mean, you don't keep
anything, really.
- No.
- Security.
Things. Things.
- You know?
- Mm-hmm.
It's just... you try
to stave off insecurity.
You can't do it.
- No.
- No. That's what I'm telling you.
Stocks, bonds, objects of art,
real estate, what are they?
An opportunity.
To what? To make money?
Perhaps. To lose money?
Perhaps.
To indulge and to learn
about ourselves? Perhaps.
So fucking what?
What is it? They're an opportunity.
That's all they are.
They're an event.
A guy comes to you,
you make a call. You send in a card,
I have these properties
I would like for you to see.
What does this mean?
What do you want it to mean?
You see what I'm saying?
Things happen to you.
Glad I met you.
I'm glad I met you,
James.
I want to show you
something.
It may mean something to you,
it may not.
I don't know.
I don't know anymore.
What is that?
Florida.
Glengarry Highlands.
Bullshit.
And maybe that's true.
And that's what I said.
But look at this.
What is this?
This is a piece of land.
Listen to what I'm going
to tell you now.
- What happened?
- Where do you work?
I work, yes.
I work here.
- What is it? What happened?
- Robbery.
Williamson. Williamson,
did they get the contracts?
All right, tell me.
Now. Tell me.
- They stole the contracts?
- Excuse me, sir.
- Did they get my contract?
- Excuse me, fella.
- Did they?
- Would you excuse us?
Don't fuck with me, fella.
I'm talking about a Cadillac car
- that you owe me.
- They didn't get your contract.
- I filed it before I left.
- They didn't get my contracts?
They got... excuse me.
Fuck.
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Williamson!
- Williamson, open the fucking door.
- Who are you?
- They didn't get the contracts.
- Did they?
They got... listen to me.
They got some of them.
- Some of them?
- Who told you?
Who told me?
Who told me we had a robbery?
We got a fucking board
up on the window.
Who is this? Yes.
Yes, I confess. I did it.
Now, leave me
a second here, please.
- Okay, now, talk to me.
- I'm still trying to sort it out.
- So far...
- Talk to me. Talk to me.
They got some
of the contracts?
Lingk. James Lingk,
which I closed last night.
- You closed it last night?
- Yes.
- I filed it. It went down.
- You filed it?
- James Lingk?
- Yes.
- It was sent downtown?
- Yes, all right?
I filed it last night.
It went to the bank.
- It went downtown, all right?
- You filed it?
Then I'm over the fucking top,
you owe me a Cadillac.
- I don't...
- I don't want to hear any shit.
I don't give a shit.
Lingk puts me over the top.
You filed it. It went downtown.
Now you owe me the car.
- The robbery makes difficult...
- Fuck you! You owe me the car!
See, 'cause this is how
we keep score, "bubby."
You told me, "Close thus,
and so you get the car."
- I got it.
- Would you excuse us, please?
You hear what I said?
Do you hear what I said?
Hey, pal!
Your excuses are your own!
"Recontact James Lingk.
6:00 P.M. Morton Grove."
Ah-ha.
When do you expect
her in?
This is Ricky Roma
from last night.
She'll remember.
Just, just... wait a minute!
Just to say... to thank her
for a wonderful time.
Thank you.
I'll call back later. Thank you.
They should check
if we're insured.
Uh-huh.
"10:00 P.M., Octavia."
Please don't leave.
I'm going to talk to you.
- What's your name?
- Are you talking to me?
- That's right.
- My name is Richard Roma.
I... you know,
they should be insured.
- What do you care?
- Then they wouldn't be so upset.
- Huh?
- They wouldn't be so upset.
- Mitch and Murray.
- Yeah, you're right.
That's right.
How are you?
I'm fine.
You mean the board?
You mean on the board?
Yes. Okay.
The board.
I'm fucked on the board.
I can't...
My mind must be other places,
'cause I can't...
What?
You can't do what?
- I can't close them.
- Well, they're old.
Look, look at this shit
they're giving you. Huh?
- Yes, they are old.
- They're ancient.
"Clear Meadows."
This shit's dead.
- It is dead.
- Waste of time.
- Yes. I'm no fucking good.
- Hey, fuck that shit, George.
You had a bad month.
You're a good man.
- I am?
- Yeah, you had a bad streak.
Look at this. 15 units, Mountain View,
the fucking things get stolen.
- He said he filed...
- He filed the big one.
He filed the guy from the bar
that I closed last night.
All the little ones,
I got to go back.
Can you believe this?
I got to go back and close again.
I mean, talk about
a fucking beat
that would sap anyone's... wait,
wait, wait. Where are the phones?
- They stole...
- They stole?
- What kind of an outfit is it...
- They stole the phones.
...when criminals come and they take...
they steal the phones?
They stole the leads.
They stole the phones,
they stole... aw, Christ.
What am I going
to do this month? Shit.
You think they're going to catch...
where are you going?
Down the street.
- Where are you going?
- To the... what do you fucking care?
- Aren't you going out today?
- With what, John? With what?
Well, answer me.
They stole the Glengarry leads.
- They stole Rio Rancho.
- I have stuff from last year's file.
Oh, oh, oh.
Your "nostalgia" file.
Oh, great. That's great,
'cause I don't...
- Do you want to go out today?
- I don't have to eat this month.
Great.
Give them to me.
Bring them.
Come on.
Fucking Mitch and Murray
are going to shit a...
What am I going
to do all month?
See, the thing
of it is,
is were the leads insured?
You think?
- What?
- Were the leads insured?
I don't know, why?
'Cause if they weren't,
I know Mitch and Murray...
- What?
- They'll be upset.
That's right.
You're right.
He said we're all going
to have to talk to the guy.
- To...
- The cop.
Great. We have to talk
to the cop.
- Another waste of time.
- A waste of time? Why?
Why? 'Cause they're not going
to find the guy.
- The cops?
- Yes, the cops. No.
The cops aren't going
to find the guy?
- Nope.
- Why do you think so?
Why? Because they are stupid.
Where were you last night?
- Where were you?
- Where was I?
- Yeah.
- I was at home.
- Where were you?
- At home.
See? Were you the guy
who broke in?
- Was I?
- Yes.
- No.
- Then don't sweat it. You know why?
- You have nothing to hide.
- When I talk to police, I get nervous.
- Yes, you know who doesn't?
- No. Who?
- Thieves.
I don't know
what I'm going to tell them.
The truth.
Always tell them the truth.
It's the easiest thing
to remember.
Whoa, whoa!
"Patel"?
"Ravidam Patel"?
How am I going to make a living
on these deadbeats?
- Where did you get this from, a morgue?
- Look, I'm...
Come on. What's the point?
What's the fucking point?
I got to argue with you,
I got to knock heads with the cops,
I'm busting my balls
to sell your dirt
to deadbeats...
money in the mattress.
I come back, you can't even
keep the contracts safe.
I got to go out...
fuck this shit.
I'm going to go out
and re-close last week's stuff.
No, the word from Murray
is leave them alone.
If he needs a new sig,
he'll go out himself.
- Murray's gonna go out?
- He'll be "president of the company
just in from out of town,"
all right?
Okay, okay, okay.
Give me this shit.
- I'm giving you three leads.
- Three? I count two.
- There's three leads there.
- Patel? Fuck you.
Fucking Shiva handed
this guy a million dollars,
told him, "Sign the deal,"
he wouldn't sign.
And the god Vishnu, too,
into the bargain. Fuck you.
You know your business, I know mine.
Your business is being an asshole.
If I find out whose fucking cousin
you are, I'm gonna go to him
and figure out a way
to have your ass... fuck you!
I'm waiting
for the new leads.
Get the chalk!
Hey! Get the chalk!
Get the...
I did it... I closed 'em.
I closed the cocksucker.
Get the chalk.
Put me on the board, John.
Put me on the Cadillac board!
Williamson,
pick up the fucking chalk.
- Rick... eight units, Mountain View.
- You sold eight Mountain View?
You bet your ass!
Who wants to go to lunch?
Who wants to go to lunch...
I'm buying.
Williamson... $82,000,
12 grand in my commission.
On deadbeat
magazine subscription leads.
- Who?
- Bruce and Harriett Nyborg.
Read it.
What the hell happened here?
Fuck! I had them
on River Glen.
- What happened?
- Somebody broke in.
- Eight units!
- Yeah.
- Shelly!
- Big deal... I broke a bad streak.
Shelly "The Machine" Levene.
That's great.
Thank you, George.
Hey...
- grab the phone, call Mitch.
- They took the phones.
- Huh?
- Aaronow?
They took the leads,
the cash, the contracts.
- We had a robbery.
- When?
- Last night, this morning.
- They took the leads?
Fucking asshole.
What? They beat you
with a rubber bat?
Cop couldn't find his dick
with two hands and a map.
Anybody who talks to this asshole
is a fucking asshole.
- You gonna turn state's?
- Fuck you, Ricky.
I ain't going out today.
I'm going home.
I'm going home because nothing's
accomplished here.
- Anybody talks to this guy...
- Guess what "The Machine" did.
- Fuck "The Machine."
- Mountain View, eight units.
Cop's got no right to talk to me
that way. I did not rob the place.
- Did you hear what I said?
- Yeah, he closed the deal.
Eight units,
Mountain View.
- You did that?
- Yeah.
- Fuck you.
- Guess who?
- When?
- Just now.
- Guess who?
- You just... this morning?
Harriett
and blah blah Nyborg.
- You did that?
- Yeah... $82,000.
- Those fucking deadbeats.
- My ass. I told 'em... listen to this.
- I don't want to hear your war stories.
- Fuck you, Dave.
I said, "You have to believe
in yourself."
Give me a lead.
I'm going out. I'm getting out.
- Fuck the leads. I'm going home.
- "Fuck me, Bruce.
- You have to believe in yourself."
- We haven't got a lead.
- Why not?
- They took 'em.
They're fucking garbage, any case.
The whole goddamn...
"You look around, you say,
'This one has so-and-so. I got nothing.
But why? Why don't I get
the opportunities?"'
- Did they steal the contracts?
- What the fuck do you care?
What the fuck
is that supposed to mean?
Will you shut up?
I'm telling him something.
Could we get
some coffee?
- How are you doing?
- Fine.
Uh-huh.
Anybody's going out,
I could use some coffee.
- "You do get the opportunity."
- Fuck is that supposed to mean?
"You do get the opportunities.
You get 'em as I get 'em,
- as everybody gets 'em."
- I don't care they stole the contracts?
I got 'em in the kitchen,
eating their crumb cake...
- What does that mean?
- It means, Dave,
You haven't closed
a good one in a month.
None of my business,
you want to push me to answer you.
So you haven't got a contract
to get stolen and so forth.
You got a mean streak in you.
Shut the fuck up!
Ricky, you got a mean streak in you,
and what are you babbling about?
You bring that shit up...
on my volume?
If you were on a bad one and I
brought it up to you, you'd harbor it.
You'd harbor it a long while
and you'd be right.
- Who said "Fuck 'The Machine"'?
- Fuck "The Machine"?
Fuck "The Machine"?
Fuck "The Machine"!
What is this, courtesy class?
You're fucked, Rick.
Are you fucking nuts?
You're hot, so you think
- you're the ruler of this place.
- Wait a minute, Dave.
- Shut up!
- Okay...
You want to decide who
should be dealt with how, is that it?
I come into the office today,
I get humiliated by some jag-off cop.
I get accused of...
I get shit thrown in my face because
you're top name on the board?
Is that what I did, Dave...
I humiliated you?
- Oh, my God, I'm sorry.
- Sitting on top of the world.
Sitting on top of the world...
everything's fucking peach fuzz.
I don't get a moment to spare
for some bust-out humanitarian
- down on his luck lately?
- Fuck you!
Fuck you, Dave...
you know you got a big mouth.
You make a close, this whole place
stinks with your farts for a week...
how much you just ingested.
Oh, what a big man you are!
"Let me buy you a pack of gum...
I'll show you how to chew it."
Your pal closes, and all that comes
out of your mouth is bile.
How fucked-up you are!
Who's my pal, Ricky? Hmm?
And what are you?
What are you, huh,
Bishop Sheen?
What the fuck are you,
"Mr. Slick"?
"Friend to the working man"?
Big deal!
Fuck you!
You got the memory
of a fucking fly!
I never liked you,
anyway.
What is this,
your farewell speech?
- I'm going home.
- Your farewell to the troops?
I'm not going home.
I'm going to Wisconsin.
- Have a good trip.
- Aw, fuck you!
Fuck the lot of you!
Fuck you all!
You were saying?
Huh?
Come on.
Come on... you got 'em
in the kitchen,
you're in
your shirtsleeves,
you got
the stats spread out,
you can smell it.
Come on, snap out of it.
- You're eating her crumb cake.
- Oh yeah, I'm eating her crumb cake.
- How was it?
- From the store.
- Fuck her.
- "Bruce, Harriett...
we have to admit to ourselves
that we see that opportunity
and take it... and that's it."
Now, we just sit there.
- I got my pen out.
- "Always Be Closing."
God, that's what
I've been saying... the old ways.
Convert that motherfucker,
sell him, make him sign the check.
They got their money
in government bonds...
I said, "Fuck it... let's go
all the way, the whole route."
I take it and plat it out... eight units,
82 grand, and I say to them,
"This is now. This is that thing
that you have been dreaming of.
You are going to find
the suitcase on the train.
The man walks in the room,
that bag is filled with money.
Harriett, this is it, and Bruce...
I don't want to fuck around with you.
No, I don't. I don't want
to pussyfoot around.
You think you got to look back
on this thing? I do, too.
Now, I'm here to do good
for you and me... the both of us.
What is the point
of some interim position?
The only arrangement
I will accept is full investment.
And I mean it, that's it...
all eight units. Period."
Now I got the pen
in my hand, Rick... hey.
I turned that contract around...
that's eight units, 82 grand...
and I said,
"I want you to sign."
I sat there five minutes.
Then I sat 22 minutes
by that kitchen clock on the wall.
Ricky... not a word,
not a motion.
And what am I thinking?
"Is my arm getting tired?"
No. I did it.
Just like the old days,
like I used to,
like I was taught.
- I did it.
- Like you taught me.
Nobody ever...
well, if I did, I'm glad.
No, what I did...
I locked on 'em.
I locked all on them...
nothing on me... on them.
And, oh God, I am holding
my last thought,
"Now is the time."
They signed.
It was great.
It was so fucking great.
It was like
they wilted all at once.
- Mmm.
- No gesture, nothing... just together.
Honest to God, they both
imperceptibly slumped.
And then he reached
and he took the pen and he signed,
passed it to her
and she signed.
It was solemn...
fucking solemn.
I let it sit, and then I nodded.
I said, "Harriett, Bruce,"
then I pointed into the living room
to the sideboard.
I didn't know there was
a sideboard in there.
He went over,
he brought us back a drink...
little shot glasses
with a pretty design in 'em.
And we just toasted
in silence.
Great sale, Shelly.
Great.
Fuck! Send me out!
Give me leads!
- Williamson! Send me out!
- Whoa!
- The leads are coming.
- Get 'em to me.
I talked to Mitch and Murray
an hour ago. They're coming in.
- They're a bit upset over this.
- Did you tell 'em my sale?
How could I tell 'em your sale?
I didn't have a tele...
I'll tell 'em your sale
when they bring in the leads.
We had a little... you closed the deal,
you made a good sale. Fine.
- Better than a good sale.
- I have a lot of things on my mind.
They're coming and they're very upset.
I'm trying to make...
All I'm telling you is, you can tell
them it was a remarkably good sale.
The only thing remarkable
about it is who you made it to.
- What the fuck does that mean?
- If the sale sticks it'll be a miracle.
"If the sale sticks"?
Why shouldn't the sale stick?
Oh, fuck you!
You do not know your job.
Do you know that?
A man is his job!
You are fucked at yours.
You hear what I'm saying to you?
Your "End of the Month"
fucking boar...
you do not know how
to run this office.
You haven't got the sense.
You haven't got the balls.
Have you ever been on a sit?
Has this cocksucker been on a sit?
- Did you ever sit...
- If I were you, I would calm down.
Would you?
What are you gonna do, fire me?
Oh, oh, Rick, ooh.
- It's not impossible.
- Really? On an $80,000 day?
- It's not even noon yet.
- You closed 'em today?
I got up early this morning,
tracked 'em down, and closed it.
What I'm saying to you
is that things change.
That's where you fuck up.
You don't know. You can't look back.
You don't see who's coming.
Maybe it's someone new, huh?
Maybe it's someone else,
but you don't know...
you can't look back, because
you don't know your history!
When we were on Rio Rancho,
who was the top man, huh?
For what,
two months, three months?
How about eight months,
for three years in a row!
Luck... was that it, John?
Or purloined fucking leads?
- It was talent!
- Yes.
Door to door.
It's called "cold calling," John.
Shit, I don't even know their name.
They don't want to buy what I've got.
Soft sell... we were doing it
before we had a name for it.
- Am I right?
- You're right, you're right.
You wouldn't know, you cock...
he doesn't even know what a streak is.
What the hell are you?
You're a fucking secretary.
Fuck you!
That's my message to you...
fuck you, and kiss my ass.
If you don't like that, I go across
the street and speak to Jerry Graff.
Period. Fuck you.
Listen to me... you put me
on that fucking board,
and I want three
promising leads for today,
I don't want any bullshit,
and I want 'em close together,
because I am
going to close them all.
And that's all I have
to say to you.
He's right, Williamson.
I'm sorry, but it's wrong,
and you know whose fault it is?
Mitch and Murray.
To hell with him.
Let's get some lunch, huh, Rick?
The leads won't be
up here till later anyway.
You're a client. I just sold you
five waterfront Glengarry Farms.
I do this with my hair,
throw me the cue "Kenilworth."
- Which is it?
- Kenilworth.
I own the property.
My mother owns the property.
I put her into it.
You look on the plats
when you go home. You'll see...
A-3 through 10,
26 through 30.
- Take your time. If you still feel...
- I won't need more time, Rick.
- I've bought a lot of property.
- I've got to talk to you.
Jim, what are you
doing here?
Jim Lingk,
D. Ray Morton.
- I'm glad to meet you.
- I put Jim into Black Creek.
- Are you acquainted with...
- Black Creek? No.
- Ooh, in Florida!
- Yes.
- I meant to speak to you about that.
- We'll do that this weekend.
My wife suggested
I look into it.
Beautiful rolling land...
I was telling Jim and Jinny.
Ray, I got to tell you something.
You eat in a lot of restaurants?
I know you do.
Ray is with American Express.
- Can I tell Jim what you do?
- Sure.
Ray is the director of all
European sales and services...
what I'm saying is, you haven't had
a meal until you've tasted...
I was at the Lingks'...
what was that service feature
you were talking about?
- Which...
- "Home cooking."
- You had a tag phrase you used?
- "Cooking"...
"Home cook..."
the monthly interview.
- The magazine!
- Yes.
Is that something
I can talk about?
It won't be out until
the February issue, but go ahead.
- Are you sure?
- Go ahead.
Ray was eating at one of his
company men's homes in France.
- The man is French?
- No, but his wife is.
His wife.
Ray, what time
do you have?
- 12:15.
- I got to get you on the plane.
- Didn't I say the 2:00?
- No, the 1:00.
Remember the 1:00... that's why
we couldn't talk till Kenilworth.
You're right, the 1:00...
let's scoot.
- A pleasure.
- I got to talk to you.
I got to run Ray to the airport.
Let's hustle... John!
Get on the phone to Pittsburgh,
American Express there, for Mr. Morton.
Tell them he's on the 1:00.
I'll see you.
Christ, I'm sorry
you came all the way in.
I'm running Ray to the airport.
You wait here and...
no, I can't. I'm meeting your man
at the bank.
I wish you'd have phoned!
Are you and Jinny going to be home?
- I don't know.
- Rick?
- What?
- Kenilworth?
- I'm sorry?
- Kenilworth.
Oh, God. Excuse me, Ray...
just a minute.
Jim, I told you who he is... the senior
vice-president of American Express.
His family owns 32 per...
over the past years, I have sold him...
I can't tell you the dollar amount...
but quite a lot of land.
I promised him five weeks ago that I
would go to the wife's birthday party
in Kenilworth tonight.
I have to go, you understand?
They treat me like a member
of the family. I have to go.
It's funny... you get a picture
of the corporation-type company man,
all business...
this guy, I'll tell you.
We'll go to his house
someday.
Let me see. Tomorrow.
I'm in L. A?
Ah, Monday.
I'll take you to lunch.
Where would you like to eat?
- My wife...
- Rick?
I can't talk now, Jim...
I'll call you tonight. Coming, Ray.
My wife said I have
to cancel the deal.
That's a common reaction, Jim,
and let me tell you what it is.
That's why you married her.
One of the reasons is prudence.
No, it's a sizable investment.
One thinks twice.
It's also something women have.
Reaction to the size of the investment.
Monday, you invite me
to dinner again...
- This woman can cook.
- I'm sure she can.
We are going to talk.
I want to tell you something.
Something about your acreage
I want you to know.
I can't talk about it here,
I really shouldn't, and by law...
the man next to you...
bought his lot at 42...
phoned to say
he already had an offer.
- Rick.
- I'm coming.
Ray, what a day.
I'll call you this evening.
I'm sorry you had to come
all the way in. Monday lunch.
- We have to go.
- Monday!
She called the consumer...
the attorney general?
- They said we have three days.
- Who'd she call?
The attorney ge...
it was some consumer office.
Why'd she do that, Jim?
I don't know.
But they said
we have three days.
They said
we got three days, yeah.
Three days?
- To... you know.
- No, I don't know.
- Tell me.
- To change our minds.
Of course you have...
three days.
So we can't talk Monday.
Monday...
you saw my book.
Jim, Jim... I can't.
You saw my book.
I can't.
We have to before Monday
to get our money back.
Three business days,
they mean.
- Three business days.
- Wednesday, Thursday, Friday.
- I don't understand.
- That's what they are, three business...
if we wait till Monday,
my time limit runs out.
- You don't count Saturday.
- I'm not.
I'm saying you don't include
Saturday in the three days.
- It's not a business day.
- I am not counting it.
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday...
so it would have elapsed.
What would have elapsed?
If we wait till Monday
it would have elapsed!
- When did you write the check?
- Yesterday.
- What was yesterday?
- Tuesday.
- And when was that check cashed?
- I don't know.
What was the earliest
it could have been cashed?
- I don't know.
- Today.
Today. Which, in any case,
it was not...
there was something on the agreement
I wanted to go over with you.
It wasn't cashed?
I just phoned downtown...
it's on their desk.
- Rick.
- One moment.
One point, in fact, of which
I spoke to you of which,
I can't talk to you
about it here.
- Levene!
- Listen to me.
The statute is for your protection.
I have no complaint with that.
In fact, I was a member
of the board when we drafted it.
So quite the opposite.
It says,
"You can change your mind
three 'working days'
from the time
the deal was closed."
- Levene!
- Wait a second!
Which is not until
the check is cashed!
I'm through with this "meshugaas."
Nobody should talk to a man that way.
- How are you talking to me that way?
- Levene!
- How can you talk to me that way?
- I'm gonna flag a cab.
- I didn't rob...
- Shelly, get in the office.
"Where were you last?"
Is anybody listening to me?
- Where's Moss?
- Is this Levene?
Perhaps I could assist you.
Excuse us, will you?
I work here! I didn't come in here
to be mistreated!
- Go to lunch, will you?
- That's why I came in to work today.
The leads come in,
I'll let you know.
- That's why I came in!
- Just go to lunch.
- I don't wanna go to lunch!
- Go to lunch, George.
Where does he get off
talking that way to a working man?
Take it outside. We have people
trying to do business.
That's what I came in here for.
That's what I'm trying to do!
- I meet Gestapo tactics.
- Excuse me.
I meet Gestapo tactics!
I meet Gestapo tactics.
That's not right.
No man has the right...
no man has the right...
"Call an attorney"...
that means you're under...
he says, "Cooperate
or we'll take you downtown."
That's not...
as long as I've...
Will you get out of here?
Will you?
I'm trying to run an office here.
Now, will you go to lunch?
Go to lunch.
Will you go to lunch?
- Excuse me.
- Where did Moss?
- Excuse me, please?
- Did he go to the restaurant?
Will you
excuse me, please?
I'm sorry, I...
I apologize to you. It's...
It's not me,
it's my wife.
What is it?
- I told you.
- Tell me again.
- What's going on here?
- Tell me again... your wife?
- I told you.
- Tell me again.
She wants her money back.
We're gonna speak to her.
No, she told me,
"Right now."
- We're gonna speak to her, Jim.
- She won't listen.
- She...
- Roma!
She said if don't get my money back,
to call the state's attorney.
No. No.
This is something she said.
- We don't have to do that.
- She told me I have to.
- No, Jim.
- I do.
Listen, I do...
if I don't get my money back...
Roma,
I'm talking to you.
Listen... will someone
get this guy off my back, please?
- You have a problem?
- Yes, I have a problem!
Yes, I do, my friend.
It is not me
that ripped the joint off.
I'm doing business.
I will be with you
in a while, got it?
Where are you going?
This is me!
Jim, this is
Ricky, Jim.
Jim, anything you want,
you want it, you got it.
Understand?
This is me.
Something upset you.
Yes.
Sit down now.
Sit down.
You tell me what it is,
am I gonna
help you fix it?
You're goddamned
right I am.
Sit down.
I'll tell you something,
sometimes we need
someone from outside.
Sit. Talk to me,
come on.
I can't negotiate.
What does that mean?
What?
Say the words.
I don't have the power.
Okay, I said it.
- What power?
- To negotiate.
To negotiate what?
This.
- What this?
- The deal.
The deal?
Forget the deal, Jim.
You got something on your mind,
what is it?
What?
I can't talk to you.
You met my wife.
- What?
- Aw...
I met your wife,
what?
What, Jim?
Come on, let's go.
Let's go, let's go.
Get a drink,
come on.
No, no, she told me
not to talk to you.
Come on, we're gonna
go around the corner.
We'll have a drink.
Who's gonna know?
She told me to get
the check back, otherwise...
Forget the deal, Jimmy.
Forget the deal.
The deal is dead.
You know me, the deal's dead.
Am I talking
about the deal?
That's over.
Please...
let's talk about you.
I'm gonna tell you
something.
Your life is your own.
You have a contract
with your wife,
you have certain things
you do jointly,
you have a bond there.
And there are other things,
and those things are yours.
You needn't feel ashamed.
You needn't feel
that you're being untrue
or that she would
abandon you if she knew.
This is your life.
Yes?
Now, I want to talk to you
because you're obviously upset,
and that concerns me.
Let's go,
come on, right now.
Let's go, come on.
Roma.
- What?
- The check, it's...
What did I tell you?
No, what did I tell you
about the three days?
Roma, would you?
I'd like to get some lunch.
I am talking with Mr. Lingk,
if you please.
I will be with you in a while.
Just check with Mr. Williamson.
- People downtown said...
- Call them again. Mr. Williamson!
Yes?
Mr. Lingk and I
are going to go to the...
Oh, yes, please.
The police can be...
- What are the police doing here?
- It's nothing.
- We had a slight burglary last night.
It's nothing,
I was just assuring Mr. Lingk.
Mr. Lingk? James Lingk?
Your contract went out.
- Nothing to worry about.
- John, John...
- Your contract went out to the bank.
- You cashed my check?
- Mr. Williamson...
- The check was cashed.
The contract was filed
and deposited in the bank,
and we're completely insured
in any case, as you know.
- You cashed the check?
- Not to my knowledge, no.
- Though I'm sure we can...
- Not to my knowledge.
Christ! I...
Oh, Christ.
Don't follow me,
just don't follow me, okay?
I've let you down.
I know I've let you down.
I'm sorry, forgive me. I-I...
I don't...
I don't know anymore.
I... forgive me.
You stupid fucking cunt.
You, Williamson,
I'm talking to you, shithead.
You just cost me
$6,000.
$6,000, and one Cadillac.
That's right.
What are you gonna
do about it?
What are you
gonna do about it, asshole?
You're fucking shit.
Where did you
learn your trade,
you stupid fucking cunt,
you idiot?
Who ever told you
that you could work with men?
Could I?
Oh, I'm gonna have
your job, shithead.
I'm going downtown.
I'm gonna talk to Mitch and Murray.
I'm going to Lemkin!
I don't care whose nephew you are,
who you know,
whose dick you're sucking on,
you're going out.
I swear to you...
Hey, fella,
let's get this done.
Anyone in this office
lives on his wits...
I'm gonna be with you
in a second.
What you're hired for
is to help us.
Does that seem
clear to you?
To help us!
Not to fuck us up!
To help men who are
going out there
to try to earn a living,
you fairy.
You company man.
I'll tell you something else,
I hope you ripped the joint off.
I can tell our friend here something,
might help him to catch you.
You wanna learn
the first rule
you'd know if you ever
spent a day in your life?
You never open your mouth
till you know what the shot is.
You fucking child.
You are a shithead,
Williamson.
Can't think on your feet,
you ought to keep your mouth closed.
Can you hear me?
I'm talking to you.
Yes, I hear you.
Ricky's right. Can't learn in an office,
gotta learn it in the street.
And you sure can't buy it,
you gotta live it.
- Mmmm.
- "Mmmm," yeah!
Precisely.
Because your partner depends...
I'm talking to you,
trying to tell you something!
- You are?
- Yeah, I am.
- What are you trying to tell me?
- What Roma was trying to tell you.
What I told you a long time ago.
You don't belong in this business.
You might listen to me.
One day you could say,
"Hey, maybe the guy..."
oh, fuck it.
Listen to me now.
Your partner depends on you.
The man who is your partner,
depends on you.
You go with him
and for him or you're shit!
You are shit...
you can't exist alone.
- Excuse me.
- "Excuse you," nothing!
You be as cold as you want.
You just fucked a good man
out of $6,000
and his goddamned bonus
because you didn't
know the shot.
You can do that and you're not
man enough to say it gets you?
I don't know what...
if you can't take something from that,
then you're... scum!
You're fucking white bread.
A child would know it,
he's right.
If you're gonna make something up,
be sure that it helps.
Hmm?
Or keep your mouth shut.
I'm done with you.
How do you know
I made it up?
What?
How do you know
I made it up?
What are you
talking about, huh?
You said, "Don't make something up
unless it's sure to help."
- How did you know I made it up?
- What are you talking about?
I told the customer his contract
had gone to the bank.
Yeah. Well, hadn't it?
No, it hadn't.
Don't fuck with me.
Don't fuck with me!
What are you getting at?
I'm saying this, Shelly...
usually I take
the contracts to the bank,
last night I didn't.
Last night I stayed home
with my kids.
How did you know that?
One night in a year,
I left a contract on my desk.
No one knew that but you.
Now, how did you know that?
You want to talk to me or you
want to talk to someone else?
Because this is my job!
This is my job on the line
and you are gonna talk to me!
Now how did you know
that contract was on my desk?
You are so full of shit!
- You robbed the office.
- Oh, sure, I robbed the office.
Oh sure! You asshole.
What did you do
with the leads?
You wanna go in there?
I tell him what I know,
he's gonna dig up something.
You got an alibi last night?
You better have one!
What did you do with the leads?
If you tell me what you did
with the leads, we can talk.
I don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
If you tell me where the leads are,
I won't turn you in.
If you don't, I'm gonna tell
the cop you stole them.
Mitch and Murray will see that you
go to jail, believe me, they will!
Now, where are the leads?
I'm walking in that door.
You got five seconds
- or you are going to jail!
- Go ahead.
I don't care,
you understand?
Where are the leads?
All right.
I sold them.
To Jerry Graff.
How much did you
get for them?
How much did
you get for them?
Five.
Five grand.
- I got half.
- Who got the other half?
Do I have to tell you?
Moss.
Well, that was easy,
wasn't it?
- His idea.
- Was it?
I think he got
more than five, actually.
- Uh-huh.
- He told me my cut was 2500.
Mmm.
Wait a minute.
Okay... hey, hey, John!
Wait... okay, John!
Hey, Johnny.
Listen.
Come here, come here.
Eh, John?
Last night...
I gotta tell you,
I'm ready to "do the Dutch."
I'm done. Moss gets me,
"Do this, we'll get well."
Why not? Big fucking deal.
I'm halfway hoping to get caught.
Hey... put me out of my misery.
It taught me something, John.
What it taught me...
you gotta get out there!
I'm not cut out to be a thief,
I'm cut out to be a salesman.
And I am back.
I got my balls back.
Now... you got a slight
advantage on me.
But whatever it takes, John,
to make things right,
we're gonna make it right.
We are going
to make it right.
I want to tell you
something, Shelly.
- Eh?
- You have a big mouth.
What?
You've got a big mouth!
And now I'm gonna show you
an even bigger one.
Where are you going?
You can't do that!
You don't want to do that.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait.
It's $2,500. Go ahead
and take it, take it all.
No, I don't think so.
I don't think I want your money.
I think you fucked up my office,
and I think you're going away.
Are you nuts?
I'm gonna close for you! Take...
I'm gonna make this office and be
number one on that board again.
Wait, John.
John... okay.
This is what
we're gonna do... 20%.
I'm gonna give you 20%
of all my sales.
20%, as long as I'm
with this firm.
50.
- 50% of all my sales.
- What sales?
What sales? My God,
I just closed 82 grand.
Are you out of your fucking mind?
I'm back! This is just the beginning!
Just the beginning?
Where have you been, Shelly?
Bruce and Harriett Nyborg...
do you want to see the memos?
They're nuts.
They used to call in every week...
when I was with Webb...
we were selling Arizona.
They're nuts.
Did you see how they were living?
How can you delude yourself?
- I've got their check.
- Forget it. Frame it.
- It's worthless.
- The check is no good?
You want to stick around?
I'll pull the memo. I'm busy.
The check is no good?
They're nuts?
You want to call the bank?
I called them.
I called them four months ago
when we first got the lead.
The people are insane.
They just like talking
to salesmen.
- Don't!
- I'm sorry.
- Why?
- Because I don't like you.
My daughter.
Fuck you.
Asshole.
Guy couldn't find his fucking couch
in the living room.
What a day.
Whoo...
I haven't even had
a cup of coffee.
Jag-off John opens his mouth,
blows my Cadillac.
I swear,
it's not a world of men.
It is not
a world of men, "Machine."
- Huh?
- It's a world of clock-watchers...
bureaucrats...
officeholders, what it is.
It's a fucked-up world.
No adventure to it.
Dying breed.
Yes, it is.
We're the members of a dying breed.
That's... that's...
that's why we got
to stick together. Shel?
- Huh?
- I want to talk to you.
I've wanted to talk to you
for some time...
for a long time, actually.
I said, "The Machine"...
there's a man
I would work with.
There's..." you know,
I never said a word.
I don't know why I didn't.
I should've, I don't know why.
And that shit you were slinging
on my guy today...
that was so good.
That... it...
excuse me for saying this,
it's not even my place to say it.
That was admirable.
It was the old stuff.
Hey, I've been
on a hot streak.
So what?
Things I can learn from you.
- You eat today?
- Me?
Yeah.
Want to swing around the Chinks'...
watch me eat, we'll talk?
I think
I'll stay around awhile.
Hello, Mrs. Schwartz?
This is Richard Roma
with Premiere Properties.
You or your accountant requested
information on a land investment
which would offer you
depreciation and the chance
of a substantial return
on a small investment.
I'm in from Florida
just for one day...
- Mr. Levene?
...so I only have that one lot left.
Would you come in here,
please?
I don't have too much time
and I'm on the midnight plane back,
so if you or your husband
are truly interested...
because I can't hold
this parcel past...
Yes?
Well, what would be better
for you... say, 6:00 or 8:00?
Go ask him. Shel... we're gonna talk?
I'm going to the Chinks'.
When you're done, come down.
We're gonna smoke a cigarette.
- I...
- Get in the room.
Hey. Hey, easy, pal.
That's "The Machine."
This is Shelly
"The Machine" Levene.
- Get in the goddamn room.
- Rick, I...
- I'll meet you at the restaurant.
- Ricky...
- Ricky can't help you.
- All I want is...
What do you want?
You want to what?
- Rick? Rick?
- Hello? Excellent.
8:00 P.M.
6947 Euclid.
Not at all...
thank you very much.
They find the guy
that broke in the office?
No. I don't know.
Did the leads
come in yet?
No.
Oh God,
I hate this job.
Anybody wants me,
I'm at the restaurant.
Hello, Mrs. Delgari?
Yes... you requested some information
about Rio Rancho Properties?
# Blue skies smiling at me #
# Nothing but blue skies
do I see #
# In the morning
there's bluebirds #
# Singing a song #
# Nothing but bluebirds #
# From now on #
# I never saw the sun
shining so bright #
# Never saw things
going so right #
# Noticing the days
hurrying by #
# When you're in love,
my, how they fly #
# Blue days,
all of them gone #
# Nothing but blue skies
from now on... #
# Blue skies
smiling at me #
# Nothing but blue skies
do I see #
# In the morning
there's bluebirds #
# Singing a song #
# Nothing but, nothing but
bluebirds from now on #
# Let me tell you
I never saw the sun #
# Shining so bright #
# Never saw things
going so right #
# Noticing the days
hurrying by #
# When you're in love,
my, how they fly #
# Blue skies
smiling at me #
# Nothing but blue skies
do I see #
# In the morning
there's bluebirds #
# Singing a song #
# Nothing but, nothing but
bluebirds from now on #
# Let me tell you
I never saw the sun #
# Shining so bright #
# Never saw things
going so right #
# Noticing the days
hurrying by #
# When you're in love,
my how they fly #
# Blue days #
# All of them,
all of them gone #
# Nothing but blue skies
from now on #
# Now on #
# Nothing but blue skies. #