Five soldiers condemned to death were lead to
the sector of Bullavent,
near the Somme River.
The first one was a great adventurer many years before
He wore on his neck the number 2124.
He came from a recruitment center of La Seine
He was wearing boots
He took them from a German soldier.
Before, soldier 2124,
called Bastoche
was with a beautiful redhead girl
called Véronique Passavant.
He was carpenter in the " La Bastille"
Sometimes between two furniture pieces
They went to drink a beer in the pub of Petit
Louis on the street "The Golden Hand"
He took the boots from an enemy
who didn't need them any more.
in order to replace them,
once filled up with straw and newspaper paper,
They replaced his former boots.
He went before a military tribunal
for voluntary mutilation.
They found residue of gunpowder in the wound on his
hand, and he was condemned to death.
The second soldier wore the number 4077, and
was from another recruitment center of La Seine.
He worked on the Steel for the state railroads in
Manille.
His name was Francis Ganière, We called him "Six Soux"
He knew that the poor
were building the cannons
which will kill them
and that the wealthy people sold them.
He tried to explain it during
the barrackings, but he didn't explain well.
In addition, the cheap wine : their friend in the
misery, made the soldiers so pissed,
that he didn't even know how
to interrupt them.
1818 was without any doubt the bravest soldier,
And the most dangerous one.
He once killed the officer of his team.
An officer who hit the dead.
Get up ! Get up !
You, go away!
No one knew it.
Benoît Notre Dame was a farmer.
One morning in the month of August,
they went to take him away from his farm,
and they forced him on the train.
Be aware of the cables!
The phone cables were
the only way to connect to the world of the living.
By that fine thread, they were hoping for
the grace of the president Raymond Poincare
to spare their lives.
Even if the only one here who believed
that was him...
Number 7328,  recruited from
the island of Corsica.
was Ange Bassignano
According to all people who knew him,
no one ever had a more unsuitable name.
'The Angel' was a liar, a cheater, a fake.
An informer and agitator.
Before, he had been the procurer (pimp) of Tina Lombardi
Because of her,
He had been condemned to jail for five years
for an honor or love crime
.
Depending on the whether they
were a woman or a man.
Actually... it was a deal
between
the procurers (pimps) of the village.
During the summer of 1916 they recruited
delinquents
in order to be able to replace losses within the
massacred regiments
In Berdun hell, it was up to them.
For whom are Those tombs ?
Well Actually... well... as tomorrow they are
going to attack...
So we anticipate.
Be aware of the cable.
The fifth soldier was a kid who belonged to the section of 17.
He just needed 5 months to be 20 years old.
And now, he was afraid of everything.
Of the French cannons which were firing so much.
Of the wind that spread
the gas of the hunters of robbery, of the executions.
Before the war he was not like this, he was just the
opposite...
He defied storms to help keep lighthouses
working when the tide rose.
Charge !!
Then one detail will change everything.
There you go kid, you will return to see your
fiancee, you just got your way out.
Yep, you got your way right to the court-martial.
My sergeant, close your eyes for a change,
he already suffered enough, don't you think?
Sergeant they may condemn him to death
Be understanding for a change!
Shut your mouth!
Come on Sergeant..
Shut the fuck up !
When Mathilde and Manech made love for the
first time
Manech fell asleep with his hand over her left breast.
Whenever he felt the wound on his hand beating,
it was like feeling
Mathilde's heart beating.
And each beat will make him closer to her.
If Manech were dead, Mathilde would know.
After the news of his death,
she desperately clung
to her intuition like a fine thread.
Still, she never gets discouraged.
Mathilde has a cheerful disposition.
She knows that if ever her thread
doesn't connect her to her lover
Well that's not too bad,
she still can hang herself with it.
In June of 1920
Mathilde received
a letter from a nun.
A sick man from the "Le Reim"
hospital wanted to meet her.
He was with Manech
in January 1917, on the front
of the Somme.
In August 1912, he was a good
looking man, wasn't he ?
It is of lemon, with direct gear box.
Please tell me what happened to Manech
In January 1917 they ordered me to
escort five
condemned men to the front.
Was he among them ?
Yeah.
I had to take them to the first line of
the trench.
Gendarmes waited for us with the prisoners next to
a small cemetery in ruins.
What the fuck are you doing with those German boots?
I am waiting.
Waiting for what ?
To be spared by Poincare?
You can dream on Dude!
He already signed it.
Normally I should not have been
condemned.
I am from Corsica, you know, not French!
Let him be. He loses a wee bit his head for
Lucky him.
Are you done, lieutenant?
That soldier, He doesn't have long before
he dies, the cold will kill him.
What about Manech? ...Does the wound on his hand make
him suffer badly??
We had to amputate two fingers,
but it seemed he was doing okay.
They took them to a trench called "the
bingo twilight".
Fucking hell. Could you make sure to kick these
useless people out of the trench on your way ??
To kick their ass so as to come along faster?
My orders were to deliver you
the five condemned men, I don't care about
the rest.
Then I will tell them what my orders are...
to throw these guys from  the trench.
and to let them die like dogs between the two
firing lines.
Those are my fucking orders
Sergeant!
You understand Sergeant, we have a special
tactical agreement with the Germans.
The sector is wee bit sleepy, a kick in the
ass and all the shit will explode in our faces !
The soup guys, You are lucky it is warm.
And what would you like to get kiddo?
A chocolate cup and a piece of bread with honey.
Unless I have to kill my parents: I will get that for you.
Do you mind lieutenant?
Don't worry, he is an orphan,
but he will no doubt get you what
you want.
He is the chief of the kitchens.
15 minutes later, he brought everything.
Bread with salt, honey of lavagne and...
Cacao of Nigeria.
Happiness
There you go kid, do you have anyone to write to?
Do you have a girlfriend?
Mathilde
His girlfriends's name is Mathilde.
I feel like her heart beats in me with Morse code.
We are about to get married.
They condemned us and we don't have to wait for the
end of war anymore.
I will go Home when the
execution is over.
Maybe it is better that I don't tell you the
end.
I am lame, not stupid
Tell me what happens.
We opened a breach in the wire fences.
and helped the five soldiers to fight against the cold.
Célestin Poux gave your boyfriend one of his red wool
gloves, so that the hand was protected.
Is it far away ??
Less than 100 meters. Far for the grenades and
close for the artillery.
And not to mention the gas.
Do you think that they will be all right?
If they don't fly in the air,
they will very likely die of hunger and cold.
In any case the Germans will shut up for a while.
Bastoche the carpenter has been embraced
by a corporal.
It was obvious they knew each other before the war.
Soon... we took them outside the trench.
- Assholes.
- Shit!
- Shut up!
In September 1914, I could easily lift 70 kilos.
Moreover I was already not in great shape like
in the past.
But that morning, in january 1917
was Manech still alive?
At the dawn, Favart shout out their names.
All, except the farmer from Dordogne, responded.
- Bassignano?
- Present.
- Bouquette?
- what the hell do you want?
- Langonnet?
- Yeah, I am here.
Man, you should hide in a better spot.
Notre Dame? Notre Dame?
I know nothing else.
I retired to write my report
young lady.
At last soldier, the English have come
to take our place, we can go.
And the subject bingo?
What is that?
The list of the condemned signed by
Captain Favourier.
Do I leave it there?
Nope, give it to me.
Don't stay there like an idiot.
What are you waiting for?
You are promoted sergeant first thing in the
morning and leave for the Bosbos.
Even so my commander, this mission is
going away to be stuck in my throat.
Good news, there are balsamic caramels for the
throat there.
The caramels of the Bosbos.
We are done.
Some months later, I had been
hurt in the Somme.
I found myself in the same ambulance as
Chardolot.
One of the officers in "the bingo twilight".
But he only had a few days to live.
Eh oh, It is me Esperanza.
Bingo twilight, you remember?
Oh, sorry I didn't recognize you.
Tell me, my no man's land boys...
How did the story finish ?
What do you think ?
No survivor ??
Do you feel remorse?
You should have stayed with us in Bingo.
I saw the capital Ms written down
... underpants, an albatross.
You are delirious. You have the flu.
We threw between two lines five boys alive,
then we recovered five cold pieces of meat.
So...
I lost my vision sergeant, but
I imagine your face.
That makes my day.
He really spoke of capital Ms and an albatross?
Yep ... and of underpants.
There you go Young lady,
everything the condemned men
in Bingo ever possessed.
They asked me to send everything to their families.
My health didn't allow me to do it.
It is a copy of the letter of the farmer Benoît
Notre Dame to his wife.
I sent the original one to her
when I left Bingo.
His health is due to the gas in the lungs right?
Nope, it is because he got the Spanish flu.
You can notice, the death is lurking and catches
us totally by surprise.
Mathilde, you don't have to be pissed off,
you can talk to me.
If you can't talk, just stay quiet.
But sometimes when we start speaking, it's
when we start crying.
And when crying
we talk about what you didn't want to
hear, you know what I mean?
I will not have to bear that silly face anymore.
Petit Louis tell Vero that I will always think about
her and that it is too bad she doesn't want to
talk to me, I met Biscotte again
and we made up. Good bye
my friend, Bastoche
Benoît Notre Dame Number 1818
I will not be able to write again
for a while.
Tell Berney I will pay everything by the month of March.
He sells his installment for too much.
You have to be careful.
Tell my Bagtistan that I hope nothing bad will happen to him.
I have never known such a nice person.
I love you, Benoît.
For Tina Lombardi from Ange Bassignano.
If the dog enters the room before they call me
for the dinner, Manech must be still alive.
I am not hungry.
The dinner is ready.
Come Malthide, let's go to eat.
I'm coming.
Mathilde was born on the first of January 1900
That makes it very easy to determinate one's age.
In 1903 her parents passed away in
an accident on bus 44.
Since then Mathilde kept saying
Late parents... late parents...
Her Uncle Sylvain and Aunt Bénédicte
took care of her.
Thanks to the life insurance managed by the
lawyer of her parents, Pierre Marie Rouvières.
At five years old, Mathilde caught the polio virus.
She stayed several months in the bed in spite of
the mustard cataplasms,
the pendulums,
and the infusions of shamrock with four leaves.
Today Mathilde is 20 years old, she plays tuba,
because it is the only instrument that seems to
give the distress signal.
The dog always farts when it sleeps
Whenever Bénédicte hears the dog, she says
the farty dog betrayed.
Mathilde needs to get daily massages for
her legs.
Georges Cornu the champion of Britain in free
style swimming gives her massage.
At the beginning she was anxious.
But she got used to it.
When Mathilde was in the mood, she imagined that
Georges Cornu admired the shape of her body.
and he couldn't repress his desire.
As a matter of fact, one day he dared to remark :
You have very beautiful curves young lady,
and I can assure you that I have touched lot of women.
So Mathilde didn't know anymore
if she could call him :
My dear Gorge...
My loved Gorge...
Gogo
Sometimes, before sleeping she imagined herself in
hot situations
Mathilde never had to use
all her imagination to succumb to the pleasure.
But since he disappeared, she cannot think
about her fiance when she seeks pleasure.
If I was you I would forget everything Mathilde, it is of no use to
look for nothing.
Moreover if he were alive why did he not give any sign, huh?
Because he had been made a prisoner.
He stayed with a german girl
with two blond tresses with big tits.
A Breton eating sauerkraut every single day. ..impossible.
Are you sure you don't want me to help you??
Oh no but I prefer you to keep your feet on the ground.
Well I will need to feel my legs for that!
What did you say??
Nothing
I did hear you.
What you just said doesnt make any sense.
Manech cannot be a prisoner in Bingo, because
It is where we find the enemy lines.
Generally winners can take the prisoners.
Maybe he lost his direction, or he hides somewhere
so as not to go to jail.
My sweet Mathilde you read
too many novels.
You have to go back to reality.
You are young and beautiful,
you could easily find a husband
in spite of....
In all that story there is something
that does not add up.
I must find back
the plunderer of kitchens... Célestin Poux.
What would you want kiddo?
Or maybe the prostitute from Corsica, maybe
she knows things more than I do.
Tomorrow I go away to Paris.
What ?
What for??
To look for a survivor of Bingo twilight.
... I have archives all the way up to the ceiling.
You can't imagine the number
of cases which never saw the light of day.
If Germain Pire did not come in hand.
Have a look at this,
A big case, an extremely delicate one. In 1917 a train
with soldiers derails
427 dead.
Thanks to the investigation we discovered that
the official
gave the order to leave although the brakes
did not work.
It was a concealment maneuver
from the government of Poincare.
The only option for the victim
families was to find
the official... Germain Pire.
The spy that chirps.
Oh way worse, young lady. And I found the official.
For the sorrow of the high military spheres.
Allright, in the cemetery of Craon.
As soon as I packed my suitcases I left to go after them,
Poux Célestin and his lover from Corsica.
And what about the fees ?
Look my lady, The spy that chirps
knows to whom he should pluck.
For you it would be 20 francs per day.
Without the expenses of course.
And why would you do me that favour?
Hélène come on to say hello !
Don't worry about the expenses of Germain Pire.
He eats little, and does not drink.
And he is very sparing in gratuities.
Good morning.
Notre Dame de Paris?
No, not Notre Dame de Paris, I call you from
Paris about Notre Dame, Benoît.
Ah Benoît Notre Dame yes, a strong farmer and of
great heart.
He died for the mother country, we say that the
mother country has cleared me of good people.
His wife and her small Bagtistan
still live there?
Madame Minne I can't hear nothing!
No, one day she sold everything and they went
away without leaving direction.
Is it a choir that I hear behind your back?
it's a choir indeed dear lady, I am in the church.
However that is not an excuse
for not hearing you well.
Thanks Father, Good bye.
You're welcome.
Bingo twilight.
That does not have feet nor head. This is a scandal.
I thought that your vocation was to defend lost
causes.
When you were 10 years old your insolence had
grace, not when you are 20 years old.
As a matter of fact, it would be
time to take me seriously.
Mathilde, Mathilde, you squander your inheritance
in an absurd chimera.
Bingo twilight, and why not Yupi Tralalala...
I want to consult military files.
Mathilde let's say
there were any truth in there.
And if one of the condemned
men ever survived he would face
forced labor. And you know it!
Your investigations would cause him
very dangerous problems.
Be sensible, they trusted the interests to me...
... your parents.
Late parents.
Actually, my happiness was one of their interests.
Good bye, and thanks.
My sweet Mathilde
do not be like that please.
I think about your future,
it hurts me much to see you got
worse despite your massages.
All right all right I will see
what I can do.
I can't put that though in Lourdes..
Good morning lady I am looking for Tina
Lombardi I've known her since she was a kid and..
Pardon ladies I am a political uncle of Tina
Lombardi and I would like to er....
Please, I am in charge of the interests of the
Lombardi family in the continent,
and I am looking for Tina. It is about a small heritage...
Are you the man who is looking for Tina
Lombardi?
No, in fact no.
Don't you know Corsica ? It is very pretty place.
Very colorful.
But Tina
Lombardi went away after
the bad business
Luckily a member of the police
found her whereabouts in the Leville Bar.
Valentin Emilia Maria Lombardi, called Tina,
had been registered
in 1916 near the quarter of regiment 23 in
Marseilles.
After that she ran away.
I lost her tracks in Lyon, and trust me I didn't
stop looking.
She has disappeared in the
district of the Croix Rousse.
What you mean is you have given up.
Not at all, Pire never lets it go.
Pire is obstinate, a detective who gives up,
he doesn't exist young lady.
Perfect, thanks.
Not the eyes, no
What do you drink ?
This is my fiance, and there is the
carpenter.
I believe that you know him.
No. I am suddenly thirsty, do you mind a
glass of wine?
It gives force and it cheers the way.
My great aunt told me the same thing.
She died in Besançon in 1911 at the age of 99 years old.
And she had never been ill.
Good luck.
I touch wood.
The war.
No, a hyena in the botanical garden.
I wanted to stroke it to be a smart ass.
Bastoche and his friend did this for me.
Biscotte?
His best friend. They met in 1910
while saving a woman from drowning in a flood.
Bastoche was skillful, but Biscotte...
He was an artist, the king of firmer chisel.
He did all the joints.
It is a wonder!
It is for you.
Petit Louis tell Vero
that I will always think about her
and that it is too bad she doesn't want to
Talk to me, I met Biscotte again
and we made up. Good bye
my friend.
Bastoche
If they made up, they must have had a fall out.
Do you know the reason ?
A mystery.
But to tell you the truth, they went through so much together,
And out of the blue, they can't bear each other.
Biscotte went away to another army.
And he died in the bombing of a
military hospital while he was injured.
Anyway, I am glad they made up before.
It seems that it will not be
very busy here today.
Do you serve drinks?
It seems you are again thirsty huh?
Maybe he has a wooden hand
but he still has a big heart.
Let's drink to love. The true one!
Do you know who that is, Véro?
Véronique Passavant. His girlfriend, his lover.
He often came here with her.
What could have happened as
she didn't want to talk to him anymore ?
I suppose he has been unfaithful
and she never forgave him.
Voila, here is the place for the year 1917.
What are the red files about ??
Top Secret Defense
We need higher clearance for them.
This way please,
upstairs.
Go to help him
Oh right.
Suppose that the highest person is yourself
... then Mr. Rouvières and I would have
clearance right ?
If I had that kind of mind
I would not be an Official.
Mathilde please consider yourself lucky
to have been able to come here.
Normally it would take months.
Like I told you, they say everything is in order
but actually it is totally in chaos.
To see... in front of the Somme.
Sector of Bullavent, trench 108.
You know what I mean. This is a chaos!
It is a real mess.
Can I help you?
I thank you for the management
... with the General, I say.
Good, he is a great friend of mine.
I know the sector very well,  two
friends of mine died there.
Then it has been a very bloody war...
I don't think that things will get better
It is very difficult to find a maid nowadays.
It seems like a lie.
We would like to know that passage in trench 108.
... 104, trench 105, 107, where is the 106 one ??
See? A mess.
Trench 108... this is a bloody mess.
Good 108, here these...
... Taken by us in October of 1916
and renamed Bingo twilight.
And why not trooi Tralala?
on 6 January there is nothing
on 7 january great confrontation with numerous losses...
Favourier captain, the professor of history died
in combat...
The lieutenant... An adviser of insurances!
The corporal.... Good that but it gives...
That is weird, a part of the losses are classified confidential.
Confidential? It means...
I am sorry.
And we can do nothing about it?
No nothing
We can only get up to here.
I am sorry.
Not even the general himself could do
anything about it.
Even so, I thank you for your time.
I am sorry, there is nothing which can be of any help to you.
Really ordinary files.
It was one possibility.
Everything is a chaos!
You are incorrigible Mathilde...!
... no lady, that is totally impossible
No, without the seal of the ministry it is
impossible.
I hope that this leaf is not classified..
Pierre Marie, if it is important You must tell me.
Nope, that is nothing. Only one permission.
Of the president ?
So what, every so often the president can give
it to soldiers who deserve it.
That is it.
I take both of you out
Corporal Bouquette Clevert, Ganière Francis
Soldier Notre Dame Benoît, soldier Bassignano
Ange
Soldier Langonnet Manech
By voluntary mutilation the sentence to capital
punishment.
I count up to 7 and if the train doesn't enter a tunnel
Or the conductor does not come. Manech is dead
One, two, three,
four, five, six
Tickets please.
April fool !
As soon as you finish eating your meal, we will
pay your announcement.
It compensates all information referring to
Bingo twilight. is that okay for you??
Yes, try to encourage her, it would
give her appetite.
You would have taken her to the
camperre festival.
What for?
To  distract you a wee bit.
Not to mention you
could find a nice boyfriend.
But what for ??
So you can marry and raise a family!
Tell her!
Can I have some too?
Do you drink wine now?
A wine glass gives force and cheers the way.
Where did you get that from ??
On the street "the gold hand", the owner of the
bar The Dead Hand, He has a wooden hand.
His great aunt said that before
dying, at the age of 99 years old
in Besançon in 1911.
Can you say that again?
In Besançon, in 1911
... one old lady lived until 99 years, who died leaving
behind a little nephew who has a wood hand
He is the owner of the dead hand,
a bar on the street the gold hand.
You see it? Already pissed off.
Look !
This is the Albatross.
It knows that it can use the wind at will.
Oh my gravel! My gravel!
Véronique Passavant on July 17th 1920
Lady, I write you from the bar of Petit Louis who
told me about you.
I have to tell about a meeting I  had
which gave me a fright.
I was coming to the factory of Bastoche because
I was melancholic.
I would like to speak with Bastoche
Bastoche, but he died...
... in the front of the Somme, you didn't know?
But I am looking for something else.
What exactly??
In the hospital where I help the patients, there
are terminal syphilitics.
One of them has given this to me for you.
If you don't want to die covered by
purulent abscesses, you would do better
answering me!
The companion with whom Bastoche hides
Tell me, tell me who is he?
Well well I would not let myself be upset by
some young lady.
Tina Lombardi knows something we don't
What did you say??
Tina Lombardi knows something which
eludes us.
Something that would prove
that Bastoche is still alive.
And the other condemned men.
It is obvious she believes I am his angel.
But if Bastoche has been saved, Then I am sure
that he protected Manech.
If he ever survived it.
Wait.
It can, but if not outside for that reason,
single I would have left to hang to me.
Are you winding me up you smart ass ?
Whenever you come here I must fix
the gravel.
As for the gravel, it is a question about style.
A letter for the young lady.
Ironworks R. Leprince, Paris 1920 July 25.
Young lady, I take advantage of Sunday today to
write to you with respect to your announcement
where it says that you are looking
for Célestin Poux and
other survivors
of Bingo twilight.
I knew that guy very well,
he was the best go-getter that
I ever met.
Thanks to him
I never starved myself.
Olivier Nergeton mechanical
toys manufacturer.
Célestin Poux was our provider, we called
him the terror of the kitchens
He falsified the numbers of losses, so as to multiply
the money in order to get the soldiers more foods.
If you ever meet him, Tell him that the veterans
of Fontenau will never forget him.
Etienne Mauriaux, Professor, August 3 of 1920
He made us laugh ours heads off,
to get us food, he would even
tame the mascot of the company.
Good morning Madam, Germain Pire private
detective.
Oh yeah, Mathilde told us about you.
Sylvain Tell Mathilde to go downstairs,
the detective wants to see her.
The great Pire moves like hell, he can spend a
day in each site.
In any case we will need luck and patience to
get him.
A shame.
Mathilde I got you some salty cakes.
You will see if you like them.
You won't be better in the kitchen?
Thank you Bénédicte.
Allright, I leave you alone.
Poux is a mystery, whereas Tina Lombardi
that is another story
She misleads us with dead end leads.
And to make matters
worse she changes identities.
Anything new about Biscotte ?
Wait !
Look at this, this is Benjamín Gordes
it is the day where they got the carpentry
prize,
for the sixth consecutive year.
But!
And yes, young lady.
Biscotte, the best friend of Bastoche, is none
other than Benjamín Gordes.
And a soldier of the company told me
that they were close-knit before
they fought.
Leave me alone.
I do not want to fight with you.
Calm down!
Bastard, Asshole .
Who got that idea ??
Me??
It was your idea.
It was just for a skirt matter.
Véronique Passavant broke up with
Bastoche in June 1916.
And immediately afterwards, Bastoche fought with
Benjamín Gordes.
You don't have to be a lynx for that huh?
So they didn't see each other again until
in Bingo twilight?
Bingo twilight is where
everything finishes.
No, it is where everything started, Mr. Pire.
Where everything starts.
Tina Lombardi is sure Bastoche
is still alive.
What made Bastoche different from the
others in Bingo twilight?
That he was the only carpenter, no?
There is a thing that differentiates Bastoche
from the others...
... the German boots.
He was the only one to
wear German boots!
But of course !
You are right !
Tina Lombardi just knew that her man
by wearing German boots
he could have got away with it.
It would suffice that they
had seen him with some companion.
I met two Frenchmen
they looked like tramps.
... One of them got boots.
He got them from a german soldier
In addition to the german boots, we know that Bastoche
made up with his best friend.
Exactly! Who knows if it doesn't
make any change during that night.
If I can peel that apple without breaking
the skin then
Gordes found a way to help out
and save Bastoche,
and Manech.
At that rate I won't put the cake in the oven
before the next year!
I must return to Paris.
What ??
I have to return to Paris.
Again? The inheritance
of your parents will go away like smoke.
Late parents.
Excuse me,
where is Elodie Gordes?
That's the woman with the carrots.
Ah, thanks Sir.
Elodie Gordes?
Here for you.
I do not know him.
Which person don't you know??
Would it be that one by any chance?
Because Bastoche and
Biscotte had a fall out?
Was it because
of you??
You exagerate,
I do not have anything
to tell him.
No, I just need to know.
Leave me alone!
They saw each other for the
very last time in the
bingo twilight
My fiance was there too with Bastoche
In that excrement trench.
I need to understand.
I need to understand!
It is not what you think.
I can tell you everything.
Give me your address,
although I have misspelling,
I will put everything in a letter.
I promise you.
No letter for me?
What did you say?
There is no letter for me ?
Only the newspaper...
It talks about the all world but
not about Elodie Gordes.
Very funny.
You are wrong.
You can learn a lot of interesting things.
The president has opened an investigation on
the condemned men of Bingo twilight?
A man fell out of the train in the middle of the night
and in pajamas
At least him, he sleeps with pajamas.
Eh?
He sleeps with pajamas!
... and we recovered five cold cuts
You are already a thief, and now
you are pyromaniac.
Did you hurt yourself ??
No, I am fine.
For a change I don't have to gather the gravel, but
to collect the mailman.
You took away the gravel!
A good war!
There is no good war.
Do you want to drink something?
Yes please.
Miss, please keep secret my little secrets
When I met my husband,
he had four children from
a first marriage.
Not one kid was his.
By generosity he married with a
young tuberculosa widow
of Polish nationality, like me.
He considered the children as his
before she died.
Myself, I was unmarried mother
of a girl of 3 years.
So we found ourselves with a family
with 5 children,
We had four years of happiness.
We had many plans. We dreamed to be able to
see the sea once in life.
But then the war started.
At first I thought that Bastoche's friend would
take care of him because they were together,
but when he came back for the first time, in
September of 1915
Right after the campaign of Artois,
I understood right away nothing would
be like before.
This gives us the force to get on in life.
A day in a battlefield in flames I saw my
companions
exploding like they
were firecrackers.
One time we even used the body
of a companion,
to use as a shield.
He had been thinking about something
for a long time
it was in the second night that it started
You will understand that if I desert
they will arrest me.
The only way of getting away is to have
a sixth child.
When someone has 6 children, they send
the soldier back home.
As I already told him, He can't have children.
I could not imagine what to think.
But voila, he brought up the subject again.
But it is me who asks you, Elodie, that is not
adultery.
And even less
if it is with Bastoche.
Don't touch !
None of the five children is mine,
who cares about another one??
Although it embarrasses me,
we would have to wait 9 months
... by then the war would already be over.
But now it will never be over!
Those nine months will represent
a hope for me.
Don't you have more compassion??
Then one day I found
a letter of Clevert Bouquette,
AKA Bastoche in the letterbox.
I put something colorful at the window
so he knows where to show up.
Good morning.
I made some coffee, do you want some?
Oh yes, it would be nice, thank you.
Come in.
No, You first.
Thank you very much.
Do you want sugar ?
No, thanks.
It is of nacre?
Yes,  Benjamín made it.
It is curious we never met
Yes, before.
Are the children not home?
Yes, they are playing in the backyard.
A digestive with the coffee ?
Yes please.
In fact not... I am sorry.
I don't need it
I don't need it either.
Elodie look, we told him we did it.
So we are at peace for a while.
That is for the best.
For you, for me, for everybody.
It is funny, when you smile it looks like
a bracket.
It will close but the possible thing late.
The day after tomorrow, in the station.
Time to go, a very last smile okay?
In order to close the bracket.
I never have been pregnant.
But soon after, it was not the fear
which was tormenting my husband,
but the jealousy.
Where? When? Whichever times?
In which positions? Did you enjoy yourself?
It became an utter torture for him and me.
Now Bastoche died...
And my husband died in the hospital bombing.
It did me good to be honest with
you Miss.
Sometimes I am scared of becoming crazy.
Elodie Gordes.
Mathilde hurry up, This Mr. Rouvières is on
the phone waiting for you.
Move, Move.
Hello.
Mathilde, It's me Pierre Marie.
Erm, I have bad news for you.
Good or bad news, You were expecting for them,
... and that from now on, you will not be able to
continue ignoring.
The bottom line is, you
were right about one thing.
Manech and his 4 companions
were indeed in that trench.
They are buried in the Tertullian cemetery
They were first buried below a canvas
in a crater
There there, my little Mathilde.
In June of 1909 Mathilde was 9 years old,
Manech Langonnet... 10
Does it hurt when you walk?
It must have been Friday or Saturday.
Mathilde doesn't remember anymore.
Do you have friends?
If you want I could be your friend.
What is wrong, do i smell like fish?
Have you ever gone up the lighthouse?
I can carry you up there!
...my father is the lighthouse keeper.
As you wish, you are a stuck up little girl!
Hey! Do you want me to kick your ass?
How far can you see from the top of the lighthouse?
Lunch.
If dogfart stinks - furtune will come!
Manech Loves Mathilde
Mathilde Loves Manech
Take this
But I don't smoke!
I know, I know, just take it.
It will help you make friends.
If I get to the curve before the car
Manech will come back safe
If I get to the curve...
If I get to the curve before the car
Manech will come back safe.
If I get to the curve...
Good morning.
You used to brag about being
a year older than me.
Now I am older.
The name of the one that gave you
the glove is Poux.
Célestin Poux. He is very slippery
The detective I hired is called Pire.
Germain Pire.
He hasn't found neither him nor
the prostitute from Corsica.
The thread has been broken Manech
...but I will not quit.
I have faith in Tina Lombardi's clue.
I need to know. Do you understand?
That is why it is important that
I find Célestin Poux.
Well it's really a great pity, you know?
We would be very happy by now.
Let's go Mathilde.
It's getting cold.
Killed in combat
June 7th, 1917
Thouvenel?
What do you want?
Who are you?
Are you the one who called me?
The days passed without news
from Celestin Poux.
Mathilde was overwhelmed
with sadness.
She has to eat or she'll get sick.
Then leave her the best part.
She'll end up leaving us a taste
for tragedy, you'll see!
At last, on September 15th, 1920,
at midnight.
The thread connected again...
"Victory! I have finally found
that slippery Poux"
I'm sending him with God's blessing
and Harley Davidson's.
Expenses included, of course.
Germain Pire.
Célestin Poux, Road Terror.
Is this your announcement?
Mathilde clenched her fists together,
it was all she could do to avoid
shaking, crying
or looking like an idiot.
I didn't see your fiancé fall,
I had gone to look for the ranch
Then I met with Levert, a guy
I met at the Boscos.
A negihbour of the Mosa Valley.
More a jerk than a neighbour!
But he knew how to distinguish Arabic coffee
from any other medicine.
We had a big problem when we mixed
coffee with charcoal.
To trade it for Dutch tobacco.
The last time you saw Manech,
was he alive?
It was impossible not to see him,
instead of hiding.
He was carving an M on the trunk
of a charred tree.
He had time to carve three M's before
the albatross took him down.
The albatross?
Albatross. Big sea bird
that follows
like a travel companion without worries,
the ship that sails the bitter depths."
It's a poem by Baudelaire
But in 1915, it was also a German plane,
with a machine gun on the back.
Back then, it was impossible to shoot
through the helices.
Did you give him the glove?
Red, thick wool. I had a girlfriend
that used to knit scarves.
and gloves. I traded them with the Senegalese
that had frostbite on their fingers
for gold teeth that they took out of
dead german soldiers.
I melted them and thanks to them
I could buy the Harley.
But, are you sure Manech is dead?
A mate that saw the body told us,
that with a wound like that, there was
no doubt about it.
Of the 5, i only saw 3 of them get killed,
with my own eyes
I give up...
I give up... Don't shoot.
Mercy...I give up...
Let me through!
I'm on your side...
Mercy!
I'm not French!
I'm Corsican.
I have nothing against the German.
Poor man.
So you are not French.
Then lets nullify your birth certificate.
It was one of our soldiers who shot.
Thouvenel
He had an itchy trigger finger, with a heart
of stone and eagle's eye.
Poor man.
Do you want the truth?
I'm an easy man, I would kill
my whole family for a stew.
Don't worry, he is an orphan!
As well as for pickled meat and truffle puree
I just came from...
Ok! Who did you see die
with your own eyes?
The one infected with gangrene.
Six-Soux?
Yes, the welder.
Comrades, before I die
I have a last wish.
I would like to pee standing up.
like a man!
After that, comrades,
fire at will!
Good bye to life
Goodbye to love.
And to all the women.
It is over.
It is the end.
I curse this damn war.
This is the end.
We will lose our lives.
We are all condemned.
They are sacrificing us.
And Bastoche?
He was very well hidden and
we couldn't find him.
The morning when we called all the names
he answered but no one could find him.
He was like a ventriloquist.
No, he was a carpenter.
For what I heard, the albatross shot him down
at the same time as your fiancé.
The explosion set afire the albatross
that went down on the German line, at home.
And what happened to the
farmer of Dordoña.
He faked death from the beginning,
but it didn't do him any good.
The Germans didn't like what
happened to their plane.
When I came back with the ranch
the shooting had begun.
Then they started bombing.
Those that haven't lived it
don't know how it is.
Your legs shake, they don't respond.
The heart beats like that of a terrified animal.
Then I saw the farmer from Dordoña get killed.
We have to attack before they kill us.
Prepare bayonets!
What I'm telling you is music
compared to what happened.
For France...Attack!
We had left behind the prisoners' bodies
When the shooting of the
machine guns started, the Maxim.
...It was a masacre.
Lavrouye kept the paper...
Bring the stretchers!
A paper? What paper?
There wasn't time to say anymore.
That night there were triple soup servings.
Favart and Chardolot were doing
the report of casualties.
Why are the five condemned
listed as soldiers of the batallion?
We are following orders.
That sounds like fiddling.
Fiddling !!
??????????????
C'mon, the soup is getting cold!
It is already cold.
But out of the 5, you only saw 3 die.
With your eyes.
Lady, false hope can only
cause pain.
No, it is not false hope.
Will you taste my plum pie?
I don't think I should!
With a little cream.
I like it when people
appreciate my cooking.
You better lie down.
We all need to rest.
Easy, easy!
You need more dignity, style!
It is clear that farming is your thing.
Hope in Mr. Mailman, I'll take
you to the next mailbox.
But my bicyle. I'll take care of it.
I'm no quitter, I have been in the war.
Let's go!
...is not my fault, i have asthma.
Yes, and asthmatic that rides a bicycle!
But near the sea.
Oh sure, near the sea!
Careful Célestin, you are not on a sidecar.
Men, they are like children, eh?
As long as they don't play at
being soldiers.
...tell Barney i want to liquidate
everything by the first days of March.
Sale the manure very expensive...
I can't believe this is about
such trivial things.
Don't you think?
It might be in code.
But the code of lovers cannot even be
solved with divine inspiration.
And Bastoche? If he was seen with the German
boots, he had to come out alive!
Not at all, miss.
Private Gordes didn't want Bastoche to come out
of the trench with the enemy boots.
If the Germans see you with them,
they will know you took them
from one of them.
Then Tina Lombardi started with a wrong clue.
Her soldier with German boots...
wasn't Bastoche!
It was Gordes, exactly madam.
He was acompanied by a young
man from the class of 17
called Derochette.
I ran into some stretcher-carriers
that had just seen them.
Eh, are you from Bingo?
Why?
Tell that Private Gordes was
wounded on the head
That we saw him next to a young
man in worse condition.
His name is Derochette,
they were going to the aid station.
Hooray for anarchy.
Anarchy!
What's wrong Mathilde?
Mathilde, open up!
Please, be reasonable!
Could you tell me what you did to her?
Nothing...
You have known for three years
that Manech is dead.
That's what I call stubborness.
No, it is called hope,
and Mr. Poux just killed it.
Can I do something to make
it up to you?
Yes
Take me to Bingo Crepuscule.
You look like an Indian princess
riding an elephant.
With her court,
riding her sadness.
Here it is!
There it is, 100 meters ahead...
...the German trench.
And the tree, the charred tree,
where is it?
Oh! the trunks and all the bodies
were used to cover both trenches.
The five of them had one hand wrapped,
we found them there, 20 meters ahead,
below a canvas with a little
dirt thrown on them.
It was not a pretty sight.
I can imagine!
The youngest looked like a boy.
Do you remember if he had a glove?
A red glove, of thick wool?
All of them had one hand wrapped,
i can remember that.
But nothing on the other hand,
I didn't see a glove.
Athos!
I don't like him removing the dirt.
On this zone you remove the dirt a little
and you could find a mine
that could blow an arm or leg in
the blink of an eye.
That's a crypt, there was a chapel
between the german line and ours...
...all that is left is a bunch of ruins.
I can't rememeber anything!
I can't recognize anything!
Is it possible Manech lost
the glove when he fell?
It was made of thick wool,tightly woven.
It fit very tight, the other
one lasted me until the end of the war.
Maybe he took it out to write
on the trunk.
That I don't know,
but I don't think so.
And what kind of red was it?
Bright red?
Intense red. It had white dots woven in it,
it looked like an apple with worms.
Excuse me for approaching you
like this, but my husband's family
suffered a lot during the war...
And I don't want anyone to see me get
near the table of a French veteran,
do you understand me?
What do you know?
Before he died, my brother
saw your fiancé...
...carve three letters on the
trunk of a tree
He had a red glove with white dots.
A friend of his told me everything.
When one of our planes shot
at your fiancé...
...he got disgusted by it.
And just after that...
...all hell broke loose.
That day, God saved the
life of that French soldier twice.
Suddenly, your men returned the attack...
...they killed my brother!
He was 23. I have come to see
his cross at the cemetery.
I'm very sorry.
Time heals everything.
You'll see!
I have to come back,
or they will start to wonder.
Then I haven't completely killed it!
What?
...hope!
Now what?
Tina Lombardi.
She is going to be beheaded.
They are calling her the Officer's Killer.
She killed Lavrouye and Thouvnel
amongst others!
She had intended to kill Mariscal Piton.
When I think you used a wheel
chair to get my pity...
You are the only one i have
agreed to talk to...
...becuse I know we are alike.
Fine! Let's leave it.
What I did, you could have done too.
No, I don't think so.
I would have been too scared.
I am not afraid.
Nor do I regret anything.
Except my hair...
...they will cut it before executing me.
I will look like Joan of Arc
when i meet my Ange.
Why Mariscal Piton,
what did he do?
It was his idea to throw out the
mutilated soldiers from the trenches.
And why not Poincare,
he denied the pardon.
What, you don't know?
He had pardoned them, the five of them.
It is only a license.
Lavrouye kept the paper...
And why did Lavrouye do that?
Because pigs act like pigs!
But don't worry, I took care of him.
We have carried out the same investigation.
Each one in her own way.
Looking for any Bingo veterans...
...I found a sick man that had healed
my Ange and the others.
This sick man, Philippot,
had seen one of the five.
A strong young man, wounded on the head
He was strong, wounded on the head,
he had German boots.
According to him, he had German boots.
And was carrying a thin young man.
I think so...
...i mean, i'm sure!
...strong, wounded on the head.
his boss suggested he kept quiet.
You, better than anyone, can
understand the hope I felt.
But some time later I met the one
who killed all my illusions.
First Sargent Favart.
He told me how that Thouvenel
pig murdered my Ange.
With a single shot.
I also took care of him.
I only had one thing in mind...
...eliminate everyone that hurt my Ange.
Your Ange left this for you.
Revenge is useless, try to be happy.
And don't waste your life for me.
Ange
...Gordes, the one that traded
the German boots with Bastoche...
Was he strong?
Biscotte?
No, he wasn't athletic,
he was like you or me.
And, have you heard anything
about Jean de Desrochelles?
Desrochelles?
Ah yes, he was not very sociable,
he lived alone with his mother.
I'm sorry, I have to leave you.
I'm leaving in one hour for Venezuela.
Good luck Célestin.
Same to you.
When I think you didn't tell
me about Poincare's pardon...
It would only have made things worse, please understand.
I have a last favor to ask of you Pierre Marie.
I suppose it has to do with Bingo.
Son of the bookshop owner Paúl Desrochelles
dead February of 1897.
Jean Desrochelles that's it!
Wait!. Yes in Somme.
Yes, fine. Thanks
Tell me Mr. Pierre, Tina Lombardi,
you must have known what she had planned!
It was wiser not to interfere with her.
If things get ugly,
the spy disappears ?
No...those who spy try not to be seen.
By the way I have a last clue to give to you.
Jean Desrochelles
evacuated from Somme Front on January
of the 17th, only relative, her mother.
Widow of Paul Desrochelles.
Rue de la vie 22.
And what do you want me to do?
Did you want to talk to me?
Yes
My brother's friend, the one
i talked to you about,
he remembered something...
...that could be of interest to you.
The two French soldiers that escorted him,
that Monday morning,
wanted to go again through "No man's land"
They saw the bodies of the condemned,
one of them was in some kind of cavity
and the two French seemed surprised.
I don't know if that could be useful miss?
Thanks.
...tell Berney that I want to
liquidate everything by the first day of March.
Sell all the manure really expensive,
you better be careful with him.
Sell all the manure really expensive.
Well, it has to be in code.
Mr. Pire called.
He didn't find anything in Saenz...
I know.
Hello, who is it?
Yes miss, I remember you
Berney? No that doesn't sound familiar.
I don't know anyone with that name.
Benoit Notre-Dame fertilizes his lands with
his animals' manure, he didn't buy any.
Thanks father.
I have to decipher that letter.
I'm getting close.
I will be...Berney...March...sell... everything.
Say...nothing...no one
Benoît.
Excuse me sir, the farm
at the end of the world?
The last house, at the end of the road.
And what if he doesn't come?
He'll come! Don't worry.
Come back in two hours.
Hello Mathilde.
It is dangerous to bring back the dead.
When I saw your announcement in the paper
I knew it was a matter of time until the
gendarmes catch me.
Don't worry, Ii could have killed you...
...but i didn't.
You're not only a thief,
but also a pyromaniac!
I couldn't kill you.
When we need to kill a rabbit or a
chicken my wife takes care of it.
War has left me unable to do so.
You know what I want to hear!
Is Manech alive?
The last time I saw him he
was not well.
But he is stronger that he seems.
We have to stay together.
When the fighting ended, I rested to
gain back my strength.
What do you want?
Notre-Dame?
Then the Corsican decided to surrender.
After that they killed the welder from Paris.
Then your fiancé carved some letters on the trunk
of a tree and the German albatross arrived.
I regained my consciousness when the earth trembled.
I still don't understand what happened...
...the only thing i saw was a trap door
that the projectile uncovered.
...For France! Attack!
They got into No Man's Land and
on the second line
they were all killed by the shotguns. A few
hours later, I was awakened by some voices.
Oh my God!
Bastoche is dead!
We can't leave him here.
We will come for him later,
he won't go anywhere.
Oh Bastoche is dead
Look! That one is moving.
That one is the kid,
he is going to die too.
The explosion destroyed the trap door.
One of the soldiers was badly wounded.
Bastoche is dead!
We are all going to die.
He was Bastoche's friend, the one who
had taken the German boots.
After eating I smoked his tobacco.
Then I heard more voices.
Oh shit!
Isn't that the kid!
What is he doing here?
And the farmer from Dordoña, where is he?
Sir!
I'm cold!
Be calm!
Although he was badly wounded,
your fiancé wanted to live,
I could see it in his eyes.
I carried him on my shoulders and
started walking by the trench.
He had a high fever,
i could feel it on my back.
He was delirious.
He talked about a heart beating
in his hand.
Private! The hospital is 500 meters ahead.
Do you want us to carry him on the stretcher?
No. If you find any Bingo sub-officer,
Tell him that Private Gordes went to the
hospital with Soldier Desrochelles.
Ok, as you wish.
I arrived before the explosion.
I have to say that the major state
didn't have a better idea than to place
the hospital in a hangar
with a blimp full of hydrogen.
The kid was evacuated in the convoy
that just left.
Will he be ok?
The wound on the hip is not bad
but the pneumonia doesn't look good.
I listed you by the name
on your tags.
I don't want to know anything else.
Good luck.
The lever!
Please!
Then I arrived at Berney, on foot.
I couldn't have known if my
wife had received the letter.
So everyday
I waited for her at the station.
With the money of the sale we
bought this farm.
The farthest we could find
I called it "The end of the world".
Goodbye.
It is curious, you punctured
your life line
Is normal
I died...at Bingo Crepuscule
just like your boyfriend.
If you ever find Jean Desrochelles alive.
Let me know.
You know where to find me.
Come on in! Feel at home,
at Christmas you can enter through the chimney.
For Miss Mathilde
Ok. I'll give it to her later.
I think you should wake her.
What is going on?
He is alive!
Don't move Mathilde,
whatever happens, don't move.
I'm on my way.
Germain Pire
I'm such a fool!
Nicer than the marten and
much faster than the gazelle.
He is alive and well but
he can't remember anything.
His amnesia is total. He even had
to learn to read and write again.
The psychiatrist that treated him since
the 17th doesn't have much hope.
But everyone knows...
...that there are as many amnesias
as amnesiacs.
Where is he?
Orphan for the second time. He just lost
his adoptive mother
Pierre Marie, do you know Mr. Pire?
Only by reputation.
Nice to meet you.
Mathilde I'm telling you i won't
believe it until I see it.
With your own eyes!
When Jean Desrochelles was born, her mother was
40 years old and she had no other children.
When the gendarmes came for him...
...to support the front.
Yes.
She fell into a depression.
One day she received the visit of a
mate of his son, his name was...
Chardolot!
...sadly it was Jean
A bullet had reached him,
and he had been dead for hours.
I also have to tell you...
It is possible that the youngest of the
condemned stole Jean's identity.
Exchanging their tags.
I think she lost her mind the
day they called her to the hospital.
To tell her that her son was there.
He is asleep.
I'll leave you alone.
Good morning!
Who are you?
Your mother, little one.
I am your mother!
I have conducted the official investigation and
Mrs. Desrochelles died two months ago.
She was hit by a truck after having
a discussion with a merchant.
And this is not a lie.
We know that!
Mam please, calm down.
Mrs. Desrochelles didn't suffer, she died immediately.
I'm not crying about that.
I'm an idiot.
I didn't believe you little one.
Please forgive me!
I should've known.
What she later would call
the Millie expedition:
the sun, the sky and all of nature,
were on her side.
Flaunting her femininity,
she fixed herself as best as she could.
Dressed in white, the color of purity,
she painted her lips for the ocassion.
She outlined her eyebrows and without
rimel to extend her eyelashes.
She knew what would happen if
she lost her composure.
We told him about your visit.
We told him that a young woman
that he loved very much was
coming to see him.
He asked your name and
thought it was beautiful.
He is waiting in the garden.
Does it hurt you when you walk?
Do you want to see what i'm doing?
I'll let you see it when I'm done.
Why do you cry?
And Mathilde sat there with her back
straight against the chair's back.
With the hands on her skirt and looked at him
Under the harmony that enveloped them,
Under the light of the garden,
Mathilde looked at him,
looked at him...
...looked at him