The place where you sleep.
Your kids, your wife.
But when it's your fault...
...it shouldn't be so
easy to sleep at night.
Especially when we know where you live.
Barry Redmond, CEO of Lorex Oil.
2641 River Rock Road, East Hampton.
You dumped fifteen million barrels of
crude into the Atlantic.
We don't care how rich you are.
We want all those who are guilty
to experience the terror of their crimes.
Because it shouldn't be
so easy to get away with murder.
Lie to us... we'll lie to you.
Spy on us... we'll spy on you.
Poison our habitat...
...we'll poison yours.
We are The East
and this is just the beginning.
We will counterattack three corporations...
...in the next six months
for their worldwide terrorism.
No matter what happens today,
you're still a winner to me.
I'm only a winner if I get it.
Your mysterious assignment.
I think I knew more about you
when you worked for the FBI.
Want to meet at Clyde's after work
and watch the game?
You're on.
Wish me luck.
Serving the nation's capital,
you're listening to Washington D.C.'s...
...premier Christian radio.
Hello, Jane. Good to see you.
Good morning.
Jane?
Sharon's ready for you.
Who would you choose?
Me.
I'm unexpected.
Being unexpected
is the only advantage that matters.
But you chose Tom.
Why do you say that?
He's your last interview.
You remind me of myself at your age.
Smart enough for it to be a disadvantage.
You haven't failed
at anything yet... not really.
That kind of arrogance is dangerous.
They'd smell it on you.
I've been researching this field
exclusively for nine months.
You had a goldfish as a kid?
- Sure.
- You remember taking it home?
You had to float the bag in the aquarium...
...gradually letting the water in
little by little, so the fish can adjust.
Okay.
Don't follow your ego out of the bag early.
That's how you end up dead.
You put your first choice in the middle.
Because to put it last is expected.
Talk to your doctor to see
if Denoxin is right for you.
Be sure to ask about the free trial offer.
Oil tycoon Barry Redmond
is the latest high-profile CEO...
...to be targeted by
the eco-terrorist group, The East.
Redmond announced he is taking...
...a leave of absence to spend time with
his family, pending...
Welcome to Washington Dulles
International Airport.
I was thinking maybe
when you get back from Dubai...
- ...maybe you and I...
- Tim?
Can we just see if I can
pull this off first?
Yeah.
I'm going to miss you.
Text me when you land?
This is the final boarding call
for Emirates flight 2046 to Dubai...
...at gate D-30.
Final boarding call for
flight 2046 to Dubai.
Hiller Brood is the top...
...private intelligence firm in the world.
Anti-corporate terrorism is all about risk.
Our job is to assess that risk for you.
Are you dealing with a fly?
It's harmless, easily swatted.
Or is it a mosquito?
Can it draw blood?
Or... is the threat the black widow?
Sending you to the hospital,
crashing your stock.
Let's say it's a fly.
You deal with it internally.
Mosquito, our operative handles it...
...neutralizing the threat. Now...
...if it's the black widow...
...we'll have to see.
We can extract our operative,
liaise with the FBI and leave no trace.
Gentlemen, we are in thirty-two countries,
protecting your good names.
Which is why it is essential
very few have ever heard of ours.
Please give me the strength to do well.
To not be arrogant.
But to not be weak.
Amen.
Hi. Checking in.
Where are you?
Delaware Seashore State Park.
I've been sleeping here.
How'd you get there?
Rideshares off Craigslist.
Smart. Any luck?
No. Building confidence. Meeting dropouts,
counterculture types, freegans.
Have fun.
You get any matches on the pictures
I sent you?
Just dead ends. If any of these kids
are part of The East, someone's been...
...covering their online footprint.
I haven't met anyone
even close to that sophisticated.
What about Trevor Landen?
Served a year for ski resort vandalism.
Facebook links him to
the Katrina Anarchist Kitchen.
I saw him again last night.
He mentioned hopping to Pittsburgh.
I'll check him out.
Anti-corporate activism initially surfaced
with groups like Earth First!...
...but now more radical cells,
like The East...
It's picking up speed.
I'm looking for The East tag.
I've heard folks from
The East hop out in Pittsburgh.
I heard The East doesn't exist.
Said I ain't no doctor
Ain't no doctor's son
But I'll cling to him
Until the doctor come
Everybody out! Move it now!
Let's go! Get up!
Move it, move it. Come on.
Move! Let's go!
Get off my train!
Let's go.
That means you, too, you dirty queer!
We're moving out.
Wipe that off your face.
No one's being violent.
Hey, that's a girl, you animal!
Who gives a shit?
Who the hell are you?
I'm cuffing you till the cops get here.
Come on, come on.
What are you doing?!
Stop, you stinking trash!
Come on. Get in.
Go, go, go.
Are you hurt?
- I can help you.
- No, I'm okay. Just hungry.
I know a good place to eat.
Eat these. You need some sugar.
I'm going to dive the next one. Stay here.
Trevor was a fed.
I've been following a fed.
Jesus Christ.
I'm in some weird van.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to check into a hotel.
Take a shower.
Jane?
Let me call you back.
They're good, yeah?
Let me see that arm.
- No, I'm fine.
- Hold on.
Is that from the fence?
You need stitches.
I can't go to a hospital.
Do you have a phone?
You only have nine numbers.
- What are you doing?
- You want our help?
Don't...
Hello?
Sarah, are you there?
Just say something, honey,
so I know you're okay.
The dogs miss you.
All right, I'll talk and you can listen.
You don't have to say anything
if you don't want to.
Sarah...
Sarah?
What is this, Luca?
I thought you were scavenging for the jam.
I was. She's in trouble, dude.
No, Luca, she needs to go.
She needs to see Doc.
You should talk to Benji first.
Doc?
This is Sarah. She slipped the cops.
She's got a bad gash.
Benji know?
Sit down.
Drink this. It'll numb the pain.
I'm okay.
It's no chemical. Purely vegetal.
- What is that?
- Superglue.
That doesn't seem safe.
It's a trick I learned in med school.
It's perfectly safe.
You're a real doctor.
Sort of.
Most people don't like to look.
I'm looking because I don't want to.
My uncle has Parkinson's.
That's not Parkinson's.
I was in Kenya as an aid worker
and I took an antibiotic called Denoxin.
Had an adverse reaction.
Snapped tendons, seizures, brain damage.
From an antibiotic?
Did you sue them?
Oh, no. Those side effects
are listed on the side of the bottle.
That's how they rape you.
In broad daylight.
I feel... I feel dizzy. Do you have water?
Just relax. Don't fight it.
Don't fight it.
You smell like soap.
I snuck into a hotel.
I'm just here to watch you.
Who's deaf in your family?
No one.
My friend growing up.
What's your name?
Sarah.
I'm Eve.
Sometimes
living like
a stray dog
sucks.
We've been squatting here
for three months. It's nice.
Benji doesn't like to stay
in one place that long.
Who's...
- ...Benji?
- You'll meet him.
Benji made me speak.
He told me I was waking people up...
...with my voice.
You have to put this on.
I'm not wearing that.
If you want to come to dinner,
you wear this.
Sarah Moss from Arizona.
Who used to work in an office
but is now a traveler.
Sit.
Since you're new...
...we'll wait till you begin.
I've never eaten this way before.
Do as you wish,
but we'd rather wait till you begin.
There's no wrong way.
What are you doing?
I'm going to hitch a ride.
I can't let you leave on your own.
Luca will drive you back
to wherever he picked you up.
Come get something to eat before you go.
So you can keep making
an example of me to your followers?
I have no followers.
Well, I think you all made your point.
Really?
What do you think we figured out?
That I'm selfish.
Maybe that's what you figured out.
Why does self-righteousness
always go hand-in-hand...
...with resistance movements?
I don't know.
I hear you got in some kind of trouble.
I can handle myself.
So why come here?
I was hurt. There was a doctor.
And now you're better.
So you should go.
You wouldn't like
what you find here anyway.
What?
I said, you wouldn't like
what you find here, anyway.
Why?
Because this is the end of the road.
There's nowhere to hide.
And I'm not tough enough for the truth.
No. I think you're not soft enough for it.
No one should be by the road.
She's right.
Let's go back inside.
Not her.
Who is she?
Who are you?
I'm Sarah.
- Drive her back.
- Izzy.
She took a punch for me today
and fought off a bull.
Since when do we turn away outlaws?
Two nights.
That's it.
Can we get a hand?
Found her shot dead in the woods.
Thrill kill.
Idiots.
The best way to honor her
is to not let her go to waste.
You can remove the innards.
Cut along here.
Slow.
Slowly.
More to the left.
Not that far!
Intestine got clipped.
That's just shit you're smelling.
Every day our society
abuses the environment.
What's the easiest way to handle that pain?
Never talk about it.
Yep.
To bury the horror, pretend it isn't real.
If it's real, you have to do something.
Like this deer.
Someone hurt her.
Someone you trusted, because...
...you trusted the system, trusted
the government, trusted the church.
Please stop talking about it.
Feel her.
Feel the last of her living parts.
What if they share?
People don't share champagne.
- Champagne, sir?
- May I have your glass?
Enjoy.
Champagne, sir?
Doc!
He's having a seizure!
Get away.
Doc, we're all here for you.
Relax.
Don't say another word.
The stress of all this
is too much for his system.
What if this happens when we're there?
Why?
I'm
undercover.
Do you know what happens
to terrorists these days?
I'm not a terrorist.
Life
in prison.
He's back.
- Hey, Doc.
- Doc, are you okay?
Sit up.
I know
Eve
is not your real name.
No one uses their real name.
J - E - S - S - I - C - A
JESSICA
How do you know that name?
I know
a lot
about you.
One, two, three.
Let's get him back inside. We're done.
Where's Eve?
- Don't tell them. Don't.
- Where did she go?
Jessica.
Don't throw
everything away
because these people
have convinced you
that no one
could love you
but them.
- Where did she go?
- Eve!
Eve, you have to stay focused,
even when shit hits the fan.
I had to take a piss. Relax.
- What did Eve mean?
- I'm not sure, but her stuff is gone.
I knew it.
Eve's chickenshit.
Better to know now than later.
This always happens.
And you always act so surprised.
When it comes to actually breaking
the law, most people can't handle it.
We shouldn't have given an important role
to a 22-year-old deaf girl.
We don't need Eve.
- We can do it without her.
- I disagree. It's too risky.
He's a child. He needs distraction.
Don't look at me. I'm not an option.
What was Eve supposed to do?
- Maybe I can do it.
- No.
No.
- You can't.
- Why not?
She only needs to know her part.
You'd only know your role, right before
you do it. Would you be up for that?
You helped me when I needed it.
I'll help you.
Are you serious?
There are consequences.
I know.
I'll do it.
It's not a good idea. She can't do it.
Sorry.
All in favor?
So if anything goes wrong, we split up...
...go back to the streets. Lawyer's number?
212-555-0106.
You only have one job on this jam.
Keep your mark engaged in you and not us.
Okay?
He's a sex addict, so...
...you have that in your favor.
Thomas, you son of a bitch!
You a famous doctor yet?
Peter. This is Sarah,
the girl I told you about.
Very nice. Want a lick?
In this weather? I'll pass.
- You're not deaf.
- No, that was a joke.
You're a sick dude. I love it.
You got nasty in Africa, didn't you?
At Groton, this guy's name
comes up all the time.
Tommy wins this award,
Tommy's banging so-and-so.
The past few years,
I haven't heard the name.
Which is, frankly, quite a relief.
I feel like less of a loser.
Porty, my two friends I was telling
you about, Edward and Isabella.
Porty McCabe. Porty McCabe.
Tommy, you're kind of rolling deep.
I mentioned them in my email.
Porty, come on.
Tommy.
I'm sorry.
They're my friends.
I thought it was a party.
It is, it is.
But it's kind of a work party. So it's...
You brought us to a work party?
Yeah, yeah, but it'll be fine.
It'll be fine, come on.
Come on!
You're protecting the jam. I get it. But...
...I don't want to mess this up because
I don't know what's going on.
You're doing fine. Just don't leave the tent.
Keep Porty occupied.
And don't drink the champagne.
I have to go.
Can I get you a drink?
- No, I'm great.
- You are great, aren't you?
I guess a match isn't in our future.
I like hard courts.
You're too young to know better.
Edward, this is Rory Houston.
He's on Mr. McCabe's board.
Nice meeting you, sir. Edward Eneicher.
I didn't realize you had a glass, honey.
Want some champagne?
Thank you.
Have you felt the fake grass courts
with your bare feet?
It's impossible to tell the difference.
That's why there's such a fervent
pro-life movement in this country.
I don't follow.
Everything else is dead or dying.
Even the grass is fake.
We should probably go find...
- Porty.
- Excuse us.
Cool it.
Here you go.
Bob, Sarah. This is my stepfather.
This is his party.
Robert. Is this your friend
from boarding school?
I went to public school.
Me, too. I believe in pulling yourself up
by your bootstraps.
Nothing to stop you
but laziness and terrorism.
Where did you find this firecracker?
It's nice to see so many people in uniform.
You're in the military?
I work in the private sector now.
Robert is being modest.
He's the McCabe in McCabe-Grey.
The pharmaceutical company.
Excuse me.
Sir?
Can I use your phone?
Yes, but this one's actually dying.
I have one in my room.
You want to...? Wonderful.
This way.
Just a minute!
Our Vice President, Paige Williams.
Tonight we're happy to announce...
...the government will be supplying
our miracle drug, Denoxin...
...to every man and woman in uniform.
Allow me to introduce our CEO...
...who has led this particular charge
and welcomed us into his home.
Mr. Robert McCabe.
Thank you, Paige.
It's me. Can you hear me?
- Where are you?
- Cape Cod.
I'm at the home of
the CEO of McCabe-Grey.
I think they're poisoning
the company with their own drug.
- When?
- Right now.
- What's the potential damage?
- I don't know.
But the side effects seem severe.
There are families downstairs.
You talking to your boyfriend?
You there?
It wouldn't be on the market
if it were life threatening, okay?
No, just listen.
Stay calm. You hold your cover.
That's our asset.
But people could get hurt.
I have no idea...
...what the dosage is.
McCabe-Grey is not my client.
Better? Who were you talking to?
Told my mom we got here safely.
A little old to be checking in with Mom,
don't you think?
- I came up here to use your phone.
- Yeah, you did.
Where you going?
Stop. Stop!
Calm down!
Tonight marks a special occasion...
...in the McCabe-Grey family with
this announcement.
It warms my heart to be surrounded
by so many familiar faces...
...at our party.
At McCabe-Grey, we always ask...
...how can we keep people healthy...
...so they can enjoy their lives
to the fullest?
- I'd like to refresh your glass for you.
- And among those we care about most...
...are our young men and women
in the Armed Forces.
Hi, I'll bring a new
glass in just a second.
I'll take that for you.
Pardon me. Let me take that, thank you.
Protecting them from
Third World diseases...
...and biochemical agents
such as anthrax...
...allowing them to continue bringing
freedom and democracy...
...to the darkest regions of the world.
To them...
...and to us.
I'm sorry we couldn't tell you before
we started. It must have been hard.
What's going to happen to those people?
Nothing.
If their drug is as safe as they claim.
But you know Porty.
Couldn't you have just
talked to his stepdad?
Please.
They make $1.4 billion
a year off of Denoxin alone.
They don't give a shit.
Maybe, but wouldn't people know about it?
Doc...
...tell her.
She deserves to know.
Tell her everything.
My sister traveled with me
to do aid work in Kenya.
She took Denoxin.
I prescribed it as an anti-malarial.
Some weeks later,
she woke up one morning...
...and didn't recognize
her face in the mirror.
The drug I had prescribed...
...had damaged her brain.
It's a condition known as prosopagnosia.
No one believed it was the Denoxin, but...
...I prescribed myself the same drug.
And day by day...
...my mind and body deteriorate.
She killed herself some months later.
We are The East.
And we are your wakeup call.
And we are not hiding from you.
We are you.
We are the morning you got off the
treadmill and ran under the open sky.
We're the first time you kissed someone
and they kissed you back.
We are the night you couldn't sleep.
The night you stared at the ceiling,
thinking, "Is this it?
"Is this the best life has to offer?"
No.
There is a freedom in you
that knows no fear.
Last night, we gave
pharmaceutical giant McCabe-Grey...
...a taste of their best-selling poison,
Denoxin.
We encourage the media to follow
the company's members.
We will counterattack
two more corporations for their injustice.
We will not show mercy.
So you spin the bottle.
Whoever it lands on is your partner.
You ask them permission
for what you want to do.
Like, "Can I shake your hand?"
And they'll say, "Yeah", or...
..."No, I'd rather not."
Or they'll pose an alternative, like...
..."Why don't we high
five?" Or something.
Here you go.
Can Thumbs and I hug you for one minute?
All right.
Come on.
This is ridiculous.
Thank you.
I would like you and Thumbs
to hug me for one minute.
Can I kiss your belly button?
You may.
Thank you.
Can I kiss you?
Oh, that's good.
Okay. You may.
Can I kiss you?
Can we hug instead?
Sure.
I can't believe these were
going to a landfill.
Tess.
- Where'd you harvest?
- Hartford.
New apples come in, old ones are dumped.
Give me a hand?
Where's Benji been?
He sometimes takes days to himself.
Guys?
You should see this.
Shocking news Friday that the board of
McCabe-Grey...
...had been drugged by a terrorist group...
...calling themselves The East.
McCabe-Grey Vice President...
...Paige Williams spoke to reporters today.
I had a bad rash
and a nasty stomach ache...
...but those are mild side effects
for a drug that has...
...and will continue to save
thousands of lives.
As you can see, I'm in perfect health,
so we at McCabe-Grey...
...are glad to be given a taste of
our own medicine. It tastes great.
We should have used the higher dose.
They've paid hackers to break
the encryption on my last video.
They won't break it, but...
- You don't know that.
- I do.
Mine makes theirs look like pig Latin.
We still have two more jams
before we leave.
I think we should let other collectives draw
some attention first, and cool out for a bit.
I agree.
Let's break for a while.
It's a good opportunity to keep up cover
on the outside, for those of us who do.
If you like it better, stay.
If not...
...come back.
We have a lot of work to do.
Ladies and gentlemen,
next and final stop, Union Station.
Watch your step as you exit the train.
Thank you for choosing Amtrak.
Wow.
Your hair.
I didn't even recognize you.
How was Dubai?
Can we not talk about it?
So you missed me a little bit?
Excited to sleep in your own bed?
Mr. Douglas, step aside
for additional screening.
Hello, Jane. Good to see you back.
The group says they have two jams left...
...until they disappear and resurface with
a larger organization.
How will they do that?
There's a girl they call Tess.
She's interfacing with other cells
in the deep Web.
What cells?
We assume other likeminded groups.
But we don't know who or where.
We need to start information sharing with
the Bureau to cover ourselves.
You've been in the field quite some time.
There are too many unanswered questions.
Too many questions.
Understood, but we were able to identify
two key members.
That's William Woodhouse III.
We're waiting on real estate records...
...but we think it's his property the group
thinks they're squatting on.
Using Stanford medical records,
we were able to identify Dr. Thomas Ayers.
That is his current Facebook page.
"Mimi" is a fake profile.
That's how 450 friends think
they're in touch with you...
...when no one has actually seen you
for years.
Okay, Bob, exactly what
are we talking about?
We're talking about a class of drugs...
It seems so loud.
You usually ask me to turn it up.
You okay?
Just jet lag. I'm just tired.
I know you're not allowed
to talk about what's happening...
...but do you want to...
...talk to me about how you feel?
Like I've been in a foreign country.
But I was there for such a long time that
it all started to feel really familiar.
So when I came home...
...it feels like a foreign country, too.
That's hard.
Yeah, it sucks.
Maybe we can make something
familiar for dinner tonight.
To welcome you back into this country.
Like what?
Like spaghetti and meatballs.
Really?
Okay, yeah.
Or, we can go to the store
together and find...
What's she saying?
Turn it up!
Why?
And...
...I don't know, it's hard...
It's hard to communicate
what it feels like to have...
...your mind and your body taken hostage.
And I don't just mean...
...my body. I mean, my mind.
My mind, I feel different. I feel...
I don't feel...
I don't recognize myself in the mirror.
I used to hear about their stories.
How do they let this stuff on the market?
Oh, my God.
We never took any of that stuff, did we?
No. I checked your medical records.
I forgot something at work...
...so I have to run to the office.
I'll stop at the store on my way home.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
I do love to be proven wrong.
When you came to me...
...with those videos
and wanted to start a file on those kids...
...I thought I'd recruited
another Bureau idiot.
Robert McCabe called me himself.
I told him, in one month's time...
...I would have the identities of every
person who poisoned his company.
We'll send you back in.
Why not just raid the house?
Have you been smoking pot with them?
They don't smoke pot.
We're not some blue-collar security firm. I
didn't send you there to find the location.
I have GPS for that.
We spend 99% of our time
pitching clients we never sign.
I want to know what the next two jams are,
avert those disasters...
...come out looking like a leader
in the intelligence community...
...with two new clients.
Then you can lock them up till middle age.
What are we not talking about?
Getting attached to them is all right.
It's human.
We know it happens.
It's the first thing we cover in training.
If you spent every day with
a pack of White supremacists...
...you'd develop feelings for them, too.
But do not get soft.
If they find out who you are, they won't
give a second thought to your destruction.
Sarah!
You dance, don't you? Come on.
Guess you didn't like it better
on the outside.
The jam worked.
Is that why you came back?
I came back because
I missed being uncomfortable.
You want to keep going?
Yeah.
Sorry.
That's okay.
You left. I thought you got lost.
I couldn't sleep.
- Want to go for a ride?
- Yeah.
We can go down there.
You know these woods well.
Have you lived here before?
Yeah. I was born here.
How did the house burn?
I set it on fire.
Where was your family?
My parents were already dead.
We were out on a night sail...
...Mom, Dad, and my dog, Growl.
Your dog's name was Growl?
We hit a submerged shipping container
and the boat capsized.
Growl and I ended up beside it,
and Mom and Dad underneath.
At first, I could hear them in there...
...and then I couldn't.
So when I got back, I had all this money
and this huge house and everything.
And people had changed.
They treated me differently.
Everyone. My friends,
my uncles, my grandparents.
But what scared me...
...was the fact that I let them.
That I liked it.
I saw how money corrupts everything
and I felt that it started to corrupt me.
That's why I set the house on fire.
Things would be easier
if we didn't feel the need to fight.
If we could just let go.
Maybe you should.
Just disappear one night.
Can we wash you?
I don't think I'll feel comfortable
unless you say it.
Yeah.
You all can wash me.
Are you okay?
I don't think so.
Nothing will happen that you don't want.
You're in control.
Do you want to stop?
No.
I want to keep going.
Okay, we're going to wash you
as fast as we can. Will you help?
Sweetie! Sweetie, please! Hey!
Set a good example for your brother.
Stop it.
I have an idea.
You do my head and I'll do my body,
then it's faster.
Why is she timing them?
Because the water's filled with
arsenic and lead.
It's Ambler, Pennsylvania.
The whole town's downstream
from a Hawkstone mine.
They've pumped waste
into that ground for years.
Just like Sago, where I grew up.
Get in bed and I'll read you a story.
Pick one out.
We put the house on the market...
...once we found out the water was eating
away at the enamel in Taylor's teeth, but...
...unfortunately, no one wants to buy
a house in a town with poisoned water.
My husband's work gets
a great deal on bottled water.
We use it to brush our teeth.
We're really lucky.
The little one died three months ago.
Brain tumors.
Okay, I think that's enough.
Okay, do we agree on the plan?
An eye for an eye.
Can't be more. Can't be less.
So, technically, we could kill them
and be in your moral clear.
That's not funny.
How we perform a jam
is as important as its outcome.
What outcome? Nobody cares about
that freaky Paige Williams anymore.
The McCabe-Grey jam
worked like gangbusters.
True, but it's blown over now.
People don't respond to your intellectual
bullshit. They respond to firepower.
It's like 9/11. That's why I was in Iraq.
You got to get people mad.
Okay, just wait.
What are the real risks here?
Twenty-five years for kidnapping,
if they can prove intent to bodily harm.
Sarah...
...what do you think?
I think hurting people
isn't going to bring that little boy back.
Paige is going to have seizures like Doc.
We saved tens of thousands of
people from that fate.
But if we hurt people,
aren't we just as bad as they are?
Then why are you here?
What, I have to agree? Are we fascists?
Of course not.
You told me five years ago,
individuals had to be held accountable.
I joined this group for this jam.
This is my jam.
It's our jam! We work together.
Don't forget that.
Hi. I'm Diane Wisecarver,
senior-level management at Hawkstone.
You'll notice behind me here,
an array of large machinery...
...but rest assured, it
is state of the art...
...up to the latest environmental
codes and standards.
This beautiful lake is a natural wildlife
preserve. It's tested twice a year.
We have an abundance of
wildlife that visits.
And we've had all nearby creeks tested
by three independent agencies.
There is nothing wrong with
the water in Ambler.
Katie.
Hello, Dad.
What are you doing here?
I set this up.
You're so different.
Beautiful.
Not that you haven't always been beautiful.
More beautiful in a dress.
You're a woman.
All grown up.
Where have you been?
Around.
Traveling.
Have you seen your mother?
Does she know you're back?
I'm not back.
And since when
do you care about my mother?
Looks like you stopped
running with those freaks.
Are you okay?
Are you short on funds?
I don't need anything from you.
I came to ask you a question.
You came all the way to this hotel...
...and my company's summit...
...to ask me a question.
Shoot.
Did you know Johnny Perkins
died from brain tumors?
Who the hell is Johnny Perkins?
He died from cancer because the water
in his house was filled with arsenic.
He was four.
And he lived in Ambler.
What is this?
Is this part of some rehab or something?
A lot of people have been hurt...
because of what you've done.
I just need to hear you say it out loud.
I'm not playing this game with you.
You know how they say two wrongs
don't make a right?
I'd say whoever said that
has never been wronged before.
Sit.
Help! Someone call an ambulance!
I'm a doctor! I can help!
What's wrong with the fish?
Nothing is wrong with the fish. They're
dying because you poisoned the water.
This has gone on far enough.
We've had enough of this.
It's 2:58.
Almost time to get in.
I don't understand.
It's pretty simple, really.
You make your living by poisoning
this creek and other rivers and lakes.
You separate yourselves
in gated communities with golf courses...
...from the world you're destroying.
From the families who cannot afford
to move away from this creek.
Or from the cancer their children
are dying of.
You create for a living...
...toxic chemicals that will
outlive us all and feel nothing.
But tonight, you will feel something.
Strip.
Be reasonable.
You're threatening our lives.
You're the CEO of this company.
How many lives are you threatening?
- We can't go in there right now.
- Why?
Why can't you go in there?
What happens at three?
Take off your clothes or
I will do it for you.
We could pay you.
We could pay you to have it cleaned up.
- Just tell her the truth.
- Shut up, Sarah.
Time to get in.
We can pay you!
That's enough! Izzy!
Sarah, back off!
- I didn't know!
- You did!
You did know!
It's just easier to pretend you didn't!
Get in the water!
All right, okay, yes!
Yes, we treat the coal!
We treat the coal because
it burns more efficiently!
Yes, we do! And we dump the slurry in the
river because it has to go someplace!
People need power for their homes!
Get in the water!
She said it! We made our point!
We made our point!
God help me.
I don't know how it got this far.
I'm sorry, Katie.
I'm so...
...sorry.
- Pigs!
- Let's go!
Dad?
Izzy, we have to go!
Get off!
Let me go!
Freeze!
- Get on the bike!
- Let me go!
Get on the bike!
Okay, we're here.
Izzy, we're here.
Izzy?
Doc! Doc! Clear the table.
Somebody get Doc! Clear the table!
- She's been shot.
- Where's the wound?
In the back.
- We need a light.
- I'll get it.
I need a BMV mask. The one I showed you.
It's in my room. And I need alcohol.
And salt! Get salt.
I need to cut her dress away.
Can we flip her?
Easy.
Okay, roll her back.
I need to get to her abdomen.
Cut that cloth away.
I want you to breathe.
Just breathe.
Keep breathing. Keep breathing.
When she's out, I want you to put the mask
over her face. Regular breaths.
- She's out.
- You got it.
Squeeze it. Full compression.
Guys, he needs to focus. Get out.
You okay?
Give it to me.
Tell me what to do.
Give it to her.
Come here. Put it over your arms.
Okay, scalpel.
You need to make an incision
a quarter-inch deep...
...and two and a half inches across.
- Starting here?
- Yeah.
Good. Okay.
You'll have to go through the muscle
tissue, so you have to go deeper.
Go along the same line.
Okay, just clamp that.
Push it deeper. Now close it.
Okay, just lay that down.
You're going to need to
make your hand flat and push it...
...through the abdomen
into the large intestine.
You need to feel around
in there and find the bullet.
Oh, my God, you got it.
Thank you. We have to sew that up.
Why did you come here?
Sometimes people die before they're ready.
Perfect relationships end in ruin.
Adventures peter out.
Izzy always said she wasn't scared.
She was scared shitless.
But she didn't flee.
That's what made her braver than me.
Benji!
Stop it! Stop it!
Where are you going to go?
What did you expect, that it would be easy?
That it would be painless?
No.
A revolution is never easy.
But that doesn't make it
any less important.
You can't just walk away from it.
Yes, I can!
I would trade the revolution
for Izzy any day.
That's it.
That's the difference between you and me.
That was a Hawkstone jam.
It obviously has not been released.
The group has unraveled
without executing their last jam.
Her name was Kate Cannon.
Her cover identity was Isabella Duncan.
They called her Izzy.
She dropped out of Brown her junior year...
...when she met William.
I'm subletting a basement apartment
in Georgetown.
I don't want to lie to you.
You can still spend Christmas with
my family. You're still family.
But it's just been a long time since
I knew what you were thinking.
I haven't been to Dubai.
I've been in an anarchist collective
not that far from here.
Why does someone do a job like this?
It looks like they're regrouping.
You have to go back.
Sharon wants more intel.
The FBI's looking to make arrests.
Come sit.
I'm a pretty terrible cook,
I should warn you.
Remember when I said
you could just disappear?
I think it's time.
Izzy's dad was all over the news.
I think me and you...
I mean, Doc, everyone.
I think we should go.
- I think we have to leave this place.
- No. We can't do that.
Why?
I have something planned for us.
A jam?
Could you just forget that for a moment?
For a month?
Leave with me.
This is going to be our last jam here.
Then we'll take off.
But this has to happen now.
I need you.
I took a bullet out of Izzy's stomach.
She's in a hole in the ground.
I don't want to keep going like this.
I can't.
No one will get hurt this time.
You can't promise me that.
Okay.
But I'll do this, with or without you.
What's the jam?
- I won't go in there blind.
- You don't have to.
I'll take you there.
Tonight.
Are we almost there?
Yep.
So you can tell me where we're going.
I think you know.
Since when?
The early companies
we jammed were clients of Hiller Brood.
I've been waiting for you for a long time.
Did everyone know?
No.
Just me and Luca.
What do you want?
A list of every Hiller Brood operative
all over the world.
Their identities...
...locations, assignments.
You're going to recruit them.
No. I'm going to watch them.
Spy on us and we'll spy on you.
To even get into the building,
you need clearance.
What makes you so certain
I'll get you that list?
I'm not.
I'm not certain of anything.
I'm going to wait.
Here.
For whatever you decide to do.
Pigs!
I need to see Sharon.
She's in video conference upstairs.
It's urgent. Please let her know I'm here.
It's urgent as in "Will you go upstairs
and get her?" Right now.
What is so important
it couldn't wait fifteen minutes?
The final jam.
It's Lyra.
They're going to hack the satellite.
Turn all the cameras in the sky against
the CEO, the CFO, the COO. Spy on them.
- They can do that?
- Yeah.
- And broadcast it online.
- That's clever.
I'm glad you're back.
Safe.
Oh, the Bureau raided
The East house today.
I thought you'd want to know.
Another cell will probably pick up the jam.
I was sharing some of your report
with the Bureau...
...and they reminded me of something
I wondered about.
Why all the dumpster diving?
Why not just grow your own food?
He's got money.
Why not buy an organic farm?
They eat garbage on principle.
It's not rotten food.
It's good food that has to be
thrown away legally.
The system is broken.
And the evidence is the trash.
It has value.
I know... I've been eating
three square meals a day from it.
Step aside for additional screening.
I'm grabbing something
for Sharon from her car.
Please spread your arms and legs.
Greg?
We'll send your BlackBerry upstairs
when we're done.
Thank you.
Wait!
They raided the house.
Did you get it?
The FBI raided The East house.
Doc is probably on his way to jail.
Not in vain if you wipe out
the agents on that list.
Did you get it?
No, I didn't.
They took my BlackBerry.
I know a lot of the people on that list.
We could go to them.
If some of them saw
the things that I've seen...
...they would turn.
They would turn.
Sarah, this was supposed to be a jam.
We'd destroy Hiller Brood by posting
their agents' real identities online.
Those people work undercover. You can't
expose them. You could get them killed.
You told me you wanted to watch them.
I want them to feel the consequences
of their actions.
Then you should start with me.
I'm on that list, too.
You're burned there.
They'll be coming after us.
We have to get across the border.
I can't get on the truck.
We have to go. It's not safe for you here.
I can't go.
Can't or won't?
I won't.
Jane.
Come with me.
We don't have that list.
But if we did...
...I think that you and I would want to do
different things with it.
Please give me the strength to do well.
To not be arrogant.
But to not be weak.
Amen.