A famous man once said:
"We create our own Demons".
Who said that? What does
that even mean? Doesn't matter.
I said it cause he said it.
So now he was famous and basically
getting said by two well-known guys.
I don't, uh.. I'm gonna
start again.
Let's track this from the beginning.
Half-hour 'till the
ball drops.
Tony Stark, great speech man!
I gave a speech?
- How was it?
- Edifying.
Unintelligible.
Really? That's my favorite
kind, a winning combo.
- Hey, uh, where are we going?
- Uh, to town on each other,
probably back at your house.
I want to see your research.
Okay, you can see my
research, but that's..
I'm not going to show
you my "town".
- Mr. Stark, Ho Yinsen.
- Oh, I finally met a man called Ho.
I'd like to introduce you to our
guest, Doctor Wu.
- Oh this guy.
- Mr. Stark.
Hey.
She's going to need a cardiologist
right away.
- Bye!
- Perhaps another time?
It started in Bern,
Switzerland, 1999.
The old days.
I never thought they'd
come back to bite me.
Hey Tony! Aldrich Killian,
I'm a big fan of your work.
- My work?
- Who isn't? She needs me.
Well, of course, but Miss
Hansen my organization
has been tracking your research since
year two of MIT.
Oh wow, he made it.
He made the cut.
- What floor you going to, pal?
- Well now, that is an appropriate question.
The ground floor, actually, of a proposal
I'm putting together myself.
It's a privately-funded think tank called
"Advanced Idea Mechanics".
Uh, she'll take both. One to throw
away and one to not call.
"Advanced Idea Mechanics" or AIM
for short, you get it?
I see that 'cause it's on
your T-shirt.
Oh!!
Ladies, follow the mullet.
Ladies first.
Thank you. I'll call you.
- I am titillated by the notion of working with you.
- Yeah?
I'm going to ditch
these clowns.
I'll see you up on the roof
in five minutes.
I'm just going to try to get my beef wet real
quick if you know what I'm talkin' about.
I'll see you up there!
Damn betcha.
- Come on, I thought that was just a theory.
- Well.. it was.
If I'm right, we can access the area
of the brain
- that governs repair and chemically recode it.
- That's incredible.
Essentially, you're hacking into
the genetic operating system of a
- living organism.
- Exactly.
Can you not touch my plant? It's not..
she doesn't like it. She prefers..
She's not like the others.
Come on, let's go to
the bedroom.
Happy, leave her ficus alone.
No, seriously, don't
- And you're starting with plants?
- For now, yes.
I'm calling it "Extremis".
- Well, it's..
- Human application.
Exactly! Exactly!
Dentra-degree vitalization.
Disease prevention.
Even limb regrowth.
You're the most gifted woman
I've ever met.
- Wow!
- In Switzerland.
- That's better.
- This week.
You almost bought it,
didn't you?
This is what I'm talking
about, the glitch.
Have you checked the telomerase
algorithm?
- We're good.
- Stay down.
You're right on me..
What the hell was that?
It's a glitch in my work.
She was just talking about it.
Glitches happen.
Oh, it's not Y2K..
Hey, Happy New Year!
- Happy New Year.
Alright, I'll see you in the morning,
Okay? Good night.
- You good?
- Yep.
- I'll be right outside.
- Okay, cool.
So, why am I telling you this? Because I
had just created demons.
And I didn't even know it.
Yeah, those were good times.
Then I moved on.
After a brief soiree in an Afghan cave,
I said "Goodbye" to the party scene.
I forgot that night in Switzerland.
These days I'm a changed man.
I'm different now.
I'm.. well, you know
who I am.
Sir, please may I request
- just a few hours to calibrate..
- Nope!
Micro-repeater implanting
sequence complete!
As you wish, sir. I've
also prepared a
safety briefing for you
to entirely ignore.
Which I will.
Alright, let's do this.
Dummy. Hi Dummy.
How did you get that cap on your head?
You earned it.
Hey. Hey!
What are you doing out of the corner?
You know what you did.
Blood on my mat, handle it.
Sir, may I remind you that you've been
awake for nearly 72 hours.
Focus up ladies.
Good evening
And welcome to the
birthing suite.
I am pleased to announce the
imminent arrival
of your bouncing,
badass baby brother.
Start titan and go white.
Stamp date and time.
Mark 42 autonomous prehensile
propulsion suit test.
Initialize sequence.
Jarvis, drop my needle.
Crap.
Alright, I think we got this.
Send them all.
Probably just a little fast, slow it down.
Slow it down just a.. little bit.
Cool it, will you Jarvis?
Come on.
I ain't scared of you.
I'm the best.
As always sir, a great pleasure
watching you work.
I guess 72 hours is a long
time between siestas.
Didn't think it could
get any worse.
Then they had to go and
turn on the TV.
That's when 'He' happened.
Some people call me a terrorist.
I consider myself a teacher.
America..
Ready for another lesson.
In 1864 in Sand Creek, Colorado.
The U.S. military waited until the friendly
Cheyenne Braves had all gone hunting.
Waited to attack and slaughter
the families left behind.
And claim their land.
39 hours ago, the Ali Al Salem Air Base
in Kuwait was attacked.
I did that.
A quaint military church, filled with
wives and children of course.
The soldiers were out
on maneuvers.
The "Braves" were away.
President Ellis, you continue to resist
my attempts to educate you, sir.
And now, you've missed
me again.
You know who I am.
You don't know where I am.
And you'll never see me coming.
And now that we seem to be back,
let's recap some of the frightening
developments in this story.
American airways were hijacked.
The nation remains
on high alert.
All attempts to find the Mandarin have
so far proved unsuccessful.
Central to my administration's response to this
terrorist event is a newly-minted resource.
I know him as Colonel
James Rhodes.
The American people will soon
know him as the Iron Patriot.
And how is President
Ellis responding?
By taking the guy they call "War Machine"
and giving him a paint job.
The same suit but painted red,
white and blue, look at that.
And they've also renamed
him Iron Patriot.
You know, just in case the
paint was too subtle.
It tested well with focus
groups, alright?
- I am Iron Patriot.
- Listen.
War Machine was a little too
aggressive, alright.
This sends a better message.
So what's really going on?
With Mandarin.
Seriously, can we talk
about this guy?
It's classified information,
Tony.
- Okay, there've been nine bombings.
- Nine.
The public only knows about three.
But here's the thing..
nobody can ID a device.
There's no bomb casings.
You know I can help.
Just ask. I got a ton of new tech.
I got a prehensile suit. I got
Bomb disposal.
Catches explosions mid-air.
When's the last time you got
a good night's sleep?
Einstein slept three hours a year.
Look what he did.
People are concerned about
you, Tony.
I'm concerned about you.
You gonna come at me like that?
No, look, I'm not trying
to be a dictator.
Would you mind signing my drawing?
If Richard doesn't mind. You alright
with this, Dick?
Fine with me.
- What is your name?
- Erin.
I loved you in "A Christmas Story"
by the way.
Listen, the Pentagon is scared.
After New York, aliens,
come on.
They need to look strong.
Stopping the Mandarin is a
priority, but it's not..
It's not superhero business.
No, it's not. Quite frankly.
It's American business.
That's why I said.
I.. got it.
Are you okay?
I broke the crayon.
Are you okay,
Mr. Stark?
Take it easy. Tony..
How did you get out
of the wormhole?
- Tony..
- What did you say?
Sorry. Have to check on
the suit.. make sure.. okay.
Check the heart, check the,
check the, is it the brain?
No sign of cardiac anatomy
or unusual brain activity.
Okay, so I was poisoned?
My diagnosis is that you've experienced
a severe anxiety attack.
Me?
Come on man, this isn't a
good look. Open up.
Sorry, I gotta split.
Badge.. Badge.. Badge.
Badge, guys. I put a memo in
the toilet, come on.
Tony has got them in his basement,
they're wearing
party hats, this is an asset
we can put to use.
Uh..huh. So, you're suggesting
that I replace
the entire janitorial
staff with robots?
What I'm saying is that the human
element of Human
Resources is our biggest
point of vulnerability.
We should start phasing it
out immediately.
- What!?
- Excuse me, Bambi.
- Did you just say that?
- Security.
Happy, okay, I am thrilled that you're
now the Head of Security.
- Okay, it is the perfect position for you.
- Thank you.
- However,
- I do appreciate it.
- Since you've taken the post,
- You don't have to thank me.
We've had a rise in staff complaints
of 300 percent.
- Thank you.
- That's not a compliment.
"That's not a compliment"?
It is a compliment!
Clearly somebody is trying
to hide something.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Miss Potts, your four o'clock
is here.
Did you clear this four o'clock
with me?
Happy, we'll talk about
this later
But right now I have to go deal with
this very annoying thing.
How so?
I used to work with him, and he
used to ask me
out all the time, so it's a
little awkward.
I don't like the sound of that.
- Pepper.
- Killian?
You look great..
you look really great.
God, you look great.
I.. I.. I can't.. What on Earth have
you been doing?
Nothing fancy, just five years in the
hands of physical therapists
And please, call me Aldrich.
Uh, you were supposed to be
issued a security badge?
Happy, it's okay.
- Yes?
- We're good.
- You sure?
- Yes.
- Stand down.
- I'm going to linger.
- Thank you.
- Right here, okay.
It's very nice to see
you, Killian.
Hey, guy
Merry Christmas.
After years dodging the president's ban
on "Immoral Biotech Research",
My think tank now has a little
something in the pipeline.
It's an idea we like to call
"Extremis".
I'm gonna turn your
lights down.
Regard the human brain.
Uh, wait, hold on, hold on, that's, that's
the universe, my bad.
But if I do that..
That's the brain, strangely mimetic
though, wouldn't you say?
- Wow, that's amazing!
- Thanks, it's mine.
- What?
- This.. you're inside my head.
It's a live feed. Come on up,
I'll prove it to you.
Come on.
Now, pinch my arm. I can take it.
Pinch me.
What is that?
The primary somatosensory
cortex.
It's the brain's pain center, but this..
is what I wanted to show you.
Now, "Extremis" harnesses our
bioelectrical potential.
And it goes.. here.
This is essentially an empty slot,
and what this tells us is that
our mind, our entire DNA in fact,
is destined to be upgraded.
Wow.
- Hello?
- Is this forehead of Security?
What? You know, look, I got a real job.
What do you want?
I'm working. I got something
going on here.
- What? Harassing interns?
- Let me tell you something,
You know what happened when I told people
I was Iron Man's bodyguard?
They would laugh in my face.
I had to leave while I still
had a shred of dignity.
Now I got a real job. I'm
watching Pepper.
What's going on?
Fill me in.
- For real?
- Yeah.
Alright, so she's meeting up with this
scientist rich guy, handsome.
I couldn't make his face
at first, right?
And you know I'm good
with faces.
- Oh yeah, you're the best.
- Yeah, so I run his credentials
I make him Aldrich Killian. We actually
met the guy back in.
Where were we in '99? The
Science Conference?
Uh, Switzerland.
Right, right, exactly.
- Killian, I don't remember that guy.
- Of course you don't remember,
he's not a blonde with a big rack.
At first it was fine, they were
talking business, but now
it's like getting weird. He's showing
her his big brain.
- His what?
- Big brain, and she likes it.
Here, let me show you.
Hold on. See?
Look at what? You watching them? Flip the
screen and then we can get started.
I'm not a tech genius like you, just
trust me, get down here.
Flip the screen, then I can see
what they're doing.
I don't know how to flip
the screen!
Don't talk to me like that anymore.
You're not my boss.
Alright, I don't work for you, and
I don't trust this guy.
He's got another guy with
him, he's shifty.
Relax. I'm just asking you to
secure the perimeter.
Tell him to go out for a
drink or something.
You know what? You should take more
of an interest in what's going on here.
This woman is the best thing
that ever happened to you.
- And you're just ignoring her.
- A giant brain?
Yeah, there's a giant brain,
there's a shifty character..
I'm going to follow this guy.
I'm going to run
his plates and if it
gets rough, so be it.
I miss you, Happy.
Yeah, I miss you too but the
way it used to be.
Now you're off with
the "super friends"
I don't know what's going on
with you anymore.
The world's gettin' weird.
Hey I hate to cut you off,
- do you have your teaser on you?
- Why?
I think there's a gal in HR
who is trying
to steal some printer ink. You should
probably go over there and zap her.
Yeah, nice.
Imagine if you could hack into
the hard drive of
any living organism and
recode its DNA.
It would be incredible.
Unfortunately, to my ears it also
sounds highly weaponizable.
As in enhanced soldiers, private
armies, and Tony is not..
Tony, Tony.
You know, I invited Tony
to join AIM.
13 years ago and he
turned me down.
But something tells me now there is a new
genius on the throne, who doesn't have to
answer to Tony anymore and who
has slightly less of an ego.
It's going to be a no, Aldrich..
as much as I'd like to help you.
I can't say that I'm not disappointed,
but as my father used to say,
"Failure is the fog through which
we glimpse triumph."
It's very deep, and I have no
idea what it means.
Well, he was kind of an
idiot, my old man.
I'm sure I'll see you again,
Pepper.
Happy!
The car is ready.. if you're
ready to go.
Yes, I just um, God, I forgot my other
thing so I'm just gonna..
I'm sorry I'm late. I was..
What is that?!
You're wearing this in the house now?
What is that, like Mark 15?
Yeah, something like that. You know
everybody needs a hobby.
Oh, and you have to wear your hobby
in the living room?
Just breaking it in, you know, it's always
a little pinky in the GUI-bagger at first.
Oh hey, did you see your
Christmas present?
Yes, I did. I don't know how I could have
missed that Christmas present.
Is it gonna fit through
the door?
Well actually, uh, that's a good question,
I got a team of
guys coming tomorrow. They're gonna
blow out that wall.
So, uh, tense?
Good day?
Oh shoulders, a little naughty.
Naughty girl.
I don't want to harp on this, but did you
like the custom rabbit?
Did I like it?
- Nailed it, right?
- Wow.
I appreciate the thought
very much.
So why don't you lift up that facemask
and give me a kiss.
Huh, yup, dammit.
No can do.
You want to just kiss it on
the, uh, facial slit?
Why don't I run down to the
garage and see if
I can't find a crowbar to jimmy
that thing open?
A crowbar? Yeah. Oh, except there's
been a radiation leak.
- I'll take my chances.
- That's risky.
At least let me get you
like a Hazmat suit.
Or a Geiger counter or
something like that.
- Busted.
- This is a new level of lame.
- Sorry.
- You ate without me, already? On date night?
- He was just.
- You mean you.
Well yeah, I just mean
we were just..
just hosting you while I
finished up a little work.
Uh Huh..
And yes, I had a quick bite. I didn't know
if you were coming home
Or you were having drinks with
Aldrich Killian.
What?
Aldrich Killian? What are you
checking up on me?
- Happy was concerned.
- No, you're spying on me.
- I'm going to bed.
- Hold on. Come on. Pep..
Hey, I admit it! My fault.
Sorry.
I'm a piping hot mess.
It's been going on for a while..
I haven't said anything.
- Nothing's been the same since New York.
- Oh really?
I didn't notice that, at all.
You experience things and then they're
over and you still can't explain them.
Gods, aliens, other dimensions..
I'm just a man in a can.
The only reason I haven't cracked up is
probably because you've moved in.
Which is great. I love
you, I'm lucky.
But honey.. I can't sleep.
You go to bed, I come down here.
I do what I know, I tinker.
The threat is imminent.
And I have to protect the one thing
that I can't live without.
That's you. And my suits,
they're uh..
- Machines.
- They're part of me.
- A distraction.
- Maybe.
- I'm gonna take a shower.
- Okay.
- And you're going to join me.
- Better.
Tony!
Power down!
I must have called it in my sleep.
That's not supposed to happen.
I'll recalibrate the sensors.
Can we just.. just let me.. just let me catch
my breath, okay? Don't go, alright? Pepper?
I'm going to sleep downstairs.
Tinker with that.
- Can you regulate?
- Yes, I can regulate.
- Are you sure about that?
- Yes.
It's a decent batch.
Don't say I never did
nothing for you.
Thank you. I mean for
understanding.
I'm sorry, buddy.
What're ya doing, buddy?
You out by yourself? A little date night?
Watching your favorite chick flick maybe?
Yeah, a little movie called
"The Party's Over"
Starring you and your junkie girlfriend,
and here's the ticket.
No kidding. That doesn't
belong to you.
Savin! Help!
Help me!
A true story about fortune cookies.
They look Chinese. They
sound Chinese.
But they're actually an
American invention.
Which is why they're hollow, full of lies,
and leave a bad taste in the mouth.
My disciples just destroyed another
cheap American knock-off.
The Chinese Theater.
Mr. President.
I know this must be
getting frustrating.
But this season of terror is
drawing to a close.
And don't worry, the big one is
coming, your graduation.
- Hi.
- Oh, uh.
- Mind leaving that on?
- Sure.
Sunday night's PBS,
"Downtown Abbey"
That's the show. He thinks
it's elegant.
One more thing, make sure everyone wears
their badges. He's a stickler
for that sort of thing, plus my guys won't
let anyone in without them.
We're awaiting the arrival
of Tony Stark.
We're hoping he'll give
us the reaction.
His reaction to the
latest attack.
Mr. Stark!
Our sources are telling us that this is
another Mandarin attack.
Anything else you can tell us?
Hey Mr. Stark! When is somebody going
to kill this guy? Just sayin'.
Is that what you want?
Here's a little Holiday greeting I've been
wanting to send to the Mandarin.
I just didn't know how to
phrase it until now.
My name is Tony Stark and
I'm not afraid of you.
I know that you're a coward,
so I've decided
That you just died, pal.
I'm gonna come get the body.
There's no politics here, it's just good
old-fashioned revenge.
There's no Pentagon. It's just
you and me.
And on the off-chance you're a man,
here's my home address:
10880, Malibu Port, 90265.
I'll leave the door unlocked. That's what
you wanted, right?
Bill me.
I've compiled a Mandarin
database for you, sir.
Drawn from S.H.I.E.L.D., F.B.I.
and C.I.A. intercepts.
Initiating virtual crime scene
reconstruction.
Okay, what do we got here?
His name is an ancient
Chinese war mantle
Meaning "Advisor to the King".
South American insurgency tactics.
Talks like a Baptist preacher.
There's lots of pageantry going
on here, lots of theater.
Close.
The heat from the blast was in
excess of 3000 degrees Celsius.
Any subjects within 12.5 yards
were vaporized instantly.
No bomb parts found in a 3-mile
radius of the Chinese theater.
No, sir.
Talk to me, Happy.
When is a bomb not a bomb?
- Any military victims?
- Not according to public records, sir.
Bring up the thermo genic signatures
again, factor in 3000 degrees.
The oracle cloud has
completed analysis.
Accessing satellites and plotting the last
12 months of thermo genic occurrences now.
Take away everywhere that there's
been a Mandarin attack.
Nope.
That. You sure that's
not one of his?
It predates any known
Mandarin attack.
The incident was the use of a
bomb to assist a suicide.
Bring it around.
The heat signature is remarkably similar.
3000 degrees Celsius.
That's two military guys.
Ever been to Tennessee, Jarvis?
Creating a flight plan for Tennessee.
Are we still at 'Ding-Dong'? We're
supposed to be on total security lockdown.
Come on, I threatened a terrorist.
Who is that?
There's only so much I can do, sir, when you
give the world's press your home address.
Right there's fine.
You're not the Mandarin, are you?
Are you?
You don't remember. Why I
am not surprised?
Don't take it personally, I don't remember
what I had for breakfast.
- Gluten-free waffles, sir.
- That's right.
Look, I need to be alone with you,
someplace not here.. it's urgent.
Normally, I'd go for that sort of thing,
but now I'm in a committed relationship
- It's.. with her.
- Tony
- Is somebody there?
- Yeah, it's Maya Hansen.
Old botanist pal that I used
to know, barely.
Please don't tell me that there is a 12-year-old
kid waiting in the car that I've never met.
- He's 13. No, I need your help.
- What for? Why now?
Because I read the papers, and, frankly,
I don't think you'll last the week.
- I'll be fine.
- I'm sorry.
With Happy in the hospital, I didn't
know we were expecting guests.
We weren't.
- And old girlfriends!
- She's not really.
No, not really. It was
just one night.
- Yep.
- That's how you did it, isn't it?
It was a great night
- Well.. you know
- Yeah.
You have saved yourself
a world of pain.
- What?
- Trust me.
We're going out of town.
- Okay, we've been through this. Nope.
- Yep!
- The man says no.
- Immediately and indefinitely.
- Great idea. Let's go.
- I'm sorry.
That's a terrible idea. Please don't
touch her bags.
Tony, this is how normal
people behave.
I can't protect you out there.
I challenged.
- Is this normal?
- Sadly, that..
Yes, this is normal!
- Is very normal
- It's a big bunny, relax about it!
- Calm down!
- I got this for you.
- I'm aware of that.
- You still haven't even told me that you liked it!
I don't like it!
- I asked you three.
- You don't like it?!
- We are leaving the house, that's not even up for discussion.
- Guys.. do we hmm..
- What?
- Do we need to worry about that?
- I got you.
- I got you first.
Like I said, we can't
stay here.
Move! I'm right behind.
Get her, I'm going to
find a way around.
Stop stopping! Get her.
Get outside! Go!
Oh my God.
Tony!
Sir, Miss Potts is clear
of the structure.
Jarvis, where's my flight power?
Working on it, sir. This is
a prototype.
That's one.
Sir, the suit is not combat-ready.
That's two.
Tony!
Sir, take a deep breath.
Flight power restored.
Sir. Sir!
Alright, kill the
alarm. I got it.
That's the emergency alert triggered by
the power dropping below 5%.
Snow? Where are we,
upstate?
We are 5 miles outside of
Rose Hills, Tennessee.
Why?
Jarvis! Not my idea! What are we
doing here, this is
thousands of miles away? I've gotta get
Pepper, I've got to..
I prepared a flight plan.
This was the location.
Who asked you? Open
the suit.
I think I may be malfunctioning, sir.
Open Eject.
That's brisk!
Maybe I'll just cozy back
up for a bit.
I actually think I need
to sleep now, sir.
Jarvis.
Jarvis?
Don't leave me, buddy.
Stark Secure Server: Now transferring
to all known receivers.
Pepper, it's me.
I've got a lot of apologies to make
and not a lot of time, so first off.
I'm so sorry I put you
in harm's way.
That was selfish and stupid and
it won't happen again.
Also, it's Christmas time. The
rabbit's too big. Done.
Sorry.
And I'm sorry in advance because..
I can't come home yet.
I need to find this guy. You
gotta stay safe.
That's all I know.
I just stole a poncho from
a wooden Indian.
Let's get you comfy.
You happy now?
Freeze!
- Don't move.
- You got me.
Nice potato gun.
Barrel's a little long.
Between that and the wide gauge, it's
going to diminish your FPS.
And now you're out of ammo.
What's that thing on
your chest?
It's a electromagnet. You should know,
you've got a box of them right here.
What does it power?
Oh my God!
- Is that Iron Man?
- Technically, I am.
Technically, you're dead.
- A valid point.
- What happened to him?
Life. I built him. I take
care of him.
I'll fix him.
- Like a mechanic.
- Yeah.
If I was building Iron Man
and War Machine,
- It's Iron Patriot now.
- That's way cooler!
No, it's not.
Anyway, I would have
added in the retro..
- Retro reflective panels?
- To make him stealth mode.
- You want a stealth mode?
- Cool, right?
That's actually a good idea.
Maybe I'll build one.
Not a good idea!
What are you doing? You're going
to break his finger?
He's in pain. He's been injured.
Leave him alone.
- Sorry.
- Are you?
Don't worry about it.
I'll fix it.
So, uh, who's home?
Well, my mom already left for the diner
and dad went to 7-11 to get scratchers.
I guess he won 'cause that
was six years ago.
Which happens, dads leave. No need to
be a pussy about it.
Here's what I need: a laptop, a
digital watch, a cell phone,
The pneumatic actuator from
your bazooka over there,
a map of town, a big spring,
and a tuna-fish sandwich.
- What's in it for me?
- Salvation. What's his name?
- Who?
- The kid that bullies you at school, what's his name?
How'd you know that?
I got just the thing.
This is a piñata for a cricket. I'm kidding.
It's a very powerful weapon.
Point it away from your face,
press the button on top,
It discourages bullying.
Non-lethal, just to cover
one's ass.
- Deal. Deal? What'd you say?
- Deal.
- What's your name?
- Harley.
- And you are..?
- The mechanic..
Tony.
You know what keeps going
through my head?
Where's my sandwich?
Stark Secure Server. Retinal
scan verified.
Pepper, it's me.
I've got a lot of apologies
to make
and not a lot of time,
so first off.
I'm so sorry I put you
in harm's way.
That was selfish and stupid and
it won't happen again.
Why were you at the
house tonight?
What was so important that you
had to speak to Tony?
I think that my boss is working
for the Mandarin.
So if you still want
to talk about it,
I suggest we get ourselves
someplace safe.
Your boss works for the
Mandarin you think,
but Tony says you're a botanist.
That figures. What I actually am is a
biological DNA coder running a team of
40 out of a privately-funded think tank,
but sure you can call me a "botanist".
This boss of yours, does
he have a name?
Yeah, Aldrich Killian.
Well we took the house down sir, but
there's no sign of a body.
- I see.
- No Stark.
I have to go.
The Master is about to record
and he's a little..
Well you know how he gets.
Keep your appointment tonight and
call me when it's done.
Alright everybody. No talking and
no eye contact,
unless you wanna get
shot in the face.
The Master is traveling.
Well then, what are we waiting for?
The sandwich was fair, the
spring was a little
rusty, the rest of the materials
I'll make do.
By the way, when you said your
sister had a watch, I
was kinda hoping for something
a little more than that.
She's six! Anyway, it's limited edition.
- When can we talk about New York?
- Maybe never, relax about it.
- What about the Avengers, can you talk about them?
- I don't know. Later.
Hey kid, give me more space.
What's the official story here?
What happened?
I guess this guy named Chad Davis,
used to live roundabouts.
Won a bunch of medals in the army.
One day, folks said he went crazy
and made, you know, a bomb.
Then he blew himself
up right here.
- Six people died, right?
- Yes.
- Including Chad Davis?
- Yea.
Doesn't make sense.
Think about it. Six dead,
only five shadows.
Yeah, but people said these shadows are
like the mark of souls gone to Heaven
Except the bomb guy, he went to Hell on
account of he didn't get a shadow.
- That's why there's only five.
- Do you buy that?
That's what everyone says.
You know what this crater
reminds me of?
I have no idea. I don't care.
That giant wormhole, in
um, in New York.
Does it remind you?
That's manipulative. I don't want
to talk about it.
Are they coming back?
The aliens?
Maybe, can you stop?
Remember when I told you that
I have an anxiety issue?
Does this subject make
you edgy?
Yeah, a little bit.
Can I just catch my breath
for a second?
Are there bad guys in Rose Hills? Do you
need a plastic bag to breathe into?
- Do you have medication?
- Nope.
- Do you need to be on it?
- Probably.
- Do you have PTSD?
- I don't think so.
Are you going completely
mental?
I can stop, do you want
me to stop?
Remember when I said
to stop doing that?
I swear to God, you're going
to freak me out.
Ah man, you did it, didn't you?
- You happy now?
- What did I say?
Hey, wait up!
Wait, wait.
What the hell was that?
Your fault, you spazzed me out.
Okay, back to business.
Where were we?
The guy who died.. relatives? Mom?
Ms. Davis, where is she?
- Where she always is.
- See, now you're being helpful.
Sorry. Lady, this uh,
Thank you.
Nice haircut, suits you.
- Nice watch.
- Yeah, limited edition.
Oh, I don't doubt it.
Well.. have a good evening.
Ms. Davis, Mind if
I join you?
- Free country.
- It sure is.
Alright
- Where'd you like to start?
- I just want to say I'm sorry about your loss.
I want to know what you
think happened
I brought your damn file.
You take it and go.
Whatever was in here, he
wanted no part of it.
Clearly, you were waiting for someone else.
Supposed to meet somebody here?
Yeah.
Ms. Davis, your son didn't kill
himself. I guarantee
you he didn't kill anyone.
Someone used him.
- What?
- As a weapon.
You're not the person who called
me after all, are you?
Actually, I am.
Hey, hey! What's all this about?
The hell's going on here?
It's called an arrest.
- Sheriff, is it?
- Yes ma'am, it is. And you are?
- Homeland Security. We good here?
- No, we're not good.
- I need a little more information than that.
- Well, I think it's a little above your pay grade, Sheriff.
Yeah, well, why don't you get on the
horn to Nashville and upgrade me?
Alright, you know what, I was hoping
to do this the smart way, but uh,
The fun way's always good.
Deputy, get this woman and..
Hey hot wings, you wanna party?
You and me, let's go.
- Crazy, huh?
- Yeah.
Watch this.
You walked right into this one. I've dated
hotter chicks than you.
That's all you got? Cheap trick
and a cheesy one-liner?
Sweetheart, that could be the name
of my autobiography.
- Let me go!
- Help me! Help me!
Hey kid, what would you
like for Christmas?
Mr. Stark, I am so sorry.
No, no, I think he was trying to say
"I want my goddamn file."
It's not your fault kid.
Remember what I told you
about bullies?
You like that, West World? That's
the thing about smart guys.
We always cover our ass.
You're welcome!
- For what? Did I miss something?
- Me saving your life.
A: Saved you first
B: Thanks, sort of
And C: If you do someone a solid, don't
be a yurts alright,
just play it cool otherwise you
come off grandiose.
Unlike you?
Admit it: you need me.
We're connected.
What I need is for you to go home,
be with your mom,
keep your trap shut, and
guard the suit.
And stay connected to the
telephone because
if I call you better
pick up. Okay?
Can you feel that?
We're done here.
Move out of the way or I'm going to
run you over. Bye kid.
I'm sorry kid. You
did good.
So now you're just going to leave
you here, like my dad?
Yeah. Wait, you're guilt-tripping
me, aren't you?
I'm cold.
I can tell. You know how I can tell?
'Cause we're connected.
It was worth a shot.
What happened to the picture?
The entire East coast.. the
satellites are down.
We have an unauthorized broadcast
Mr. Vice President, I think
you should see this.
Oh my God, not again.
Is the President getting this?
Mr. President.
Only two lessons remain.
I intend to finish this before
Christmas morning.
Meet Thomas Richards. Good strong
name, good strong job.
Thomas here is an accountant for
the Roxxon Oil Corporation.
And I'm sure he's a
really good guy.
I'm going to shoot him in the head,
live on your television, in 30 seconds.
The number for this telephone is in your
cell phone. Exciting, isn't it?
Imagining how it got there.
America, if your president calls me in
the next half-minute, Tom lives.
Go.
How did he hack my phone?
We can't allow terrorists
to dictate
I have to make this call.
I'd strongly advise
against that.
This is the right thing to do.
There's just one lesson left,
President Ellis,
so run away and kiss your
children goodbye
Because nothing, not your army,
not your red,
white, and blue attack dog,
can save you.
I'll see you soon.
Tell Rhodes, find this lunatic
right now.
Sir, we tracked the broadcast signal.
We have a possible point of origin in
Pakistan and the Patriot is ready to strike.
- Right now!
- Yes, sir.
Don't move!
Uh, hang on a second.
Hello.
You ever look up and everything starts glowing
from the inside out, a kind of bright orange.
- Yeah, I've had that. Who is this?
- It's me, pal.
Now last time I went missing, if I remember
correctly, you went looking for me.
- What are you doing?
- A little talking, making friends in Pakistan.
What are you doing?
- Your re-design, your big re-brand,
that was AIM, right?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna find a heavy-duty comsat
right now, I need your login.
Same as it's always been,
War Machine 68.
And password please?
Well, look, I gotta change it every time
you hack in, Tony.
It's not the eighties, nobody says "hack"
anymore, give me your login.
"War Machine ROX" with
an X, all caps.
- Yeah okay.
- That is so much better than Iron Patriot.
That ain't gonna cut it.
Excuse me sir, I don't know who..
Mom, I need to call you back. Something
magical is happening.
- Tony Stark is in my van.
- Keep it down.
- Tony Stark is in my van!
- No, he's not.
I knew you were still alive!
Come on in and close the door.
- Wow, can I just say sir?
- Yeah.
I am your biggest fan.
First, is this your van or
is anyone else gonna come in?
No, no, it's just us.
What's your name?
- Gary.
Oh wow.
Right there's fine. I get a
lot of this, it's okay.
Can I just say?
- Yeah.
- I don't know if you can tell but I have like
Patterned my whole look after you. My
hair's a little,
it's not right because there's
some product in it.
Right.
I don't want to make things
awkward for you
- No.
- But I do have to show you.. boom!
Hispanic Scott Baio?
- Oh, I'm sorry, is that me?
- Yeah.
It's.. I mean. I had them do it
off a doll that I made,
so it's not like it's off a picture. So
it's a little bit.
Jerry, for a moment, listen
to me here.
I don't want to clip your
wings here.
We're both a little over-excited.
I have an issue. I'm chasing bad
guys, trying to grapple
with something from some
hard-crypt data files.
I don't have enough juice.
I need you to jump on the roof,
recalibrate the ISDNs
- Pump it up by about 40%.
- Got it.
Alright, it's a mission.
Yeah.
Tony needs Gary.
And Gary needs Tony.
Be quiet about it.
Go.
What would you regard as the defining
moment of your life?
Well uh, I think that would be the day I
decided not to let my injury beat me.
- Can you please state your name for the camera?
- Ellen Brandt.
Okay, so, the injections are
administered periodically.
Addiction will not be tolerated and those who
cannot regulate will be cut from the program.
Once misfits, cripples.. you are the next
iteration of human evolution.
Hi everybody. Before we start, I promise
you, looking back at your life there will be
nothing as bitter as the memory of that glorious
risk that you prudently elected to forego.
Today is your glory. Let's begin!
We gotta get out of here! Gotta get out of here!
Get 'em out! Get 'em out of here!
A bomb is not a bomb
when it's a misfire.
This stuff doesn't always
work, right, pal?
It's faulty, but you found a
buyer, didn't ya?
Sold it to the Mandarin.
What happened? Fun fact.
Before he built rockets
for the Nazis.
The idealistic Werner von Braun dreamed
of space travel.. he stargazed.
You know what he said when the
first V2 hit London?
The rocket performed perfectly.
It just landed on the wrong planet.
See we all begin wide-eyed..
"pure science".
Then the ego steps in,
the obsession
And when you look up, you're
a long way from shore.
You can't be too hard on yourself, Maya. I
mean you gave your research to a think tank.
Yeah but Killian built that think tank
on military contracts.
That's exactly what we used to do.
So don't judge yourself.
Thank you, Pepper.
I really appreciate that.
Hi, good evening
- Good evening.
- Come on in.
Maya, run!
Hi Pepper.
So you want to tell me why you were
at Stark's mansion last night?
I'm trying to fix this thing. I didn't know you
and the Master were gonna blow the place up.
Oh I see, so you were trying to save Stark..
when he threatened us
I told you, Killian, we can use him.
Pepper, Pepper, Pepper
Look if we want to launch product
next year, I need Stark.
He just lacked a decent incentive.
Now he has one.
This is Support Team Blue 0, sending coordinates
for suspected Mandarin broadcast point of origin.
Copy.
Nobody move!
Support Blue 0, unless the Mandarin's
next attack on the U.S.
involves cheaply-made sportswear, I think
you messed up again.
Yes, you're free, if you weren't
before. Yes ma'am.
Iron Patriot on the job, happy to help,
no need to thank me, it's my pleasure.
Savin, I've acquired the Patriot armor.
You want this suit? You gonna have
to pry at my cold dead body out of it.
That's the plan, Colonel.
Harley, tell me what is happening,
give me a full report.
Yeah, I'm still eating that candy, do you
want me to keep eating it?
How much did you have?
Two or three bowls.
- Can you still see straight?
- Sort of.
That means you're fine,
give me Jarvis.
Jarvis, how are we?
It's totally fine sir. I seem to do quite
well for a stretch and
then at the end of the sentence I
say the wrong cranberry.
And sir, you were right. Once I factored
in available AIM downlink
facilities I was able to pinpoint the
Mandarin's broadcast signal.
What're we talkin'? The Far East, Europe, North
Africa, Iran, Pakistan, Syria, where is it?
Actually, sir, it's in Miami.
Okay, kid, I'm going to have to walk
you through rebooting Jarvis's
speech drive, but not right now.
Harley, where is he really?
Just look on the screen and
tell me where it is.
Um.. it does say Miami, Florida.
Okay, first things first,
I need the armor.
Where are we at with it?
Uh, it's not charging.
Actually, sir, it is charging, but
the power source is questionable.
It may not succeed in revitalizing
the Mark 42.
What's questionable about electricity?
Alright, it's my suit and I can't..
I'm not gonna..
- Oh God, not again.
- Tony
Are you having another attack? I
didn't even mention New York.
Right, and then you just said it, by name,
while denying having said it.
Okay, um, uh
Oh God, what am I gonna do?
Just breathe, really just breathe.
- You're a mechanic, right?
- Right.
- You said so.
- Yes, I did.
What don't you just build something?
Okay, thanks kid.
Why is it so hot in here? I told
you to put it at 68.
My fault again.. let me tell you something
sweetheart, I am not your personal..
I wouldn't go in there for twenty minutes!
- Now, which one of you is Vanessa?
- That's me.
Ah, Nessie.
Did you know that fortune cookies
aren't even Chinese?
There's some guy over here.
They're made by Americans,
based on the Japanese recipes.
Hey!
Bloody hell. Bloody hell.
- Don't move.
- I am not moving.
If you want something, take it, although
the guns are all fake
because those wankers wouldn't trust
me with the real ones.
- What?
- Hey, do you fancy either of the birds?
Heard enough. You're not him, the
Mandarin, the real guy, where?
- Where's the Mandarin? Where is he?
- He's here. He's here.
- But he's not here. He's here but he's not here.
- What do you mean?
It's complicated, hey, it's
complicated, alright?
- It is?
- It's complicated.
Uncomplicated. Ladies out, get out
of the bed
get in the bathroom.
Sit.
My name is Trevor, Trevor Slattery.
What are you?
What're you a decoy? You're
a double, right?
What? No. An understudy?
Absolutely not.
Don't hurt me please!
I'm an actor.
You got a minute to live, fill it
with words.
It's just a role. "The Mandarin", see,
it's not real.
Then how did you get here,
Trevor?
Um, well, uh, I have a little problem
with, um, substances,
and I ended up doing things..
no two ways about it
- In the street that a man shouldn't do.
- Next!
Then, they approached me about the role
and they knew about the drugs.
What'd they say they'd get
you off them?
Said they'd give me more.
They gave me things. They gave
me this palace.
They gave me plastic surgery. They
gave me things.
Did you just nod off?
No, the lovely speedboat! And the
thing was, he needed someone.
To take credit for some
"accidental explosions".
"He"?
- Killian?
- Killian.
- He created you?
- He created me.
- Custom-made terror threat
- Yes!
Yes, his think tank thinked it up, the
pathology of the serial killer.
The manipulation of Western
iconography.
Ready for another lesson?
Blah blah blah.
Of course, it was my performance that
brought the Mandarin to life.
Your performance? Where
people die?
No, no, look around you,
costumes, green screen.
Honestly, I wasn't on location for half this
stuff, and when I was, movie magic, love.
I'm sorry but I got a best friend who's in
a coma and he might not wake up.
So you're going to have to answer for that.
You're still going down, pal.
Okay, Trevor, what'd you tell him?
- I didn't tell him anything.
- Nothing?
- No.
- You should have pressed the panic button.
Well I panicked, but then
I handled it.
Just like old times, huh?
Oh yeah, with zip-ties.
It's a ball.
It wasn't my idea.
Okay, so you took
Killian's card
I took his money.
And here you are 13 years
later in a dungeon.
- No.
- Yeah.
- No, you're in a dungeon. I'm free to go.
- Yeah..
A lot's happened Tony,
and I'm close.
Extremis is practically stable.
I'm telling you it isn't.
I saw him on the street, people are going 'bang', they're
painting the walls. Maya, you're kidding yourself.
Then help me fix it.
Did I do that?
- Yes.
- I remember the night, not the morning
Is this what you've been
chasing around?
- You don't remember?
- I can't help you.
You used to have a moral psychology.
You used to have ideals.
Wanted to help people, now
look at you.
I get to wake up every morning
with someone who..
still has a soul.
Get me out of here, come on.
You know what my old man used to say to me?
His favorite of many sayings.
"The early bird gets the worm, the second
mouse gets the cheese".
You're not still pissed about
the Switzerland thing, are you?
How can I be pissed you, Tony?
I'm here to thank you. You've
given me the
greatest gift that anybody's
ever given me.
Desperation. If you think
back to Switzerland,
you said you'd meet me on
the rooftop, right?
Well for the first 20 minutes, I actually
thought you'd show up.
For the next hour, I uhh..
Well I considered taking that one step
shortcut to the lobby, if you know I mean.
Honestly, I'm still trying to figure out
what happened to the first mouse.
But as I looked out over that city, nobody
knew I was there,
nobody could see me, no one
was even looking.
I had a thought that would guide
me for years to come.
Anonymity, Tony.
Thanks to you, it's been my mantra
ever since, right?
You simply rule from behind
the scenes.
Because the second you
give evil a face
Bin Laden, Gaddafi, The Mandarin
You hand the people a target.
You're something else.
You have met him, I assume?
Yeah, Sir Lawrence Oblivion.
I know he's a little over the top sometimes..
it's not entirely my fault.
He has a tend.. he's
a stage actor.
They say his Lear was the toast of
Croydon, wherever that is.
Anyway, the point is ever since that big
dude with the hammer fell out of the sky.
Subtlety's kinda had its day.
What's next for you in your world?
Well, I wanted to repay you for the same
gift you so graciously imparted to me.
Desperation. Now, this is live. I'm not
sure if you can tell.
But at this moment the body is trying to decide
whether to accept Extremis or just give up.
And if it gives up, I have to say the
denotation is quite spectacular.
But until that point, it's really
just a lot of pain.
We haven't even talked
salary yet.
What kind of perk package
are you thinking of?
Let him go.
- Hold on, hold on. Maya
- I said let him go!
What are you doing?
1200ccs, a dose half of this
size and I'm dead.
It's times like this my temper
is tested somewhat.
Maya, give me the injector.
If I die Killian, what happens to your soldiers?
What happens to your product?
We're not doing this, okay?
What happens to you? What happens
if you go too hot?
The good news is, a high level position
has just been vacated.
- You're a maniac.
- No, I'm a visionary.
But I do own a maniac, and he takes
the stage tonight.
When we get the Iron Patriot, it'll take
me nine to ten minutes for a take down.
That's great. The last time I looked
there was somebody inside of it.
Afternoon, gentlemen.
Hello Colonel.
Step aside.
We'll get you out of there,
don't worry.
You'll damage the armor.
Yes, I will, but you can
fix it, right?
I'm going to take the suit up to base
camp, and I want Potts with me.
She's still in Phase 2.
You're not going deaf, are ya?
Careful there, it's a limited edition.
Hey, uh, ponytail express.
- What is the mileage count between Tennessee and Miami?
- 832 miles.
Very nice.
- Are you gonna stop that?
- Break it you bought it.
Okay, that wasn't mine to give away, that
belongs to my friend's sister,
and that's why I'm gonna
kill you first.
- What're ya gonna do to me?
- You'll see.
- You're zip-tied to a bed.
- This.
That.
Are you comin' out?
Do not open, do not open, don't open,
don't open, don't. Alright, let's go.
You breathe fire? Okay.
It's a glorious day, Savin.
This time tomorrow, I'll have the West's
most powerful leader in one hand.
And the world's most feared
terrorist in the other.
I'll own the War on Terror.
Creates supply and demand for you
and your brothers and sisters.
Trust me, you're going in a puddle of blood
on the ground in 5, 4, 3, Come on!, 2
How did we get this shit?
Alright, I'm going to give you a chance to
escape, put down your weapons.
And tie yourselves into those chairs
and I'll let you live. In 5, 4
You should be gone by now, you
should have already been gone.
I'm just beyond terrified.
Here it comes.
3, 4
- Shut up.
- 5..4..3..2..1.
I told you.
Where's the rest?
Honestly, I hate working here..
they are so weird.
Better late than never.
Not this time. Not the face.
Phew, it's good to be back. Hello,
by the way.
Oh, hello sir.
All personnel, Stark is loose and
somewhere in the compound.
Repeat: Stark is loose and somewhere
in the compound.
Ah, crap.
- Tony.
- Rudy, tell me that was you in the suit.
No, you got yours?
Uh, um, kind of. Main house
as fast as you can.
Somebody I'd like you to meet.
You, you. Move!
Get out!
The room is secure. I have eyes
on the Mandarin.
What's this? I had winner's.
What've you come as?
Make a move and I'll break
your face.
I never thought people had been hurt.
They lied to me.
This is the Mandarin?
I know, it's, it's embarrassing.
Hi, I'm Trevor,
Trevor Slattery.
I know I'm shorter in person, I'm a bit
small, everyone says that but, uh, hey
if you're here to arrest me, there are
some people who I'd like to roll on.
Here's how it works,
Meryl Streep.
You tell him where Pepper
is and he'll stop doing it.
Doing what? Oh, I get it! Ow!
That hurt! I get it! I get it!
I do not know about any Pepper,
but I know the plan.
- Spill.
- Do you know what they did to my suit?
What? No. But I do know what's happening
off the coast.
Something to do with uh.. a big boat.
I can take you there.
Tony, I swear to God, I'm going
to blow his face off.
Oh this next bit may include the
Vice President as well.
- Is that important?
- Somewhat.
Yeah, a little bit.
- So?
- Uh, what are we gonna do.
We don't have any transport.
Hey, Ringo, didn't you say something
about a "lovely speedboat"?
If he's right about the location, we're
20 minutes from where Pepper is.
But we also have to figure out this
Vice President thing, right?
I wonder who I'm calling right now.
Oh, that's the Vice President.
- Hello.
- Sir, this is Tony Stark.
Welcome back to the land
of the living.
We believe you're about to be drawn
into the Mandarin campaign,
and we've got to get you somewhere safe
as soon as possible.
Mr. Stark, I'm about to eat honey roast
ham surrounded by the agency's finest.
And the President is safe on Air Force One
with Colonel Rhodes.
I think we're good here.
Sir, this is Colonel Rhodes!
They're using the Iron Patriot
as a trojan horse.
They're gonna take out
the President somehow. We have to
immediately alert that plane.
Okay, I'm on it. I'll have security
lock it down. If need be,
they can have F22s in the air in 30 seconds.
Thank you, Colonel.
Rhodes and Stark out.
Everything okay, sir?
Couldn't be better.
I love you, baby.
Colonel Rhodes. Glad to see
you could make it, son.
I feel safer already.
We gotta make a decision.
We can either save
the President or Pepper.
We can't do both.
Sir, I have an update
from Malibu.
The cranes have finally
arrived and the
cellar doors are being
cleared as we speak.
And what about the suit
I'm wearing?
The armor is now at 92%.
That's gonna have to do.
Oh, here he comes, here he comes,
get a quick picture.
Sure.
Is everything all right,
Colonel?
It is an honor,
Mr. President.
If you're gonna do it, do it.
Whoa. Cool your boots, Sir.
That's not how the
Mandarin works.
Sir. Air Force One's
been compromised.
Internal shots, temperature
spikes.
Get me eyes on it now.
Image coming through now, Sir.
Is that Rhodes?
The President.
Now.
He's not here.
Try the jet stream.
Speaking of which, go fish!
Walk away from that, you
son of a bitch.
- How many in the air?
- Thirteen, sir.
- How many can I carry
- Four, sir.
Slow down, slow down. Relax, what's
your name? Heather..
Listen to me, see that guy?
I'm gonna swing by him
and you're just gonna grab him.
You got it?
I will electrify your arm,
you won't be able to open
your hand.
You can do this, Heather.
Easy, see? Eleven
more to go.
Remember that game called
Barrel of Monkeys?
That's what we're going to do.
18,000 feet.
Come on, people! Everybody, grab
your monkey!
- Nice!
- 10,000 feet.
- 6,000 feet.
- Come on, people.
Come on, come on, come on
- Yeah!
- 1000 feet.
400 feet. 200 feet,
sir.
It's a tricky monkey,
let's get him.
Hello.
Nice work guys.
Excellent.
Good team effort all around.
Go us.
Alright, Jarvis, but it's only half done,
we still gotta get Pepp..
That came out of nowhere.
Gimme some good news man.
- I think they all made it.
- Thank God.
Yeah, but I missed the President.
You couldn't save the President
with the suit,
how are you gonna save Pepper
without it?
Uh, say Jarvis, is it
that time?
The "house party"
protocol, sir?
Correct.
Hi.
You think he's gonna help you..
he won't.
Having you here is not just
to motivate Tony Stark,
it's actually more embarrassing
than that.
- You're here as my, um
- Trophy.
Good evening, sir.
Welcome aboard,
Mr. President.
You ever heard of an elephant
graveyard?
Well, two years ago, the elephant in
the room was this scow.
This is the Roxxon Norco.
Of course you remember when she spilled 100
million gallons of crude off Pensacola.
Thanks to you, not one fat
cat saw a day in court.
What do you want from me?
Uh, nothing, sir.
I just needed a reason to kill you
that would play well on TV.
You see, I've moved on. I've found myself
a new political patron, and
At this time tomorrow, he'll
have your job.
String him up.
Come on.
You're not gonna freak out
on me, right?
I hope not.
Oh my God.
He's strung up over the oil tank, they're
gonna light him up, man.
Viking funeral.
- Public execution.
- Yeah, death by oil.
Broadcast will commence shortly.
Take final positions.
Okay, that's good.
Now give me cameras A through E
and we'll do a full tech rehearsal.
Is your gun up?
Yup, what do I do?
Stay on my six, cover high, and don't
shoot me in the back.
Six, high, back. Alright.
You see that? Nailed it.
Yeah, you really killed
the glass.
I was aiming for the bulb?
You can't hit a bulb from
this distance.
I'm out. Gimme, gimme, you got
an extra magazine?
They're not universal, Tony.
I know what I'm doing, I make this stuff.
Gimme another one.
I don't have one that
fits that gun.
You've got like five of them.
Alright, here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna spot. Ready?
What'd you see?
Too fast, nothing.
Here we go.
Three guys, one girl,
all armed.
God, I'd kill for some
armor right now.
- You're right, we need backup.
- Yeah, much.
You know what?
- Is that?
- Yep.
- Are those?
- Yeah.
Merry Christmas, buddy.
Jarvis, target Extremis heat
signatures.
Disable with extreme prejudice.
Yes, sir.
What are you waiting for?
It's Christmas.
Take 'em to church.
Jarvis, get Igor to steady
this thing.
This is how you've been managing
your downtime, huh?
Everybody needs a hobby.
Heartbreaker? Help Red Snapper
out, will ya?
Nice timing.
Oh yeah, that's awesome. Give me
a suit, okay?
Oh, I'm sorry. They're
only coded to me.
What's that mean?
I got you covered.
- Good evening, Colonel. Can I give you a lift?
- Very funny.
- Sir, I've located Miss Potts.
- About time.
Stop, put it down, put it
down, put it down.
See what happens when you hang out
with my ex-girlfriends?
You're such a jerk.
Yup, we'll talk about
it at dinner.
Come on, a little more, baby.
Is this guy bothering you?
Don't get up!
Is it hot there?
Stuck? Feel a little stuck?
Like a little turtle, cooking in
his little turtle suit?
Tony..
She's watching.
I think you should close
your eyes.
Close your eyes.
Close your eyes. You don't
want to see this.
Yeah, you take a minute.
Jarvis, give me a suit
right now!
Aw, come on!
Mr. President! Just hold on,
alright? I'm coming.
Just hold on.
Hold on.
Buh-bye.
Brace yourself!
You look damn good, Mr. President, but
I'm gonna need that suit back.
The President is secure, Tony.
I'm clearing the area.
Nice work.
- Ready sir?
- What do you mean "ready"?
Pep, I got you. Relax, I got you.
Just look at me.
Honey, I can't reach any further, and
you can't stay there, alright?
You gotta let go.
You gotta let go. I'll catch
you, I promise.
What a shame, I would
have caught her.
Eject.
Well here we are, on the roof.
- Mark 42 inbound.
- Well I'll be damned.
The prodigal son returns.
Whatever.
You really didn't deserve
her, Tony.
It's a pity. I was so close to having
her.. perfect.
Okay, okay, wait, wait, slow down,
slow down.
You're right. I don't
deserve her.
But here's where you're wrong.
She was already perfect.
Jarvis, do me a favor and
blow Mark 42.
No..!!
No more false faces.
You said you wanted
the Mandarin.
You're looking right at him.
It was always me, Tony, right
from the start.
I am the Mandarin!
I got nothing.
Jarvis, subject at my 12 o'clock
is not a target, disengage!
What? Oh what, are
you mad at me?
Honey.
Oh my God.
I was really violent.
You just scared the devil out of me.
I thought you were
I was dead. Why? Because I
fell two hundred feet?
- Who's the hot mess now?
- Still debatable.
Probably tipping your way
a little bit.
Why don't you dress like
this at home?
Hmm? Sports bra, the
whole deal.
You know I think I understand why you
don't want to give up the suits.
What I am gonna complain
about now?
Well, it's me. I'll think
of something.
- Don't touch me. No, I'm gonna burn you!
- No, no.
You're not hot.
Am I gonna be okay?
No, you're in a relationship with me,
everything will never be okay.
But I think I can figure
this out, yeah.
I almost had this 20 years ago when I was
drunk. I think I can get you better.
That's what I do.
I fix things.
And all your distractions?
Uh, I'm gonna shave them
down a little bit.
- Jarvis, hey.
- All wrapped up here, sir.
Will there be anything else?
You know what to do.
The "clean slate" protocol,
sir?
Screw it, it's Christmas.
Yes, yes.
Okay so far?
You like it?
It'll do.
And so, as Christmas morning began, my
journey had reached its end.
You start with something pure,
something exciting.
Then come the mistakes.
The compromises.
"We create our own Demons".
It's great to see you.
As promised, I get Pepper sorted down
Took some angry..
and then I talk to myself,
way stop there.
Of course, there are people who
say progress is dangerous.
But I'll bet none of those idiots ever had
to live with a chest full of shrapnel.
And now.. neither will I.
Let me tell you, that was the best
sleep I'd had in years.
- It's okay, it's okay.
- No!
So if I were to wrap this up tight
with a bow or whatever.
I guess I'd say my armor was never
a distraction or a hobby.
It was a cocoon.
And now, I'm a changed man.
You can take away my house,
All my tricks and toys.
One thing you can't take away..
I am Iron Man.
You know, and thank you, by
the way, for listening.
There's just something about getting
it off my chest and putting
it out there in the atmosphere
instead of holding this in.
I mean, this is what gets people
sick, you know?
Wow, I had no idea you were
such a good listener.
To be able to share all of my intimate
thoughts and my experiences
with someone, it just cuts the weight
of it in half, you know.
It's like a snake swallowing
its own tail.
Everything comes full circle.
And.. and the fact that you've been
able to help me process..
- So, uh..?
- You with me?
I was, yeah. Mm..hmm. We were..
uh, we were at, uh..
You actively napping?
I..I was.. I.. I..
I drifted.
Where did I lose you?
Elevator in Switzerland.
So you heard none of it?
I'm sorry, I'm not that
kind of doctor.
I'm not a therapist, it's not
my training.
- So?
- I don't have the..
- What? The time?
- Temperament.
You know what? Now that I
think about it,
Oh God, my original wound.
1983, alright?
Yes.
I'm 14 years old, I still have a nanny?
That was weird.
SubText: NoRMITA.326