When I die and they lay me to rest
Gonna go to the place that's the best
When I lay me down to die
Goin' up to the spirit in the sky
- Goin' up to the spirit in the sky
- Spirit in the sky
- It's where I'm gonna go when I die
- When I die
When I die and they lay me to rest
I'm gonna go
to the place that's the best
Prepare yourself, you know it's a must
Gotta have a friend in Jesus
So you know that when you die
He's gonna recommend you
to the spirit in the sky
Gonna recommend you
- That's where you're gonna go when you die
- When you die
When you die and they lay you to rest
You're gonna go to the place
that's the best...
Oh, thank you very much.
May I trouble you for a pillow?
- Sure.
- Great. Thank you.
The temperature in Miami
is currently 86 degrees and muggy.
We will be starting our descent
for landing in just a few moments...
Herman Gotlieb...
Gotlieb.
Please remain seated
with your seat belts on
until the captain has
turned off the seat belt sign.
All passengers holding tickets
to Eastern Flight 162 to Tampa
please come to the ticket counter.
Hey.
Wow, thanks.
All passengers leaving on Flight 266
please go directly
to the check-in desk at Gate 6.
All passengers leaving...
Hi.
Please go directly
to the check-in desk at Gate 6.
Hi.
Hi there. Going home?
I'd like to tell you about a book.
It's a classic of the Vedic literature,
"The Knowledge of God."
Have you seen the movie "Gandhi?"
My name's Ravindra. What's your name?
Trouble.
Mr. Gotlieb.
You know, anything you want...
Hey, send me up a girl, Pablo. Now.
You got any of that hundred
I gave you last week?
I got all of it, man.
But I'm not lending you no more money.
Come on, Blink.
Look, 50 bucks till payday.
Moseley. Homicide.
A what died?
All right. Right away.
I'll pay to find the dumbbell killers.
What's it worth to you?
$61 .35.
$65.59.
Thanks, Blink.
Hey, man, replace your teeth.
Hi.
Pablo sent me.
How old are you anyway?
19. And my name is Pepper.
You got a driver's license
on you, Pepper?
What's wrong with Susan Waggoner?
You know, Susie, this license here
says you're 23 years old.
I know what it says.
You can call me Junior.
You around a size 7?
Where?
Dress.
Oh.
Uh... 6.
Sometimes 7. Depends on...
- Here. Try this on.
- Okay.
Could you turn around, please?
- Oh, yeah.
- Thank you.
Okay.
Can you zip me up?
Yeah.
Oh...
That looks nice to me.
You want me to wear it?
Fuck, no. I want you to buy it.
50 bucks?
It might be worth a suck.
Is that what you're getting
for a suck these days, 50 bucks?
Christ.
Where'd you get all these nice things?
Oh, when I left my wife,
I took 'em with me.
Figure I paid for 'em.
They're my clothes, right?
Oh.
You left your wife?
How long you been working for Pablo?
Since the beginning of the semester.
I go to Miami-Dade.
I-I'm majoring in business,
but I also take English classes...
Yeah, well, the first thing
they should have taught you
at your hooker classes
is you shouldn't ask the client
so many fucking personal questions.
I'm sorry.
Are you going to call down
and cancel me now?
That's okay. Don't feel bad about it.
Um... I hope, uh...
the next girl's more to your liking,
and I hope that you enjoy
your stay in Florida. Mr. Gotlieb.
- I'm giving you your dress back.
- No, forget about the dress.
Honey...
If I upset you, I'm sorry.
So you want me to stay?
Yeah.
Okay, then.
Let's do it.
Ready?
Turn over.
Is something wrong?
I haven't been with a woman
in a long time.
Oh.
Wow.
I'm sorry.
Nobody kisses us.
"Pepper."
Okay, Henderson, what's up?
These two Krishnas have been working
the airport for a couple of months.
Now they'd been warned
about bugging the passengers.
- Should've listened.
- Yeah.
How was he killed?
He fucked with some guy
wearing a suede leather sport coat.
So the guy takes his finger,
bends it back, breaks it, then disappears.
Now the witness lady says
she thinks that, uh...
well, he hopped on one
of the hotel courtesy vans.
We got a partial description.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
The Krishna died of a broken finger?
I mean, is that a homicide?
Well, I guess he died of shock.
Well, it hurts like hell
to have your finger bent back.
My sister used to do it
to me when I was a kid.
Yeah, but you didn't die.
Now, if this was an accident...
it'd be simple assault, right?
However... if the guy
in the suede sport coat
knew that Krishnas
had a bad habit of dying
every time you bent their finger back...
- Murder one?
- Yeah.
Boy, the guys at the station
are going to laugh their asses off.
Yeah.
Your turn to notify next of kin.
No way!
I did the fat lady that sat on a kid.
- That's good for two.
- Next week?
I'll be retired by then.
Shit.
Well, you try the hotels.
See if anyone got off one of their
courtesy vans wearing a suede sport coat.
Ah, shit.
This is good here.
Oh, excuse me.
- Maybe we should try in here.
- All right, all right.
Price check. Uzi squirt gun.
Disregard.
What's up?
In the bag. In the bag. Now!
Against the wall. Against the wall. Now!
Be cool. Be cool. Be cool, brother.
Hey, he's got a gun!
Let's get out of here! Move it!
Give me a day's notice
before it runs out, okay?
Wednesday.
Tell me Tuesday.
Looky, looky, looky.
We got a million dollars.
We got a million... Brazilian dollars.
Absolutely worthless.
That's a lot of money, man.
That's a lot of fucking money.
I don't think you are
a Porsche customer...
Mr. Frenger.
I don't think you really
want to buy a Porsche.
Do you want to buy a Porsche?
No, man! I'm here to waste my time.
How much for the speedboat, man?
Oh, the speedboat
is very expensive, sir.
That speedboat is $50,000.
Wrap it up, man.
Yeah, the bellman said
some guy matching the description
got off a courtesy van,
registered, yeah.
Got a name?
Name was, uh... Herman Gotlieb.
Yeah. I'm in the room right now.
Coat's here, too.
Coat? What else?
Well, the bellman also said
the guy had a hooker with him, yeah.
- No lie?
- I got an address on her.
- An address?
- Right.
Oh, man.
Got a pen handy there, Hoke?
Give me the hooker's address.
- Hi!
- Hey.
You showed up. I brought you a present.
Oh, really? I got you one, too.
A present from a client.
Well, hey, I'm more than a client.
"Shit happens when you party naked!"
Look at us.
I was just gonna get you
the plain "Shit happens,"
but I thought you'd like
the "party naked" part.
Hey, that's the best part.
Hi. Um... circe salad, Noira.
It's real good, Junior.
Two.
Right away.
So, uh... Susie...
tell me how you wound up
living in Miami.
Oh, I got a job
at a Burger World up in Hollywood
and I was gonna, you know
save up and get my own franchise
but Pablo offered me this job.
Well, it pays a whole lot better.
This is a nice cup, Junior.
I'm gonna get a lot of use out of this.
It's a good cup.
Hey, did you see the swimmers?
That's why I picked this place.
They do, like, a water ballet.
Ballet in the water. I like it.
'Cause I like to swim myself.
I'd rather do that kind
of work, you know?
But you gotta train for a long time.
So now I want to take
a Spanish course in college.
You know, in my business,
a lot of people don't speak English.
So I think I'd be better at it if I spoke...
thank you.
- We'll take a check now.
- Yes, sir.
You know, like, well, Cuban, also.
And I think that's sort of like Spanish,
Cuban, but it's a little different.
This ice cream dressing is sour as shit.
It's yogurt dressing, not ice cream.
Where you been?
Oh, that's okay.
I never had yogurt dressing
up in Okeechobee.
Where is that?
That's where I'm from.
You heard of Lake Okeechobee.
I'm from California.
I don't know shit about Florida.
You ever heard of Lake Tahoe?
Lake Tahoe?
- How is it?
- Lousy.
- Who is he?
- We're engaged.
Hey, separate checks.
- My treat.
- Good luck.
Hey, Susie we're not gonna be
calling it a night, are we?
I got a homework paper.
I gotta write a haiku for English class.
I tell you what.
I'm real good at making up things,
you know, poems.
I could come over.
I could help you write your, uh...
- Haiku?
- Definitely.
Okay.
Let's get out of here.
Thank you. I'm sorry. I liked the food.
Bye.
So you think this unidentified
assailant who broke, uh...
Ravindra's finger did it on purpose?
Sorry, uh... Ramba.
That's all right.
That was a short engagement.
Hey, you know, you still
haven't told me what it is you do.
Oh, I got investments.
I take people's money
and put it to work.
You got any?
I got a $10,000 CD
and I take the interest from that,
and I put it into a N.O.W. account.
Jesus Christ.
That's the biggest
frigging racket going.
I want you to march straight down
to the bank first thing in the morning
and cash in both of those things.
I can't let my fiancee get ripped-off
when I can double your money.
- Double?
- Yeah.
Hey. Hey.
How 'bout that poem we were gonna write?
Okay.
We make love a lot.
We make love right now.
No, it's seven in the second line.
- Seven in the second line?
- Uh-huh.
Splashes around... in his pond
Could you close the door, please?
Thinking... he's...
alone.
Breaking... entering...
the dark... and lonely place... places.
Finding a...
big gun.
Yeah.
Smelling like a rose.
- Any luck?
- I wrote two.
Wow, maybe I'll get extra credit.
Hey, where'd you get these?
Dumb question. Are you a nosy rosy?
What the hell was that, man?
The doorbell.
Talk about dumb questions.
- Yes?
- Susan Waggoner?
- Uh-huh.
- Can I come in?
I bet you're Herman Gotlieb.
How much?
Sergeant Hoke Moseley. Homicide.
Herman Gotlieb.
I'd like to ask you
a few questions. Routine.
Boy, you got a grip there, Herman.
Been working out?
Can I get you a cold one there, Sarge?
Well, why not?
Two Polars, honey.
You down at the airport today, Herman?
Yeah, I was.
Somebody broke the finger
off a Hare Krishna
and the son of a bitch died.
No shit?
No shit.
I didn't do it.
Oh, no, no, no,
we're just looking for someone
who might have seen anything.
I'm curious, uh...
you own a suede sport coat?
Yeah, I do.
Okay. You're probably the one.
Did you get on the courtesy van
to the Grand Prix Hotel?
Hey, fuck this nonsense, man.
Hey, you're misunderstanding this,
Herman.
Who got killed?
You know, if I had something better to do
like sit at home with a beautiful girl
I wouldn't even be
bothering you, but, uh...
you were mentioned
as a possible witness.
See anything?
Nope.
We got this forensic dentist.
And I, uh... I talked him
into pulling my teeth
and fixing me some new choppers.
It took two months of his spare time.
And I got so used to drinking
without 'em, I just pull 'em out.
Bother you?
Junior?
You want me to fix those pork chops now?
Hell, I'll put 'em
back in for pork chops.
Pork chops comin' up.
Herman?
Your fiancee
is the best cook in South Florida.
More taters?
Junior?
So, Herman, where'd you do your time?
Time? What do you mean?
Well, the way you're guarding that food.
You know, like another con
could take it away from you.
Well, I was raised
in foster homes, you know?
I didn't get no dessert
till I was in eighth grade.
Damn.
I got a daughter in the eighth grade.
Half my paycheck goes
to her orthodontist.
She's got your teeth, man.
Yeah, the joint's about the only place
you got time to work out
to get a grip like that.
I was an aerobics instructor.
Shoots the shit out of that theory.
Any more Polars?
Oh... Junior got the last one.
I could run out and get some.
Beer's gone, I'm gone.
Aw, you're kidding.
But, you know,
I gotta get that pork chop recipe first.
No. Are you serious?
It is so easy, what I did.
You are definitely
not gonna have to write this down.
All it is is pork chops in a frying pan.
And just cook 'em
in their own fat with a lot of salt.
Oh, well, they sure were good,
but you know what I really like...
is native Florida cooking.
Now, did you ever have
chestnut batter on your pork chops?
Boy, I never did.
You got a recipe for that somewhere?
Uh... yeah, I do, as a matter of fact.
I'll give it to you. Just a minute here.
Oh, I appreciate that.
Great dinner.
Get you something to go, Sarge?
Just you.
Kidding, Herman.
Listen, if you think of anything,
just, uh... give me a call.
That's my home phone.
Look, it's a hotel,
and the old guy at the desk is deaf,
so, uh... just let it ring
till he sees the lights.
Oh, and, uh... when we round up
the usual airport hoodlums,
maybe you could shoot by
and take a look at a line-up.
Take you five minutes.
Oh, yeah.
You mind standing in the line-up, too?
We're a little short of bodies.
You ever stood
in a line-up before, Herman?
Never been caught, Sarge.
Ah, you ain't got one beer rat-holed
I can take with me for the road, do you?
You got it all, man. Dog biscuits, too.
See you.
Night, Susie.
Years ago, I started
preaching catch-and-release.
Back then, a lot of things
seemed to indicate
that our bass resource
in many areas of the country
was rapidly diminishing.
Today, there is no doubt about it,
and I'm very concerned
about what the future holds
for this great sport.
In simple terms we don't have
the vast water we once had
and there are several reasons for it...
pollution, illegal netting,
the pressure of removing
too many adult bass
from their environment.
You know, they're kind
of like money in the bank.
I got news for you.
I'm not coming back. I'm married.
I am so married. I gotta go. Bye.
You like ham and eggs?
Hey! Drop it.
Smells good.
- Who was that, anyway?
- Pablo. The cops rousted him.
I guess they're giving him
a hard time because of you.
We got to go for a little ride, honey.
What? What about breakfast?
It was gonna be a surprise.
I was gonna bring it
in to you on a tray, and then I...
Make it to go.
Okay.
Not too tired for some fun?
Call it a night, sister.
Aye, aye, sir.
I got something that I gotta tell you.
I used to be in prison.
What'd you do to get there?
I used to rob people who robbed people.
Kind of like Robin Hood?
Yeah.
Except I didn't give the money
to the poor people.
Oh.
You don't do that anymore, do you?
I got investments now.
Good. You got me out of the life.
Now you stay out of crime.
Sounds good.
Promise?
Yeah, sure. Why not?
Say you promise.
I promise.
Henderson? Sanchez. Homicide.
- Oh, my replacement.
- How is he?
He's got a cervical disc injury,
a dislocated jaw, bruises,
uh... got a concussion,
I don't know how bad it is.
Somebody really worked him over.
Did he tell you who did it?
What happened?
No, he's in and out of consciousness.
Drop the knife, Pablo.
My name isn't Gotlieb.
Sergeant Hoke Moseley, homicide.
That little girl you sent up to my room?
She's 15 years old, man.
She's 23, man. She's not 15.
Look. Sergeant Lackley checked her I.D.
Why don't you call him?
I pay him every week.
Maybe you two guys can get together.
How much you pay Lackley every week?
$500 a week. Don't.
All right, from now on,
Lackley gets 250.
The other 250 to me at the Primrose Hotel.
You got it, man?
Lackley's not gonna go
for any split like that.
You tell the guy at the desk
to leave it for me in the safe.
Hi. What can I get for you?
- Ice coffee.
- Okay.
Hey! What are you doing?
Open it!
Open the goddamn drawer now! Do it!
Stop or I'll shoot!
You just shot me.
I fired a warning shot, and it hit you.
You're no cop.
No problem. There is no problem.
Police. Homicide.
You people go about your business.
You finish your lunches,
your breakfasts, whatever.
Don't worry, lady,
I'm gonna call an ambulance now
on the radio in my police car.
Yeah. I'll be right back.
Slow down.
Go ahead.
Stop right here!
- Furnished?
- Yeah, with almost antiques.
How much?
I been worried sick!
Where you been all day?!
Dumb question.
Did you get the money?
I cashed in the $10,000 CD,
but I decided to keep
the N.O.W. account open
for eight more days.
What did I tell you? Huh?
They said if I keep it
open for eight more days,
I'll be eligible for a teapot.
I'm sorry.
It's just 8 more days.
You'll still be here, won't you?
I don't know.
My problem is that I can have everything
and anything that I want
but I don't know what I want.
Tell me again about
that Burger World franchise.
Okay.
Okay. You need $50,000.
You borrow another 50,000
from Burger World
and you wait for an opening.
But why? What's the purpose?
To make a living, that's all.
You hire kids
so you can pay 'em nothing.
And you watch 'em real close
or they will steal you blind.
And... and you save your money,
and you buy a nice little house
with a white picket fence.
And you live happily ever after.
I tell you what... let's go straight
to the "happily ever after" part, okay?
I can't see any point in hanging out
at a Burger World
no matter how much money
you're gonna make.
It's stupid.
You can forget
about Burger World, honey.
Okay.
I'm gonna take care of you,
and you're gonna take care of me.
That's our purpose.
Do you know any married people today?
Hmm? They're a team.
They pull together, and they get rich.
They got it all.
And you know that little house
you were just talking about?
I rented us one in Coral Gables today.
Oh, Junior.
That's what you were up to all day?
I'm gonna take such good care of you.
He was a big guy, man. Bigger than you.
Got up from the table,
said he was homicide.
Pulled a badge?
After he whacks the dude.
It was cold, man, ice cold.
Thanks, Blink.
What do I owe you?
It's on the house, bro.
Come on.
I like the air conditioning on "frozen."
Me, too.
- Half-ounce. Primo, man.
- Thanks, man.
Hey, half that's mine.
Fuck you! I sold it. I keep the money.
These are my contacts.
They're my people.
I don't give a shit about your contacts.
Don't turn your back
when I'm talkin' to you.
I'm tired of your shit.
Get out of my face!
Police! Freeze!
Stand over there.
Put that on. Right through there.
You know what to do, Shorty.
- Hey!
- I don't believe this.
I'm gonna let you two guys go...
with a little warning.
- Don't get caught.
- Shit!
Police! Don't move!
You can go now.
Give me your wallet!
Come on, man. Move it
Police! Drop it!
I said drop it.
Shoot him!
Make it, Julio. Comprendo?
Yeah. Yeah.
That's my purse! Stop him!
Stop! Somebody please help me!
Go get him.
Thank you, officer.
Yeah, that's great, lady.
But... you're a cop!
Hey! Police! Police!
You have anything against broccoli,
cauliflower, stuff like that?
I don't want to talk
about that at this time.
Oh.
What are you going to do
now that we're married?
Take care of the house,
shop, fix dinner.
Take care of the babies.
Is that what you'd like to do?
Be a mother?
Well, I don't...
I guess so.
I... I don't... I don't know.
I lived with a girl once for 2 months.
She didn't do anything a housewife
was supposed to do.
I thought you said you were married.
I told you that before
I really knew you.
What I'm driving at, Susie,
is I want to have a regular life.
I want to go to work in the morning,
sometimes at night, come home
to a clean house and a hot meal
and a loving wife just like you.
I don't want to have any babies.
This world's a shit hole.
You think you can handle that?
I do.
It's better than counting money.
These yours?
I can't tell.
Yeah. This, uh... nail polish.
We found two muscle heads
cuffed together.
Jesus! He's making arrests?
We did some routine prints.
They match those taken
from the scene of the dumbbell murders.
I've been working
that case for 15 months.
Congratulations. Case is closed.
Find Gotlieb?
We're looking for him.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
- Okay.
- I'll find him.
Yeah, maybe you should wait
and let him solve
a couple more from your case load, huh?
Will you have a seat, please?
- Where, here?
- Your name, please?
Ziffel. Fred Ziffel.
Is that the way you want
the account to read?
No. I want it to read "Arnold Ziffel."
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Hey, Eddie.
Here's the key to your new suite.
Oh, and some Cuban kid
on a bicycle made two deliveries.
Uh... 250 in both.
I'm sorry. I opened them.
It's okay, Eddie.
- Thanks.
- Uh-huh.
- Who is it?
- Lackley. Vice.
Slide your I.D. under the door.
- Are you fucking serious?
- Try me!
Next thing you hear will be a bullet
coming through the door!
Pablo sent this.
- What?
- What's the matter, Sarge?
Got a guilty conscience?
I just got out of the hospital.
I know. I know all about you.
I like your place here, too.
It's very nice.
You also got a little something
that belongs to me, don't you, Gums?
What the fuck you talking about?
Never seen you before in my life.
Now, listen, Sarge you think
you're moving in on my territory?
I think you better cough up
some "do-re-mi" right now.
500 bucks. Let's have it.
What 500 bucks?
What are you talking about?
- Fuck off!
- Fuck off?! Fuck off?!
You go to Pablo,
you cut yourself in on my action.
You don't think I'm coming after you?
Jesus Christ! You got a lot of balls!
And Pablo wants the hooker
back on the job
tomorrow at 10:00,
and all is forgiven, Gums.
What hooker?
10:00.
He got your gun and your badge...
and your teeth?
You are a disgrace to the police force.
Fucking Junior "Bullshit" Gotlieb.
- Hey, you got a piece, Eddie?
- Teeth?
- No. A gun. A gun. I need it.
- Hold on.
Hair trigger.
Hollow points.
Thanks, Eddie.
Where's Antonio?
On your feet, pal.
Turn around.
Move it!
Police raid! Everybody freeze!
Run for it!
Yo! Hey, guys!
Come on back. Where are you goin'?
Come on. I got this covered!
At ease, officer.
I think you'd better
check with your superiors.
Remain silent.
Hey, I pay good money
to the right people, huh?
Were you out at the airport today?
Was I out at the airport today?
What, are you crazy?
- You ever stood in a line-up before?
- Oh, yeah. I stood in a line-up before.
Okay, I want you to line up there!
Hey, what the hell's going on here?
Shut up!!
You own a suede sports coat?
Courtesy van?
You ain't no cop.
Oh, I'm a cop.
Prove it, slick.
You're not walking... agh!
You crazy son of a bitch!
I'll kick the living shit...
Hey, Scanlan.
Hey.
Hey, Smiley. How are you?
Ellita Sanchez?
Hoke Moseley.
I've been calling you.
Don't they have someone
at that desk to answer?
Yeah. But he's deaf. Got something?
Prints I.D. on those beer bottles.
That's the son of a bitch!
"Frederick J. Frenger, Junior."
Junior Gotlieb.
I knew that was bullshit.
I got something on the real Gotlieb.
Mugged, DOA at
the San Francisco Airport Hospital.
Sound like Junior's MO?
Murder one.
We can nail him as
the Krishna finger killer, I bet.
He's grown up behind bars.
And look at this.
Someone charged a suede sport coat
on the real Gotlieb's credit card
after he was dead.
We got the motherfucker!
Thanks.
I'm sorry. Habit.
I ran his real name by the utilities,
but it turned up nothing.
He wouldn't use his real name.
Well, if he did, we'd be knocking
on his door right now.
What about Waggoner?
I called every utility in Dade.
Even bottled water.
I'm sitting here having my lunch
waiting for a call back, okay?
Sitting on your lunch?
Try Broward.
Look, I know you think
I'm a weak suck, but I don't care.
The guy who did this to me,
this Frenger, Junior,
he's got my old badge, Sanchez.
He's running around playing cop
assaulting and beating people.
I'm doing everything I can to help.
Call me if you hear anything.
Put the funny book down!
Give me the fuckin' cash
or I'll blow your fuckin' head off!
Come on, don't count it, God damn it!
Police! Drop the gun, son.
I know what it's like to be
on the other end of that gun.
You're making a big mistake.
I tell you what.
You put down the gun, give back the money
and I'll let you walk on out of here.
You walk out that door
your life is gonna change forever.
Hold your fire, you asshole!
What the fuck?!
Hey.
Hey, you okay? Hey, mister.
Get this thing off me. I'm a cop.
I think I hit him.
You didn't hit shit.
Where is the whipping cream?
We're out.
Oh, my God.
Okay, I want you to do something for me.
Go get me some cotton balls... aah!
Some peroxide...
some bandages,
and bring me a small mirror!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh, fuck me. Okay.
Okay. Okay.
I want you to go and get me
your smallest needle,
a small needle and thread it
with black thread, okay?
Here. I got it.
I got it. I got it. I got it.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Oh, fuck. Oh, God. Oh, God.
Okay, Now I tell you what...
I want you to sew my eyebrow back on.
Okay?
Hey, hey! Now, come on, come on.
Come on. You're gonna be okay. I got it.
I'm sorry. I'm no good at this.
I got it.
What? Okay. Okay.
I got you. I'm gonna get you a doctor.
Oh, no. No doctors. No... no doctors.
I want you to get me a bottle of gin.
I nursed my husband
for 3 years before he died
but you're not going to die.
Here.
- It's gin, Junior.
- Drink it.
We're gonna need this.
This is going to hurt.
You move and you're a blind man.
Scissors.
Okay. Okay.
Hold it. Hold it.
You're doing real good, Junior.
I'm just gonna move down a bit.
Now we just have one more. Just hold on.
That'll hold you.
Your husband must have been glad to die.
Thank you.
Yeah, thanks.
You got a real nice touch there, lady.
So are you gonna tell me about it?
Yeah, I'll tell you about it.
This straight life
that we've been living
has been giving me this
misplaced sense of security!
I thought for one minute there I was some
kind of fuckin' solid citizen or something.
All I want to know
is what happened to you.
Some guy in a blue
Toyota pickup ran me over.
I thought it must have been
something like that.
An anonymous,
apparently off-duty police officer
interrupted a robbery tonight
at a Coral Gables convenience store,
heroically confronting an armed robber
with only bottles of spaghetti sauce.
The officer then left the scene of the crime
without identifying himself.
Police speculate that it...
Yeah?!
Ellita Sanchez.
Come in.
What's this?
Susan Waggoner, telephone order.
There's an address in the Gables.
The Gables.
- What time is it?
- It's 1:00.
I was going out on a date.
I've got a relative with Southern Bell
or we wouldn't have gotten
the number for days.
That's great. Thanks.
What are you going to do?
I'm gonna check it out.
Sanchez? Thanks.
Out of all the boys in the world
I choose you again...
You feeling better?
What would you like for breakfast?
I carefully consider
every choice and then
- Out of all the boys in the world
- You're not hungry?
I'd choose you again...
Okay, well, I'm just gonna
run some errands and then I'll be back.
I'd choose you
If God gave me the chance
To do it all again...
I love you.
Oh, I'd carefully consider...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Hey! Susan, uh... Waggoner, right?
- Remember me?
- No, sir.
Hoke "Pork Chops" Moseley.
God, what happened to you?
Ah, some psycho jumped me,
almost broke my neck,
stole my gun, my badge, and my teeth.
- Teeth?
- Yeah. These are temps.
Hey, I got something for you.
Do you do your marketing here?
Excuse me, would you
like to try some sausage?
- No, thank you.
- Are you sure? It's really good.
Remember that...
pork chop recipe I promised you
with the chestnut batter?
Glad I ran into you.
Oh, this is great.
I can't believe you remembered.
That is so nice of you.
I'm gonna put it on my list,
and I'm gonna make it tonight.
Hey, is that an invitation?
I'll be there.
Oh.
I got class tonight. I'm sorry.
You're still with that guy, huh?
No. Um... I kicked him out.
Well, good for you.
You know who he really is?
He's a murderer.
Herman Gotlieb isn't even his real name.
He spent his life in prison.
Frederick J. Frenger, Junior.
Junior.
Yeah.
Hate to run into Senior.
Oh... hey, you ever made vinegar pie?
Vinegar pie? My mother used to make it.
I can still taste it.
Oh. Seedless raisins for a start.
Chop 'em up real fine.
And you beat the egg yolks
and the butter until they're creamy
Wait a second.
And you beat the egg whites
until they're stiff,
and then you fold them in,
and you take one cup of sugar.
And, um... here's the tricky part, okay?
This is the key.
You use 5% vinegar, no stronger.
And just three teaspoons, that's all.
Just three little teaspoons.
That's where Mama went wrong.
Yeah, probably so.
You don't know where I could find
that old boyfriend of yours, do you?
No. He's gone for good.
I know you wouldn't lie for him.
He was the liar.
Well, uh... enjoy that recipe.
I will.
Look, my number's on it.
If you really like it, give me a call.
Oh, my God.
One.
Two.
Three.
What are you doing tomorrow?
I was gonna paint the security bars.
Oh, no, I got a million errands
I gotta run tomorrow.
I wanted to go in
and cash in my coin collection.
I need you to drive me around some.
We'll be done by noon.
Can't you drive?
Oh, no way, honey.
Honey, I gotta...
I'm gonna be hopping in and out
of a hundred different places.
Cost me a fortune just to park
if I could find a place.
That dessert?
I'll bring it to you. Just go sit down.
So, you gonna drive me around tomorrow?
Junior, are you sure
this is just an errand?
You promised no more illegal stuff.
You saved my life, Susie.
Would I fuck up the best thing
that ever happened to me
just to make you
some kind of a wheelman?
Would you?
We made a deal.
I promised.
Like it?
This is really great.
It's great!
Great.
One of your best.
If a cop should come by and hassle you,
then you just drive on around the block.
Why would anyone hassle me?
You parked in a yellow zone.
Oh.
Police officer. Buzz me in.
You say these coins
are stolen, Sergeant?
Sergeant, uh
Moseley.
Homicide.
We picked him up on a fencing sting.
We figure if we could get a line
on the owners, we could solve the crime.
This a valuable collection or what?
This is by no means a rare collection.
When I take
this fleeting breath
When my eyes,
they'll close in death
Just a cursory look at these coins
tells me they're in fair condition.
That was cursory?
You ever seen them before?
Seen lots like them.
What happened to your eye?
Car accident.
You should sue the doctor
who sewed you up.
You could make a bundle.
He said it'd be fine
after it scarred over.
He lied.
How come a homicide detective
is so interested in stolen property?
First of all, that's
confidential information.
Second of all, I'll ask all
the questions around here.
I'm working on a tip.
I'm thinking of putting
a stakeout in here.
You know, before I put that window in
I was hit three times in one month,
but I don't need no stakeout now.
Yeah? Why's that?
Because of Pedro. Pedro!
He's been watching you the whole time
through a peephole in the door.
It's okay, Pedro.
This is Sergeant Moseley.
He's with the police department.
Pedro!
You bitch!
Oh, God.
You promised!
What the fuck are you doing?!
- Freeze! Police!
Hold it!
Hey, move it!
Stop! Police!
Not again! No!
Get out of the car!
Shit.
What happened to you?
Raise your hands level
with your shoulders.
What are you gonna do if I don't, Sarge?
Shoot me?
What was the bullshit with the money
you left me, Frederick?
I don't give nothing away.
What did the Krishna do to die?
Where did you get that jacket?
Herman Gotlieb.
Stand up. Back up slowly.
Turn around and face the wall.
I don't think I can do that.
I'll pass out.
Most of my fingers have been cut off,
and I'll probably go into
shock any minute now.
Move it!
Everything's turning
all orange and silver.
Susie's gonna get you, Sarge.
Did you kill him?
Yes.
Good-bye, Junior.
You don't have to answer
if you don't want to, but, uh...
gotta clear a few things up.
Did you know Junior
was gonna rob the store?
I was hoping he wouldn't.
He swore to me.
I had to give him
the benefit of the doubt
because he had some good qualities.
He always ate everything
I ever cooked for him.
And he never hit me.
There were lots of good
things about Junior.
Listen, Hoke, this is exactly what happened
or you're in big jurisdictional trouble.
You were tailing him, a murder suspect.
You see him coming out of the coin shop
with a gun in his hand.
Suspecting him of robbery,
you called for back-up
and you followed him to the house.
He pulled a gun on you,
and you shot him.
- Something like that.
- Exactly like that.
There's only one problem,
though... the girl.
She'll blow holes in this story.
Cut her loose.
Is she really Princess Not-So-Bright
or is she just pretending?
Ah, she's been through hell.
Leave her alone.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
You look different.
Got my teeth back.
When I die and they lay me to rest
Gonna go to the place that's the best
When I lay me down to die
Goin' up to the spirit in the sky
- Goin' up to the spirit in the sky
- Spirit in the sky
- It's where I'm gonna go when I die
- When I die
When I die and they lay me to rest
I'm gonna go
to the place that's the best
Prepare yourself, you know it's a must
Gotta have a friend in Jesus
So you know that when you die
He's gonna recommend you
to the spirit in the sky
Gonna recommend you
- That's where you're gonna go when you die
- When you die
When you die and they lay you to rest
You're gonna go to the place
that's the best
Never been a sinner, I never sinned
I got a friend in Jesus
So you know that when I die
He's gonna set me up
with the spirit in the sky
- Oh, set me up with the spirit in the sky
- Spirit in the sky
- That's where I'm gonna go when I die
- When I die
When I die and they lay me to rest
I'm gonna go to the place
that's the best
Go to the place that's the best.