I always believed
it was the things you don't choose
that makes you who you are.
Your city.
Your neighborhood.
Your family.
People here take pride in these things.
Like it was something
they'd accomplished.
The bodies around their souls.
The cities wrapped around those.
I lived on this block my whole life.
Most of these people have.
When your job is to find people
who are missing,
it helps to know where they started.
I find the people
who started in the cracks,
and then fell through.
This city can be hard.
When I was young, I asked my priest
how you could get to heaven
and still protect yourself
from all the evil in the world.
He told me what God said
to his children.
"You are sheep among wolves,
"be wise as serpents,
"yet innocent as doves."
You live just across the street.
Is that right, ma'am?
That one on the corner,
that's our house.
You know, to get Annette
in high school, you have...
- I heard they had an opening.
- Yeah, me, too.
The thing is, she always
had a smile on her face.
That was her. She was always smiling.
I mean, who would take my little girl?
She never hurt anybody,
never caused...
Whoever you are, if you have her,
you just let her go.
Now, we won't charge you,
but if you're out there,
just let her come home.
All right? Let her come home.
I mean,
who would take my little girl?
- You fucking cops.
- She never caused no trouble,
she never got in any fights,
she's a sweetheart.
- This is just unbelievable.
- She was a good kid.
The whole force
standing outside the house,
guarding the sidewalk
with their arms crossed.
I mean, are the kidnappers
coming back?
Amanda McCready
was taken from her home
between 8:00 and 8:30
Wednesday night.
She's four years old,
has blond hair and green eyes...
- Hey.
...weighs 35 pounds
and is 40 inches tall.
- You know I love you, right?
- Yeah. I know.
A beleaguered
police force and a weary citizenry
have been left with so little to cling to.
A blanket, a back door,
and a doll named Mirabelle.
The neighborhood's
really coming together.
We're gonna have a rally.
Everyone's gonna have a vigil.
We're gonna have a vigil tonight.
You know, the neighborhood's all alert,
everybody's alert of what's going on
and everything that...
The surroundings. We got flyers up,
posters up, we have all that stuff up.
So everybody's well aware
and everybody's looking for Amanda.
In related news,
the Boston police captain
responsible for preventing
crimes against children
spoke a few words a moment ago,
words of comfort.
I know the pain of losing a daughter.
We will not fail.
We will pursue every avenue.
Do you know the mother?
Captain Jack Doyle on
details of the missing Dorchester girl...
Little bit.
I was a freshman, she was a senior.
She was blowing Mike Gulley
down the post
when he was still 14 and innocent
and milking cows up Vermont.
I don't know about innocent.
Her mother says Amanda
may be carrying a little girl of her own.
Mirabelle was last seen with Amanda.
It's her favorite doll.
This is horrible.
- Not if you're Channel 9.
- Turn it off.
Good night.
- Hey, Angie. Get the door?
I'm in the bathroom.
It's 7:00! Seven in the fucking morning!
What?
Are you Patrick Kenzie?
- Yeah.
- Bea and Lionel McCready.
Our niece was kidnapped
three days ago.
Please, come on in. Come on in.
I have to apologize.
You know, there's been some problems
with kids in the neighborhood,
kind of ding-dong ditch,
ringing the buzzer and running away.
So that's the reason for the language.
- Oh.
- Well, we can come back later.
No. Please, please.
Make yourself comfortable.
Here, we're just...
I'm sorry about the mess.
We've been...
I had a late case, and a lot of cases.
We've just been...
We've just been working a lot,
we worked on a case last night,
you know, so we just...
Please sit down, though.
Or...
My associate'll be in in just a minute.
She's in the other room.
How can we help you?
Do you know people
in the neighborhood
who don't talk to the police?
Yeah, one or two.
We wanna hire you to augment
the investigation of Amanda.
Is that right?
You know how in JonBenet Ramsey
the family hired investigators?
So... Are the police all right
with youse hiring outside help?
The police need to worry
about finding my niece.
Hi. I'm Angie Gennaro.
I work with Patrick.
Hello. I'm Bea McCready.
This is my husband, Lionel.
- How do you do?
- They wanna hire us
to augment the investigation.
You should talk
to Precision Investigators.
- Who? I...
- I don't know, I meant...
Well, let's hear them out, Ange.
Well, aren't you
missing persons detectives?
Yeah, that's what your ad says
in the paper.
Yeah, we are.
We are missing persons detectives.
I'm sorry, she...
I think that what Angie means to say is,
just for the sake of disclosure,
up to this point,
our experience has been primarily,
you know, finding missing persons
who've gone missing that they...
You know, they just stop payments on
their Jet Ski
and they went to New Hampshire...
Every police officer in this state
is looking for your niece right now.
And I'm not sure
how much more help we could be.
Well, you're not gonna
do any harm, are you?
All right, look.
I got a pension coming up with Edison.
- So, that's collateral, if...
- No. It's not that.
Why is this so hard?
The cops don't want me coming here.
- Lionel don't want me coming here.
- Don't worry.
- Now you don't want the job?
- No, it's not that we don't want the job...
We consult privately
before we make decisions like these.
- We do.
- Helene puts her to bed.
She goes across to Dottie's.
Maybe gone a half hour, watches TV.
Then she comes home
and Amanda is gone.
She was watching Wife Swap.
She remembers,
'cause that's her favorite show.
And do youse two live upstairs?
Yeah, when our folks died
they left us a unit and my sister a unit,
so, you know,
basically we got no choice.
And with the acoustics
in the apartment,
you can't get away from it.
Why don't you just
come over the house, all right?
- Just talk to Helene, you know.
Lionel, talk to Helene?
Look, she don't show it,
but she's hurting right now.
- Please. Please!
- All right. Lookit, all right?
I was no saint. All right?
I had my own problems.
I took a hard bust at 22.
Bea straightened me out.
My sister Helene has not had that.
Talking to the mother's
the least we could do.
- We'll come right over.
- Thanks a lot.
Yeah. Pleasure, Lionel.
Oh, you'll find us
in that brown three-decker by the park.
- You know where it is.
- Be hard to miss today.
Look at this. Jesus.
Fucking block party here.
Four Cape Verdeans
got killed here last year.
No one gave a shit.
We have a good life, right?
Is that a trick question?
I don't wanna find their little kid
in a dumpster.
Maybe she's not in a dumpster, babe.
I don't wanna find a little kid after
they've been abused for three days.
Hon, nobody does.
All right.
Listen, we'll just go up
and we'll talk to them,
and you don't wanna do it after that,
I won't argue with you.
Okay.
Hi. Please, come on in.
Helene.
This is Patrick Kenzie,
Angela Gennaro.
- Hi.
- I remember you from high school.
I see you're still a little conceited, huh?
Would you excuse us, Dottie?
Dottie's my best friend, Lionel.
She could be in my house if she wants.
Helene, we don't wanna
get in your hair.
We're just gonna ask you
a couple questions
about your daughter,
then we'll be out of here.
- Everyone wants their part now.
- I know.
I already talked to the cops forty times.
- We're sorry to take up your time.
- Listen, we're not the cops.
Beatrice asked us to come over here
and see if we could help out
finding your daughter.
Why don't Bea mind her business?
It's my kid.
'Cause everyone gotta
have their moment, now.
- Right?
- Right.
Beatrice hired these people to help
find Amanda with her own money,
so you had better show them
the goddamn courtesy
- and respect they deserve!
- She's in grieving, prick.
She could grieve
how she wants, Dottie.
- You don't live here!
- Asshole.
Don't you fucking yell at her, Lionel.
You ain't her father!
Fuck you, Lionel.
Go fuck yourself. Cocksucker.
Fuck you.
Get the fuck outta here.
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- Maybe we should go.
- I understand. I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
Maybe we should go?
Look. Can we all just have a few words
in the hallway, please?
Excuse us, Helene.
- Helene's got emotional problems.
- It's not that, Lionel.
- What is it, then?
- She's a cunt!
- Beatrice, don't use that word.
- God help me, it's true.
This is a child.
And I don't know where she is.
Well...
We can't do any harm, right?
It's all right, Bea.
It's all right, Bea. Huh?
Thank you.
Now...
Well, she's quiet.
She tries very hard to be a good girl.
What about Helene? Her friends?
People she hangs out with?
She got a lot of people
come by the house?
I don't know.
She's at the Fillmore all the time.
She's at the Fillmore Lounge?
Yeah, she drinks every day.
She's got the gene, you know?
The disease. Our parents had it, too.
She use drugs?
I think she does a little coke.
How much is a little?
I don't know. Few times a week, maybe.
I mean, how much is a lot?
Few times a week's a lot.
Then she does a lot.
I don't know anything about that.
I put the plug in the jug myself,
I got 23 years sobriety, so, I'm good.
Congratulations.
Do you mind if we see her room?
- Kidnapped the furniture, too?
- Patrick.
10-7 investigation.
Solved it yet?
Captain, Patrick Kenzie.
This is my associate, Angie Gennaro.
Mmm-hmm?
I see Beatrice went on
and hired someone.
I take it that wasn't
your recommendation.
It was not.
That woman would mortgage her home
to every snake doctor
taking credit cards if she thought
it would help find her niece.
My job's hard enough
without inviting the circus in here.
Captain, this isn't
about the money for us.
You ever investigated
an abduction before?
I think Mrs. McCready was hoping
we could help
with the neighborhood aspect of this
investigation, the people, you know.
How old are you?
- I'm 31.
- He just looks young.
A four-year-old child is on the street.
It's 76 hours and counting.
And the prospects
for where she might be
are beginning to look grim,
you understand?
Half of all the children in these cases
are killed, flat out.
If we don't catch the abductor
by day one,
only about 10% are ever solved.
This is day three.
He may look young,
but if he wants to work this case,
he'd better not act it.
Well, he's been hired by a woman
who's the victim of a crime,
and by law he's entitled
as her representative
to be cooperated with
by the Boston Police Department.
So he expects to be.
And he will be.
He and his better half will be contacted
by two of my senior men,
at their convenience,
and be permitted to observe.
We're just trying to help, Captain.
Look, I don't care who does it.
I just want it done.
Good afternoon.
Ready to get started?
All I'm saying is that
we heard Helene comes in here.
We're not asking
for the combination to the safe.
Listen, I ain't saying a fucking word.
I already talked to the fucking cops.
All right.
- Dave, right?
- Big Dave.
Big Dave. All right.
I'm Medium Patrick. Nice to meet you.
You're a little fucking light in the ass
to be talking shit, ain't ya?
Jesus, pal,
I'm just playing.
Listen, buy a couple
of fucking drinks or screw.
Okay, we'll take a couple tonics.
Jesus Christ.
Steve Penteroudakis!
The Grecian Formula!
Oh, shit! What are you doing here?
Look at this little motherfucker
at the Fillmore, what's up?
Gyro!
Beers and keno, 2:00 in the afternoon.
- What up?
- Oh, yeah.
Yeah, listen,
I been fucking everywhere
putting up posters, man, you know?
Every project hallway,
all over City Point, everywhere.
You know? I mean, it's a real tragedy.
She used to come in here,
sit up at the bar and shit.
- You know, she was like our mascot.
- Helene brought Amanda in here?
No, mostly in the afternoons.
I mean, it's no place for a child at night.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah.
Hot tempers, lot of drugs, trust me.
So how often Helene come down here?
Five nights a week.
Come on, guys, please.
She's a fucking coke ho, okay?
She's in here fucking doing lines
just about every night.
Trust me, all right?
It's not a real shocker, so...
- She's that bad, huh?
- Huh?
Oh, she's fucking terrible.
Listen, remember that night
when the kid got kidnapped?
You saw her on the news, right?
She's saying, "Oh, I was at my
neighbor's house for a half hour."
Bullshit. She was in here for, like,
two hours bumping rails. Oh, yeah.
What time did she come in?
- 8:00.
- Are you sure it was the same night?
- Fucking positive,
'cause she was in the shitter,
fucking banging down rails with Ray,
and I was banging on the fucking door.
- Who, Ray? Skinny Ray?
- Yeah. Ray Likanski.
He's in there ducking me
like a fucking faggot.
I was banging on the door.
He thought I didn't know
he was in there,
but I know he's fucking in there.
- Don't lend him any money...
- Hey, Stevie.
- What the fuck you doing?
- Nothing. What's up, Lenny?
Don't talk about people you don't know.
What do you mean?
These are my friends.
- I know them for years.
- What's the problem, guy?
You said you weren't a cop.
Right, "guy"?
- Yeah, I'm not a cop.
- Yeah, then why don't you fuck off?
Why don't you mind your business?
He's gonna come in here
and be a smartass?
You're awfully worried
about people's asses there, Dave.
Yeah, you probably got
a fucking ass like a Skippy jar.
What are you doing here, anyway?
Dave can't make a martini worth a shit.
Trying to help Helene
find her daughter. Is that all right?
Listen, don't come in here
running your mouth,
thinking you're better than me.
I'm not the fucking one.
- All right, just cool it.
Cool it.
- Listen to this douchebag.
- Bet she fucks this asshole in half.
Jesus Christ. What the fuck
is the matter with you guys?
You, you punk fucking jackass.
We're leaving, all right?
You know, Dave,
I think it's your good looks...
'Cause there is some fine pussy
in here tonight.
Open that door, rummy.
- Open the door, Mike.
- Now.
You ever wanna get fucked,
let me know.
How's that, motherfucker?
Now you know.
Keep your fucking mouths closed.
What, you wanna
say some shit, Fat Dave?
- Fuck you!
Make me a martini,
you fucking fat bastard!
- Make it!
- Get the fuck out.
Make me a fucking martini,
you fat fucking retard!
Fucking unbelievable.
- Can I help you?
- You Detective Bressant?
- That's right.
- Patrick Kenzie. Did you just call me?
Oh, sorry.
Sergeant Detective Remy Bressant.
How you doing?
- Should we... Sit down?
- Something wrong?
No! I just...
I think Nick was expecting
an older couple, maybe.
Life's full of surprises.
Corwin Earle.
Serial molester, recently work-released.
Went AWOL around the time
Amanda disappeared.
Known associates, Leon Trett
and his handsome wife, Roberta.
The Tretts were released six
and eight months ago, respectively.
They have drug habits.
We don't know where they are,
but we think Corwin's with them.
Jailhouse snitch claims
that Corwin confided in him
and told him when he got out,
he was gonna move in with his family.
Apparently the three of them
have some kind of
Addams Family deal going on.
Corwin's plan is to keep a kid
in the house to have sex with.
- Well, that sounds promising.
- Not for Amanda, it doesn't.
Do you think
this is who has Amanda?
Well, there's a lot
of holes in our theory.
I mean, Corwin likes
little boys, you know?
He likes them seven or eight or nine.
So that's it, that's all we got,
there's no other leads, three days in?
No, we got more.
We got six psychics telling us to look
in six different states,
we got Lionel and Bea
with airtight alibis,
we've interviewed every neighbor
in a mile radius
and we got a convicted finger-blaster
who just happened
to cut off his ankle bracelet.
- Take it easy...
- No, no, no, no, no!
Who the fuck is this guy?
You're here because Jack Doyle
had us extend you a courtesy.
You got something to contribute,
you know, be my guest.
Otherwise, hey, you...
You know, you can go back
to your Harry Potter book.
Isn't it usually somebody
who knows the victim?
I think there's plenty of people
in Helene McCready's life
that are capable of doing this.
So then you probably
talked to Ray Likanski.
- Who?
- Ray Likanski.
"Skinny Ray," they call him, 6'2",
about 160 pounds.
Does blow. Helene's boyfriend. No?
- Never heard of him.
- Well, with all due respect,
I think we might be able
to contribute on that point.
- Really? How's that?
- The night Amanda went missing,
Skinny Ray was down
at the Fillmore Lounge
doing coke for two hours,
between 8:00 and 10:00.
Fascinating.
- With Helene McCready.
- You're shitting me.
She did bullshit us.
I'm gonna have to tear her
a new asshole.
Meet you down there.
So what kinda name is Bressant?
It's the kind they give you in Louisiana.
Oh, yeah?
Thought you were from here.
Well, it all depends
on how you look at it.
I mean, you might think that you're
more from here than me, for example.
But I been living here
longer than you been alive.
So who's right?
I'll mull it over.
- What's up, sucker?
- Bubba.
- Good to see you, brother.
- Good to see you.
- How you been? You been good?
- Yeah.
Yeah? What's up, Angie?
How you doing, baby?
You seen those people?
Drug addict, drug addict, fucking...
Pedophile.
What the fuck makes you think
I know people like this?
Bub, I know you don't pay your rent
doing people's taxes.
Yeah, I don't pay my rent
selling penny rocks
to walleyed child molesters, neither.
They're not all three child molesters.
Just... Just this one, Corwin Earle.
The other two are just baseheads
he hangs out with.
What are the two of yas,
crime dogs, now?
We got hired to find that little girl.
Turns out the mother was down
at the Fillmore all night
while the kid was taken.
- With Skinny Ray.
- Skinny Ray is a fucking bitch.
- I thought Ray was your boy.
- Work for me?
Skinny Ray, he's a fucking cokehead.
He works for the Haitian.
Ray works for Cheese?
Yeah, Cheese, Ray, Chris Mullen,
whole trash-picker crew.
Did you ever sell to Helene?
There's reasons why
there ain't three inches of Plexiglas
between us right now.
That's 'cause I don't fuck
with skeezers like Helene.
Or coconuts like Cheese.
You should know better by now.
I'm the king of this
motherfucking jungle.
I'll let you know
if I hear anything, though.
- Thanks, bro.
- Peace.
How well do you know
"Cheese" Jean Baptiste?
- Who?
- Come on, sweetheart.
"Cheese" Jean Baptiste?
Oh, sounds familiar.
No. No.
It don't "sound familiar," Helene.
He's a violent, sociopathic
Haitian criminal named "Cheese."
Either you know him or you don't.
Who is he?
He's a drug lord
or something, isn't he?
Helene, who is he?
- He's just a guy, Lionel.
Thank you.
He is, among other things,
Mrs. McCready, a drug dealer, yes.
- What other things?
- I don't know.
Why don't you answer
your brother's questions, Helene?
Why don't you go
suck a nigger's dick, Bea?
You listen to me!
You don't disrespect my wife,
and you don't make racial remarks
in my kitchen.
- Who is this man?
- It's my kitchen, Lionel.
You know what I mean!
Hey, hey, hey. Take it easy.
Take it easy.
He's a drug dealer, a pimp,
a pornographer. All right?
Perfect.
You associate with a pimp.
A pornographer? Helene.
And we think he rolled up
Pokey Jackson in a carpet
and shot him in the head
on Castlegate, so there's that, too.
What do you do for him?
I just mule.
Occasionally, not making
a habit out of it.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
Lionel, what does that mean?
It means she's a drug runner, Bea.
It means she carries drugs.
- Isn't that right, Helene?
- Oh, my God, a few times.
- Where?
- Providence...
Does it fucking matter?
You think I'm fucking around, here?
You think I'm playing games, here?
'Course it matters.
Better answer
his question, Helene.
- For what?
- Fuck's sake, Lionel.
- What do you think? Money, taste.
- Of what, drugs?
No, little puffy heart stickers
for my locker.
What kind of drugs?
Cocaine and heroin.
- No, I would've seen the track marks.
- Not if you snort it. Right, sugar?
Yeah, less addictive that way.
Piece of work.
What the fuck is that?
Where are you going?
Oh, yeah.
I keep thinking about this thing I heard.
- You know where I'm going with this?
- No.
Did you know I used to work DCU?
- I give a fuck.
- Okay.
So, I still know some of those guys
real well.
Anyway, I heard someone
ripped Cheese off
on a New Hampshire run.
- Did you hear anything about that?
No.
- Care to take a polygraph?
- I already took one.
Different questions this time.
Come on. It's all right.
We don't care about a
couple of hopheads beating each other.
We care about your child.
So come on.
How much?
You even give a fuck about your kid?
'Course I do.
And we know you took the money.
So just tell us how much you took.
How much?
One thirty.
- $ 130,000?
- Yes, Bea.
How'd you do it?
Me and Ray had to do this
run up Nashua, right?
Yeah.
We dropped four ki's on these bikers.
When we was walking back
through the motel with all the money,
these cops just swooped right in,
went right for the bikers,
and Amanda was with us,
so we just pretended to be like a family.
- And we got in the car, took off.
- You took Amanda with you?
Oh, what am I gonna do?
Leave her in the car, Bea?
I don't got no daycare.
It's really hard being a mother.
It's hard raising a family, you know?
All on my own.
But God made you barren,
so you wouldn't fucking know.
- So I understand, Bea, okay?
- You are an abomination.
- Hey, hey, hey. Right here.
As God is my witness.
Right here. What happened next?
We was driving back,
and Ray, fucking Ray was like,
"You know everyone's gonna think
the cops got the money."
You told Cheese the cops got it.
But you and Ray
kept the money.
- This whole fucking thing is Ray's fault.
- Where's the money now, Helene?
- It's with Ray.
- And where's Ray?
- Chelsea.
- Let's go. Come on.
She rides with you.
I don't want her in my car.
- Go on. Move your bike!
- Go fuck your mother.
- What the...
- Beat it, sucker!
Helene, you used to go
with Scott Flaherty, didn't you?
- How do you know?
- You know, I went to Saint Mark's.
I was a freshman when you were
a senior. You don't remember me?
No.
Whatever happened to Scott?
He stabbed a foreign exchange student
in the chest.
He got life in Walpole.
He's a faggot now.
He was kind of a faggot in high school.
Oh, man.
You're terrible. He was cute.
Well, he kind of wore them tight shorts.
Oh, who's a faggot now?
You're dating a faggot.
So, how did the...
How'd the money end up in Chelsea?
I thought youse and...
You and Ray went home after.
No, we dropped off Amanda
and went back to Ray's.
But fucking retarded Ray
left his baby rock at my place.
You know, right then, I'm like,
"I'm gonna drop this motherfucker.
"I don't care if he does got a big dick."
So we went back to the apartment
and Ray was hollering,
he was gonna wake up Amanda,
she needs her sleep, you know?
So, we went back to Ray's,
- or Ray's mother's. Whatever.
- Yeah?
I don't know where that mother went,
but she left all her fucking cats in there,
and it smells like cock.
And Cheese never contacted you,
never left you a note?
No.
We didn't hear nothing from Cheese.
That's why Ray said, "Don't say shit."
You didn't think it was worth it
for your daughter's sake
to tell people what happened?
Cheese has your kid.
God fucking knows
what he's doing to her.
What am I gonna do?
Call Cheese and be like,
"You got my daughter?
"'Cause I just ripped you off,
and I'm just checking."
Yeah!
- Helene, sit back.
- Oh, my God!
Oh, I'm gonna call the cops, too,
and be like, "You know,
"just so you know, wanna know
I run coke and heroin
"in case that's irrelevant."
All right, calm down.
Calm down.
You make me sick.
What makes you think Ray hasn't
spent all the money, Helene?
Nigger, please. I hid it.
Pull over.
Looks like somebody had a little talk
with Ray before they shot him.
- Looks like he held out pretty good.
- He didn't have it.
He couldn't tell them where the money
was, because he didn't know.
Helene hid it.
Ray made poor relationship choices.
Guess they didn't believe him.
Poor prick.
I'm not waiting
in a fucking car.
- Where's the money, Helene?
- I give a fuck about the money.
- Helene...
- I just want my daughter home with me.
I know it. I know, I'm... I'm sorry.
It's very upsetting about Ray. But...
- Where's the money?
- It's right there.
- Where?
- Buried it when Ray was passed out.
What was that book about,
Everything You Need
Is in Your Own Backyard?
- I think it was a French book.
- Yeah, that wasn't a book.
- That was a book.
- No, it was a cartoon.
- The fuck out of here.
- Right, Helene?
- Fuck youse both.
Should we bring in the FBI
at this point?
- That's the worst thing we could do.
- Why is that?
'Cause I don't wanna see Cheese
kill Amanda
after he opens a bag
full of newspapers.
It's kidnapping.
- I don't see a note. You see a note?
- Nope. No note.
We're investigating
a missing children's case, here.
Kidnapping has nothing to do with it.
Fastest way to get Amanda home
is go to Cheese,
swap the money for her and walk away.
- Plain and simple.
- Do you know Cheese?
Knew his brother better, Jude.
He was a sweet kid.
Cheese went another way.
- He wouldn't hurt her, right?
Ask Ray.
All right, listen.
All he cares about is his money.
If he gets it back...
He's not gonna hurt Amanda.
Just keep your mouth shut, okay?
We'll get her back. It'll be fine.
- Oh, you're gonna talk to him?
- Yeah, that's the idea.
Okay. Well, tell him I'm sorry, all right?
I mean, he knows me,
just tell him I apologize.
Yeah, I'm sure that'll fix everything.
Just take her home.
- We'll take care of this, all right?
- We'll meet you over there.
I'm hungry.
All right. I'll get you something, Helene.
No, her.
That's what she said to me
right before I put her to bed.
She said, "I'm hungry."
I mean, they fed her, right?
She's not still hungry?
I don't know.
I know I fucked up.
I just want my daughter back.
I swear to God,
I won't use no drugs no more.
I won't even go out,
I'll be fucking straight.
Cross my heart.
It's all right.
We're gonna find her, Helene.
You have to. You promise?
Yeah. I'm gonna try. I will.
Promise. You have to promise me.
I promise.
All right.
Where do you
think you're going?
Talk to Cheese.
No, you're not.
No, get back in the car.
No, that's a mistake.
He's never gonna talk to a badge.
No. No way.
It's too important.
You wanna get the girl back, or not?
I know him.
If there's a deal to be brokered,
- we're the ones who can do it.
- No, me and Nick are handling this.
Get back in the car.
Guys, you two go in there
and negotiate a ransom for a little girl,
then it is the FBI.
'Cause it's kidnapping.
All you're gonna do
is scare him.
The more you scare him,
the worse it is for her.
All right. Go ahead.
Just fucking relax, sit tight. I know him.
I'm gonna take care of it.
Good luck.
It's been a long time.
No. I quit.
I'm gonna talk some private shit.
- Don't wait, but don't get too far.
- You know I'll be right here.
Bitches love the cheddar.
- How you been, Chris?
- Better than you.
Yeah. Good to hear it.
- Fuck you.
- Man, be cool.
It's been too long not to see a fool.
I grant you audience.
Go.
We found what you
were looking for in Chelsea.
What I care about Chelsea?
'Cause one of the idiots
that robbed you lived there.
What idiot?
The one that you and Chris
beat with a pipe and shot in the chest.
I don't know about nobody getting kill.
But if somebody rob me
and end up dead...
Well, you know, life is a motherfucker.
Cheese, we got your money.
It was buried in Ray's backyard.
We wanna give it back to you
in exchange for Amanda McCready.
The two police outside
are the only other people who know.
No one gives a fuck
about what you did.
I mean, I didn't even
like Ray that much.
You're gonna get your money,
the mother gets her daughter back,
and we'll say we found the kid
in the bushes, or whatever.
It's either this, real quiet,
or it's a thousand fucking cops
kicking your door in,
putting their fat knees in your neck.
Hold up.
Whoa. Whoa.
What the fuck is this?
Lift up your shirt.
- Come on, man.
- Motherfucker, you heard me.
Lift up your shirt.
- It ain't like that, Cheese.
- My CC, I ain't down with you.
Lift up your shirt.
You, too, baby.
Ain't no gender immunity.
Let me see some tit.
Don't ever come in my spot like that.
You got my money,
you leave that shit in the mailbox
on your ass way out, you feel me?
Some other motherfuckers
let fool rob on them.
I don't play scrimmage.
But I don't fuck with no kids.
And if that girl only hope is you,
well, I pray for her,
'cause she's gone, baby.
Gone.
Cheese, if you ever
disrespect her again like that,
I'm gonna pull your fucking card.
Okay?
So you're saying you didn't do it, fine.
We'll take your money,
and we'll be on our way.
But if it turns out you're lying,
I'm going to spend every nickel
of that money to fuck you up.
I'm gonna bribe cops to go after you,
I'm gonna pay guys
to go after your weak fucking crew,
and I'm gonna tell everyone I know
that you're a CI and a rat.
And I know a lot of people.
And after that, you're gonna wish
you had listened to me,
'cause your shitty, pool-hall,
crime-syndicate headquarters
is gonna get raided.
And your doped-up bitches
are gonna get sent back to Laos,
and this fucking retard right here
is gonna be testifying against you
for a reduced sentence while you're
getting cornholed in your cell
by a gang of crackers.
'Cause from what I heard,
you guys that get sent up Concord
for killing kids,
life a motherfucker.
If I see you again,
I'm gonna get discourteous on you.
And get that sausage off my lawn.
Well, what happened?
- He said he didn't know anything,
but if you had his money,
you could put it in his mailbox.
- That's what he told you?
- That's it.
Nothing else?
Yeah. He said that he wanted
you two off his lawn.
I thought you said
you knew this fucking guy.
Half the guys he knows
are degenerates.
Yeah, you know
what the other half are?
- What?
- Cops. Don't hold it against me.
No, no. I won't hold it against you.
You know what I'll hold against you?
We had one chance to make this deal.
You said you knew him.
You said you could do it
and you fucked it up.
Now I gotta get a warrant for a tap,
start surveillance,
hope to Christ we get lucky.
You know, if Amanda
dies because of this,
I won't have to hold it against you.
You'll hold it against yourself
for a long, long time.
Hope we didn't fuck this up.
- Yeah.
- Cheese called in.
Says he'll take the deal with Amanda,
but he wants to go tonight.
- Great.
- Well, it is and it isn't.
They record calls at the station now.
- Jack got a hold of the transcript.
- What does that mean?
It means our badges are
basically fucking forfeit at this point.
He wants you both down here, now.
Oh, and, hey, Cheese said
he left something in a mailbox
to prove that he's got Amanda.
This is a transcript of a recorded call
that came in this morning.
Care to read the highlighted portion?
Aloud?
Uh.
"Caller: Bitch,
you better have my money.
"Detective Bressant: Who is this?
"The caller:
You know who the fuck this is, fool...
"Creole curse words.
If you want that girl back,
"you need to meet me up
Quincy tonight.
"Fuck around for a minute
and I'll throw that girl in the lake."
The lake he refers to is the water
in the abandoned quarry.
Detective Bressant goes on to make
an unauthorized ransom arrangement
to exchange Amanda McCready
for $ 130,000 tonight
in just that location.
After some discussion,
Detective Bressant was kind enough
to produce this.
Recognize it?
The four of you have involved me
in an illegal activity
without my knowledge or consent,
and I don't fucking appreciate it.
- You don't have to be a part of it, sir.
- The hell I don't.
If I delay this now, after this agreement,
I just further endanger
the life of that child.
Does that sound like something
you expect me to do?
No, sir.
I went in there. I'll accept responsibility.
You'll accept nothing!
Don't come in here
trying to get noble, boy.
Let me see that note.
My God.
He wants to separate us.
The note instructs you guys to be
on the east side and wait for Amanda,
me and Nick to be at the clearing
by the edge with the money.
Once Amanda's turned over to you,
you give us a call on the radio,
we turn over the cash.
- Who's he likely to bring with him?
- Chris Mullen.
He was at the club
when we made the offer.
What do you know about him?
It was probably him
who killed Ray for Cheese.
If I had to guess.
All right.
Nobody else knows about this, right?
- I don't know.
- Yes?
I'm asking if keeping it quiet is better
for Amanda or is it better for us?
Do you have any children,
Miss Gennaro?
No, sir.
My only child was murdered.
She was 12. Did you hear about it?
What you probably didn't hear,
and what I hope
you never have to deal with,
Miss Gennaro, is what that feels like.
What I have to deal with.
Knowing that my little girl likely died
crying out for me
to come and save her.
And I never did.
My little girl died afraid and alone
in a shallow ditch bank
by the side of the road
not 10 minutes from my house.
I know what it feels like to lose a child.
Now, damn it, you force my hand
and then you question
the way I handle it.
No one's questioning you, sir.
I honor my child with this division.
So that no parent
has to go through what I've known.
This child.
That's all I care about.
I'm gonna bring her home.
Why'd he bring us all the way up here?
I don't know. It's big. It's dark.
It's easy to get away.
No.
They're gonna kill her.
This asshole could've found
some level fucking ground somewhere.
This is where we part ways.
You guys'll be on top of that cliff.
We'll be right across from you.
Give us a call on the radio
when you have her.
- We will.
- Well, good luck.
Let's go.
How are they gonna
get Amanda up here?
Ambush! Ambush!
Hey, Remy! Fucking Cheese!
Where is she?
There she is.
I can see her. It ain't the way it is!
Someone hit Cheese!
You sure you heard something?
Yes!
- Over there!
What happened?
I don't know. I heard a splash.
Down there!
Somebody took Cheese out,
- and then all hell broke loose.
Where's Amanda?
- Shots were fired from over there.
I don't know!
Something went in the water!
- What?
- You sure you heard something?
- Yeah, something went in, but I...
- Where did it go?
There! Right there!
Oh, my God.
Oh, no.
Jesus Christ!
Paging
Dr. Goldsburn. Dr. Goldsburn to ICU.
- Hi.
- How's the leg?
- It'll be fine.
They find anything?
- They got divers in there now.
- She could still be alive.
Maybe she's hiding.
She could be stuck.
Right?
I don't think so.
Hey...
He's ever seen
in all his years,
on a little girl called Amanda
and a doll named Mirabelle.
This quarry is
extremely deep and treacherous.
All too often,
she keeps that which she takes in.
A sad end
to that story, Suzanne.
It sure is, Phil.
And Ron is next with
sports. The Bruins in action tonight?
Yes, they are, Phil.
The B's took a crack
at the Flyers tonight,
and the rough stuff started
in the first period.
And like that, she was gone.
We gave our statements.
Nick and Remy the same.
All of us spared any blame
for Amanda's death.
Jack Doyle resigned on the condition
that he and he alone
be held accountable.
The legendary captain
of a unit dedicated to children
stepped down today
in the aftermath of controversy.
He was granted
the dignity of early retirement.
But the humiliation of half a pension.
It was an ignominious end
to an illustrious career.
Chris' run lasted a day and a half until,
from what they could tell,
he ran into someone who wanted
the money more than he did.
Twenty-nine-year-old
Chris Mullen
was gunned down last night
in an apparent robbery.
The police commissioner
defended the rising tide of crime
as a statistical aberration tied
to growing unemployment
and the humidity of...
Enough time went by
and they called off the search.
They issued Helene
a death certificate.
The frame and the casket were
donated by the funeral home,
but had to be returned
at the end of the afternoon.
You know I love you, right?
Yeah.
I just wanna be alone for a while.
I don't know if she blamed
me or if she blamed herself.
But when she didn't think I was home,
or if she thought I couldn't hear,
she would cry.
I couldn't stop running it over
and over and over in my mind,
the vague and distant suspicion
that we never understood
what happened that night,
what our role was.
Or maybe it was just that,
like the hundreds of other children
who disappear each year
and never return...
Amanda was even more haunting
for never being found.
What they did find
was another big story,
and I couldn't help but find it strange.
Not two months later and not far away,
another child went missing.
...and community watch patrols
are being formed.
A bicycle left
roadside. A tire left spinning.
Late-breaking news
on that story.
Little Johnny Pietro is also wearing
what this reporter believes
might be a sign.
Johnny Pietro was wearing the
medallion of St. Christopher,
patron saint of...
Johnny Pietro
and his medallion.
What I didn't find strange
was this time,
no relatives came knocking
on our door.
- Hey, Patrick.
- Hi.
- I need you to come on a ride with me.
- Where?
To Everett.
- What, no parties in Lynn?
- Funny.
- You got your toast with you, right?
- My what?
Your gun, dummy.
Yeah.
This ain't no
strip-clubbing in Lynn, Patrick.
I got something better for you, buddy.
You asked me to find
some people for you.
I think I found them.
What you getting me into?
You don't give a fuck about this
Corwin Earle dude no more?
Yo, 'cause the fat bitch
and the old dude are in there.
My man didn't know about the diddler.
Come in with me. Watch my side.
We'll find out
if this motherfucker's in there.
You know what, Patrick?
If you don't wanna come in,
you don't have to come in.
If you don't wanna come in, fuck it.
Let's go.
Guess who?
- Jerome Miller?
- No, it's the coke fairy.
- Open up.
- I got the money right here.
Marmaduke, you think you're gonna
hand me money on a fucking porch?
Open the door.
Who's he?
He's your father.
Open the fucking door!
- Look out.
- Okay, man!
Chill! Chill!
What are you guys, starting a band?
No one's starting a band.
It's a taste.
Cocaine for the old man.
Fucking Christ.
Want me to change
a roll of quarters for you, too?
I told you to tell me when they got here!
They just got here.
- You already did some!
- It was a taste bag.
Sorry, love.
Here, count this fucking mess.
Where's the rest, man?
As soon as he's finished counting
that fucking mess you gave me.
- Mr. Miller, do you mind?
- No, I don't mind.
- Excuse me!
- You're excused.
- Hey, please don't snoop around, sir.
Hey, relax, handsome.
Excuse me!
Where the fuck you think you're going?
Mr. Miller, I'm warning you!
Stop!
Patrick, shoot this bitch.
You fat busted cunt.
You put a gun on me, you better use it.
Just give us the fucking wizza!
You don't wanna shoot her, Patrick?
Who's this guy?
Corwin!
Go back to your room!
It's not a party?
No, it's not a party.
How much money's there, Patrick?
Enough.
Want this?
What are you doing?
Pick up the fucking money.
At least two guns in
the house. Roberta's carrying hers.
What else?
- Well, they're definitely high.
- On what?
- Cocaine.
Your friend tell you that, too?
SWAT'll be here in five minutes.
You're not gonna wait for them?
Did you or did you not tell me
you saw Corwin Earle
with the medallion of St. Christopher
around his fucking wrist?
I definitely saw Corwin Earle.
We're not waiting.
Stay here.
And don't fuck around, all right?
Good job.
Fuck.
An... An officer... Shots are fired!
An officer down... Shots...
Listen to me!
A police officer has been shot
at 33 German Road!
Get away from him!
It was an accident.
Wait!
Hey.
You okay?
They told me what happened.
I'm proud of you.
That man killed a child.
He had no right to live.
- You're proud of me?
- Of course I am.
You did what you had to do.
Let's go home.
I gotta stay here awhile.
- See you at home.
- Yeah.
Thanks.
It was fucked up, right?
They tell you anything about Nick?
They said he could be okay.
I don't know.
They say how old that little boy was?
Seven.
Second grade.
Should be proud of yourself.
Most guys would've stayed outside.
I don't know.
What don't you know?
My priest says shame is God
telling you what you did was wrong.
Fuck him.
Murder's a sin.
Depends on who you do it to.
That's not how it works. It is what it is.
I planted evidence on a guy once,
back in '95.
We were paying $ 100
an eight-ball to snitches.
We got a call
from our pal, Ray Likanski.
He couldn't find enough guys to rat out.
Anyway, he tells us there's a guy
pumping up in an apartment
up in Columbia Point.
We go in, me and Nicky.
Fifteen years ago, when Nicky went in,
it was no joke.
So, it's a... It's a stash house, right?
The old lady's beat to shit,
the husband's mean, cracked out,
tries to give us trouble,
Nicky lays him down.
We're doing an inventory,
but it looks like we messed up
because there's no dope in the house,
and I go in the back room...
Now, this place
was a shithole, mind you.
Rats, roaches all over the place.
But the kid's room, in the back,
was spotless.
No, I mean, he swept it, mopped it,
it was immaculate.
The little boy's sitting on the bed
holding onto his PlayStation
for dear life.
There's no expression on his face,
tears streaming down.
He wants to tell me he just learned
his multiplication tables.
Christ.
I mean, the father's got him
in this crack den,
subsisting on Twinkies
and ass-whippings,
and this little boy just wants someone
to tell him that he's doing a good job.
You're worried what's Catholic?
I mean, kids forgive.
Kids don't judge.
Kids turn the other cheek.
What do they get for it?
So I went back out there,
I put an ounce of heroin
on the living room floor,
and I sent the father on a ride,
seven to nine.
- That was the right thing?
- Fucking A!
You gotta take a side.
You molest a child, you beat a child,
you're not on my side.
If you see me coming, you better run,
because I am gonna
lay you the fuck down!
Easy.
Don't feel easy.
Is the kid better off without his father?
Yeah.
But okay, I mean,
could be out there right now,
pumping with a gun in his waistband.
It's a war, man.
Are we winning?
No.
Would you do it again?
Clip Corwin Earle?
No.
Does that make you right?
Hmm?
I don't know.
Doesn't make it wrong, though,
does it?
- Hey.
- Hi.
How's Remy?
He lied to me.
What did Remy say about Ray
back in Roxbury?
- Never heard of him.
Now he says Ray's been snitching
for him for 15 years.
He called him his "old pal."
Said he couldn't find
enough people to snitch out.
Patrick...
And Ray Likanski is the reason
Amanda got taken in the first place,
and Remy lies about knowing him.
Let it go.
Why would he lie?
What's he have to hide?
Amanda's dead.
Let it go.
Babe.
Nick died.
Left. Left.
Mr. Kenzie.
Nice fucking job on Corwin Earle.
Amen.
- Sorry about Nick.
- Yeah, thanks.
I was thinking about our conversation
the other night.
Well, I said some things
I shouldn't have.
You know, too much rum.
Yeah, like what?
Don't fuck with me, Patrick. Not today.
Oh, I wouldn't fuck with you.
Oh, you wanna play it like that, huh?
Okay.
Forget about the other night,
and we'll be friends.
What if I don't?
That's not an "if"
you wanna bring into your life.
Had lunch with him last week.
Dana had lunch with him last week?
Excuse me.
Hey, Dev.
- Hey, how you doing?
- All right, how you been?
I can't complain.
- Can I talk to you?
- Yeah.
Not here.
If it's like that, then
you're gonna have to buy me lunch.
- How's the Chart House, half hour?
- Sounds about right.
Hey, Remy used to work Narcotics
with you, right?
DCU, yeah. What's up?
Why'd he leave?
Had a habit of just
rubbing people the wrong way.
Like what? What'd he do?
Like marry a prostitute, for one.
Come on.
Might not wanna do that
if you're a cop, right?
if you're a plumber.
So, what happened?
He says he loves her,
tells Mike Snell to go fuck himself,
and puts in for a transfer.
What, to Doyle?
Doyle brought Remy
from Louisiana, back in '72.
You don't think that Remy's
dirty, though, do you?
What's "dirty"?
- I know he planted evidence once.
- Oh, you do?
Yeah. Why?
Look, man. CSI is killing us out here.
Every other juror, all they wanna know
is where the microfibers are.
Certain people are workers.
Don't wanna plant it,
but you know how it is.
So they don't mind it.
So tell me something,
what you fucking with him for?
He lied to me.
I can't think of one reason
big enough for him to lie
that's small enough not to matter.
All right, look.
I know one thing, but it's third party,
so you gotta play it like that.
Helene and Ray took Cheese's money
back in June, right?
Yeah.
One week later,
Remy goes to a cop in DCU
asking if anybody knew
who robbed Cheese.
So what?
So my informant tells me,
Cheese didn't even know
he got robbed until two weeks later.
So Remy knew Cheese got robbed
before Cheese did?
How'd he know that?
Let me tell you something.
You better think long and hard
before you start running around here
investigating the police.
You try and take food out their mouths,
and they will fuck you up.
Thanks for the steak.
All right.
Hey.
I got it.
We need to talk to you, Lionel.
About what?
About the acoustics in your apartment.
What?
Oh, we live
in a three-decker, too, Lionel.
I got nothing to talk about.
Well, that's fine.
We can talk to the state police.
Meet me at Murphy's Law.
I don't meet him
down Murphy's,
he's gonna call the staties.
He's putting a
move on you. Don't go down there.
I can handle Patrick Kenzie.
- This is an oath we took.
- I started this.
- This has to be protected.
- I got things to protect, too.
- Listen to me!
- All right, Remy.
You leave that house,
you're an enemy to me.
- Just trust me, all right?
- No! Trust me!
Where I come from,
you die with your secrets!
How long have you known Remy?
Detective Bressant? Just in...
Met him through
the investigation of Amanda.
- That's it?
- Yeah.
How long you known Remy?
What is this?
They got the Internet, now, Lionel.
You know how it is in town.
Everybody knows everybody.
No. Everybody don't know everybody.
- What're you talking about?
- Why you lying?
I'm not.
You bragged about taking a hard bust
on the first day we met you.
- No, I didn't.
- Bullshit.
You're hiding something, Lionel,
and you better fucking tell it,
'cause you came to our house
and you asked us for help.
And we killed ourselves
trying to save Amanda.
And I know you ain't being 100%
with me right now,
and it's really fucking pissing me off
that you're lying,
so you better interrupt me at any time,
'cause I'm about to lose...
Okay. Fine, fine. All right?
Don't have a heart attack.
I haven't been honest with you.
It's just not something I'm proud of.
You know?
I got in a bar fight back in the day.
The other guy cracked his skull.
At some point,
I must've said, "I'll kill you."
So they had me up for attempted.
It's my word against this other guy's.
Witness testified to my version
and the jury believed him.
- 'Cause he was a cop.
- Yeah, he testified for me.
So you knew Detective Bressant.
- It's not like we were best friends.
- But you lied.
- Why did you call Remy?
- He's a cop.
- That's not why you called him, Lionel.
- Come on.
It's a small place.
You heard them arguing.
- They were being loud.
- Who? Who... Who...
So you called Remy, and you and him
took Amanda to blackmail your sister.
Why would I do that?
I don't know, Lionel. I really don't know.
Maybe because after all the
"I put the fucking plug in the jug,"
and the "count your blessings"
and the "watch your language,"
you're just like everybody else.
You saw a bag of money
and you wanted it.
And you thought
you could get away with it.
But Bea called the media
and made a big thing of it.
And then she called us,
and then you were fucked.
The case is closed, Patrick.
The case is closed.
Coke-dealing Haitian's
a pretty easy target for a frame.
- Lionel?
- Excuse me.
- Look at me.
- Okay. Excuse me.
You took your niece,
and you laid it off on a black guy.
- Pardon me.
- Lionel, tell me what happened.
Can I get some service?
Yeah.
What?
- Three shots of Cutty and a tallboy.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Just give me a second.
Twenty-three years
is something, right?
Go.
I come up to check on Amanda.
She was alone as usual.
I was reading her a story
when Helene and Ray come home.
They didn't know I was there.
Stop fucking yelling,
my daughter's sleeping in there.
They started talking about how
they'd robbed this drug dealer.
You know what he's fucking gonna do
if he finds out?
What's the monkey gonna do?
- Oh, you know...
- I'm not...
And they were talking
about leaving the state.
So I called Remy and told him.
There's another drug run
up to Nashua. Taking cocaine...
And then what?
We took her.
Remy laid out this plan.
It seemed easy.
We take her, force Helene and Ray
to cough up the cash,
then we put her back. You know?
Amanda gets to spend
a weekend in the country.
My sister learns a lesson.
And fuck it, everybody gets paid
on top of it.
I got no problem taking money
from a guy like Cheese.
They were gonna handle the cops.
But Bea, she went nuts.
Started calling the papers. Hired you.
Lionel don't want me coming here,
now you don't want the job?
But once you found the money,
they had Amanda and the money.
So they decided to set up
a fake exchange for you to witness.
They got Chris Mullen
to set up Cheese at the quarry.
15K and a chance to be the boss.
Cheese figured out
what was happening.
Even though it was too late,
he started shooting.
Panicking.
And she just fell. I mean, she just...
She fell in.
She's gone.
It was an accident.
It was just an accident.
She was your sister's kid, Lionel.
- Your sister's child.
- You think I don't miss her?
She was more my kid than Helene's.
Last summer, Helene and Dottie
took Amanda to the beach.
It was a real hot day.
Amanda fell asleep.
They left her in the car
while they go off into the dunes,
smoke a doobie with some guys.
Two hours.
Amanda literally roasted.
She was three.
Later on, I was holding her,
trying to help her get to sleep.
My little Amanda, she was so hot.
She felt like something
just come out of the oven.
Like a fucking pot roast.
So don't feel too sorry for my sister.
Because she never gave a shit
about anyone but herself.
Bartender. Open the safe. Now.
Everybody needs to shut up and stay
calm. On the floor. On the floor!
- Hands on your head. Do it.
Oh, my God.
Everybody stays calm,
this'll be over in a minute.
Hey, do you know
whose bar this is, shithead?
Or you can get wise, it's up to you.
What did you say?
You're a talker, huh?
Just keep revving, motherfucker.
Don't antagonize him.
He's got a gun.
- Oh, just keep yapping away.
- I didn't say nothing.
You should learn
to keep your mouth shut.
Shut the fuck up,
for Christ's sake.
- Just keep talking, pal.
- I didn't say nothing.
Close your eyes.
- Fuck!
- Remy Bressant.
Amanda McCready
was taken by Remy Bressant.
Oh, fuck, God. Amanda McCready
was taken by Remy Bressant!
- Wait. Wait. Jesus.
Remy Bressant.
God damn it. Remy Bressant!
Amanda McCready was taken
- by Remy Bressant.
- Jesus. I told him.
I told him we took her for ransom.
I told him. I told him, Remy.
Please, I told him we took her
for ransom. I did it.
Remy, please.
Please.
Are you all right?
Stay with him.
Drop your gun.
Put it down!
That bartender wasn't fucking around.
What did you do?
Did you get her killed?
Say yes.
Say yes!
What're you gonna do? Shoot me?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
She was a child.
I love children.
Why would I expose a conspiracy
that I was a part of?
I mean, did Lionel contradict
anything I've said?
Did any of the witnesses at the bar
contradict anything I've said?
A police officer was killed today.
That's not looked on lightly.
Is corruption looked on lightly?
Is a little girl getting killed
looked on lightly?
Whoa, hold on.
You charge people money
as a detective.
Now, you're at the quarry
the other night, right?
And you have no idea
that this is a setup?
You're baffled. Right?
No, because, strange as it might seem,
I believe the police
when they tell me something.
You're a fresh prick. You know that?
And because I had a ransom note
and Amanda McCready's blanket
put in my mailbox.
And because I read a transcript of
a call that Cheese put into the station.
A 911 call?
No, it was a call
Cheese made to the station.
To Remy Bressant at the station.
Or that Chris Mullen made,
pretending to be Cheese.
Or whatever the fuck it was,
but it was recorded,
and there was a call.
We don't record calls
coming into the station,
and we don't do transcripts, smart guy.
So, did you hear a tape?
- No, I didn't hear a tape.
- Okay.
Did you see a transcript?
No, I must've remembered it wrong.
Kids forgive.
What do they get for it?
Amanda literally roasted.
You think I don't miss her.
She was more my kid than Helene's.
I love children.
This is the kind of thing that if you do,
Patrick, you wanna be sure.
Are you sure?
No.
Are you coming?
Doyle brought Remy
from Louisiana back in '72.
Care to read
the highlighted portion?
Taking a trip?
Patrick Kenzie.
To what do I owe the pleasure?
Remy Bressant died last night.
I was told. It's a shame.
Yeah, it's hard to understand.
Because he seemed like a good man.
He was a good man.
We don't know
why people do what they do.
Everybody looks out his own window.
And everyone's got their reasons.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Good.
Nick! They're firing at me.
Nick, you hear me? You okay?
They're firing at me!
Remy!
- I heard something go in the water!
- Ambush! Ambush!
- Something went in!
- Run. Remy. Run!
Panicking.
Amanda got scared.
She started running.
She just fell. I mean, she just fell in.
Twenty-nine-year-old
Chris Mullen
was gunned down last night
in an apparent robbery.
You go back inside with Frannie.
Papa will come in soon.
Make you a sandwich, okay?
- All right.
- That's my girl.
Don't go down there.
If I think he has the evidence,
I'll take the hit.
I got no problem doing the time.
Fuck up, and it's Amanda and her life.
All right.
I got things to protect, too.
You leave that house,
you're an enemy to me
and you're a danger to Amanda.
Please, I told him
we took her for ransom. I did it.
I told him. Remy, please.
So now you know.
My sister's not stable.
She's on crack.
She's talking about leaving the state.
I'm scared for my niece.
- Who's gonna take care of her?
- We'll do something.
We'll figure it out.
She's an addict.
Bigot. Drug mule.
The child will be dead
or on the street in 10 years.
What about the uncle?
He can never tell anyone.
Not even his wife.
Or he'll never see her again.
It's worth it to him.
Know she'll have a better life.
Do one last good thing
before we hang it up.
How many children
have we seen destroyed?
Enough.
Does it make you feel better?
Telling yourself you did it
for the right reasons?
That you took her to be saved.
From her own mother?
We're just trying to give
a little girl a life.
Wasn't your life to give.
Helene's her mother.
If you thought she was a bad mother,
you should've gone to Social Services.
Short of that, she's her mother,
and that's where she belongs.
You turn around.
You go back to your fucking car,
and you wait 30 years.
You don't know
what the world is made of yet.
I'm calling state police in five minutes.
They'll be here in ten.
Thought you would've
done that by now.
You know why you haven't?
Because you think
this might be an irreparable mistake.
Because deep inside you, you know
it doesn't matter what the rules say.
When the lights go out
and you ask yourself,
"Is she better off here or better off
there," you know the answer.
And you always will.
You... You could do a right thing here.
A good thing.
Men live their whole lives
without getting this chance.
You walk away from it,
you may not regret it
when you get home.
You may not regret it for a year,
but when you get to where I am,
I promise you, you will.
I'll be dead, you'll be old. But she...
She'll be dragging around a couple of
tattered, damaged children of her own,
and you'll be the one
who has to tell them you're sorry.
You know what? Maybe that'll happen.
And if it does, I'll tell them I'm sorry,
and I'll live with it.
But what's never gonna happen
and what I'm not gonna do
is have to apologize
to a grown woman
who comes to me and says,
"I was kidnapped
when I was a little girl,
"and my aunt hired you to find me.
"And you did, you found me
with some strange family.
"But you broke your promise
and you left me there.
"Why? Why didn't you bring me home?
"Because all the snacks and the outfits
and the family trips don't matter.
"They stole me.
"It wasn't my family
and you knew about it
"and you knew better
and you did nothing."
And maybe that grown woman
will forgive me,
but I'll never forgive myself.
I did what I did for the sake of the child.
All right. For me, too.
But now, I'm asking you
for the sake of the child.
I'm begging you.
You think about it.
She's happy.
What?
She's happy here. I saw her.
Angie, don't do this.
If you call the police,
they will send her back.
I'm not sending her anywhere.
Helene is her mother.
She's better off here.
Why? Because he's got money,
and he makes her sandwiches?
Because he loves her.
- Helene loves her, too.
- Helene doesn't treat her that way.
Well, maybe she'll change.
She won't change.
People don't change.
Helene is arsenic.
Angie, I know that this is hard.
Look at me, I know it's hard.
But I need you to stand by me.
I need you to say,
"We're gonna make the right decision,
"and we're gonna
make everything okay."
Everything will be okay.
Because we're gonna leave her here,
and every now and then
we're gonna talk about her.
And where she is,
and about what grade she's in.
And that'll be okay, because
we're gonna know what school she's in,
and we're gonna know she's happy,
and she's got birthday parties,
and she smiles every day,
and she has sleepovers.
Baby, I'm sorry.
But you can't ask me
to do something that I can't do.
And you can't ask me to live with it.
Patrick, for me. Please?
I will hate you for doing this,
and I don't want to.
Once an icon of justice
and a model for crusaders,
Jack Doyle is behind bars tonight.
Evelyn?
Social Services, as demanded by law,
will take time to examine little Amanda
before returning her to home,
and the arms of a mother
who never gave up hope
that she would see
her daughter again.
- Helene, how do you feel...
- Helene, what does it feel like
- to have your daughter with you now?
How do you feel?
Helene, how you feeling
right now? How you feeling...
Back up. Back up. Back up. Back up.
Amanda, how do you feel
to see your mom?
Hey, Amanda.
Helene, how you feeling?
- Tell us how it feels.
- Tell us what you're thinking right now.
You must be so excited.
Give us your feelings.
Oh, my sweetheart. Oh, my.
Helene, the whole world wants to know
what you're feeling right now.
How are you, sweetheart?
Oh, my heart is brimming.
And just God bless to everyone
and thank you to all...
To all the policemen and the firemen,
I feel like 9l11 right now.
Oh, I swear to God, I mean, just...
Do you have any
comments for parents out there
that might be in a similar situation?
Oh, just never let
your kids out of your sight.
Don't trust them to no one.
And just keep them in your arms,
as much as they're in your heart,
you keep them in your arms.
How about that?
A great end to that story.
- Good news for everybody.
Yes, it is.
- Sorry, I had to get some stuff.
- It's all right.
You wanna talk for a minute?
There's nothing to say.
Sorry for being rude, I gotta be
out of here in, like, two minutes.
Do your thing.
- Think he'll like me?
- Who?
My date.
Oh, how could he not?
You're sweet.
He seen me on my American Victim.
He wrote me letters,
I was like, "Whatever."
But then he seen my Meredith Vieira,
he drove down here from Providence.
I'm like, "That's romantic." Right?
How's your girlfriend?
She's all right,
she's at the North Shore with her sister.
Oh, hope she got
better family than I do, right?
Those dirty motherfuckers.
She don't get smart, I'll take you out.
- How's Bea?
- Fuck Bea.
I banned her from the apartment.
She sold her unit,
moved out fancy-pants Melrose.
Don't think she don't hate you
for Lionel going to jail, neither.
Well, that's probably
why she never paid my bill.
You should fucking sue.
How about you, Helene?
You hate me?
Fuck no.
Brother or not, he took my kid.
Fuck Lionel. She could have been hurt.
- What about Amanda?
- Who's gonna watch her?
- Dottie.
Yeah, does Dottie know that?
- She will in five minutes.
- Great.
Fuck, I'm gonna be late, too.
Unless you don't mind sitting for her.
- Yeah, sure.
- For real?
- Yeah, that's fine.
- She likes you.
Bye, sweetheart.
You're a godsend, Patrick.
Bye.
Is that Mirabelle?
Annabelle.