(MAN SPEAKING ON RADIO)
(ACOUSTIC GUITAR PLAYING)
TOMMY: Eyeball, be sure
to get me in focus, man.
BRANDON: Make sure
you take the lens cap
off this time.
STEVE: Hey,
let's play some spades.
BRANDON:
Hey, Tommy's got to go.
EYEBALL: All right.
Are you out, Tommy?
# When we see
old Glory flying
# There's a lot of men dead
# So we can sleep
in peace at night
# When we lay down
our head
ALL: # My daddy
served in the Army
where he lost his right eye
# But he flew
a flag out in our yard
# Till the day that he died
# He wanted my mother,
my brother
my sister and me
# To grow up and live happy
In the land of the free
# Now this nation that I love
has fallen under attack
# A mighty sucker punch
came flying in
from somewhere in the back
# Soon as we could see clearly
through our big black eye
# Man, we lit up the world
like the Fourth of July
Don't take my leader book.
# And Uncle Sam puts your name
at the top of his list
# And the Statue of Liberty
started shaking her fist
# And the eagle will fly
and there's gonna be hell
# When you hear
mother Freedom
start ringing her bell
# And it feels like
the whole wide world
# Is raining down on you
Okay, open the door.
Open the door.
# Brought to you courtesy
of the red, white and blue #
(CLAPPING)
MAN ON RADIO: Okay,
the squad unit
is on the road...
What is that?
Any Mexicans in there?
Fucker!
What's that?
No...
Okay, okay.
Okay, close.
(GUNFIRE)
Hey, get these guys
the fuck out of here.
Just pop shots, guys.
Stay alert.
STEVE: Get these guys
out of here.
Good to go.
Yeah, Sarge,
just waiting around
to get blown up, huh?
(GRUNTS)
Yo, check this out.
Mich, she just sent
this to me yesterday.
Damn, Sarge.
Your fiancee is hot!
Appreciate it.
She and I will make
some cute Tex-Mex babies.
That's it.
Now you're cleaning
the shitters. Keep it up.
Just keep it up.
Go ahead.
Oh, that's personal.
That's personal.
Sergeant King,
I just saw
Michelle's tits.
Congratulations, Private.
EYEBALL:
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, titties?
All right, Steve,
deal with that car.
Eyeball, take
your post. Come on.
EYEBALL: All right,
all right.
STEVE:
Whoa! Stop! Stop!
(FIRES GUN)
BRANDON: Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hold your fire!
MAN 1 ON RADIO:
Two Apache gunships
are on their way for support.
Do you copy?
We have
two men wounded,
one killed.
We need emergency medevac
immediately. Over.
MAN 2: Checkpoint two,
we confirm
your transmission.
Medevac is on its way.
Sending a
Quick Reaction Force
to your pos at this time.
MAN 3: Roger.
Quick Reaction Force
for position, over.
Make it quick.
I have two men shot up!
I need help, now!
Units are
on their way.
All right.
Send them through.
Get out of here.
BRANDON: Mount up!
Mount up!
Let's go!
We're requesting
a Quick Reaction Force. Over.
We are pursuing insurgents
in a white taxi
north through
the city. Over.
Frank, do you see
anything up there?
North!
He's turning north!
All right,
he's on our 11.
He's on our 11.
Rico!
You see it?
Fuck! Damn!
Steve, you stay on them.
Can we hit him on the .50?
Not yet, there are
too many civilians.
We cannot fire.
I got them on my 11.
You okay, Tommy?
Hold on, here we go!
Look for a clear shot, Frank.
I will give you an order.
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
Fuck!
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Randy, Frank,
cover high. Come on.
RANDY: Roger.
EYEBALL:
Open door left.
Psych it up.
Go!
Straight ahead!
I got stairs!
(BABY CRYING)
Stay there!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Stay calm.
RICO: Adjacent room.
STEVE: Rico, clear?
Clear!
EYEBALL: Clear!
Stay calm! Coming out!
Rico, coming out!
BRANDON: Shrive,
that's a dry hole!
RICO: Coming out!
BRANDON: All right, move!
Tommy, let's move.
BRANDON: Go, move.
(CHILD CRYING)
It's an ambush!
Let's prepare to move back!
Ready!
Move back!
I got two Hajis
right across the street!
(MAN GROANING)
Smoke! Smoke!
Preacher, call in!
Tell them we need
immediate extraction!
Tell them we've
taken enemy fire!
Two went down!
PREACHER: Shadow 6,
this is Shadow 3,
Lollipop Quebec
Romeo 1-3-3.
We're pinned down.
We need
immediate extraction.
Move!
We have two KIA. Over.
RPG!
Preacher, are you hit?
I got two guys up front.
PREACHER: Rico's hit!
PREACHER: I need help!
BRANDON: Is he all right?
Come on!
Preacher, get Tommy!
Tommy, come on. Get up!
Get him out of the street!
Come on,
get against the wall.
You okay?
Rico, no sleeping
on the job, buddy.
Come on.
STEVE: Contact in
the front of the street!
Somebody get some
smoke in that alley!
Get that door open!
(GUNFIRE)
(MUMBLES)
Stay with me.
Can you look at me?
Is he breathing?
Yeah, he's breathing.
Eyeball, help me
get him in here.
Preach? Preacher?
Preacher's hit!
Get him out of there!
Tommy!
Get your ass inside,
right now! Come on.
Tommy!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
Tommy, get your ass
in there now!
Get down! Get down!
Steve, don't go in there!
God damn it.
(BABY CRYING)
Steve!
(GUNFIRE)
STEVE:
Man, I'm hit!
I'm hit!
I'm on my last mag!
How many?
Got a guy at
the top of the stairs!
There's another guy
at the end of
the fucking hall!
Coming straight up.
Steve?
Steve!
(STEVE COUGHS)
You all right?
I'm all right.
(COUGHING)
All right, Steve-o.
Let's get you out of here.
I'm all right.
Come on.
You got it.
Look at you, man.
(COUGHING)
(RADIO BEEPS)
All right, we're coming down.
We're gonna need cover.
# Truth of the matter is
# Nobody really know what's
gonna happen to 'em
# When it's gonna
happen to 'em
# Or where it's gonna
# You know, it's like we
just out here waiting
for it to happen
# It's no place to be
# And I tell you firsthand
# I'm just to the point now
where fuck it, you know?
# Just let the cards fall
as they may
# I'm halfway home,
but it's still a long road
to be traveled
# And I know
at any given moment
# Things could go sour
# From sweet to
the streets on fire
# Problems unravel
# Still holding my breath,
boots laced for battle
# In a place
where they would gladly
# See me scattered
all over they streets
# 'Cause here,
my life don't matter
# And though they smile,
underneath those grins
# They only waitin'
on their next chance
to try to kill me again
# And don't be caught
thinking out here
that your chances are slim
# 'Cause there are those
who have thought it
who will never think again
# Look here,
I'm trying to keep it together
# But things fall apart
# Especially when
I'm gone for so long,
losin' feeling in my heart
# Desensitized to
my surroundings,
every color's turning dark
# I don't see nothing
beautiful no more,
only targets my reticle marks
# Was emotional,
then emotionless,
now I don't feel a thing
# And though it once
killed me to kill,
I'd gladly do it again
# If only you
could really understand
the state of mind that I'm in
# Only then could you feel me,
only then will I make sense
# If only I hadn't have been
to some of the places
I've been
# If only I wouldn't
have seen what I saw,
maybe I could feel again
# But it's too hard
to separate
what's going on within me
# It's just so much easier
to let hate be my remedy
# So for everything
I'm guilty of,
let the Lord sentence me
# If only I wouldn't
have let everything
I been through get to me
# Things could
have been different,
but that is not my reality
# And either way,
it's only a matter of time
before I'm outta here #
Sergeant Shriver,
I saw your last
range scores.
You ever thought
of sniper school?
I used to.
I'm getting out.
I'm getting married, sir.
You're a hell of a shot.
I know, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Puffing on Boot's
cigar pretty hard,
ain't you?
(PUFFING)
(CHUCKLING)
"I know, sir. Thank you, sir.
I know, sir. Thank you, sir."
BOOT: All right, men,
listen up!
We have a bit of
a surprise for you.
The good folk
of Sergeant King
and Sergeant Shriver's
hometown, Brazos,
(MEN CHEERING)
are throwing them
a getting-out parade.
You represent
the United States Army.
(ALL GRUNT)
I expect every one of you
to be on your best behavior.
Here's a list of things
you will not do
while on leave.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
You will not
drink and drive.
You pick up
a young lady,
let her drive.
(LAUGHING)
Let her get the DUI.
You will not
beat up civilians!
You will not fuck
anyone underage.
I say again,
you will not fuck
anyone underage.
(MAN LAUGHING)
You will not
beat your wife,
(WOMEN CHEERING)
you will not
beat your kids.
You will not
kick your dog.
Am I understood?
(ALL GRUNT)
Okay. I'll see you
in Monday's formation,
0700. That's it.
Oh.
Enjoy your stay
in Brazos.
(ALL CHEERING)
(WHOOPING)
STEVE: Did you
get her on tape, man?
No, I didn't get
her on tape.
It's incriminating.
She said she was 18,
so fuck all y'all.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(PLAYING STARS AND STRIPES
FOREVER)
WOMAN: Welcome home, Brandon!
MAN 1: Welcome home, Steve!
MAN 2: Well done, Shriver!
MAN 3: Guys, welcome back.
MAN: Welcome home.
Thank you.
(ALL CHEERING)
Hey, baby!
(WHOOPS)
MAN: Welcome back,
soldier!
STEVE: Hey, Michelle.
Come here.
Beauty.
WOMAN: God bless the U.S.A.!
WORRELL ON MICROPHONE:
Two boys from Brazos,
best friends since
they were kids,
distinguished themselves
by leading Brazos
High football
to a memorable,
barn-burning division
championship...
MAN: All right, Steve!
...and have gone to war
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
and returned as heroes.
Staff Sergeant
Brandon Leonard King.
(ALL CHEERING)
We honor his
exceptional courage,
loyalty and selfless service
with this Purple Heart
and Bronze Star with Valor.
(ALL CHEERING)
Let's hear from
one of Brazos' own.
Yeah! Speech,
Brandon, speech.
ALL: (CHANTING) Speech!
Speech! Speech!
Come on, Brandon.
Sign them up,
Sergeant.
(ALL CHEERING)
SHORTY: Come on, Brandon.
I wasn't...
I wasn't planning
on giving a speech.
I was just...
I was just over there
trying to do my job,
like everybody else.
Trying to bring
my men back safe.
You know, most of my men
ain't from Texas.
It's kind of hard for me
to describe to them
what I love most.
(LAUGHS)
Ribs at Smitty's, or
the way they keep
the beer in tubs
at the Ajax Bar,
being out at
the ranch with
my folks.
On the bus ride over here,
I saw a truck hauling onions.
And I couldn't get
the window down,
'cause I...
I wanted to smell them.
See, onions smell
like home to me.
They smell like Texas...
That's right,
Sergeant King.
We're over there
killing them in Iraq
(ALL CHEERING)
so we ain't got to kill
them in Texas!
ALL: # For purple
mountain majesties
# Above the fruited plain
# America, America
# God shed His grace on thee
# And crown thy good
with brotherhood #
Tony, how are you, son?
Brandon.
Ma!
Oh, God!
Let me see you.
Oh, you're
home now, baby.
I'm home.
ROY: Let him breathe, Ida.
Oh, he can breathe.
Dad.
Good to have
you back, Son.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
It's good to be back.
Brandon King!
Yes, ma'am.
MAN 1: Mr. King!
Good to see you, sir.
MAN 2: Sergeant King!
Good to have you back.
Yeah, well, baby.
Hey, Thomas?
You going with us?
Yeah, I'll be
there in a second.
I am real proud
of you, son.
Hello.
I'm pulling some strings,
trying to move your
Private Rodriguez
from the hospital
in Germany to an
Army hospital stateside.
Anything else
you need,
you call me.
Thank you, sir,
I will.
I'm real grateful
about Private Rodriguez.
I plan on seeing him
when I get out.
If you come
to Washington,
you call me.
I'll take you
around Capitol Hill
and show them
what a real Texas
hero looks like.
I'd love that.
Private Rodriguez's family
could use a word
of encouragement.
We are going to take
very good care
of your son.
Thank you.
Your brother's
gonna be fine, just fine.
Thank you.
All right, Augustin.
You stay out of trouble.
Shorty Shriver!
Hey, Brandon.
I got some
making out to do.
Sorry.
SHORTY:
Y'all so cute.
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
Have a seat.
Welcome back, baby.
Thank you.
We missed
your fine ass.
Oh, man.
Here, soldier.
Get you
some tequila.
Oh, look,
it's Brandon,
King of Texas.
Come on, Brandon.
Oh, my lord.
(CROWD CHEERING)
You back
in Texas now.
I love Texas!
STEVE: Welcome home, boy.
BRANDON: It's good to be home.
(CROWD CHEERING)
All right.
Y'all listen up.
To Steve and Michelle.
(PLAYING WEDDING MARCH
ON GUITAR)
Oh, my gosh.
Finally!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
Give it a spin
on the dance floor.
Come on.
Yeah.
I want to dance.
I formally release him
into your custody.
Thank you.
(MAN LAUGHING)
I'm all right.
Don't worry about
old Steve.
Are you okay?
No, you go ahead.
I'm gonna sit this
one out.
But we ain't
danced yet, babe.
I know. Just... You go.
I'm gonna sit this one out,
all right?
# It's dance time in Texas
# And we're
striking up the band
# We'll go honky-tonkin'
# Honey, take my hand #
You and Brandon kill
a bunch of those Iraqis
over there?
Yeah, Steve,
we winning this thing?
Look. What we need to do
is just drop a
10,000-pound bomb
on one of their cities
every time they hit us.
No more of this urban
combat bullshit.
I'm tired of going and
killing a Haji in his kitchen
and his bedroom.
Fucking-A.
When you
going back, Steve?
I'm done.
Me and B.K.
are getting out.
You know,
but if I had to do it again,
I'd be a fucking sniper.
One shot. One kill.
Let me be
the faceless enemy.
I'd go back tomorrow to get
that Haji bastard that
killed Preacher.
(TOMMY AND EYEBALL GRUNT)
STEVE: Preacher was
Tommy's best friend
over there.
TOMMY: I fucking
loved that guy.
He took a round in the face.
It blew his jaw all
the way off.
Then he took
one in the neck.
ROY: Hey, Steve.
He was dead before
he hit the ground.
Yes, sir?
Just take out Haji
and his whole fucking
family.
Send them right
back to Bible times.
(CHUCKLES)
MAN: What about you, darling?
No, thank you.
Sure?
I'm one hell
of a dancer.
No. I don't doubt it, but...
Hey.
Hey, my wife said no.
You fucking deaf?
I get it, man,
no problem.
You're the hero.
JEANIE: Tommy!
Tommy!
Ah, shit. It's on!
(CROWD CHEERING)
WOMAN:
Get him, Tommy.
Oh, shit.
(MUSIC STOPS)
Tommy! No, Tommy!
At ease, soldier.
You hear me?
Soldier, at ease.
Fucking ease!
Listen to me!
All right, you good?
You good? Huh?
You hear me?
All right. Calm down,
let's get a drink.
Come on, man.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Hey, it ain't a party
without a fight!
(ALL CHEER)
Oh, snap! Tommy.
EYEBALL:
Okay. It is midnight,
and all the shit
the U.S. Army done
issued to your ass
still ain't accounted for.
And when you turn
all the rest of
this shit in,
you gonna have
to owe about $1000.
Oh, Eyeball,
I am getting out.
Man.
That's what's up, man.
Except I'm keeping this.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Good choice.
Good choice,
as your face has been
known to scare kids
and make dogs bark.
You're funny.
(GROANS)
Where's my phone?
Hello.
MICHELLE: Bran?
Hi, Mich.
Yeah, I'll be right over.
Dude, come on.
You all right?
He's got a gun.
What you doing,
Steve?
What the fuck
do you think?
You hitting the rack?
(GRUNTS)
Yeah.
Do you want
to know what...
What pisses
me off is just...
Soon as I get dug in,
those fuckers are
gonna move us out.
I'm gonna have
to do this shit
all over again.
Roger that.
What the hell?
Your mama made
all these by hand.
She loves you
like a daughter.
Steve was yelling at them
like they're alive.
Then he kicked
over the table.
A lady at the base
said not to rush
the fooling around.
But you know Steve.
He'd been drinking.
He couldn't...
He hit you?
He got rageful.
Did he hit you?
I caught a backhand.
I told him,
"Get the hell out."
He's so goddamn
drunk right now,
he thinks
he's on a mission
outside the wire.
You know he loves you
more than anything.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
What up, Tommy?
Hey.
I just woke up
and I was here.
What are you
guys doing?
Fucking RoboSoldier dug
a ranger grave in Michelle's
front yard.
(CHUCKLES)
You want a beer?
Yeah.
Ain't it time you and Jeanie
open your wedding presents?
Jeanie threw me out
until I get my
shit together.
I was wondering, maybe
I could stay out at the ranch,
just a couple days.
I was thinking
maybe we'd all go,
get out of town for the day.
What about RoboSoldier?
(COCKS GUN)
(ALL CHEERING)
(WHOOPS)
Fucked that one!
That's my boy.
Read the card.
(COUNTRY MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
"Uncle Vern
and Aunt Tilly
"hope you and Jeanie get
a bun in the oven soon."
Out of the way!
(ALL LAUGHING)
(WHOOPING)
(SCREAMS)
You know, it used to be,
the protocol for
a busted marriage
was to return
the wedding gifts,
Thomas?
Read the card, Shorty.
"To Tommy and Jeanie,
for a long and happy
life together.
"From Tom
and Charlotte."
Out of the way!
(WHOOPS)
(LAUGHING)
(POUNDING ON TRUNK)
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
(ALL CHUCKLING)
BRANDON: There she is!
Morning, sweetheart!
RAINEY: Oh, yeah, baby.
(ALL LAUGHING)
What's the matter, Robo?
You wake up
on the wrong side
of the spare tire?
(MEN LAUGHING)
(COUGHS)
TOMMY:
Shorty, read the card!
DENNIS: Hey, princess,
don't throw up
in there, man.
I'm gonna need
a beer in a minute.
Shorty, read it!
"From Steve
and Michelle."
Can we fucking cease fire
for a little while?
Yeah, sure.
(GUNFIRE)
God damn it!
I'm sorry.
Brandon,
you motherfucker.
God damn!
An old
granddaddy rattler!
Right where you would
have stepped, cousin.
I should've
let it bit you.
God damn!
SHORTY: Good shooting, B.K.
She's beautiful.
(RAZOR BUZZING)
I'm used to that shit, baby.
Just 'cause y'all
are so busy...
MAN: Careful. Careful.
STEVE: Mr. T.
"I pity the fool."
I pity the fool
that let Preacher cut
their motherfucking hair.
# One, nothing wrong with me
# Two, nothing wrong with me
# Three, nothing wrong with me
# Four, nothing wrong with me
# One, something's got to give
# Two, something's got to give
# Three, something's
got to give
# Now!
# Let the bodies hit the floor
(SCREAMS)
# Push me again
All right.
You've been busting
my fucking balls all day.
How are you
gonna explain
that black eye
in safety brief
on Monday, huh?
I walked into a door.
You and Michelle walk
in the same door?
Look, I fucked up.
I don't even know
what happened.
Okay, I kind
of blacked out.
All I know is I remember
waking up in the trunk
of Tommy's fucking car.
Well, it ain't
gonna happen again.
You copy me?
Do you copy me?
I said I know and
I said I fucked up.
(SIGHS)
Come on.
Watch the venom.
You watch it.
Don't fucking touch
me with that shit.
Watch the venom, man!
I think I broke skin.
I'm gonna
fuck you up.
Come on.
Look at y'all.
Crazy.
It's over now, baby.
What are y'all
doing over here?
# Hey... Go!
# Hey... Go! #
(HISSING)
Hey.
Tommy?
You all right?
I shouldn't have
shot that shit up.
Sarge Shriver.
Sarge King.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CHUCKLING)
(EXPLOSION)
Man, I'm gonna
miss blowing shit up.
Next.
Gas mask.
Check.
Poncho liner.
Sergeant King.
Waterproof bag.
Check.
Did you cover
for me in formation?
Come here.
Look.
Me and Steve
are getting out.
It's up to you and Eyeball
to lead the recruits.
All right.
This new squad leader,
he's a Baptist.
I'm a Baptist.
All right.
He's a real Baptist.
Listen, man,
you got to get
a fucking grip.
You smell like
a fucking brewery.
Come on.
That's 'cause
we were drinking
last night.
Tommy.
Wait! Come on.
WOMAN: Okay.
You're all good to go.
Says here you have
orders to report to
the First Brigade.
Not me.
I'm getting
out today.
Brandon
Leonard King?
Yes.
Out to
the First Brigade
on the 22nd.
This is a mistake.
It's all there.
You leave on the 22nd,
shipping back to Iraq.
Sub-section
12305, Title 10.
By the authority
of the President.
You've been stop-lossed.
Lieutenant Colonel?
Sergeant King.
I teed you up
for a recruitment
pitch in Brazos,
and you gave me
an onion patch.
It's what came
to mind, sir.
What's your problem,
Sergeant?
I'm supposed to
be getting out today.
Now they're shipping
me back to Iraq.
You understand
why it's important
we win over there?
Why we need
good soldiers
like you?
Yes, sir.
You have extenuating
circumstances?
You gay or pregnant?
Sir, you know me.
I'm a squared-away
soldier.
Because I have
an extenuating
circumstance, Sergeant.
It's called a war.
It's in Iraq.
I know, sir.
I volunteered
to fight in it.
I ran over 150 combat
missions for you,
no complaint.
Contract says
stop-loss is only
in a time of war.
This President said
the war's over,
so legally...
You a lawyer, son?
No, sir.
But after doing
right by this Army,
I'm getting burned
by some fine print
in a contract.
Now the President
himself said...
The President is also
the Commander-in-Chief.
I think he trumps
you either way.
With all due respect, sir,
fuck the President!
Fuck the President?
Yes, sir.
He's not over there
fighting this war.
He's not there
seeing his buddies
burned alive in Humvees.
I lost three
men last month,
and I almost got
the rest of us killed.
Those were my men, too,
and I lost more than that.
You're an excellent leader,
and you are going back.
For 11 more years?
It won't come to that.
How do you know?
I think the President
trumps you in
this matter.
This, sir,
is bullshit,
and you know it!
Lieutenant, you just heard
Sergeant King disobey
a direct order.
Yes, sir.
I also perceive him
to be a flight risk.
Escort him to
the stockade so he
can readjust his attitude.
You're making
a big mistake.
I'm doing you
a big favor.
End of discussion.
Make sure he ships
to the First Brigade when
it goes out on the 22nd.
Roger, sir.
Come on, hotshot.
Don't you
fucking touch me!
(SOLDIER GROANS)
Steve, I fucked up real bad.
Hey, man. What?
What'd you do?
I put down a couple guys
and now I'm AWOL.
(STEVE LAUGHS)
What the fuck...
I got stop-lossed
back to Iraq.
Shit!
Oh, okay.
Look, take it to Boot.
You're gold
with him,
he'll fix it.
Yeah, Boot was
trying to send me
to the stockade.
I shook loose
and I took off in
your Jeep, man.
You definitely have
fucked up now.
I know.
I know,
I just got triggered.
I lost my shit.
All right. Wait, look.
All right, get a grip,
calm down.
I'll try to figure out
what's going on here,
and cover your six.
Thanks, man.
I knew you would.
I'll hit you later.
ROY: Come on in, Sheriff.
SHERIFF: Ida,
listen to this.
These MPs came
to me and said
Brandon's gone AWOL.
How in the hell
can he be AWOL if
he's getting out today?
Boot's hopping mad.
He called me personally
to put out a statewide APB.
Get Brandon to turn
himself in and get
this thing sorted out.
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
I don't understand.
They stop-lossed you?
How can they do this?
They're doing whatever
they wanna do.
With a shortage
of guys and no draft,
they're shipping back soldiers
who's supposed to be
getting out.
It's a backdoor
draft, is what it is.
What about Steve?
Mich, I don't know.
Some of us are getting it,
some ain't.
This cannot
be happening.
No! You almost
died over there.
What do you
want to do?
You want me to
take you to Mexico
till this blows over?
No, no, no.
Out of the question, Mom.
I ain't dragging
my tail across
to Mexico.
I'm getting my keys.
Brandon.
Listen to me.
If you're spooked,
it's okay.
There's no
shame in that.
I ain't scared.
I'm pissed off!
This family is done
fighting this war.
He ain't scared, Roy.
He's just being sensible.
I just don't want him
to get in any deeper,
is all.
Maybe ruin
his whole life.
I ain't gonna
let it go that far.
Ruin his life?
How about getting
himself killed?
God damn it, Ida.
Hold on! Hold on!
The Senator said
to my face if I ever
needed anything, he'd help.
That is
a big-ass mistake.
You go out of
the chain of command,
over Boot's head,
you're doubling your trouble.
He's gonna make
an example of you.
I ain't worried
about Boot
once I explain
the whole thing
to the Senator.
I just need to run
up to D.C. right now
and get this sorted out.
Okay. I'll take you.
You can't.
They're gonna be
watching y'all.
They won't be
watching me.
I'll take you.
Michelle, Steve would
have my ass if I let you
get mixed up in all this.
He could be next.
Let's go.
This is wrong,
Brandon.
MICHELLE:
Steve don't talk much
about being over there.
Sand.
Fleas.
Flies.
Heat.
Boredom.
Or you can
get shot at.
Or blown up.
That's pretty much it.
Sheep on the highway.
Where?
In Iraq.
(CHUCKLES)
Big-ass
flocks of them.
Yeah?
Jeanie, it's me.
I need you
to cover my shift
at work tomorrow.
Sorry I woke you up.
No, I was up.
I was up.
And covering your
shift's no problem,
since neither one of us
has a fucking job.
What?
Tommy drove his
car into our work,
drunk as fuck.
He got two DUIs
in the last two days.
What the hell's happening
to these guys?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Are you all right
out here?
I thought I saw somebody
down by the drain.
You okay?
Yeah, sure.
You should try
and get some sleep.
I'll be all right, Mich.
(MACHINE GUNFIRE)
I know what I'm doing.
Listen, Mich, you need
to be getting home.
You need some
dry clothes.
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
(OFFICER KNOCKING ON DOOR)
OFFICER: Michelle Overton!
You taught me
everything I know.
You made me
everything I am.
Can't be anything else, sir.
I'm no good as anything else.
DEVER: Then stop
your drinking!
I will, sir.
(DIALING PHONE)
All I wanna be
is a soldier.
I just want to
go back to Iraq.
I'm gonna be better.
Hey, baby.
If I ever...
Put Brandon
on the phone.
Put him
on the phone!
All right.
Hey, man.
Where the hell are you,
man?
I have a situation
you need to step
into right now.
I've been trying to
reach you all night.
Where you been?
I've been at
the fucking jailhouse
all night,
trying to bail Tommy out
of a DUI shitstorm.
God damn it!
Boot is about
to kick Tommy out.
Squad leader is
supposed to be here,
and that's you.
Steve, I can't.
I'm on my way to D.C.
to see the Senator.
You're what?
You're fucking AWOL,
and you're taking Michelle
to fucking D.C.?
I'm gonna cut
her loose at
the state line.
DEVER: You haven't
proved it to me yet!
I need you to handle
this until I get back.
Just a couple of days.
This better be
the last time...
It can't wait that long.
...you drive drunk!
And you, my friend,
you are in deep
fucking shit with Boot.
TOMMY: I'm gonna
make this up.
It's all I got.
This is everything to me.
Army's my family.
I know I'm a little sideways,
but give me one more chance,
please.
What's up?
Gonna head north
on the 55 into
Memphis.
Long way around.
There's something
I got to do.
I'll drive.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and
the Holy Spirit.
MAN 1: Congratulations, man.
MAN 2: It'll take a lot
more than water
till I'm saved.
Thanks, man.
MAN 3: Attaboy, Preacher.
You saved him.
I think you need
some more blessing, bro.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Preacher and the chaplain
baptized a lot of guys
over there.
Come on, sit down.
Just wanted to pay
my respects, sir.
Very grateful
that you came.
You said you
had a bad feeling
about Paul's last tour?
Mmm-hmm.
Why'd he go back
so many times?
He was stop-lossed.
Couldn't find
a way out?
There were people right here
in Memphis on the lay low.
Stop-lossed soldiers
filing a lawsuit.
But he wouldn't listen.
Excuse me.
And how would someone
find these guys with
the lawsuit?
Depends on who
wants to know.
I'd like to know.
It started out just
like any other day.
We were manning a checkpoint,
but we came under attack.
And standard operating
procedure is to pursue
the attackers, and...
Go on,
we want to know.
We followed them
into an alley.
I led my men
Preacher, Paul,
was covering our flank.
We got hit
from both rooftops.
RPGs, small arms,
bullets, explosions...
It was an ambush.
Leading your men into
an ambush is standard
operating procedure?
PASTOR COLSON:
That's enough, Michael.
I remember...
I was yelling at him
across the alley.
And he got on
the phone to call for
reinforcements, and
he must have seen somebody
drawing down on Thomas,
'cause he fired
a few shots in
that direction.
And his rifle jammed.
That's when...
That's when he got hit.
Did our son suffer?
No, ma'am.
No, he was...
It all happened
real fast.
My brother's life
was wasted over there.
Your brother died
doing what he knew
in his heart was his duty.
And he died
in the arms of
his best friend.
I can tell you that.
He's the one
that sent the picture
right after we lost Paul.
Read the back.
(PASTOR COLSON READING)
He calls, sometimes,
late at night.
Mmm-hmm.
I think he's
been drinking.
You keep that.
Thank you, sir,
I will.
We want to thank you,
Sergeant King,
for coming.
Because I know that
these meetings must be
very difficult for you.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you,
Sergeant.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you.
Good luck
getting out.
That was real nice,
what you did back there.
So you wanna go find
this place Preacher's
brother told me about?
I'm going straight to D.C.
End of discussion.
All right.
Damn.
Wait here!
Brandon.
It don't matter.
(MAN LAUGHING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
You got my shit, asshole.
Get the fuck out
of here, man.
I want my fucking shit.
(GROANS)
(GROANING)
(COUGHING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(COCKS GUN)
Break yourself, fool.
Break yourself.
All right! All right!
Calm down.
(GRUNTS)
Stay down!
Okay, Hajis.
On your knees,
hands behind your heads.
Now, I said!
Do it!
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING)
Hands behind your head.
You having fun, Haji?
You having fun?
Who wants to play
"Let's start shooting people"?
You're up.
You're fucking up!
Right in the back
of your head.
(GROANING)
Oh, yeah, yeah.
You ain't dead yet?
Just give
him his shit!
Come on now.
We're just getting
started, here.
Your shit's over there, man.
It's over there.
Just go get it.
Oh, yeah? What?
I can't hear you.
What'd you say?
(CAR TIRES SCREECHING)
Who's next?
You, you're next.
Y'all better start
praying to Allah, son.
Man, please.
Please don't
shoot me.
(GUN FIRES)
Brandon, don't shoot.
MAN: Oh, shit!
Oh, my God.
I've got everything.
I've got all
our stuff.
Okay?
On your faces.
On your faces!
That's enough.
Put the gun down.
Get away!
Don't you hit me!
Give me the gun.
Give me the gun,
or I'm gonna leave
you here right now.
On your face!
I swear!
I swear
I ain't kidding!
ROANS)
(HORN BLARES)
You're gonna
need some stitches.
Here.
Let me help you.
I got it.
(GRUNTS)
Before Steve
came home,
they told us how
a soldier could be
a danger to himself
or other people.
You think I'm a danger?
I've been knowing
you since third grade.
I think we've
got both kinds
of danger here.
(GRUNTS)
I'm sorry.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(GROANS)
(PEOPLE YELLING)
What's going on?
Same shit every night.
Drinking,
fighting, hookers.
And I got
babies in here.
Cops will be here soon.
Hey.
You laying low here?
How'd you
find this place?
Brother of a guy
in my squad.
Guy pushing a lawsuit
in the lay low?
Didn't tell you
about our first case,
did he?
Army came down hard.
Locked the guy up,
took everything.
Even his wife left him.
I ain't got no
time for no lawsuit.
Good.
There ain't
a judge in this country
going up against the military
while this war is on.
And let me tell
you something
about laying low.
Can't get a job.
Can't cash a check.
And they're probably
tracing your calls.
Now go on in there
and brush your teeth
so we can leave, okay?
My youngest boy,
we can't even take
him to the doctor.
You're on the run 24/7.
And God forbid
you get pulled over
for having
a busted taillight.
You going to jail.
So where you
headed now?
North. Canada.
I can't put my
family through this
no more. Thanks.
What about you?
D.C. Going to
see a senator.
Why don't you write
a letter to the editor
while you at it?
Listen, man, you
should try to reach
my guy, Ron Carlson,
old peacenik lawyer,
works out of New York,
takes people north.
He'll help you get
across the border.
Listen, man,
I ain't interested
in dealing with
no shitbag coyote.
Suit yourself.
But we've been on
the run 14 months,
and I can't
take it no more.
Here's the number.
Take it.
Keep it.
I got it memorized.
Another way out of this,
I would have done it.
Good luck.
Y'all hurry up, now.
You feeling
all right?
Yeah?
Here, let me
see about you.
(BOMBS EXPLODING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BABY CRYING)
(GUNFIRE)
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Oh, fuck!
You told him
where we were.
MICHELLE: He's come
to take me home.
I'll leave you
my car, okay?
Thanks a lot.
Hey, baby.
Good morning.
Morning.
God damn, soldier.
What happened to you?
What you gonna tell Boot?
You walked into
a fucking door?
I ain't telling
Boot shit.
Yeah, you are.
I'm here to
take you back.
You ain't taking
me anywhere.
Okay, tough guy.
Let me lay
it out for you.
Boot said if I
get you back on base
in the next 14 hours,
all charges are dropped,
no stockade.
I don't need you
making deals
with Boot for me.
Hey!
You don't know
what I've been through
to scrape the shit
off of your shoes.
You ought to be
thanking me.
You steal my Jeep
and you run off
with my girl.
That ain't how
it happened.
You know that.
I was trying
to help him.
And that's what
I'm trying to do.
This is a straight
deal from Boot.
It's what's best for him.
What's best for me?
What's best for you, Steve?
Showing up here
in your Class A's.
What kind of
deal did you make
with Boot? Huh?
You took him up
on sniper school,
didn't you?
God damn!
You re-enlisted?
How could you do this?
STEVE: How could you
run off with Brandon
for three fucking days
and not call me?
We don't call you
and you re-enlist?
That's bullshit!
And you know it.
How could I not?
Michelle,
it got real clear to me
that this, this is safe.
It's safe?
And when are we
getting married, Steve?
When I get back
from my next tour.
When you get back?
You've been saying
that to me for
five fucking years.
It's clear you've
made your decision.
This is good for me.
I got a future in this.
This is something
that I can be proud of.
Did you really see me
selling cars for Rainey?
Get out of here.
Look, I'm sorry.
Hold on. Please?
Don't.
Please come here.
Please, just...
Don't.
Get out of here!
Fucker, get out.
I said get out!
(MICHELLE PANTING)
Fuck!
Did that really
just fucking happen?
MICHELLE:
Fucking motherfucker!
That was fucked up.
What did you expect?
God damn it.
How did everything
get so fucked up?
You, Tommy,
now Michelle?
What's wrong
with Tommy?
He's too messed up, man.
I can't get through
to him like you can.
He just won't
listen to me.
Look, come on.
Come on.
We'll go and
we'll knock out
another tour,
and we'll come home.
Another tour?
You're always
talking about how
snakebit this war is,
how they won't
let us fight it
the way we need to win it.
Now you want
to go back?
That makes no
fucking sense.
Like this makes
any fucking sense?
This isn't who
we are, man.
Man, look, we didn't
get through all
this shit together
just for you to
end up like one
of these AWOL shitbags.
We ain't like
these guys.
We're soldiers.
We stand for
something, man.
We're from Texas.
All right.
Stow the Boot talk, man.
You let him talk
you into going back?
That's fine.
You got a right
to be stupid.
Well, fuck you, man!
I did what I had to do
for the time I had to do it,
and I ain't
gonna do it anymore.
You can take
that back to Boot.
You're the only person
who thinks you're
getting out of this!
Boot called the Senator.
He knows what
you're up to.
You're AWOL, Brandon.
No senator is
gonna help you.
You're done!
Steve, you know
what they're doing
is wrong.
I'm not going back.
I'm fighting this thing.
Hey!
Watch your six.
(MAN CHATTERING)
WOMAN: Sergeant King,
I've told you
several times already,
the Senator
cannot see you.
BRANDON: Ma'am,
I'm a decorated soldier.
Now, a Purple
Heart and a Bronze Star
got to mean something.
I understand.
But you're a fugitive.
No U.S. official,
no government official
is gonna help
a soldier on the run.
Go back to your base
before you get arrested.
(DIAL TONE)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(ROCK AND ROLL MUSIC PLAYING)
# Now, when I was
just a little boy
# Standin' to my daddy's knee
Tequila.
You know,
it's happy hour.
You can get
two for one.
Well, lucky me.
Double, double.
# 'Cause he'll get you
now, now
# And I can remember
the fourth of July
# Runnin' through
the backwood, bare
Can I join you?
# And I can still hear
my old hound dog barkin'
# Chasin' down a hoodoo there
# Born on the bayou
# Born on the bayou #
The way I see it,
Steve's married
to the Army.
It's everything to him.
(SIGHS)
I can't go another year
without having
him touch my face.
I can't be a military wife.
I just ain't that strong.
Well, Michelle,
you know,
life is very long, and...
Brandon.
...you're very young.
Shut up and drink.
Yes, ma'am.
We're both fucked.
Same again.
All right, men.
You all straighten up
and walk sober, all right?
Yes, sir.
Sergeant Shriver,
the man in charge.
What are you doing
with a fucking bottle, man?
You ain't even
supposed to be drinking.
Come on, man.
What are you...
Where are you going?
Over to Jeanie's.
Jeanie don't
want you, dummy.
That's what
a restraining
order means.
STEVE: Come on, Tommy.
You can stay at
my house, man.
I'm gonna make it better.
Swear to God.
Just propose again.
We'll get married again.
Only thing you
proposing is to
get locked up, man.
Let's get
out of here.
All right.
Come on, man.
You know I ain't gonna
let you go over there.
Let's go.
You talking
about Jeanie?
You can't even manage
your own woman.
No, I didn't mean
it like that, Steve.
Steve.
No, seriously.
No, come on.
Tommy. Tommy!
I'm sorry.
Steve, come on.
(ALARM BLARING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(GRUNTS)
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
I smell a woman,
and it ain't a nurse.
Then who?
Hola, Private Rodriguez.
Sergeant King!
My first visitor.
You found me.
I did.
And who?
Michelle.
Hey, Rico.
Sergeant
Shriver's Michelle.
Sunny blonde hair,
green eyes.
Steve showed us
your picture
a million times.
Sergeant King came to see me
with his best friend's girl!
(RICO CHUCKLES)
It's a long story.
Yes, sir,
I bet it is.
Sit, man.
I got time.
Good to see you.
It's good to see you.
How's my mother?
She's good.
She's missing you.
Yeah. And my brothers?
They're getting big.
Growing up.
They strong?
Seem to be.
Taking after
their brother.
Not as handsome.
Close.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
I'll let you
guys talk.
All right.
Thanks for
coming to see me.
(BOTH LAUGH)
She sounds cute.
How're you feeling?
Feeling good, sir.
Just as comfy
as a Humvee.
You think?
I wouldn't have thought,
but...
They taking good
care of you?
First-class
treatment, Sarge.
Good. So I don't have
to talk to anybody?
No, sir.
All right.
Nice break.
Thank you.
(LAUGHS)
That's impressive.
Sloppy.
What can I say?
You're in, though.
Come on.
I think she's
a butter face.
Yeah?
She's hot,
but her face.
But does she
give a good bath?
She's got
some soft hands.
Well, there you go.
That's what matters.
I haven't felt
anything else,
but that'll change.
Soon as I get
the rest of this.
All right.
Man, I had this thing,
like a dream, all right?
You were at the bottom
of a swimming pool,
and I dove in to
try to save you.
But I couldn't.
It's okay, man.
You did save me.
I'm right here.
And seeing stuff, man?
Here, at night?
Sounds like
a fucking horror movie.
Guys screaming,
nightmares...
Sarge,
we got out
just in time.
I mean,
Haji's new bombs...
You don't want
to survive, man.
Sounds crazy,
but I feel lucky,
you know?
They want to send me back.
I hope you told
them no fucking way.
I mean,
I might go back.
'Cause if I got killed,
my family would
get green cards.
Sir.
Yeah?
Could you move
me out of the sun?
Okay.
So, I'm sorry,
but I got to ask.
What you doing
with Sergeant
Shriver's fiancee?
They broke up.
She's just giving me
a ride.
She was giving
you a ride before
or after they broke up?
Not like that.
Michelle's
close to my family.
She's just helping me out.
She's somebody...
(SHUSHING)
(LAUGHS)
What?
You should hear
the way you sound, Sarge.
You a Jody.
It's time for you to
go back to your room,
Private Rodriguez.
# Jody got your girl
and gone #
Sing it.
I don't know
the words.
You sing it.
# Ain't no use in going home
Jody got your girl and gone #
You watching this one?
Mmm-hmm.
Nice shot.
Now we're even.
What you laughing at?
You lost.
That's pretty funny.
"Give you a hand."
Dumbass.
Help me push it.
Yeah.
Thank you.
It's fucking strong.
Is it?
I'll be in touch, Rico.
Tell the boys I said,
"What's up?"
I will.
I signed up,
thinking I was
gonna go over there
and protect my country.
My family.
We wanted
payback for 9/11,
and you get there,
and you realize
the war wasn't even
about any of that.
The enemy ain't
out in the desert.
They're in
the hallways and rooftops,
living rooms, kitchens.
Everybody's got a weapon.
Everybody.
Nobody knows who's who.
The only thing
you can believe in
is surviving.
Protecting
the guy to your left
and the guy to your right.
Side by side,
willing to die
for each other.
By the time
you start seeing
good friends'
bodies held together
by a belt after a car bomb,
you get
a kill-or-be-killed
mentality.
It's okay.
No, it ain't.
Michelle, I'm worried
if I tell you these things,
you're gonna think
differently of me,
and I...
I couldn't stand that.
I ain't gonna
think that.
(SIGHS)
Our last mission,
in the alley,
well, when Rico got hit,
I looked in his face,
and most of it
was burned off.
I had to go
in to get Steve.
I knew he
was in trouble.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
I'm done with killing.
And I ain't leading
any more men into
a slaughter.
You have to
call Carlson.
I know.
(SNIFFLES)
Mr. Carlson.
My name is...
CARLSON: No names.
All right.
What's the problem?
I'm a Staff Sergeant,
a squad leader,
two tours,
Afghanistan and Iraq,
and I just got stop-lossed.
They're shipping me back
at the end of the month.
There's so many of
you guys out there.
I've heard it before.
It's the same story,
and you eventually call me.
Do you understand what I do?
I strip away who you are.
I set you down
in a foreign place
where you're gonna live
the rest of your life
pretending to
be someone else.
Do you want that?
I can't go home.
I can't go back.
I got no other options.
I need your services.
I won't be able to
discuss this further
over the phone.
Do you have some money?
Like a grand?
I have a few bucks.
Well, when you get a grand,
start driving north
toward New York City.
700, 800, 900, 1000.
Not a bad price.
Thank you, sir.
Come on.
This is a good
opportunity.
Rainey said that
people will just line up
to buy a Cadillac from a vet.
Yeah, not with a BCD.
It's not like you're
gonna hang it on the
showroom wall, Tommy.
What's a BCD?
(SIGHS)
It's the big
chicken dinner.
It's what we
call it in the Army.
It's a Bad
Conduct Discharge.
We gonna shoot
this shit up, or what?
That shotgun loaded?
What's the first rule
of weapon safety, Tommy?
Always assume
every weapon
is loaded.
Yes, sir.
Sorry.
(CHUCKLES)
Where are you going?
I'm going back
to the bunkhouse,
write a hit song.
# Don't feel like
shooting shit up today
ALL: # 'Cause we'll put
a boot in your ass
It's the American way
# Hey, Uncle Sam... #
Later, guys.
All right, man.
SHORTY: Later, Tommy.
# Brought to you courtesy
of the red, white and blue
# Of my red, white and blue #
I spotted you guys
from a mile off.
Oh, well.
What happened?
I just had a run-in
with a couple guys.
Yeah.
That kind of shit happens
when you're on the run.
All you guys get
popped eventually.
Is this a package deal?
Just one for now.
You thought about this?
Yes, sir.
'Cause one-way
means one-way.
You go,
you're going for good,
unless you get
fucked with extradition.
Pardon my French.
I don't want you
calling me up crying
how you can't go
to grandma's funeral
back in Tennessee.
Texas.
We're from Texas.
(CLEARS THROAT) Whatever.
I just want it all
laid out straight.
Canada's not that bad.
I just had a guy up there,
got married to
a real sweet local girl.
Loves Toronto.
Says it's a lot
like New York.
I ain't so crazy
about New York, so far.
You got any other options?
Like, what about Mexico?
Look, I don't know
shit about Mexico.
Here's your new I.D.
They'll fix in the photos
before you leave.
Day after tomorrow,
somebody will meet you
at this address in Buffalo.
Take you over.
You got the money?
MICHELLE: Here.
No refunds, right?
Got it.
Half now and half across.
Go make your calls.
Say your goodbyes.
Hi, Mom?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
He did what?
When?
I don't...
Let me call you back, Mom.
(BRANDON BREATHING HEAVILY)
Tommy shot himself
out at the ranch.
(GUN FIRES)
(TAPS PLAYING)
OFFICER: Left, face.
This flag
is presented on behalf
of a grateful nation
and the United States Army
as a token of appreciation
for your loved one's
honorable and
faithful service.
(SIGHS)
Come on, Ida.
Let's go.
(SOBBING QUIETLY)
Look who came home.
(BRANDON COUGHING)
That's for fucking
running out on us.
And that's for coming
back too fucking late.
And that's on
general principle.
(COUGHING)
Fuck you.
You're throwing everything
in your life away.
You stupid...
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Y'all gonna get
yourselves killed,
you know that?
Do you hear me?
Shut the fuck up.
So you just go
over there and you do
your fucking duty.
You see this?
This is you next.
(BOTH COUGHING)
(BOTH PANTING)
Steve.
You don't fucking
belong here!
I don't... I don't
even know you anymore!
(SOBBING)
Maybe you don't.
Bullshit!
I've known every
thought in your head
since we were fucking
stealing Playboys from
the fucking bus station.
That was a
long time ago.
Then, please. Tell me.
Tell me what you've
been thinking,
because nothing in
the last few days
has made any fucking
sense to me at all.
You know that box
inside your head?
That box inside
your head where you...
You put all the bad shit
you can't deal with?
Well, mine's full.
And it's spilling out.
Steve, it is full
of all the people
I got killed.
Preacher.
Randy.
Harvey.
Thomas.
All the rest I've lost
in this fucked-up war.
Think how many people
would have fucking died
if you wouldn't
have been there!
Including me!
Steve, I didn't do what
I was supposed to do!
I fucked up!
If you don't
fall in beside us,
it all comes apart.
BRANDON: The ranch
always felt so safe.
You'll find another
place and make it safe.
Sir.
Damn.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
You okay?
Across that border,
that ain't gonna be me
coming up the other side,
Mich.
It's gonna be
the ghost of me.
Brandon, please.
And never the ranch.
Never you and Dad,
never Brazos.
This war ain't never
gonna be behind me.
I'm sorry, Mom.
OFFICER: Bruckner,
Rodriguez,
Naughton,
Stevens,
Williams...
WOMAN 1: Bye-bye, sweetheart.
We love you, sweetie.
We love you, honey!
WOMAN 2: Adis, Augustin.
WOMAN 1: Bye, sweetheart.
Take care of her.
Bye, sweetie.
Write to me.
MAN 1: I'll keep
those e-mails coming.
MAN 2: We're proud of you.
We love you.
Better e-mail me, Shorty!
(CHATTERING)
WOMAN 3: Take care
of each other.
MAN 3: All of you
come back safe.
(MOUTHING)
MAN 4: God bless you.
# Truth of the matter is
# And I tell you firsthand
# I'm just to the point now
where fuck it, you know?
# Just let the cards fall
as they may
# I'm halfway home,
but it's still a long road
to be traveled
# And I know at
any given moment,
things can go sour
# From sweet to
the streets on fire
# Problems unravel
# Still holdin' my breath,
boots laced for battle
# In a place
where they would gladly
# See me scattered
all over they streets
# 'Cause here,
my life don't matter
# And though they smile,
underneath those grins
# They only waitin' on
their next chance
to try to kill me again
# And don't be caught
thinking out here
that your chances are slim
# 'Cause there are those
who have thought it
who will never think again
# 'Cause we're alone
in this country
140,000 friends
# And some 20-odd million
that'd see us all dead
# You could only imagine
our struggle,
the odds we're against
# And though it once
killed me to kill,
I'd gladly do it again
# If only you could
really understand
the state of mind that I'm in
# Only then could you feel me,
only then would I make sense
# If only I hadn't have been
to some of the places
I've been
# If only I wouldn't
have seen what I saw,
maybe I could feel again
# But it's too hard
to separate
what's goin' on within me
# It's just so much easier
to let hate be my remedy
# So for everything
I'm guilty of,
let the Lord sentence me
# If only I wouldn't
have let everything
I been through get to me
# Things could've
been different,
but that is not my reality
# And either way,
it's only a matter of time
before I'm outta here #
Subtitles by LeapinLar