Stop, don't look forward.
Keep walking.
You should address him as 'sir'
when you get in.
Come in.
Have a seat.
You may feel better if you put
your hands under your legs.
Anything you would like to confess?
I didn't do anything.
I don't know anything.
You didn't do anything?
You don't know anything?
You thought the National Security
Agency would put people
in prison at random?
No, I didn't.
Even if it's true that you didn't
do anything,
we could still arrest you on the ground
of your skepticism on our government.
Let me help you with your memory:
Your friend and neighbor, specifically,
flied to the Federal Republic
on September 28th.
We have evidence that it was you
who helped him with fleeing the country.
I know nothing about it.
He didn't tell me his plan.
I thought he was flying for business.
Please detail what you have done
on September 28th then.
- They've written it down.
- I want to hear it again.
I took the kids to the park
for a walk,
and ran into Markechner, my classmate
in high school,
and we went to his place together,
listening to music, talking,
until it was very late.
You can call him and confirm it.
I can give you his number.
From this clip it's easy for
you to find
that he is trying to confront
his own country with his arrogance.
It takes patience to play with him.
The next part is the interrogation,
which lasts about 40 hours.
Let's move on.
I want to sleep.
Let me sleep, please.
Sleep? You need to trade for it
with something.
Please explain again what you did
on September 28th.
Please, let me sleep
for just one hour
Please state again what you did
on that day.
Why does the interrogation have
to be so long?
I think this is inhumane.
An innocent man, having been
questioned so long for something
he didn't do,
he should either be in a rage
or suicidal,
while a guilty person often refuse
to talk, or start to cry,
because he knows exactly why
he is sitting there.
The best way to tell whether
someone is guilty, is to question
him until he admits everything.
We met Markechner in the park,
then we went to his place together,
listened to the music and
stayed up late.
I have his telephone number,
you can give him a call and he'll
tell you what I said was true.
Is there anything interesting
to you in his answer?
It's the same as what he said
at the first time.
He hardly changed a word.
Because what really happened
would not change no matter how
you describe it.
But there is also the possibility
that he was lying.
Because he might have practiced it
in his mind for a thousand times.
But under coercion, he won't hold for long.
There are other techniques
for hard rocks like him.
If you can tell us the name
of the plane, you can go home to your
wife tonight,
if not, it's the prison that's
waiting for you.
Is that what you want?
What's the name of the plane?
Who owns it?
- Resker.
- Say it again, louder.
Risker.
It's Bernag Resker's plane.
Bernag Resker.
Silence!
Listen.
Who knows what this sound is?
This is for the trained dogs,
a piece of cloth with the criminal's
odor on it.
It comes from every interrogation,
and will be kept in a bottle forever.
Wiretapping is a common technique
used in almost every socialist country
Please never forget it.
Have a nice day.
Good! It was really good.
Bro,
we haven't hanged out for what,
20 years?
And now you are a professor.
Good for you. And I'm doing good
too, of course.
What do you need?
You think I want something from you?
- I'm inviting you to a play.
- A play?
I heard that the minister of arts
will come too.
To show the administration's
attitude to the artists, I think.
It starts at 7 tonight.
We'll talk about it.
The Lives of Others
Minister Bruno Hempf is in the middle
of the third row.
He used to be a nobody in the
Ministry of Arts.
And he is not particularly interested
in attending all these events.
Georg Dreyman, he is a poet.
He is as arrogant as
some of my students.
Not only arrogant, but also one
of the right-wing.
But he will lose his job soon.
We suspect that a few writers have
been close to the Western Germany,
and he is one of them.
The German Democratic Republic
is the best country in the world.
It starts.
What's wrong, my dear child?
Marta, what happened? Tell me!
He left me, Otto.
Otto? How can you say that your
husband is dead?
No, sisters, please trust me.
He's dead already.
There is deep fear in his paintings.
I can see it,
that terrifying love.
Why does this love feel so thorny?
Elena, let's go.
How do you think?
Are you interested?
I'll watch him.
Watch him? This is totally
different from teaching.
- We can use the best wiretappers.
- You have to risk your career.
If you lose, you are shark meat.
I'll be downstairs for a second.
We have a lot to do at this moment,
including a series of bans
on the culture.
Which party do you belong to?
I think it doesn't matter,
Mr. minister.
What matters is one's patriotism.
How much do you know about this man?
Goerg Dreyman
Maybe...
Maybe what?
Maybe this job is not as noble
as it seems.
It's such a pity that you are not
a secret agent.
I hope you could make a perfect
plan for this one. We can talk
about it later.
They have plenty of expectations
on you.
But this artist, he hides well.
It'll be tricky.
Next Thursday all those felons
will attend a party at Dreyman's,
for instance, reactionist writer Houser
and a few others. You should
plan everything carefully beforehand,
using all your old tricks,
like wiretapping.
Just keep an eye on his apartment,
don't try to follow him,
and don't report before you
have gathered all the evidence.
Once caught by us, he's dead.
Good night, Mr. minister.
What is he staring at us?
What does he want?
Is he one of your fans?
Excuse me.
Sorry for the interruption,
but I would like to say that it
was a fantastic night for the
art society.
There is a famous quote:
"A poet is an engineer in the Eden."
And Goerg Dreyman is one of our best
engineers in Democratic Republic.
- What does he want?
- Be quiet and listen, Houser.
I can't help giving him my compliment
again: Dreyman is a shining star among
the artists in Democratic Republic.
Next I wish Mrs. Dreyman's beauty
and acting skills will both grow.
- Now I see what all this is about.
- Stay with me, please.
Please continue with the music.
May I?
- I love your plays.
- Thank you very much.
And I'm very interested in you.
Yes, I mean it.
Engineer in the Eden?
Do you really understand what it means?
Of course I do.
I did throw a tons of bans
on cultural activities,
but Houser, I'm still crazy about arts.
The government will protect its artists,
but in the meantime, dear Dreyman,
they have to repay their government.
I'll dance with someone else
if politics is your only topic.
- I'm ready.
- Too late, it's too late.
- I have been following your plays.
- Yes, following is what you do, isn't it?
- Houser!
- That was a long time ago.
Schweiber.
You are busy these days, aren't you?
Your directing is not as good
as in the past.
Let's talk about it some other time.
Please allow me to disagree.
You don't have to like my plays,
but I do love this country.
Could you please leave politics
aside when you watch them?
It's impossible for everyone
to share the same faith,
but if one is truly loyal to his
faith in socialism,
he won't change his mind no matter
what kind of plays he watches.
- This is not something that can be banned.
- Would you like to have a try then?
I can certainly help you get an idea of
what a ban is like if you don't believe it.
Okay, let me put it this way:
If my work is good to the point
of making you nervous,
then it worths it, even if it's banned.
- I think you should consider my advice.
- I don't need it.
Just as you said,
I believe that a good man's love and faith
won't be changed by one play.
Dreyman, you can write whatever
you want, and people's mind won't
be changed so easily.
- Have you decided on what to do?
- People listen to their conscience,
not the nature of their jobs.
- People should never lose hope.
- Of course, you can only become
well off when you have hope.
Sometimes hope can be
the only thing that keeps people alive.
Tomorrow we'll make sure everything
works fine technically.
Most importantly,
there can't be any dead zone for
our device in his house.
It is here?
Good night.
You guys are good, pals.
20 minutes.
Mrs. Meineke, if you tell anyone,
you won't see your family again
for the rest of your life.
Understood?
yes.
Make a note on Mrs. Meineke's records.
Happy Thursday.
How time flies!
It's great to see you again.
- How are you doing?
- Not too bad.
- They don't make noise
like this all the time.
- I know, only on Thursdays.
Yeah.
- I miss the past.
- This doesn't sound like a good
beginning.
- I've had this uneasy feeling since
last night's premiere.
- Good for you. It keeps you energetic.
I can't stand this country any more.
There are no human rights, nor
freedom of speech.
This whole system drives me mad.
But on the other hands, it's
the same system that inspires us
to write,
to write about how people live
in this country, real lives.
And that's real masterpiece,
coming from our conscience.
But I really hate it like this,
Dreyman.
I hope I could be a writer again
in my next life.
What would you do about this play
if you are the director?
There are so many constraints,
you can't dig in as much as you want.
Being alive is so meaningless.
Albert, I think I'm in trouble.
It's the minister in charge of the arts,
minister Hempf.
He threatened to ban my plays.
Would it be terrible?
I don't know what a ban is like.
Really?
It's great.
The guests will come soon.
We can have a drink after they leave.
But there are still a lot of
problems.
Georg, you have to be strong.
I need you,
- no matter what's gonna happen
to you in the future.
- You are my partner for my whole life.
- You are mine too.
- Then we still have 50 years.
Or maybe 40, right?
I hope you didn't forget it. You
promised to tie up a Montblanc
by yourself on your birthday.
I did, but I don't have one.
No more excuse.
- Are you kidding?
- You said you didn't want books
as presents anymore.
But I doubt you can do it yourself.
Of course I can. I know how to
do it from the day I was born.
Don't forget I'm gonna liberate
our people on my own.
Then you have to fasten this one
on your own first.
Those women! I really can't do this.
Mrs. Meineke, can you
come here for a second?
Could you please tie my neck
tie for me?
I'll thank you for the rest of my life.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Done?
Wonderful! It's perfect.
I'll just make it look more natural.
May I ask you to keep secret on this?
It's a secret between us.
Nice! I really thought you wouldn't
be able to do it.
When did you learn that?
I learned everything when I was young.
Our first guest is here.
Our sweet little doorbell is broken again.
Get the door, will you?
Okay, I will.
- This is Our present.
- Following your instruction,
- "No books any more".
- Thank you.
- Can I join you guys?
- Sure. Long time no see.
I'll get some drinks.
What's going on?
Why is he sitting there alone?
He hardly talked to anyone.
He just sat there and read.
This is my present.
- Did you just come here to read?
- It's the Brecht.
These people don't have the thrist
for freedom, do they?
They don't? Then why are you here?
What can we do in this environment?
People get used to everything
around us.
Yes, they can now accept what used
to be unbearable.
Changes are no longer anticipated.
You are my favorite director.
Hang on, we should talk.
Let me explain to you the background
for the characters in this play.
Despair, yes, exactly.
But what should they do?
The National Security can't
gag everybody.
- I don't think they can.
- What the hell are you talking about?
Houser!
What's up?
Schweiber, I'm really sorry.
My friend is a little drunk.
What's with you? Don't you know
that he's working for the National
Security now?
No, Houser.
You don't know him well.
You are being idealistic,
you know that?
Since when have you been escaping
the reality?
They transformed you, all these
people. You are now used to your
life under despotism.
If that's true, you don't even
deserve to be alive.
Don't see me again until you want
to end all this.
- Some people still gave you books.
- Was my request too impolite?
Look at this fork.
Isn't it beautiful?
That's for making salad.
No matter what it's for,
it's beautiful.
Look at this.
I'll write with this pen.
It's from Thomas. I wouldn't
count on his taste for presents.
Some of these are pretty useful.
- This is from Albert.
- Then you are going to love it.
"Sonata from Good Men"
"11:04pm: 'Lazlo' and CMS unpacked
the presents. We speculated that
they had sex afterwards"
You are late!
I'm sorry. Something happened
just before I left home.
So I'm late for four minutes.
I apologize.
They've started doing that?
These artists! What can't they do?
I have to listen to this, how
their sex lives are different
from ordinary people.
See you tomorrow at 11am.
Albert Jerska, an old customer.
He's been banned to the core.
I knew they were close.
come on, let's go lunch.
"Volleyball game
at 7pm tonight."
I suggest we sit there.
No matter where we sit,
socialism must let us eat.
There is one thing I want you
to know, that is
it was the Minister's car that
sent Mrs. Dreyman home last night.
We don't know the details yet,
but he didn't deny it when I
talked to him last time.
Once you find anything between
the minister and Mrs. Dreyman,
just tell me, don't write it down.
What you are listening to not only
determines my future, but yours too,
if we do find something.
Why should we cover up for him?
This is not our style.
Personal affairs can be powerful
weapons for our rival parties.
He and us are all communists,
You don't want disgrace your
own party, do you?
I have a new joke, it's like this:
Erich (General Secretary) went into
his office in the morning.
He opened the window, saw the sun,
and said...what's wrong?
Sorry, I'm just...I...
It's all right, comrade.
It's okay to tell jokes about
leaders of our country.
I can tell a ton of them myself.
Go on, please.
Okay. Erich, our general secretary,
he said to the sun: "Good morning,
my dear sun."
"Good morning, my dear sun."
Is that what he said?
And the sun answered:
"Good morning."
At noon he asked again:"Good day,
my dear sun?"
And the sun said:"Good day."
After work in the evening, Erich
greeted again:
"Good evening, my dear sun."
But the sun didn't answer this time.
So he asked once again:"Good evening,
dear sun, what's up?"
The sun said:"You bastard, don't
'What's up' me, I've been tolerant
for a whole day!"
Your name?
ID number? Department?
Me?
My name is Stiller.
Adolph Stiller. I'm in the
First Informational Section.
You don't have to hear from me
how much damage you just did to
your own career, do you?
- Well...I just...
- You just what?
This kind of jokes will blemish
our party.
And you are working in the National
Security Agency.
Why don't you just go to his office
and tell the minister that joke?
Yeah, it kills me!
Good story, but needs work.
What's the difference between
Erich and a telephone?
Not at all. You just grab and
dial for both.
- Where are you going?
- Home.
- Night.
Get in the car!
You didn't forget about our date
on every Thursday, did you?
Is your poet having his birthday again?
Get in the car! come on!
I believe you understand
what's good for you.
So please think about it and
weigh the options in your mind.
Maybe it is your coldness
that makes me so crazy about you.
Are you out of your mind?
If you want to get home early,
don't fight. I'll send you
home early if you behave yourself.
You'd better see it with your
own eyes.
I'm coming!
Silly woman!
See you next Thursday.
Let's go.
Are you asleep?
Hold me, please.
How are you, sir?
You are five minutes late again.
Good evening. Eleventh Floor,
the door on the right.
Open the door.
- How did you get up here?
- I know your name.
I was able to get in just by
telling your name, can you
believe it?
No, I can't.
How was it? Did you like it?
- Stay for the night.
- I can't.
I have another customer.
I work on reservations.
It's 1:30 already, what kind of
customer is that at this time?
None of your business.
You can reserve for an hour longer
next time.
See ya.
Georg, have you heard about Houser?
No, what's about him?
National Security took
his passport, he can't go
abroad to attend the workshop.
It's because he's too proud, you know?
The Security finally had to do something.
A man who doesn't know how to
protect himself. He deserves it.
A writer should be more conscious
about the reality.
"'Lazlo' supported the forbidance
on Houser's travel abroad."
Have you seen my anthology?
The one I just finished writing.
Isn't it on your desk?
This is weird. I can't find it.
* Brecht *
"Everyday in September the early fall
was blue;
"Those young upright trees reaching
for the sky, like love they flourished
and grew;
"Above us floated the fair clear sky;
"which a cotton-white cloud
was walking through;
"And with faith in your heart
it shall never leave you."
- Yes?
- Georg? This is Vagner.
What's up?
Have you heard?
Jerska killed himself.
Georg?
I'm sad too.
I've been thinking about the last
conversation between Jerska and me.
I should listen to him and
make some change.
If he could hear this song I'm playing,
if he really can,
he would know what I'm gonna do.
Do you really Work for the National
Security Agency?
Do you know what National Security
Agency is for?
Yes. They are bad guys, they took
my dad.
Did they?
What's the name of your...?
My what?
Your ball.
What's the name of your ball?
You are strange.
Why would people name their balls?
Minister, this is my present
for you,
The best wiretappers,
and the top operators.
- We can hear every sound in every corner.
- You must find what we need from Dreyman.
Jerska killed himself, and these
artists will do something.
It was good to see you.
You should work on this, we're gonna
start watching Houser and others.
The Minister really wants to
go for it now.
It's giving me headaches.
- What's new with him and Mrs. Dreyman?
- If I didn't hear it wrong, they are
going out tomorrow night.
Good, good.
But don't spend too much time on
this love story.
We have our own business to mind.
Don't forget that.
I've been queasy tonight.
I don't want to stay home by myself,
and I can't write anything.
After Jerska's death,
I don't feel like writing anymore.
And I start to fear that you
would leave me.
Don't be like a child.
- I have to go out tonight anyway.
- Where?
An old schoolmate is coming,
- And we are gonna...
- You are not lying to me, are you?
- Is that true?
- What do you mean?
I know everything.
I know where you are going.
And I beg you not to.
You don't have to do this.
You don't have to.
I know you are doing this for me,
and for acting, which you can
never give up.
Trust me,
Christa Maria,
You are a great artist,
you always are. I know it.
And your audience know it too.
There is no need for you to
please anyone.
Don't go.
Don't go to him.
No, I don't need to do this.
I did everything in vain.
But what about you?
Don't you need it?
Do you want to give up your freedom?
You can live in your writing,
you can still write whatever in
your mind. Then why didn't you?
Because you know they will destroy you.
People can't just live on faith.
What can we do?
What should we do?
Do you want to be the next Jerska?
I don't.
So I have to go now.
You're making a point.
I can't make you change your mind.
But I beg you,
don't go.
Cherish yourself.
I'm here, sir.
What were you listening to?
You were so concentrated.
Okay, it's my turn.
I can't take the blame to make
you work overtime.
Where are you going?
To see one of my old schoolmates.
I'll write down the details.
You shall see them tomorrow morning.
Don't worry.
Good night.
There are plenty of seats inside.
Just myself.
Give me a cup of vodka.
Okay.
Can you play "The Smile" instead?
Wine, please.
How do you do, madam?
Please don't bother me.
Leave me alone.
Mrs. Sieland.
Do we know each other?
You don't know me,
but I know you well.
People love you,
because you are real.
- Actresses can't be real.
- But you are.
I've seen you on stage,
and you were just yourself,
like who you are now.
You think you know who I am?
I'm one of your audience.
- I have to go.
- Where are you going?
I'm going to see an old schoolmate
of mine.
Really? You become a different
person when you're lying.
- Do I?
- Yes.
Am I still the Christa Maria you know?
Would you leave someone who is even
more important than your own life?
Would you give away your body for art?
Give away your body for art?
That's not a good deal.
You are the greatest actress
I've ever seen.
Don't you think so?
You are a very good man.
"They brawled about whether Mrs. Dreyman
should go and see her schoolmate,
"and she went at last.
'Lazlo' stayed at home in bitterness.
"About 20 minutes later,
Mrs. Dreyman came back,
"suprisingly,
not only for 'Lazlo', but for me too.
"He was very happy.
And then the two of them made love.
"She told him she would never leave
him again. He said:"Now I have my
inspirations back."
"It is guessed that we will have
a new play soon.
"Due to all that happened last week,
he's been behind on his script.
"Why did she change so suddenly?
"I can tell that she's even more
in love with 'Lazlo' now.
"The flame of love lights up again."
Sir, I...
They were asleep, so I also...
Nice report.
You think so?
I've never been so sad in my life.
Me neither.
Never was a regime similar to socialism
in the history.
The Central keeps an eye on everything
about everybody's life.
On average, a man buys 2.3 pairs
of shoes each year,
reads 3.2 books.
And in each year there are 6,743 students
graduating with straight As.
But there is one statistics that
goes unpublished,
which might have been calculated
into the natural deaths.
If you call the National Security
Agency and ask them,
How many people kill themselves
for being suspected as related to
the Western Germany,
they won't tell you a word,
and they'll write down your name
carefully.
This is all for the country's safety.
All those dead people, are for the
country's safety and well being.
German Democratic Republic
has stopped counting the number
of suicides since 1977.
Suicides as we know,
they were already for the best.
Because they couldn't stand their lives
like that, without bleeding,
without passion.
Death was all they could choose.
Death was their only hope.
Since 9 years ago when we stopped to count
suicides, only one country in Europe has
higher death counts than Eastern Germany:
Hungary.
And then we all head for
the same destination: socialism.
Among all these people the most
distinguished was Jerska,
a great director.
What I'm writing today is the
story about him.
- I've laid down the framework for my script.
- We should believe in the statistics from
National Security.
My apartment is not sound-proof.
Let's play some music for them.
How about in my place?
"3pm, Chrenmal Park"
It's okay now.
- Look, there's a stalker.
- Invite him over.
what did you write?
Read this.
You want to publish this?
That would be great.
Can you help me?
Did Christa know about it?
no
alright, I will help you
But don't tell her anything
what?
Georg, it is for her own safety
I will contact the editor of "The Mirror"
If anyone else knows it
we will be in big trouble
Do you know Hessenstein?
I know this name, but that's it
You must meet him.
You can publish this, but only anonymously
It is to protect you and Christa.
Unless you escape to Western Germany
It is so cold out here
Let's go to my place
There is no secret agent
- no wiretapping, no surveillance
- How do you know?
My place is "clean"
but to make sure...
I have a suggestion to see if your place is under surveillance or not
I can ask my uncle Frank to help.
He is coming from Western Germany this Saturday to visit me
He has a brand new golden Mecedes
My script sounds good, right?
yes, I totally agree
it is pretty nice from all aspects
I don't understand, script like this
can't be published here?
God completely forgets us
We can submit it to some magazine in western Germany
Definitely not so many restrictions there
Where are you going to stay, uncle?
Andrea Street
He told me to meet you guys
We can talk about the script in more details
Maybe we will hear some good news from him
you know, Paul has being watched by the National Security
that agent must be watching him
ok, I have to go
Lads, come on
nothing can stop us, right?
do you think it's gonna work?
hello, this is public telephone
are you looking for someone?
hello?
strange
you are playing with me
- Georg speaking
- we overreacted
Nobody followed you?
no, seems the situation isn't that bad
- ok, I am going back to Western Germany
- I really appreciate for everything you did
- It's nothing.
- I'm glad you are not under surveillance
- alright, thanks again
- ok, see you later
- bye
if someone asks about what we are doing
what should we say?
we say...just like what we said just now
we are working on a play
to celebrate the 40th anniversary of DDR?
yes
that's what we planed
I can't believe the National Security is so lame
I thought they were at least something!
you will see!
"7:32pm: Nothing else to report."
Sir, listen to this
it's reasonable if the number of
people committing suicide is
less than 37 in a certain period.
but so far the known number is 77
you must explain it, in details,
more specifically
I want to be more literarily
- not just as a reporter to reveal something
- The article itself is great
but I think with specific numbers
it is easlier to be accepted by the public
then what do you suggest?
- Something is going on
- yes, you are right
what do you know?
They are writing a new play
for the 40th anniversary of DDR
It does not sound like that to me
then what do you think?
I don't know, but definitely not a script
my comrade, you think too much
you are not an intellectual
- me? no, I am not
- then stop your nonsense
what I need from you is technical support
so stop asking me stupid questions!
Do not try to do what I'm supposed to do!
I am sorry, I should get going
have a nice day,
and good luck with your work
then I have to rewrite it
I will give you time for that
and also provide you with necessary help
two weeks, is that enough?
so we can publish it before
the 40th anniversary
keep the title
Christa is back?
Georg?
Christa, this is Mr.Hessenstein
- I'm Christa-Maria
- such an honor to meet you at last
what are you doing?
we are working on a script for the 40th anniversary of DDR
can you make it in time?
That's why we need to discuss
- Am I the leading actress?
- That is exactly what I am going to ask
Christa, you want to play Lenin
or his beloved mother?
you can choose either one.
I think I'd better leave you guys alone
I am going to take a nap
you should be careful
the less people know, the better.
the National Security is desperate
I also brought you some presents
as cute as the cake
I have a typewriter
the National Security will
search everything here
it's not for fun
it's also for Paul's safety
unfortunately only red ink is available for this type of pocket-sized typewriter
you can switch to black after you finish the red.
who knows if that's gotta happen
you have to hide it whenever necessary
- ok, I promise to keep it safe
- it is a serious matter
I don't want you all get into trouble because of this typewriter
only the three of us know about this typewriter
are you sure your appartment is safe?
yes
even if every street in DDR is full of secret agents, this house is still safe
good, then let's wait for the hugh impact from this article
This bottle of wine is real!
Cheers! For revealing the truth
of DDR to every German!
- cheers!
- This is a historical moment
cheers
I need to see him.
I am Wiesler
sorry, if you don't have an appointment
I'm afraid...
I said...
if they still have problems
then temporarily close the church
we can arrest the priest
do it now, don't let me teach you
so, any news?
look at this book
"Studies on Ideology and Political Ideas"
isn't that academic?
Look at this.
National Security Information Section
Professor Wiesler
Wonderful! Allow me to read one paragraph on page 230
What a masterpiece
for instance, people under surveillance can be divided into 5 categories
for example, Dreyman
the guy that you are watching
is in the 4th category, historical type
very difficult to deal with
I tell you this because you are my friend
for people in this category, you can't play with them step by step
you have to get rid of him, or find some fatal clues before he notices that he is under surveillance
but be careful
don't let him notice
don't have any contact with him
don't be emotional,
don't reveal any personal information, even in the report
don't leave him any trace that he might write into his book in the future
you will be free in 10 months
completely free
I'd like to see that!
you know what's my experience?
most of the 4th category
people I know are gone
no matter what kinds of artists they are
they can feel the presure in this way
you know what
it is a gift for them!
what are you doing here?
anything new on Dreyman?
I think it's time...
it's time for what?
I mean, I can deal with it myself
I want to do wiretapping alone
- I don't trust the other guy
- you don't trust him
are you sure you can manage yourself?
- you don't want anyone else to know it?
- Does Lazlo belong to the 4th category?
the more people know
the more dangerous
then I will ask Url to stop
I prefer to work alone
why?
I think we're getting there
I can handle it by myself
I can follow Lazlo
he might also work outside
ok, I grant your request
but you must accomplish this mission
right now, I am busy with this church thing
write a report for me on this
make change on the reasons accordingly
wait
one more thing
we are not at school, what we do is not for a high score
it is for the people
agents watch everything on the street,
just like mad dogs
on average, a man buys 2.3 pairs of shoes each year
reads 3.2 books
and there are 6,743 students
graduating with straight As
"5:00pm: 'Lazlo' read Houser and Wallner
another act of the anniversary play."
"Dental Clinic"
- we are not working on a script
- you don't have to explain
but I must tell you
I don't want to hear
it might upset your friends if you tell me
I just want to stay with you
no matter what you do
the relationship between Eastern and Western Germany becomes tense, the latest "The Mirror" published an article
written by an anonymous writer from Eastern Germany
this article investigates the suicide status in DDR
the most striking part is it reveals
the suicide of the famous director Jerska
after being banned for 5 years
Jerska committed suicide
on March 5th this year
since 1977, DDR government has
never released the number of suicides
so far, Hungary is the only country with a higher number of suicide cases
General secretary, please let me explain
yes, we have been watching him
we have already contacted our agent at "The Mirror"
but we could not find the original manuscript
we can speculate from the typewriter
general secretary, I will let you know immediately when I find something.
Andria, get me a technician
if we want to speculate through the typweriter
with the level of techniques we have, it's impossible to make it.
very likely, this typewirter is made abroad
- we don't have this kind of typewriter?
- no, we don't
what about the people who has close contact with the western? like director Hauser
in principle, only reporters know this kind of machine
- but for most reporters...
- that's enough, what else?
this typewriter has a special code
- Georg Dreyman?
- it is possible, but normally he would hand-write it first
then type it, that is his general writing order
how big is this typewriter?
it's the smallest in the world
19cm by 19cm
the size of a book?
ok, you can go now
goodbye, comrade
"The Mirror--DDR's Secret Suicide Statistics"
Andria, get me through Hauptmann
"4:00pm: The group is tired from
lots of writing."
- Please
- Hauptmann, have you read the article about suicide?
the one on The Mirror?
yes, I read it
how did you know?
Hauser made three calls to discuss it
it is extremely important.
your career and mine depend on it
you know what is behind this?
what do you think?
I think Dreyman didn't write it
it is not possible
last week, our agent followed Hessenstein
the editor of The Mirror
they lost him near Dreyman's appartment
the 6th group are a bunch of idiots
does he know Dreyman?
did they contact before?
- did I write that in my report?
- no, you didn't
then who wrote that article?
our future is fucked
I will call you later
shit
come on in
brief me your surveillance
- how did The Mirror get it?
- but we have been watching him
what about my relationship with that woman?
- you know that too?
- yes
can your men keep it?
don't worry, it is all taken care of
from now on, we could only trust ourselves
arrest her and question her,
Christa-Maria Sieland.
she must have known something
no matter what you get, please release her afterwards
anyway, I want to see her on stage
you may go.
close the door!
Mrs.Sieland? Please come with us
let's go!
come on!
comrade Sieland, you are quite famous
such a pity
your performance is excellent
and you are quite tall!
sit down
do you know why you are here?
tell me, please
what can I do for you?
- for the national security?
- too late
I know almost all the artists
I can provide you with a lot of useful information
I turly believe you can
but I am not interested
there must be something else that I can help
otherwise why would you keep me here?
but you've already...
how should I put this?
you married a stupid man
therefore you lost a lot of freedom that you deserved
what can you suggest?
nothing
there is one thing that could help you
you know a lot of writers and artists
do you know the article that published last week in The Mirror?
the article about writers' suicide?
hello, please open the door!
open the door!
let Maltz open the door by force
don't give him any time
Maltz
it's unnecessary to do it by force
- what do you want?
- The National Security needs to search the house
an important mission
help yourself!
Maltz, Mutter, bed room and corridor
Galcy, Bale, follow me to the bath room and balcony
Thomas, you guys to the living room and the study
let's go
what did you burn?
some useless manuscript
is it an academic book published in Western Germany?
the author gave it to me as a birthday present
- have you started?
- yes, as planned
there is nothing, except some Western Germany newspapers and books
- we did not find the target
- search every corner
we did.
do you want us to continue?
- Should we continue on searching?
- let your men leave
this is our address
if you have anything to confess, please come to us
I'd better tidy this up first
yes, please
Wiesler, come to my office tomorrow morning at nine.
Good, I think Christa-Maria sold you out
she sold you out, then hid herself somewhere
she didn't know anything
what if she knew?
she was not there when we discussed last time
she won't tell even if she knew
she won't
if you are right
if she comes back herself
I will take care of it
I have an appointment with Colonel Grubitz
agent XX/7
come in
have a seat
And?
what's going on?
you ask me?
you suspect Dreyman?
he is good at plays
do you have any proof?
follow me
I guess she doesn't know anything
but we can dig up some valuable information eventually
this is your last chance
bring the suspect
do you still remember which side you are on?
- yes
- then I will give you one last chance
Sir, do you want me present?
this is classified, get out
- are you executive officer?
- write that down!
then execute me
only 10 hours left
no, to be accurate, 9.5 hours
do you want them to change the leading actress because of some accident?
this will be the last time for the audience to hear your name
is that what you want?
as long as you cooperate
there was no article
no typewriter, I made them up
I hope they weren't
if someone investigates it
you will spend at least 2 years in prison for perjuring.
Dreyman will be arrested anyway
even without your testimony
we've already gethered enough evidence to convict him
you'd better think for yourself
you have no idea how many people have gone j-cat in this place
- you believe in public opinion?
only he would say something like this
think about it,
what has this country done for you?
your entire life is granted by this country
it's time to return the favour
you will get what you deserve
tell me, where is the typewriter?
Dreyman wouldn't be arrested for this
I'll let you go immediately
we will protect you
if there is enough time, you can even go home first
and appear on stage tonight as scheduled
stage, lights
and the audience who love you
tell me, where did he hide it?
Spit it out
it is in our appartment
in the joint between bedroom and corridor
there is one board that could be taken off
do you mean here? Please mark it
you can get your stuff back
you must be very tired
this is a reward for serving your country
Mr. Habuna
have you seen Hauptmann?
he left after the interrogation
He did?
Good. That was quick.
you still want to go home?
what if she is there?
if she comes back, what is gonna happen?
have you ever thought about what you are going to do?
no, I don't think she will betray me
- Christa?
- don't, I haven't had showers for 2 days
I must take a shower
- why did you leave by yourself?
- should I wait for your to pick me up?
- they are both at home?
- yes
this is today's wiretapping report
hope it is the last day for this mission
why didn't you call me?
- what?
- why didn't you call me?
we went to the countryside
can you pass me the soap?
National Security agents were here, they searched the entire place
who were here?
National Security, open the door!
stay here
comrade Dreyman, we are DDR National Security agents
you must've spent a lot of time tiding up last night
start with the study
search every book, page by page
what's this?
this board looks so unstable
Would there be any secret
hidden underneath?
excuse me, I have to open it by force
this bitch is such a liar!
I won't forget what you did to me
stop talking, you will be fine
I moved the typewriter to somewhere else
forgive me, forgive me
pull back, it's over.
Mr.Dreyman, the search is over.
we found nothing
I am sorry
let's go
you know, this mission has failed
your wiretapping career is over
I will transfer you to letter surveillance section
all you have to do is open all the envelopes
and wait for them to be inspected
this will be your job for the next 20 years
20 years!
a fucking long time
4 Years and 7 Months Later
the Wall fell!
It's a festival here.
young people is flooding across the Wall
they are hailing and hugging each other.
it is unbelievable
we are now reporting from Berlin.
Nov. 9th, 1989, a day that will be
marked in the history
this is a live report from our reporters
2 Years Later
my dear child, what happened?
my lover died
lover? I saw him this morning
he was full of energy
no, sisters, believe me
he is dead, I know when he died
the sun just arose and was shining on him
there was deep fear on his face
I saw that
that terrifying love
why does this love feel so thorny?
Elena, let's go home
I want to change everything
recalled something, right?
I came out for the same reason
how are you?
now you can write whatever you want
isn't it the country you've been dreamed of?
but Dreyman, is this federal Germany really what you artists wanted?
is there anything left to write?
people don't have faith any more, nor love
this is a federal republic with real freedom.
- does it make any sense?
- I have always wanted to ask you a question
as you wish, Dreyman has the right to know everything
why wasn't I banned?
Why wasn't I watched?
of course you were watched,
completely watched
you were under full surveillance
was I wiretapped also?
absolutely, every drop of your life
impossible
use your imagination,
even your sexual life
everything
it was far beyond what you could
imagine, you little artist.
fortunately, DDR doesn't exist anymore
please wait a few minutes
there are a lot of files, we need some time to organize
these are in the order of time
from the top
take your time, they are all here
surveillance report on Georg Dreyman
if you have any questions or further interest, please contact the Information Section at National Security Agency.
"Lazlo" received Frankfort Public Daily from Western Germany
suggested Hauser and Wallner to stay low
in case to be watched by National Security
Lazlo and CMS unpacked the presents
we speculated they had sex afterwards.
Paul Hauser's uncle came to visit them from Western Berlin
They discussed together.
"Lazlo" and Hauser
were going to write a script for the 40th anniversary of DDR
they had been discussing the script
and the implication that
each character should convey
they thought that the most important element was the storyline
but the characters' personality could attract more audience
therefore became the key to the play's success.
no other reactionary opinions
HGW XX/7?
I, Christa-Maria Sieland
voluntarily cooperate with the National Security Agency
I promise to tell the truth,
nothing but the truth
all I said was for the safety of our country.
Georg Dreyman is a famous right-wing dramatist
he is very close to director Paul Hauser
Christa-Maria, March 10th, 1985
was arrested for overdose
and released on March 11th, around 3pm
while agents were searching Dreyman's place
she ran out of the apartment, died in a car accident
what's this all about?
who hid it?
for lack of evidence
The National Security had to close this case and call off all the surveillance on Dreyman
the entire mission was carried out by agent HGW XX/7
this mission was carried out on behalf
of the National Security and had
nothing to do with the agent himself
but I suggest the agent should not participate in the similar tasks
10:55, the surveillance devices were removed from Dreyman's
15:10, Christa was released from detention
then agents from the National Security searched Dreyman's place
15:15, the wiretapping was ended.
who is XX/7?
stop!
go back to Fayer street
2 Years Later
"Georg Dreyman:
The Sonata from Good Men"
"Acknowledgement for Mr. HGW XX/7"
Hi
29.8 euros
Is it a present?
no, it is for myself
subtitles by chri$'