These violent delight
were abrupt endings
And in their triumph
as wires and dust less and that ..
who, when they kiss ...
to burn
Translation and adaptation: ENGEL
Enjoy watching!!
New Moon (Bagong BUWAN)
Grandma?
Edward, no! ... You will see!
Well.
Grandma, I want you to meet him ...
In many years, Bella.
In many years.
Father, we understand
that without gifts.
Mine is not even packed.
So do not count.
In fact, it's really cool.
Thanks, Dad.
Comes with it,
of the mother.
We coordinated ...
In fact, she coordinated Me Me.
As you put pictures in it,
to remember your graduation year.
Class 12-A.
How did you grow so fast?
I have grown so much.
I do not know what to say.
Is that somehow the white hair?
No. No way.
Happy Birthday.
Very funny.
Another Tripper  disappeared.
Total is 3 and presumed dead,
while police searches
killer animal
Hi, Bella. Bella ...
- Hi.
Bella, this is the big day.
Teaching Essay
about "Romeo and Juliet"?
Yes.
"Where are you, Bella?
I want to take a picture.
Mom wants
to have an album full of souvenirs.
I take photos, not how the picture.
Yes, today you do.
I will change the nose in Photoshop
If it seems too much, right?
No where, I appear in pictures.
Nobody will look at you.
Good. It's Cullen.
Speak later.
happy Birthday!!.
I do not get remembered.
Your day of birth is certainly
a cause for celebration.
- And if not older.
- you are aging?
At 18 years is a little early
Report worry for your age.
Are one year older than you.
I did not.
Bella, I am 109 years
Can not be
to go out with a old man.
Sick ...
I should be disgusted.
We have to go in time.
Well.
Wait a second.
Someone looking for you.
Bella!
- Jacob, what ...
- I leave to speak.
How long bicep!
To know that steroids are really bad for you!
Go to end to form, Bella.
You would not jump so much in the eye
If we see more often ..
We should exchange schools
You could come to stay
with faces pale.
I'm alright.
I prefer exclusivity
School of rezervaþie.
Here let anyone through in this place.
I see.
Why are you here?
I came to buy a piece
for VW's Rabbit.
you Need to take a ride next time
It's faster?
umm.. Its decent. ..
hey..
happy birthday!
Your father told her dad. So ...
Yeah, sure.
I saw him yesterday and I thought of you.
Chase away bad dreams and you.
E. .. perfect.
Thank you.
No problem.
- I am glad I saw.
- Yes, later.
Why Jacob Black Do you can do
a gift and I do not?
Because I have not
Why would you give to you.
Bella, you give me everything
only exists in the world.
I see. Thank you.
That's all I want.
Bella!
Happy Birthday!
Ssshhh..
Alice, I said
I do not want gifts?
I have seen opening it
and guess what? He loved it!
You will wear to party tonight
at home.
Common Please? It will be fun.
ok... All right.
Super! See you at 7:00!
Wait, Jasper ...
Controls are not yet well.
I'm sorry, Bella.
Happy! Let ...
You can not trust vampires.
Trust me.
My love! My wife
your death has drank
dulceaþa rãsuflãrii ...
Poor Romeo ...
And killed the great love
of pure stupidity.
Yes.
Although one thing to envy.
Juliet is perfect ... if you like
a beauty so blatantly.
No girl - suicide.
It's almost impossible for ... some.
But for people ... Little poison,
stuck a dagger in the heart.
Have many options.
Why you say so what?
I once went through my head.
I did not know if I find the time.
I must have ... plan.
What was the plan?
He and be taken to Italy,
he and provoked the Volturi ...
Who?
On the Volturi.
Want to repeþi last reply
as you were to look closely, Mr Cullen?
Yes, sir.
Here  my bed and I tarnished the latter
And the body tired of life
I pull the yoke stars  fatal
Eye, May look a the last time
A, arms, the latter-mbrãþi and has
And, mouth, wear my heart,
seals and with a kiss you ...
Eternal death  fair prey.
( "Romeo and Juliet, Shakespeare,
trans. L. Leviþchi)
Look at the screen, people.
Volturi family is very old
and very strong.
I like some kings of my world.
That is ... Carlisle?
Yes. He was survived by her
few decades.
He described as very rafinaþi.
They have no respect
for human life, of course.
But even compliance arts, sciences ...
and laws.
Above all laws.
Vampires have laws?
Not many.
Only one is ... imperative.
What?
Secrecy to our existence.
Im not exit the track
and not kill in public
... if you do not want to be killed and I.
Not even ... You are not talking about it.
I can not conceive
to your hurt someone.
Bella, the only one who can hurt me
are you.
What else can I fear?
Not true.
Victory will come after me
someday.
But Alice will predict the decisions.
And I'll be ready.
I can defend myself.
If I turned ...
No. You already protect me ...
You're my only reason ...
to stay alive.
If I can call it that.
But the mission is to protect you
by anyone,
In addition to my sister.
Time! Time! Time!
I apologize.
I have tried to mollify Alice.
As if you have such.
In many years, Bella.
Thank you.
I found your bag.
Is it possible?
You're with a girl more than you.
Sexy!
What?
It's a necklace. Alice chose him.
Thank you.
To see how loved you!
Look, this is from Emmett.
Already we have installed in your truck.
Finally, a decent sound system
the piece that ...
I do not speak ill truck.
Open the one
from Esme and Carlisle.
Something to brighten your day.
I saw a little pale
lately.
I cut the paper.
Jaz ...
Never mind.
It's just a drop of ... blood.
Get him on Jasper from here.
Sorry ... I can ...
Will have to kick
in my office.
See what is Jasper.
I think it's very angry with himself and
and I think not listen
by anyone except you now.
Edward.
I know how to spoil a party.
Not your fault. Jasper has not renounced
the blood of man as long as we do.
It seems that only you are not affected.
I have years and years of practice behind.
Have you ever ...
to prefer the easier method?
No.
I knew who I want to be.
I wanted to help people,
it makes me happy.
Even be cursed.
Cursed?
That is the ... Hell?
Carlisle, can not be cursed.
It's like, is impossible.
Thank you, Bella.
Always have been ...
benevolent with us.
So that's the reason?
Is that not like to make?
If that were reversed,
if you have the same beliefs
as Edward
you could deprive the soul?
I can not protect.
Not much.
At one point,
something separated us.
It will be an accident, illness ...
or bãtrâneþea ...
as long as I am human.
And the only solution
is to transform me.
This is not a solution.
But a tragedy.
You will not like me
when you look like a bunicuþã.
Bella does not understand how I feel about you?
Not?
Carlisle told me what you think
your soul, but I do not think ...
So no worry to me.
Should enter the house.
Still is my birthday.
Can I ask your something?
Kiss me.
I love you.
And I.
Hi.
Come with me.
Had to leave Forks.
Why?
Carlisle should have
ten years longer than it looks.
People started noticing.
Welcome ... I ...
We need to think of an explanation
for Charlie ...
When you say "we" ...
I refer to my
and the family.
Edward, what happened
with Jasper was nothing.
You're right.
It was nothing.
Nothing more than work
to which I always expected.
Nothing in addition what could happen.
Your place is not in my world.
My place is with you.
No. Not the and a.
Come with you ...
Bella ... I do not want to come!
Do not you want me?
No.
This change things ...
well.
But, if not Do you ask too much,
I can even promise you?
Do not do any foolish act.
For Charlie's sake.
Do you And I promise you one thing,
instead.
Now I see the last time.
I will return.
And you Do you will be able to continue life
without any interference from me.
Do you swear like I will be
not and never existed.
If you do it for my soul, take it!
Do not want if you do not have you.
This is not about your soul.
You are not good for me.
Not good enough
for you.
I regret only that I left
too long and things of a.
Please ...
not ...
Goodbye.
Edward!
Edward?
I will call back to Cullen family.
They left the city, Charlie.
Good riddance.
Where did they go?
We will find, Charlie.
Thanks, Harry.
Charlie!
Good.
I have it.
Thanks, Sam.
OCTOBER
NOVEMBER
Dear Alice ... have disappeared.
As for the rest.
With whom I could speak now?
I feel ... lost.
DECEMBER
When you left ...
When he left ...
you took everything with you.
anywhere and look,
see only the absence of ...
's like in my chest
has left a huge hole ...
But somehow I'm glad.
pain is one thing
which reminds me that it was real ...
that all have been really.
E-MAIL received the
Well. Ready.
What?
You go in Jacksonville
that you are living with your mother.
Do not leave the Forks.
Bells, not return.
I know.
This is not normal behavior.
And, frankly, scares us
me and your mother.
Honey, I ...
I do not want to go, but ...
Go to Jacksonville.
Do your some new friends.
I like my old friends.
But you never see them.
Yes.
In fact, me and Jessica go tomorrow
shopping.
You hate are to go shopping.
We have to go out with girls.
Well. Exit with the girls.
Shopping.
I like.
Go to ... buy things.
Hi, Jessica. I'm Bella ...
Yes, Bella Swan.
I do not know what you like to see
As zombies kill innocent people
and not to any type pupãm with nice ...
It's disgusting.
Do not understand why there are so many
zombie movies.
E parallelism for leprosy?
My cousin had leprosy
and not fun.
It's a kind of metaphor
and excessive consumption or something?
Stop umflaþi both birds
although with your teptãciunea.
Some girls like to shop.
Not everyone, apparently.
I was surprised and that you called.
Do you understand depression.
I am very worried.
I wonder if you have problems.
And I have been through enough.
PETE CHIORU '
Like when Mike was decided
to be "just friends"?
It was very hard and i. ..
move, Bella.
is dangerous.
Come on.
I think ... ã them know the guys knew.
Seem very "nice".
Can we go?
I want to see something.
Move to, is a chef to come.
Come back.
I'm sorry.
I got confused ...
Never mind. I will be
whoever you want, doll.
What?
You promised that you will not be imprudent.
You promised to be like
not have ever existed.
You lied.
You said something, love?
You know what? No matter.
Stops. Stops! Stops!
What the hell's the big idea?
I just ... curious.
I saw something.
You're crazy. Or suicide door.
That guy could be a psychopath.
He was to arrive in the interrogation room
as in the television series.
What sensation hard!
What now are dependent of adrenaline?
Go to do jumping rope ...
Get on the engine
any missed some.
Madness!
Alice, I've seen.
Maybe I lost our minds.
I do not care.
If the danger is  need to see,
then we find him alone.
Where the hell have you been?
I brought you something.
This is crazy.
Old beasts. There was no need.
I have saved from landfill.
It cost more than I do
to fix them ...
if we somehow a friend
driver ....
I was engineer friend?
Since you like motorcycles to you?
For now.
Understand perfectly if you think it's
stupid and a reckless.
Clearly is nuts
and a reckless.
When you begin?
Now!
- Please!
- Okay.
Wait!
I really ... heavy.
Jake, you're strong!
And you only have 16 years. Do not know.
Age is just a number.
How many years have you? 40?
Sometimes I feel so.
That song is move to.
Do not you like?
Not much I still love music.
- In a way ...
- Okay.
No more music.
If we work at it every day,
and hope to do,
we should do and some themes.
Billy I do not want to believe
I have a bad influence on you.
Influence you help me?
Please.
Are greater than you.
So I'm the one that affect
and you are not influenced.
Knowledge I do
to be greater than you.
Your lack of understanding
any.
I convinced you we do in secret
I and two inãrii on two wheels of death.
Do not think it looks
that are rather small and a little naive?
Well. So how do we?
I have 35 years ...
and you no 32.
Come ...
Jake, are you there?
Nothing, my friends.
Hey, Jake ...
Hi. This is Bella.
Bella, they are Quilez and Embry.
I Quiletaire.
So the story engines
true.
Yes. I learned everything I know.
And from that you are
girlfriend?
We are just friends.
Tough.
I said it girl
and that is my friend.
Embry, Do you remember
that we would be shown the difference?
No.
So understand that I have friends.
Hard!
Sure.
Quilez came summers and time at the ball.
Yes, it still makes me laugh.
Want to hear something funny, Black?
Do you tell me one hard.
I bet five U.S. dollars on Quilez.
You got it.
I would like to we who speak ...
I'd like to tell you about Jake ...
makes me feel better.
mean ... makes me feel alive.
goal of my chest ...
when Jake,
I feel like
would be almost healed ...
for a while.
Quilez'm still wondering
and if he can come.
I think you like least about much.
Tell him you do not like
boys smaller than me.
What will all þii up and hard with age?
Cullen How many years have, anyway?
Even Jacob  fails and you
to hold the basket marurile remote ...
Nothing, Bells. You're right.
Beginning to think that
this thing has an effect,
but apparently not the and a.
Can I ask you something?
Do you spend time with Jacob?
He thought for a while
He may still.
Sometimes you have to learn to love you
What Do you do well.
You know what I speak.
Of course, you know me?
I'm just a bachelor
the terminal.
A smoothie recognized.
Well.
Go to sleep again.
I love you.
If your saying you can not fix
motorcycles, what would you say?
I doubt the skill are you?
No.
Of course not.
We can do.
Just ...
If I were to wait,
may have less time and be held.
If I said you can not fix
I would say it's a shame,
but would have
to find something else to do.
That does not e. .. Sat Uley?
Yes. Download "sect" of.
God!
Have you seen this?
Not really fight, Bella.
Jump on the rock in water.
E înfrico and ATOR like hell,
but it's a beastly sensation!
A sensation beast?
Most
jump below.
Sat only and "disciples" of
children are given above.
You got something against them?
I do not know.
They think masters here.
Embry told "bãtãu and umflaþi
of steroids "and now look at him.
- Is that Embry?
- Yes.
What pãþit?
He missed some time from school.
Then, suddenly reappeared
in GA and that of Sam, and as a cãþelu.
Just have pãþit Paul and Jared.
And Sam still look at me,
like I would expect, somehow.
I start a little scared.
Would have to eviþi.
Trying ...
- Ccžeii afraid?
- Yes.
Well.
- Fran?
- This.
Clutch? Well.
Supply?
Are you ready?
Doors URELIT ... disengages the clutch.
Bella.
stops you.
You're okay?
Try again.
Put brakes!
I want to try again.
Trying to commit suicide?
- Try again.
- Forget it.
No longer allowed to ride.
Your head ...
God, I'm sorry.
Do you apologize you bleeding?
A and a. .. appears.
It's just blood, Bella.
No big deal.
What you forget long?
You're just ... nice.
How hard did you hit your head?
Let's go.
- I really saw something in the forest.
- Sure, you think.
I did not.
He wants to stick it in bed.
A wild beast, enormous.
In four paws was higher than
a man.
Maybe it was a bear?
Or an alien.
Luckily you had not taken anything.
I've seen.
There are only.
Father receives all sorts of reports
to the department.
Five are excursion were killed and
of a bear.
I think you found the bear.
It's the last time you will
bend of my friend, bufonului.
So? I mean ...
Bella is back!
Yes, I think so.
Welcome!
Listen, now you're here,
words are ...
and eat again ...
You know you, more put some
protein in the body ...
I was wondering if you would like
to go to a movie with me.
Yeah, sure.
I.
Well ... I can see
"Spelled backwards is Amor Amor".
It's a stupid title, but ...
is a romantic comedy
or so would be ...
Without romantic movies ...
Go to "punch in the face".
Heard of him?
- It's an action movie.
- Yes, it's perfect.
Weapons, adrenaline ...
I love it.
Well.
You should call the world in May.
Want to go to see ...
- "Punch in the face"?
- "Punch in the face"? Yes!
Mike ... Þii mind trailer?
With fists in the mug ...
Fun maximum Bella ...
So going to "punch in the face"?
Do you like action movies?
Not really.
I heard it's born PA. Sorry.
You're big enough
like to see this movie?
Without adult supervision?
Yes, I buy the ticket.
Jessica holds us fold
and Angela has gastroenteritis,
So Erik takes care of it.
- I was just us three.
- Great!
Wonderful.
I kid!
I'll rip cãpãþâna
Leave your weapons!
I will rip cãpãþânile both
Welcome! Let's do
Well, I think I throw up.
- Jesus.
- What pãmpãlãu!
Should you'd expect
anyone more courageous.
Someone who laughs at the carnage
on the screen.
Yes, I þin eyes open and I.
I feel funny.
Circulating flu that ...
What?
Þin you not allowed to hand?
Sure you can.
Just ... for you means nothing
than for me.
Can you tell me?
Like me, do you?
And you seem to be ... nice?
Jake, do not do that.
Why?
Because you will destroy everything.
And I. ..
i need you.
I have a lot of time
to disposal.
I will not give up.
I do not want to do.
But ...
just because I do not want
not going anywhere.
They are very selfish.
And not like a car
that one can fix.
I will not change,
so we should be fair with you.
Because of him, right?
Look, you know what he did.
And, Bella, I do not and never has your
so something.
I will not never hurt.
You a promise.
I will not disappoint.
You can count on me.
I must return home.
I'm very sorry
I stay in the film.
What is the problem?
You are the problem.
If you feel sick, maybe they should
to go to the hospital.
You want to snap
until you get into a hospital?
Jake, Jake, are you?
You're very hot.
As if you have fever.
You're okay?
I do not know what happens.
I have to go.
That guy is weird.
Hi, Jake.
Your father said you mononucleosis.
not left me to come visit,
but can you call me?
All I am ...
Sorry
what I said at the cinema.
I just wanted to hear your voice.
Not pressure you.
Jacob. Please. Call me.
Well. We go on at 3 ...
No need
to go fishing today ...
Yes.
No, go. What are you?
Just take care.
Always have.
Ur and prove them that I'm not, Bella.
"Kung-fu" is my power.
Jake!
Are you cut?
And you have tattooed?
- Bella ...
- I thought you are too ill to exit!
Answer the phone
when you call.
Go.
What?
What you pãþit?
What ... Hey!
What happened?
Sam got to you?
That happened?
Sat trying to help me.
Do not învinovãþi him.
If you want to blame someone,
look at that blood drinkers
împuþiþi whom you love.
Cullen family.
- I do not know what words are.
- You know exactly what I speak.
I've lied to everyone. Charlie ...
But me I can not lying.
Jacob!
Look, Bella ...
We can not be friends.
Jake, I know I hurt ...
Kill me!
- Give me time or ...
- Yes.
Are you not to blame.
"There are you to blame but me, right?
Really?
It's true.
I am to blame.
There are ... good.
I was.
But no longer.
Does not really matter, do you?
It is over.
You can not separated from me.
I mean ...
You're the best friend.
You promised.
I know.
I promised that I will not hurt,
Bella.
And now I promise þin.
Go home.
And never come back.
Or you get hurt.
Alice, things ...
Things are bad again.
Without  Jake, can not endure.
not see him Edward.
I do not feel
that has ever existed.
I find that place
that I will be again.
Laurent?
I'm not expected to find you here.
I went to visit the Cullen,
but their house was empty.
I'm surprised that you have left here.
There were ...
'their pet?
Something like that.
Cullen family
often comes to visit?
Mind it.
Absolutely. All the time.
him lying better.
I will say that you stopped by.
Probably should not ...
Edward.
Because he wants too much
protect me.
But it's far, do you?
Why are you here?
I returned
I do a service to Victoria.
Victoria.
I called to see if there are
the Cullen family protection.
Victory seems as
to kill his partner Edward
if he killed her and your comrades.
Eye for an eye ...
threatens it.
Edward you are who did it.
It comes after both.
I do not think she will.
What importance do you have for him
if you had left here, without defense?
Victoria will not enjoy
I will kill you.
But I can not abþine.
Miro and to let my mouth water.
Please, no.
We have helped ...
No, no, no. Fear not.
It's a gesture of kindness.
Victoria and I had planned to kill you slowly,
painful ...
while I will be very soon.
Do you promise.
You will not feel anything.
Edward, help me.
Dad? I've seen!
What happened?
In forest. No ur and I.
How that is the forest?
Bella, what the hell is the forest?
They are wolves.
That is, some huge and wolves!
Are you sure, Bella?
Yes. I just saw.
Were taken after ... something.
Wolves?
I've seen?
Well, then ...
Harry, you feel like a hunting?
You can collect some guys?
Sure. Yes. I will ...
I know wolves are dead.
And  Laurent will be told
that are defenseless.
Victoria.
Should I go to the department.
Father!
It should ... to go.
You can stay in the house?
Bella.
You scared me.
What are you doing?
Fere and get it. URC.
Look, I'm sorry.
Why?
I wish to explain your.
But ... can not, literally.
Have you ever had a secret
that you do not and anybody can share?
One that you do not have the right
it mean?
He and the E for me.
But worse.
Nor do you know ...
how closely they are related.
This ...
I do not like what you have done.
What kills me is that you already know.
Bella, Do you remember when we
walked on the beach in La Push ...
The story ...
The story about "The Cold".
Understand if this is the only part
that you remember it.
There must be something ...
what you can do ...
No. It's a lifetime commitment.
Maybe I should run away from here
a while.
To leave.
Only two of us.
You do that?
A and do it for you.
Not a thing
You can, simply, run.
But it and do it.
A and run with you ...
if I could.
I have to go.
They begin to wonder where they are.
Come here.
Please.
Try to remember your.
It would be much simpler
if you are.
Try, but ... Jake ...
Jake, what are you doing?
Wait, Jake.
Jake ...
Well, are scared.
A   and to and should.
Bella?
Need to see.
Not here.
I'm sorry,
you really need to see.
Bella?
What you did?
What have you done?
Doors URELIT.
- Don and wanted it!
- What have I done? What did he?
What you said?
Both, calmaþi sure.
I did not say anything
for they were afraid of you!
- Now it's too late.
- Bella, back!
Chill immediately.
Bella!
Run!
Jake, run!
Jake, take her home to Bella Emily.
I think the wolf to exit it from the couch.
Alice is as possible
everything to be true?
Fairy tales and horror stories?
It may not be anything "healthy"
and "normal"?
You should go back,
to ensure that Jacob is good.
I hope Paul and stick to-dinþii in it.
Let him teach me.
No way.
Jake is a born fighter.
You saw how quickly?
Make $ 5 that Paul did not attain.
Come, Bella.
Do not about muscle.
Speaks only in your name.
Speaking of Emily, Sam's fiancée.
Try not one regards are fixed.
It bothers Sam.
Why watch and a price?
You hungry?
As if we have to wonder.
Who is?
Bella Swan. Who else?
So you are girl-vampire.
And you are ... girl-wolf.
A and to think.
"Front-wolf".
I am only engaged to one.
May you leave something and for your brothers.
And ladies are first.
Want an honors you?
Sure. Thank you.
Only Jacob was able to avoid
law of silence imposed by Sat.
He did not say anything or ...
This is something the wolves.
Alfa's orders are heard,
we do not want.
And be careful:
We hear the thoughts between us.
Why not shut up now?
These are secret, damn!
This chick is întovãrã and e and you
with vampires!
Not much I întovãrã and esc with them.
There are too fast.
- Yes?
- We are iuþi and more.
Are you scared yet?
You are not our first mon
that I have met.
Jake is right.
You got to ciudãþenii.
I apologize.
So are werewolves.
Yes. From what I know.
Several members of "lucky and" the tribe
have the gene.
When the city are drinking blood,
Master and we get a fever.
Mononucleosis.
Yes. I wish I.
I can not find a way to ...
stop you are?
I mean ... sucks.
There is a particular lifestyle,
Bella.
A and the I was born, I have no choice.
You're such a hypocrite!
What, are kind of monster
for you?
The problem is not what you are.
But what you do.
They did not harm anyone.
You have killed people, Jake.
Bella, we did not kill anyone.
Then who does?
Those that try new
to defend yourself.
The only ones that really kill it:
vampires.
Jake, can not ...
No care, we can achieve
I cut the preþio and Cullen
if it does not violate the Treaty.
Not what I wanted ...
You can not kill vampires.
They will kill you.
Really? I killed the leech codiþe
pretty easy.
Laurent?
And his girlfriend how much red
s next.
The day is here?
Was. I watched one last night
up to the border with Canada.
But it all comes back.
I'd like to know you are looking ...
I know what he wants.
Me.
Do not worry.
November guard this place.
It will move you
or Charlie.
Care must be taken.
It's quick.
You do not know what hot e.
To know that your distrust toward new
is kind of offensive.
Well. You should go.
You must go.
Yes.
I killed a vampire.
Alice, are good.
Until  be alone.
And lately,
This happens all the time.
Jacob left.
A hunt in Victoria.
And Charlie  hunt him Jacob.
I you have gone ...
And Edward.
Now there e. .. nothing.
Find anything, Harry?
Nothing.
Anyway  would have to go,
any would have to make to see again ...
not do that.
You wanted to be a simple man.
Look me.
Please.
for me.
I have no other way
to keep you near me.
Bella, please ...
Breathe.
Breathe!
Come on, Bella, breathe!
Bella? You hear me?
... Jake?
What the hell was in your mind?
I had ... to see ... something.
Send her home!
Go to Harry, help!
What happened to Harry?
Harry Clearwater
suffered a heart attack.
Charlie and my father are both there,
with his family.
Harry will be fine?
He died.
Do you will find something dry dressed
and you'll go home.
Here are 43 degrees.
God! I have frozen hands.
I think it's nice
do not you are never cold.
It is a characteristic of wolves.
I did not.
It is a characteristic of Jacob.
You are ... hot.
The sun.
It's better, now that you know about me.
But ...
You saw what he pãþit Emily.
Sat was furious ...
and lost control
only a fraction of a second ...
Emily was too close.
Will never
move to-and act.
If I angry at you?
Sometimes I feel ... that will disappear.
You can not expect
to tell you so something.
But always will.
You will lose yourself.
Do not let it happen.
Do you always say you
how special you are.
Thank you for everything.
Wait.
There is a vampire.
How you know?
I feel stink.
I take from here.
It's Carlisle's car!
I'm here.
Bella! It's a trick!
Wait. You must come with me.
I will not hurt.
If Cullen is a return here,
This falling back into their territory.
Treaty says that we can defend
only their own land.
- There can no longer protect.
- Okay.
Never mind.
No need to do.
You're about to pass
over a boundary.
Then assign you one.
Please.
Alice!
- God!
- Bella!
I'm sorry.
I can not believe you're here!
Will you explain how are alive?
What?
I had a vision with you,
You jumped off a cliff.
Why the hell you did
to commit suicide?
What about Charlie?
What about ...
I did that.
The rock salt in water.
So I can say.
It was ... funny.
I've never met anyone
with an angle so the idioþenii
which to put life in danger.
- You say?
- Yes.
He sounds just once
a few months.
He said he wanted to be alone.
Bella, what's that smell repugnant
wet dog?
Probably comes from me.
S of Jacob.
What Jacob?
Jacob is a kind of werewolf.
Bella, it's good to întovãrã and are
with vârcolacii.
Speaks only in your name.
I had to make sure
you're safe.
I thought I can not defend here.
I think I do not care.
I will not be sorry.
No, you are just a harmless Cullen.
I'm talking about the other
drinking blood.
He tried to kill Bella
because of you.
Victoria?
Yes, Victoria was around here.
I saw it.
Or that you were
removed from the water.
I can see you
the pack and your dog.
Not ... I'm angry.
- Stop. Ending, Ending.
- Things are very ugly exit.
We let a moment.
Do not go anywhere.
You get back, okay?
Once Scotland dog of the house.
He ...
Longer and others?
Cullen How many are there
and how long they stay?
Just Alice.
And I can sit however desired.
The rest of them back?
No.
From what I know ...
Is there anything else?
That's all.
If that's all,
you better run back to Sam.
I did it again.
I still break a promise.
We should not do this
each other.
Yes.
Swan family home.
Now is not here.
Organize a funeral.
Who?
I always put in the path.
- Bella, get back.
- Jake, who was?
Bella, is Edward.
I think you died.
Rose told her why I came here.
Why ...
Why did not you let you talk to him?
- I asked you!
- I do not care!
Bella! The cause Volturi.
And he wants to die.
He left, Bella.
You never wanted, Do you remember?
No.
I will not let you commit suicide
because vinovãþiei.
And your father?
I have eighteen years,
the law gives me the freedom to go.
Please.
Please. Stay here.
For Charlie ... For me.
I have to go.
I beg.
Please.
Farewell, Jacob.
Well.
You made a decision?
I fear that your gifts
are too valuable to be destroyed.
But if you are discontent among yours,
Join us.
We would be delighted to use your
talents.
You want to think about are even
whether to stay with us?
You know that I will anyway.
Not without reason.
What a waste.
I have not seen this car renting.
I hope you have something against
theft of cars.
Today no.
What? What do you see?
- It was refused.
- And I. ..
We exit the public
they will show people.
When?
We expect up to noon
when the sun is above the sky ...
- Alice, you must take time are!
- May have time.
Why are dressed in red?
Festival on St. Mark.
Commemorates the expulsion
Vampire the city.
It's an ideal context.
Volturi family will not leave
to reach far enough
order to show mulþumii.
We have at disposal
only five minutes ...
Bella? Breathe.
Bella, only to you
insight you will not coming.
If I go read my thoughts
believe that they lie and will hurry.
- Where to go?
- Will be under the Clock Tower.
- Paradise ...
- You have to move you!
Open your eyes! Look me!
I'm alive!
We have to move you!
You're here ...
I'm here.
You're alive!
Yes.
Do I see a time ...
like to know that I'm alive and that
Nothing to feel guilty.
Now ... I can let you go.
There will never be
you and me to go.
I ... I could not live in a world
that you do not have existed.
But you said ...
I lied.
I had to lie to you.
And thou hast believed so easily ...
Because it has no ninth
I love you to your ...
I ... only one man ...
trivial ...
You're everything to me.
Everything.
Eventually, we will need
your service, gentlemen.
Aro wants to talk again
with you.
No rule
was not violated.
However you should wear this
conversation in a more appropriate place.
Well. Bella, why do not you go
to enjoy the festival?
The girl came with us.
No way.
Fuck you.
Let, boys, is a festival.
I wanted not to make any scene.
There will be no scene.
Enough.
Jane.
Aro sent me to see
why it takes so.
Just do so tells you how.
Go.
Are you afraid?
You?
Buon Poemeriggio.
( "Hello")
- It's man?
- Yes.
- And you?
So why ...
He wants to become ...
And I will become.
... A desert.
I have sent you bring one
and I will bring you.
And "and unca.
What girl isteaþã.
What a nice surprise!
Bella appears to be, however,
in life.
It's great?
I love a happy ending.
There are so rare ...
La tua cantante  ...
(Your singer)
Her blood draws you so much
that excite me and I thirst.
How can you bear to know
so close to her?
Not without effort.
I see it.
With a single touch, see Aro
all I ever thought.
And now you know everything.
So Do it once.
And you cite are the soul of others,
Edward.
Although I. .. Bella can not read thoughts.
Excellent.
I would like to see if you are
and an exception for my gifts.
I do honor?
Interesting.
I see nothing.
I wonder if ...
Let's see if it immune to all
our powers. What about Jane?
Pain.
Please, stop!
Stop!
May not be sorry, please!
Jane?
Master?
Do it, honey.
It could hurt you less.
Outstanding!
We put all the difficulty.
What we do now with you?
You know already what you do, Aro.
He knows too much.
Pose a risk.
It's true.
Felix ...
Please, no!
No, no, please!
Kill me!
Kill me, not him!
Extraordinary.
You sacrifice your life ...
for one of us?
A vampire?
- A soulless monster?
- Kill me once.
You do not know anything
about him.
Maybe your soul ...
For each other.
How much tristeþe.
You have even the intention
to give him immortality ...
Please!
Bella will become one of us.
I saw.
I will turn Bella.
Excellent! To see things
glimpse of you,
before being spent!
Your gift will make you
interesting immortal creature,
Isabella  ...
Go and you prepared.
Let's over with.
Heidi could come at any moment.
Thank you ...
to visit.
We will return favor.
Did he and advise
you hold the word.
We do not offer and a second chance.
Goodbye, my young friends.
Beautiful Booty, Heidi.
Yes, seems quite ... suculenþi.
Keep something and for me.
This way, please.
Stay together ...
Stop yourself!
You're here.
Go to sleep again.
I'll be here when you wake up.
I left only
believing that protect you.
I wanted to have a chance
to a normal and happy life.
But you were so easy to leave.
In my age of life
I was not ever more difficult.
Do you swear.
I will never wrong you i.
I'm so sorry ...
Here comes Charlie.
I feel better?
Yes.
Father,
Should not your worry.
Last time you said that
have disappeared.
There I saw three days.
I'm very sorry, Father.
Bella ...
You don 't ever do that.
Never.
And are punished
for the rest of life.
Well.
In theory, now does not violate any rule.
He said that I do not have permission
to put my foot in this house.
So I went through the window.
I will not forget easily.
I know.
But you can do?
I hope that you can do.
Because, frankly, I have no idea
how I could live without you.
Come.
You can not escape me
I will make you Alice.
You will not need to do.
There are ways of hiding the truth
Volturilor.
No. Not ...
You know with what we all want.
And I know how much sky.
I think the only way to correct
is to votaþi ...
You do not know what you're saying ...
Shut up.
Alice ...
I think I have my sister.
- Yes!
- Thank you.
I vote that "yes".
We wish to be a door I do not want
all the time to kill.
I'm sorry.
We apologize both
for the way I fought.
And be grateful that you had the courage
to save my brother.
But that's life that
I had chosen one.
I would like to be a way
to vote "no" to me ...
So ... no.
I vote: "Hell, yes!
We can struggle with family Volturi
otherwise.
I think you already part
family. Yes.
Why I do this?
You know well what it means.
You are chosen to not live without it,
which does not give me choice.
No, I will lose my son.
I'll be waiting until after graduation,
I like to be Charlie's easier.
I would like you to be the
which I will turn.
He wants to talk.
I see you're alive ...
time.
I think I get þin
far from it.
Stay away from my thoughts!
Jacob, I know you have something to tell me,
but first I wish
Let me tell you something. Okay?
Thank you.
Because you held a Bella
in life when I ... I did.
So it is. You did.
And I did it for you,
Trust me.
Do you are just as grateful.
But now I am back.
And I will not leave Bella
But only if she and I will ask.
We'll see.
It's my turn to speak.
I came to remind
of a critical point of the Treaty.
I forgot.
What essential item?
If any of them
muscle that a man
armistiþiul ending.
But if you want me,
has no link with you.
No. I will not leave!
You will become one by them, Bella!
It depends on you.
You know what you will do!
I will have a choice!
- Bella, please. Come.
- Wait.
I will be sorry?
Read her thoughts.
Jake ...
I love you.
So ... please,
not make me choose.
Because I will choose him.
I always chose him.
- Farewell, Jacob!
- You are talking to her!?
Go away.
Stops you!
Încetaþi!
You can not hurt each other
without saying sorry make one thousand.
Jake ...
He's right.
It should arrive
just like me.
No one can do alone.
So please, wait.
Let me ... five years.
It's too long.
Then three.
You're so încãpãþânatã.
What to expect?
I have one condition ...
if you want to do it myself.
What is the condition?
And then ... eternity.
Do you require this.
Marry me, Bella!
With love, from Felixuca