Edward!
- Pretorious!
- Go away!
No, listen to me. I've got to talk to you.
The resonator - it's working.
If this is your idea of a joke...
No, listen to me. The new program - it worked.
Just like you said.
My God.
Ooh! Do you feel it, Crawford?
Turn it off. Edward! Shut it off.
Never!
Can't you feel it?
Crawford! In the mind.
The mind!
It's out of control. You've got to turn it off.
No! No!
No, I want to see more.
More than any man has ever seen.
Edward! It's running itself!
Something's...
...coming.
They're at it again.
With the coloured lights and the weird sounds.
Last time I called
you said you'd send a squad car
if there was another disturbance.
Well, I'm disturbed.
Hello?
Hello! Oh!
Agh!
Bunny! Come back!
Oh!
Bunny.
Oh, please.
Oh, Bunny.
- Bunny.
- Get back! It's out of control!
Edward! Turn it off! Edward!
Here we are, you little sweetheart.
Somebody! Help!
Help! Help!
Hold it, fella!
Oh God!
Oh my God!
Come on! Come on!
Bunny! Oh!
Dr Bloch, I'm Jordan Fields from the DA's
office. This is Dr Katherine McMichaels.
Hello.
I've read some of your work. Very... impressive.
Oh, yes. So is this facility.
Though if you've read my work...
you know I'm not in favour of locking away schizophrenics.
Yes, I know. You're in favour of
using them in experiments, like...
lab animals.
We've asked Dr McMichaels for her expert opinion
on the sanity of Crawford Tillinghast,
as it pertains to his ability to stand
trial for the murder of Edward Pretorious.
Thank you.
Er... Just a minute. Ray?
Oh.
Thank you.
And...
Oh.
I'm sorry. I am.
I'm sorry.
May God in heaven...
Get them out of here! Get them out of here!
He's in here, doctor.
Crawford?
This is Dr Katherine McMichaels.
Hello.
I suppose you're another psychiatrist.
- Yes, I am.
- Uh-huh.
And you're a physicist.
Your record at Miskatonic University was brilliant.
Oh yes. I had quite a future, didn't I?
Yes. You were working with Edward Pretorious.
I was assisting Dr Pretorious with his experiments, yes.
Mm-hmm.
What was the purpose of the experiments?
To stimulate the pineal gland with resonant vibrations.
The pineal gland? Why?
Dr Pretorious believed the pineal was
a dormant sensory organ.
- A sixth sense.
- Yes. Well, that's not a new theory.
The philosopher Descartes believed it was the third eye.
It's not a theory. It's a fact.
Then your experiments worked.
They proved the theory.
Yes.
Then what went wrong?
Nothing, at first.
But then we saw them.
What did you see?
We saw creatures.
We saw creatures, these...
...things that were swimming around
in the air and fill it all the time.
Are they around us now?
You bet.
Only we can't see them without
the resonator and they can't see us,
unless they're under the influence of the vibrations.
That's why I had to destroy it.
Destroy what?
The resonator - Pretorious's invention.
Because...
...it...
...came.
What came?
Dr Tillinghast?
Crawford, what did you see?
It ate him.
Bit off his head.
Like a gingerbread man.
Crawford.
- Dr McMichaels.
- I'm not mad.
I saw it.
Do you hear me? I saw it.
- Why doesn't anyone believe me?
- We can't reach him.
He keeps returning to the same fantasy.
Let's do a CAT scan on him.
Why? You've already seen everything you need to see.
There's always more to see.
No machines, please.
No, it's all right.
You'll be all right.
I promise.
Oh God.
No. No. No!
No! No!
No!
Oh my God!
- There. Do you see that?
- Mm-hmm.
The pineal gland is oversized and
extending through the optic thalami.
Think the tumour is causing his delusions?
I don't think that's a tumour.
I think the pineal gland is growing.
- That's impossible.
- I know but the CAT scan bears it out.
The pineal stalk is elongating through the brain.
Wait a minute. I don't know from the inside of brains.
What does all this mean?
Well, it could mean that the experiment they were performing
actually does stimulate the pineal.
You mean he's not crazy?
I don't know.
He actually believes that he saw these creatures.
It still doesn't explain how Pretorious
died or what happened to his head.
I'd like to recreate their experiment
and I'll need Tillinghast to do it.
That is absurd and unethical.
I know your methods. The girl wonder.
You use your patients so you can make
your great discoveries.
At least here we try to cure them.
By locking them up?
Giving them drugs? Taking their lives away?
I can give him his life back.
I'll give you an expert opinion.
Crawford Tillinghast is a classic paranoid schizophrenic
and a dangerous one.
If I can recreate the experiment,
then I can find out what happened to Pretorious.
I'd like nothing better than to lock this guy up.
I've got a dead man with his head twisted off,
covered in some shit the pathologist can't even identify.
No other fingerprints found except Tillinghast's,
no blood on the axe, no blood anywhere.
I wanna know what the hell happened up there.
He's all yours.
You're my patient now, Dr Tillinghast.
Thank you.
I'll call for an appointment.
No, no, no. Wait a minute.
You've been released into my custody.
You have to come with me.
Where do you plan on taking me?
Back to the Pretorious house.
I want you to recreate your experiment.
No.
Look... You can either stay here for the
rest of your life or you can come with me.
That's not much of a choice, is it?
I believe you, Crawford.
I wanna see what you saw.
Hi! You must be Doc McMichaels.
No. I'm Dr McMichaels.
- Oh, hi.
- Hello.
Then you must be...
- This is Dr Crawford Tillinghast.
- The crazy.
I'm Sergeant Buford Brownlee but
my team mates call me Bubba.
I used to play pro football.
We were all crazy.
Not exactly cheery.
Sorry about that. Childproof lock.
Last stop. Everybody out.
Dr Tillinghast, would you care to show us around?
Doctor, if you're telling us the truth,
the only way to free yourself
is to go back... through this door.
Come on, doc. There's nothing to be afraid of.
Look, I'll show you.
See? What did I tell you?
Bubba, you all right?
Yeah, yeah. OK.
Electrical cables.
We needed more power so... they rewired the whole house.
Where are the circuit breakers, doctor?
Doctor?
Tillinghast.
Damn! Have we lost him?
He knows this place better than we do.
First thing's to find the power.
- Hey, wait a minute.
- What?
I'll bet these cables lead to the resonator.
First we find our missing mental patient.
Agh! Agh!
I want more yelling.
This guy was into some weird shit.
Where's that mouth? I wanna kiss it.
That's him.
Dr Edward Pretorious.
I don't care about his private life.
The Pretorious resonator.
Agh!
- Is that how you hacked up Pretorious?
- That's where I hit it.
I knocked a fork off.
There.
There it is.
What do you want me to do with him?
- Let him go.
- Are you crazy too?
He's reliving it - the night of the murder. Let him go.
DA says you call the signals.
Yes.
This is how it was.
That's where it ate him.
Wait a minute. What ate who?
We can start in the morning, Crawford.
I've started.
All right.
All this talk about eating is making me hungry.
How about we have some dinner, huh?
The real danger here is starving.
Ah!
Pretty, isn't she?
She is beautiful.
So how's it going, doc?
Need some help?
He used to bring beautiful women here.
They'd eat fine meals, drink fine wine, listen to music.
But it always ended with screaming.
And I would just lie there and listen to them.
Screaming.
Your boss had some screws loose.
He was a genius.
It's just that the five senses weren't
enough for him. He wanted more.
Is it finished? Are we ready?
Yes.
I, uh...
...had to bypass the computer
because the magnetic field erased the program.
And of course the monitor's completely useless
so the entire system has to be manually operated.
And unfortunately the resonator was so severely damaged
that I had to convert it to just an on-off system.
When we reach 20,000 MHz, we throw this switch
and a powerful magnetic field vibrates
these forks at a precise frequency.
Stimulating the pineal gland, allowing us to see with it.
Listen to me.
Don't move when we're in the field of the vibrations.
- Why?
- You move and they may see you. It...
will see you.
What is this "it" anyway?
Pray you don't see for yourself.
Now, I'm staying right by this switch.
If it appears, I'm shutting down.
Are you sure we're ready for this?
- Yes.
- Please...
Remember... Stay still.
This looks real great, people.
Oh, man.
What the hell is that?
- What?
- I don't know what.
No, don't move!
Holy shit!
Is this what you saw?
Yes. These things are around us all the time.
It's coming.
- Bubba, are you all right?
- No!
Lost a little piece, but I'll be fine.
When you move in the field it can sense you.
How far does the field extend?
I'm turning it off.
Crawford!
No.
Who is it?
Show yourself.
Welcome home, Crawford.
I'm glad you came back.
Who's the lovely woman?
It can't be you.
Dr Pretorious?
You have me at a disadvantage, my dear.
Crawford, where are your manners? Bring your friend to me.
- I saw you die.
- No.
Not die. Just pass beyond.
It was horrible.
A necessary rite of passage. Quite wonderful, in fact.
Where have you been hiding?
Move toward me, my dear. I want to see you.
- How? ...did I survive?
I am the master here.
Is it...
Is it really you, Edward?
Touch me.
If it pleases you.
If it helps you understand.
It's just a body, but my mind is indivisible.
Bodies change.
That will be quite enough of that.
I feel exhilarated.
We almost died.
Incredible creature. It must have total
bodily control on a molecular level.
Yes, and Edward's mind.
He's become the thing that ate him.
Crawford, we saw the same things.
We've proved you're not insane.
I'm not so sure.
No. You faced your fear and you overcame it.
You saved our lives.
Yeah. I owe you one.
Want some breakfast?
How can you eat after that?
Can't work without eating.
What work?
I've got to record the results.
The pineal gland was stimulated.
It gave me one hell of a headache.
Expansion of the pineal.
I'll have to do a study of the CAT scans of schizophrenics.
If there's a statistical correlation
between schizophrenia and an enlarged pineal, why...
they may be seeing or feeling what we saw.
Their minds may be influenced by those creatures.
Well, how about the hard-on I got?
Is there a statistical correlation for that too?
Well, um... We know that the pineal gland
helps to regulate the sex drive.
Perhaps pineal stimulation causes a...
an accompanying sexual stimulation.
There's so much to learn.
Well, we learned what we came for.
He ain't crazy and that... "it" ate Pretorious's head.
They're gonna think we're crazy but that's their problem.
Well, we just have to try the experiment again.
Did you say "we"?
Katherine, you can't.
You don't mean go back up there now, do you?
You always run an experiment twice to check the results.
Wait.
I saw it get to him, Katherine.
Just exactly what you're feeling and it ruined him.
Pretorious.
Yes, I'd like to know more about him.
That resonator is a work of genius.
Were we in the same nightmare?
I mean didn't we just almost all get eaten by an "it"?
All it takes is a hand on the switch.
If it appears you make it disappear.
I got a better idea. How about if we disappear out the door?
Don't you understand? This is the greatest discovery
since Van Leeuwenhoek first looked through
a microscope and saw an amoeba.
Yeah, but he wasn't down there with the amoebas.
I have to find out if the pineal gland is really the key.
OK fine. Fine, but not here. Not now.
Under controlled conditions.
But we have control. No one knows
that resonator better than you do.
You're right, and that's why no one is touching it.
Crawford!
This could be the first step in curing schizophrenia.
Crawford.
My father spent 15 years in an institution - he died in one.
They called his condition incurable.
They tried everything. Drugs, shock therapy, even surgery.
But they turned him into a vegetable.
I'm sorry.
We can save so many others. Please, Crawford.
We can do it.
Help me.
Help you.
Help you to take your mind and shatter it?
I can't.
And I won't let you.
I'm the law here. You turn on that
machine, and it's reckless endangerment.
Look, we all need some rest.
Why don't we just get some sleep
and then we'll think about it.
Yeah, we'll get some rest and then we're going.
Turn it off.
No.
I have to see more.
Feel more.
Turn it off.
No.
No. No.
We've got to stop it.
Oh! Don't stop.
I'm impressed, Crawford.
Do you realise now what I was creating?
Edward, my God, what have you become?
Myself.
- Get the switch. I'll distract him.
- Ah!
Yes! I do find you distracting.
Don't! Crawford.
Listen to me.
Whatever you are, you're still Edward
Pretorious. You're still human.
More than human.
Join me, for ever.
Everyone must join me.
We'll be waiting for you, Crawford.
Where the hell are you going to now?
The circuit breaker. I've got to turn it off.
Damn!
Smell.
Taste.
In another life I would have enjoyed you in another way.
Messing with that damn machine again.
What the hell is that?
The vibrations must reach down here.
I'll be right back.
What are you gonna do to me?
I'm going to kiss you.
Argh!
Ah!
I'm sorry.
I really thought that I could control it.
It's changing us, doc.
All of us.
And not for the better.
I was wrong to turn on the resonator
with other subjects present.
It's clear now that only one person
should run the experiment.
This ain't an experiment.
It's suicide!
The presence of other subjects causes
dangerous distractions.
Now, I can stand right at the master switch
and maintain control of that resonator
but I must do it myself.
I know this behaviour. I've seen it in the streets.
You may be a scientist, lady, but
right now you're acting like a junkie.
Oh, just take him and leave.
Wrap him up. I'll get the van ready.
Put some clothes on,
unless you want me to take you
kicking and screaming like that.
What the hell are you doing?
I told you to get dressed.
I did.
The van's ready. You going like that?
Oh.
What a shame.
I just... love what you've done with this room.
You're asking for it.
Mm-hmm.
Look at yourself! Look at yourself!
Is that who you are?
I don't know.
I don't know who I am.
Listen.
- Crawford, we're leaving now.
- No, shh, listen.
The resonator. It's him.
He's trying to start the resonator from Beyond.
Son of a bitch!
Bastard!
Bubba, pull the cable!
Use the axe! The axe!
Damn!
Oh! Oh no, God!
Oh! God! Oh!
God! Oh!
No!
Bubba!
Katherine.
Agh!
- Agh!
- Crawford!
Kiss.
Kiss, my dear.
Humans are such easy prey.
Let her go.
Oh, I will...
beyond her wildest dreams.
She will go into my mind and I will go into hers.
It's the greatest sensual pleasure there is.
You never knew pleasure or gave it. Only pain.
You are evolving into a being
that has never existed before.
I'm Crawford Tillinghast.
Let it happen, Crawford.
No!
- Let it out!
- No!
Ah!
Crawford!
Oh, it's so beautiful.
So...
...beautiful!
Now you can truly see.
What have you done to him?
I only awakened his sleeping pineal gland.
It did the rest itself.
No!
Crawford!
You whore!
Die, you fucker!
Oh, Crawford!
The police are here.
She's been telling us a pretty wild story.
I have been telling you the truth.
We'd like your opinion of her mental state.
I'd rather give you my opinion of her professional conduct.
You're contemptible.
Look at her.
I doubt she even understands what she's done.
You cost Crawford Tillinghast his mind.
Quite possibly his life.
And another man's life.
That machine has got to be destroyed.
I listened to you the first time and
now I've lost one of my best men.
The DA's going to chew me a new asshole, thanks to you.
She's in your custody now.
No, no, wait a minute. You can't lock me up.
Not here, please.
I can't do much with her in this agitated
state. She'll upset the other patients.
Do whatever you think best.
Listen, Dr Bloch, please.
You know that I'm sorry for everything that I've done.
You have got to let me go back.
Don't you tell me what I have got to do, girl wonder.
You always have all the answers, don't you.
Well, you're my patient now
and I've got a few answers myself.
Prepare her for electroshock therapy.
But... Dr Bloch...
- hospital policy says...
- Hospital policy dictates
that the nursing staff has to follow
orders. Now, do as I say.
- Yes, doctor.
- No!
Stop her!
My God, Bloch! No!
Set her up in number five.
I'm going to go check on Tillinghast.
If she continues to resist, sedate her.
Please, don't do this.
It's not necessary.
I'm all right now.
He's gone.
Call security.
Crawford.
Please don't eat those.
Delicious.
They... can make you very sick.
Oh God!
What is happening to me?
We...
We don't know for sure but we're going to find out.
We're going to go in the hall now, Crawford.
Take it easy, honey.
Come quick. Something's happened and we need your help.
Wait a minute. What about her?
Lock her up in her room.
Ugh!
Katherine?
I need a drink.
Oh God! Let me outta here.
- You'd better hurry...
- Yeah, yeah.
...before he goes into DTs.
Oh, and get me a candy bar. I'm starving.
Harley.
Harley, what's going on?
Oh no! Oh, dear Lord!
Oh God! Oh no!
I saw... a snake.
A snake came out of its head and ate him. Dear Lord!
Shit, Harley, you son of a bitch, he's gone into DTs.
A long... A long...
Harley!
Oh, dear Lord! No, God!
Harley?
You all right?
That's the snake man! That's him!
Somebody! Somebody help me!
Help! Help!
Oh help! Somebody!
Help!
Crawford! Stop!
Crawford, let me go.
What are? Crawford?
Crawford, stop!
Ow!
Crawford, oh my God! Why are you doing this?
Because I love you, Katherine.
Crawford, we have to get out of here.
The resonator's going to blow up.
I want us to be together.
Listen to me.
I set a timing device on a bomb. We only have a few minutes.
It doesn't matter.
If Pretorious can turn on that machine
then he'll always have a way back here.
He's always here.
Don't you understand? He won't just influence us.
He'll devour us and the rest of the human race if he can.
You're so beautiful.
Please, Crawford.
It won't hurt, I promise.
Agh!
Crawford!
Help me!
Katherine?
Agh!
Welcome, my dear. I've been waiting for you.
- Edward! No!
- Yes!
The greatest sensual pleasure there is
is to know the desires of another mind.
I know your desires, you impotent pig!
We are the most powerful being in the universe.
She'll know, Edward, how pathetic you are.
How you can't make love.
Maybe you could teach me.
Crawford!
All right, come and get me, eunuch.
This time I'm not running away.
Katherine, run!
Crawford!
What happened?
There was a big explosion near the top of the house.
I've called the fire department.
They'll get you to the hospital.
Oh, my God!
What happened up there?
It...
...ate him.