Are you gonna...
You bringing Micky in?
Yeah, he's here.
He should come.
He should be here as well.
We thought that Micky is
coming to answer the questions.
No, they said it was
going to be both of us.
- Am I looking right into the camera here?
- Just look at me right now.
All right.
You're not going to look
at the camera with the interviews?
I started boxing when I was
twelve years old
and I lied and said I was eighteen
or whatever it was.
I had a different name and everything.
I mean, I don't have any fights,
I've done a hundred more than that
before I turned professional.
This morning you said that...
- Why are we doing this?
- One more time.
You want to go over it all?
You want to start again?
He's my younger brother.
I taught him everything he knows.
I'm still his trainer.
I know we've got different styles,
I'm fucking squirelly as fuck.
You know, like, I'm not even there.
That's what Sugar Ray said. I was the
most tricky fighter he'd ever come across.
'78, before Sugar Ray Leonard...
I told him he couldn't get to me.
He couldn't get to me.
They called me "The Pride of Lowell."
Everybody still talks about it,
you know, especially my brother.
His whole life he wanted to do
what I did, you know?
But we're very different fighters.
Micky's a heavy hitter.
He's thunderous, I'm telling you.
Thunderous left punch.
Micky, he takes a punishment.
I don't know why he does it.
I'd say "You all right?"
He likes getting on the inside.
I stay on the outside.
Come on!
Dicky...
Would you come on?
Stop.
You've got to help me finish this.
Come on!
Unpredictable as ever!
You don't have to be Columbo
to see where this fight is headed!
Yeah, bam!
All right, he punched Micky Ward down!
HBO's making a movie on me and
my comeback and my brother
is going to beat Saoul Mamby
in Atlanta next week!
The Pride of Lowell is back!
Quacker!
Who wants some?
Sync, corrected by icephoenix
www.addic7ed.com
I want a cut.
Doing good?
You guys having a good day?
How are you?
Come on. Come on. What you got?
What you got going on?
Lou! Hey, Lou DiBella!
How are you guys, huh?
I'm making my comeback.
Hey, Marty, Marty.
Come out here, huh?
Hey!
HBO is making a movie on me!
Hey, beautiful.
You got that?
Can't remember who she is.
I can't remember shit!
Hey!
Hey, Garcia!
How are you, nice?
How'd you get here?
Drive around?
Hey, Ray. Hey.
I love you, Ray.
This is what it's all about.
He make mistake?
No, he'll be here.
Like I said,
sometimes he goes on his own schedule,
but when he gets here we work hard.
Nobody pushes me harder than him.
He's supposed to be
training you right now, right?
Why don't you just go talk to them,
my sisters?
They'll talk your ear off.
You gotta pay them to shut up.
He can tell you how
Dicky was helping him.
Come on, Micky.
Okay.
Hey, we don't know where Dicky is.
You know where he is.
What's that dumb cop doing in there?
Where's Dicky?
Girls?
- I don't know.
- You see him this morning?
Your brother?
Not this morning.
Look at Mom!
All dressed up for the movie, huh?
You are smoking hot!
Get out of the ring, O'Keefe.
My Dicky should be doing that.
Dicky ain't here, Alice.
Micky's got an important fight
coming up and he's not training.
- Forget about him. Never mind about him.
- He's not doing what he's supposed to do with him.
- Start saying to Micky...
- He's not part of this, all right?
- Alice, he's not being handled right.
- Did you get me coming in all right?
You want me to do it again?
Get out of the ring, O'Keefe.
- Dicky's the trainer.
- I'm doing him favor, Alice.
I will show you over here
these scrapbooks I have been
collecting for years.
Micky used to follow
his big brother everywhere.
Taught you everything, didn't he, honey?
In '78 we got the offer
to fight Sugar Ray Leonard.
Oh, my God. Have you seen that video?
Well, you're from HBO,
you've got to see it again!
Come on. Where's the video at?
Tonight my son is going to surprise
everybody and beat Sugar Ray Leonard.
Believe me. I know it.
Sugar Ray might have some trouble tonight.
That's a good possibility.
He comes in here against a good boxer,
a young man who can punch,
and I would like to say at this time
that physically they're just about equal.
Leonard is down.
Let's see if that's a knockout.
This is unbelievable.
Eklund just walked over there.
Nobody seems to know what's happening.
Dicky did it.
Dicky did it!
Aren't you supposed to be
training Micky right now?
No, it ain't until 9:00.
Dicky, it's fucking 11:45.
- It's 11:45, Dick.
- What?
Where'd you fucking
park the car, Boo Boo?
- I didn't park it. You did.
- Huh?
Check your fucking pockets for the keys.
You've got the keys, huh?
I didn't park it, man.
- Not here. I don't know...
- Check your pockets, all right?
Oh, fuck it, I'll run.
I need the fucking road work.
Road work?
Are you crazy?
He's a great runner.
Hey.
Hey!
- I'm here!
- Hey, Dicky.
Better late than never.
Here, look.
Detectives on the scene...
Get to the bar with this...
- Figure this one out, huh?
- Why don't you...
Hold it. Hold it.
Let me get this straight.
You guys are working in the same corner
as Micky, together, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, they're both in my corner.
- This is what goes on.
- Okay. It must be...
Don't you have a job to
go to or something?
Really, O'Keefe has a job
that he should be at.
Yeah, Sergeant O'Keefe's
working overtime here.
So we go at this old man:
Jewish, black, former world champion.
I think we've got
all the bases covered.
And my kid brother,
he's lost three fights in a row.
He can't get used to losing.
It's a mental thing.
But we're gonna break that
with Mamby, right?
Yeah, I hope.
When we can train.
When we train. Right.
Don't be wasting time, Mick, you know?
- Wasting time?
- Half the fucking day's gone.
Yeah, half the day's gone.
I've been waiting for you.
Come on, move.
We're going to outbox Mamby, huh?
- Take it out on the head.
- Head, body, head. That's your combo.
Head, body, head, body.
My Dicky taught him that.
You know,
Sugar Ray's going to be there
calling the fight for ESPN.
I ain't seen him since
I knocked him down,
like, fourteen years ago
or something, right?
Let's get a real sparring going on here.
Don't want to embarrass yourself.
Don't want to embarrass yourself
in front of Sugar Ray, huh?
Come on, head, body, head.
Your punch, man!
That's your punch. Now that's your little punch.
Use your whole fucking body now.
George's fingers are so fucking big
he can't even dial the phone!
That's not helping, George!
- Wait, I'm confused.
- What?
- I'm confused, too.
- We're confused.
- George is whose father?
- You're confused?
Dick Eklund Sr. is Dicky's,
Donna's, Gail's and Phyllis' father.
- Dick Eklund.
- Yeah.
And even though Alice is an Eklund,
so are Cindy and Cathy.
George is really...
- And Micky...
- No.
Micky and I are Wards.
It's always sounded like Dick Eklund
and I were separated, right?
- And then there was George.
- Just George.
- George is my man.
- George is our papa.
After Dick, it was just George.
Come on.
Come over here...
Why don't you just go talk to her?
She's a nice girl.
I told her all about you.
I don't want to ask her.
She's going to say no.
Can't beat that ass, can you?
Get at it. Go.
Come on.
Are you just going to stand there
and stare at my ass?
Your father stares at my ass
but he talks to me.
He thinks you're the greatest.
- He didn't tell me you were new.
- Keep the change, doll.
He told me you came for you sister.
- This is a tip?
- Yeah, that's my tip!
You know what the bell says
about this one?
Cheap bastard.
Cheap fucker.
Comes in every day,
gives me shitty tips.
Yeah, fuck you, too.
You pave streets, right?
Yeah, I do. And I'm a fighter.
Oh, yeah. I heard you're a stepping stone.
- I'm no stepping stone.
- Mm.
You're the guy they use
against the other fighters
to move the other fighters up.
I've had a few tough fights,
but that's not who I am.
The next fight's going to show who I am.
Yeah, and he's going to
lose that one, too.
Scotch and soda, Charlene.
And one for yourself.
Now move that sugar ass...
Okay, be respectful.
Don't disrespect her.
Hey, don't hurt your hand.
You've got a fight next week.
Besides,
you wipe your ass with that one.
Don't wait up, or I'm going to hit
you in the car, sucker, all right?
He's gonna be so lame.
All right?
That's right.
Take your drink.
He's taking his drink.
This guy's going to be champion.
He's a great guy. He's a great fighter.
Okay? Hold on.
Thanks for the drink.
You know those cameras
are making a movie about him?
He knocked out Sugar Ray Leonard
on HBO. That's why they're following
him around with the cameras.
They're making a movie
about his comeback.
Yeah, everybody's talking about it.
But who are you fighting?
- Saoul Mamby.
- Saoul Mamby?
- What kind of name is that?
- Black and Jewish.
Where did they find a guy like that?
He's no joke.
Former world champion.
- Former champ?
- Yeah.
- I match up good with him, though.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- What does that mean?
Well, I got a light end, you know?
I've got a reputation for brawling,
but I'm not going to brawl with him.
- I'm going to try to box him.
- There's a difference?
Yeah, in brawling you slug it out.
I hit you. You hit me.
Boxing is a chess game, you know?
Got to pick my punches
to take him down.
I'm going head, body, head, body...
What is head, body, head, body?
Well, I hit him in the head, then his
hands got to go up to protect himself.
Opens up his body, then I hit him in the body,
hand goes back down. I go back up to the head,
hand goes back, and I hit him in the body.
People who don't know fighting think
you do a lot of damage hitting the head,
but you actually do more hitting the body.
So what do you think?
Can I take you out?
Are you married?
No, would I ask you out if I was married?
What kind of guy do you think I am?
Happens all the time, trust me.
I'm not like that.
I'm not married. I've got a daughter,
I see her every other weekend.
Her name is Kasie.
But that's it.
Come on, let me take you out.
When?
Saturday night I'll be
back in Atlantic City.
Is this the real number?
You'll have to call it and see.
I will.
Saturday. Dinner and a movie.
- Hey. What's up?
- Dicky, hey. How's it going?
I don't think Laurie's
expecting you right now.
What's he doing here?
This isn't your visitation day, Micky.
I just want to say hi to Kasie.
It's not your day, goodbye.
Yeah, but I'm not around next week.
Now you're ditching
the days you do have?
No, I have a fight.
I told you that.
- Jimmy...
- I can't get in the middle.
I can't talk to her, okay?
So I'm asking you, Jimmy.
I want to talk to my daughter now.
- Talk to your father.
- God damn it, Jimmy.
Hi, Daddy.
Daddy's gonna beat Saoul Mamby.
That's right. And I'm gonna tell you that
after I win, I'm gonna start making big money.
And I'll move into a bigger apartment,
like we talked about,
- so you can live with me more days, okay?
- Yeah, a bigger apartment!
- Wish me luck, all right?
- Don't hold your breath, Kasie.
It's cruel to mislead your child, Micky.
- Good luck, Daddy.
- Thanks, Kasie. I love you, honey.
Bye, baby.
- Where is he?
- Jesus Christ. Fucking holding us up.
- Quit your worrying, for crying out loud.
- All that shit in my face...
I know it's none of my business.
I go to a lot of meetings,
and they have a saying:
"Let go and let God."
- You've got to let him go, Mick.
- He's taught me everything I know.
He's been in my corner.
I can't do it without him.
- You're already doing it without him.
- No I'm not.
- Yes you are.
- Look, you know where he is.
Why don't you just go get him?
Can you get him?
I'm not fucking going to get him.
Well are we all going to go over there
in the limo with Alice? We can't do that.
Dicky.
- Your mother's outside.
- What?
Uh-oh, Dicky, your mother's outside.
She's down there.
I'm not here.
Don't, Dicky.
Dicky!
What the fuck are you doing?
You know we've got to go to the airport now.
We've got a flight to catch.
You know how important this fight is to me.
- Don't tell Mom I'm here, all right?
- She knows.
- Pick me up back at the house, all right?
- Are you fucking...
She's in the driveway right now.
All right, but hurry up.
She's in the fucking driveway.
- We've got a flight to catch.
- You do this on the day your brother's traveling?
- What are you doing?
- Just trying to see what I have.
- The fuck did you hit him for?
- Why'd you make me do that to you?
- Jesus!
- Oh, my God, Dicky...
I was on my way, Mom.
- What are you doing?
- No, Mom. Mom...
Why can't we just go to the
fucking airport for once, please?
Hey, Alice, what about your husband who's
laying on the fucking ground over here?
You want to help your husband?
What are you doing, running in here
like a silverback fucking gorilla?
- We had to get him, didn't we?
- Oh, yeah, you got him, pal.
You see Mamby?
See how Mamby's arm comes up?
Leaves his side open,
you just play him up like a pinball machine.
He'll be pissing blood.
No way you'll lose, Mick. No way.
- Hey, Lou.
- Dicky, boy.
Hey listen, boy.
ESPN can't get us better rooms than this?
I wouldn't worry about the rooms right now,
Dicky. You've got bigger headaches.
Like what?
The doctor won't let Mamby fight.
Why not?
- He's got the flu.
- Mamby got the flu?
Yeah.
Dicky, we can still have a fight.
- With who?
- Mike Mungin.
Mike Mungin, who's that?
- Guy from Philly. Been in prison.
- He's been out a few months.
I've called everybody, checked everywhere.
He's the only guy I could find.
My last three fights were rough, Lou.
I mean this one's supposed to be easier.
We've been fucking preparing for Mamby.
Right, but this guy just came off the couch.
He's been sitting on his ass.
Could be an easy win for Mick.
Joey Farrell, remember him?
He knocked his ass out.
- And you knocked down Joey Farrell...
- Exactly, and Mungin just got off the couch.
Can't make weight.
Might be a bit over, though.
How over?
- 162, 165...
- 165?
Micky dropped weight.
He's 146.
Lou, we prepared for Mamby, all right?
We prepared for Mamby!
This guy just got off the couch.
Micky's in shape.
Road work, everything else.
This other guy hasn't done dick.
Don't forget.
You don't fight, nobody gets paid.
Lou, please...
All right. Um,
Joey Farrell knocked him out...
Going to be a hell of a fight, huh?
I'm not doing this.
165 is big.
- You knocked down Joey Farrell.
- So what? He's a middleweight.
He just got off the couch.
He's got twenty pounds on me, Dicky.
Joey Farrell knocked him out.
You knocked down Joey Farrell.
- You just said that.
- Yeah but... You can't be scared.
- Scared?
- Yeah.
- Why don't you go fucking fight him?
- I'll go fucking fight him. He's fat.
Go snap out the teeth. It's your big comeback,
right? That's what Alice wants.
You knocked down Joey Farrell.
All right, I knocked down Joey Farrell, okay?
But the guy is a middleweight.
I'm a welterweight. What, they don't have
a fucking heavyweight to tow in there with me?
Tell him, Dicky. He can do it, right?
He can do anything.
Yeah, Alice. No problem.
You watch from the outside now.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mike "Machine Gun" Mungin!
Holy shit!
Hey, look.
There's Sugar Ray Leonard.
Hey, Ray. Sugar Ray.
Over here.
Dicky, come on.
Look at the size of that guy.
- Holy shit.
- Yeah, holy shit.
That guy's no welterweight.
All right, Mick. Gonna have to learn
to fuss you around. It's time now.
He did not just get off the fucking couch.
If he did, I want to buy a couch like that.
I don't care who that guy is.
I don't care. Look at me.
You're Micky Ward.
Micky Ward fighting a last-minute
replacement from Philadelphia,
a much bigger man.
Punches smashing Ward.
Ward goes down!
Micky, what the fuck is wrong?
Get rid of this dude!
Mungin didn't even know
he'd be fighting today...
Come on, now, Mick!
Ward, a respected fighter. You hope
this mismatch doesn't hurt his confidence.
- You're a loser!
- Loser!
You're a loser!
Ray! Hey, Ray! Ray!
Hey, Dicky!
- How are you doing, man?
- How are you?
165 pounds. ESPN screwed us.
- The guy was huge.
- You know what I'm saying?
You know, I knocked Ray down.
I look like shit, but I knocked Ray down.
Let me buy you guys a drink,
all right? You want a cold one?
- No, no, no...
- A cold one!
I've got to leave.
I've got a plane to catch. Next time.
Hey, Ray. HBO is making
a movie on me, you know?
Can they call you?
I'm going to get a fight.
I'd like you to be there, for old times' sake.
You can commentate or something.
What's the movie about?
My comeback, right?
- Call me.
- I'll call you.
Don't be a stranger.
He's my old pal.
- You going to the hospital?
- What is that?
Look, Mick. Nobody's got heart like you.
You're a very talented fighter,
but you're not getting the right fights.
It's killing your chances.
- What's he talking to Mike Toma about?
- I don't know what that is.
I want to give you a real shot.
I want you to come with me.
I want to pay you to train with my guys.
- Where?
- Las Vegas.
Do it right and make one last run
at this thing before it's too late.
What about my brother?
With all due respect,
he's too much trouble.
You owe it to yourself to come to Vegas.
Come on, Mick. What has Dicky done for you?
He gets you into fights.
He lets you get beat like you did tonight.
You know you never should have been in that fight.
Eighteen pounds. Think of it that way.
You should have given it up.
Get out of the car there. Come on, you!
- Sit the hell down.
- Just a little more scotch for Mom, okay?
Here you go. Nice and easy.
Don't hurt yourself coming back, old broad.
Oh, my God, that Sugar Ray...
He's a beautiful man, isn't he? Right?
A beautiful man.
You should have seen the way
he was looking at her.
- He's a pretty man, huh?
- He's a good guy. I like him. I know.
I seen him ringside, and he was
so happy seeing me and Mick together.
You know he's all about family, that guy.
Likes to see a family stick together.
Mick, what'd Mike Toma want
with you last night, huh?
He wants to train me in Vegas.
You can't trust that guy, Micky.
He ain't family, you know?
You don't know him.
He say anything about me?
He say I could come?
He didn't mention you.
What are you going to do in Vegas
without your brother, huh?
That guy just wants to use you,
like a piece of toilet paper.
What are you going to do in Vegas
without Dicky? Without your family?
- I know. That's what I told him.
- You told him that, right?
Yeah, I told him. I said
I need to be with my family.
That's right.
Nothing wrong with that.
Sugar Ray said call him.
We're going to call him, baby.
You guys can spar a little, right?
There's my champ.
Daddy's home. Daddy's home!
I love you...
Your face hurting you, sweetheart?
Because it's killing me.
- Come on...
- Uncle Micky win the fight?
No, Uncle Micky didn't win this time.
Not this time.
Hey, Mick. Take care.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Cheer up. We'll get you another fight.
I don't know, Mom.
I don't think I want to do this no more.
- What don't you want to do no more?
- I just don't want to do it anymore.
- What are you talking...
- Hey, Mick.
ESPN screwed us. They owe us.
We'll get another fight.
You heal up.
- It'll be okay.
- Yeah, listen to your brother.
They owe us big-time, sweetheart.
Hey, maybe they'll even do Dicky's
comeback fight. What do you think, huh?
Oh, come on. Cheer up.
You take a little soap when you get home.
Have a day or two to think about it.
I'll find you a better fight, sweetheart.
Much better fight.
I'm going to talk to them.
- For Christ's sake, Alice.
- What?
- He's been through the ringer. Leave him alone.
- What are you talking about?
- Leave him some time to himself.
- What is your fucking problem?
Where's Micky?
Is Micky not going to come in?
No, he's not coming in.
He needs to get back and get some rest.
Come on. Let's go inside.
He's going to go rest.
He's all grumpy.
He's tired. He's beat up.
He's a little embarrassed, I think.
Who is it?
I saw the shade move.
Micky, the shade is still moving.
I saw you come to the window.
I know you're in there.
The least you can do
is open up this door
and tell me to my face
why you didn't call me yesterday.
Why did you stand me up last night?
I started to call.
I was going to call. I just couldn't.
Because you lost the fight?
Maybe, yeah.
Because I lost the fight.
How do you know my house anyway?
I asked my brother.
Your thing's coming off.
And your other thing.
You got any tape?
Did the black Jewish guy
do this to you?
I didn't get to fight the black Jewish guy.
You didn't get to go head, body, head?
Saoul Mamby got the flu.
Guy that took his place had twenty pounds
on me. I never should have fought him.
Why did you?
Nobody would have got paid.
Everybody said I could beat him.
Who's everybody?
My mother and my brother.
So are you going to take me
to dinner and a movie, or what?
- Hey.
- You look great.
- Thank you.
You've got a nice house, too.
It's an apartment building.
There's five of them in there.
One of my old roommates lives with me.
Roommate?
What, were you in the army?
- College.
- College? Wow.
Yeah, a lot of good it did me.
I work in a bar.
You seem to enjoy it.
Very popular down there.
Ugh, yeah. Popular.
I've got to get out of there.
If I don't drink while I'm working
I'll fucking kill myself.
- What college?
- URI. Full boat.
- A full boat's a scholarship, right?
- Yeah.
For what?
- I was a high-jumper.
- High-jumper? You've got to be kidding me.
Fuck you. I was good.
I was New England champ. I cleared 5'8".
- Wow.
- Never graduated. I partied too hard.
You?
What are we doing in richie-rich Lexington?
You come to this theater a lot?
Yeah, it's a good theater.
They've got good movies here.
- Yeah? Like what?
- Belly Epi-cue.
I think it's Bell Epic.
It's epic. Bell Epic.
Belle Epoque.
The New York Times don't lie.
Well I never heard of it.
Where'd you hear about it?
The New York Times?
No, a guy from work.
And the cinematography
is supposed to be gorgeous.
Oh. Cool.
That's the movie you wanted to see?
There wasn't even any good sex in it.
Had to read the whole fucking movie.
Fucking subtitled.
Some guy from a road crew recommended it
to you? A fucking subtitled movie?
What's going on, huh?
What's going on? You got a girlfriend
or something? You hiding me from her?
I don't have a girlfriend, all right?
I like you.
I came here because
I don't want to show my face in Lowell.
I told everybody I was going to win
that fight and get back on track.
I told my daughter I was going to get
a bigger apartment so she could move in.
You don't think I wanted to call you?
I was embarrassed.
I'm sick of being a fucking disappointment.
You really think your family
is looking out for you?
Don't say that. I don't like that.
What else I can say
after what you told me?
Look at your face.
Look at you.
Bullshit, Lou.
I'm not going to stop calling until you
make this right and get us a fight that's fair.
My boy could have got killed last time.
Yeah, like what?
Just don't tell me he just got
off the fucking couch.
Mm-hm.
Coming off a loss?
That sounds very interesting.
I'll get back to you.
Got a great opportunity here.
We've got to go find Micky.
Nobody's seen him for, like, three weeks.
Jesus...
Used to be Dicky we couldn't find.
Now it's both of them?
Mom, I think he's with that girl from the bar.
- What girl?
- It's that fucking girl, Charlene.
That's who he's with. That girl from the bar.
George was all fucking eager
for them to get together.
- I heard she's into three-ways.
- Yeah, with other girls.
Yeah, like one of those MTV girls.
MTV girls? What are you talking about?
Wild.
She acts all fucking superior
because she went to college.
You girls just go find your brother Micky.
Tell him I've got important business to discuss.
I've got to go find Dicky.
Dicky!
Hey, Mom. It's not...
It's just...
It's just a friend's house.
Come on, whatever.
? I started a joke, ?
? which started the whole world crying. ?
? Oh, if only I'd seen ?
? that the joke was on me. ?
? I started to cry, ?
? which started the whole world laughing. ?
? Oh, if only I'd seen ?
? that the joke was on me. ?
? I looked at the skies, ?
? running my hands over my eyes, ?
? and I fell out of bed, ?
? hurting my head... ?
So you're Beaver,
and you're Red Bear.
Red beard.
She's Red Dog, and that's Beaver.
You're Red Dog.
You're Beaver.
- Yeah, don't use those names.
- It's just for family.
Be nice.
Don't use the nicknames.
What the fuck will I call them then?
Speaking of family...
Hello.
- Alice, this is Charlene.
- Hi.
I've heard a lot about you.
Really? I've heard a lot about you, too.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Same thing you meant.
Can we just sit down and talk about business?
I got you another fight, Mick.
Just like I said I would.
- Lou Gold and ESPN made it right.
- Just like I told you.
Joe Mellenk. Six weeks. Foxwoods.
Ten in eight. He's nothing.
- And they're going to pay us twenty grand.
- $17,500, technically.
$17,500, which is still good money, Mick.
Yeah.
That's good, Dick. I'm just trying to
figure out what's best for me.
Like what, huh?
What's best for you, sweetheart?
Come on, Mick. I thought you'd be more excited.
Why aren't you more excited?
It's a good fight, good money.
I got something with Lou Gold.
He knows us.
I know, Mom. I just don't want things
going the way they've been going.
Mick, that last fight was unfair.
It was unfair.
- And we ain't going to repeat that, right?
- Oh, not on your life.
You know, buddy,
it's just you in the ring.
Yeah, I know it's just me in the ring.
But I don't like the way
things have been going here.
- Where?
Here, this, us, Lowell, the whole routine.
- George, stay out of it!
- You're doing all the talking.
- Let him talk. Listen.
- I'm asking him.
- You're telling him. Listen.
- Stay out of it.
Hey, don't tell me to stay out of it.
Mick, what's the problem?
- Problems.
- What problems?
- Problems...
- Like what?
Like maybe you
not showing up on time to train.
Like maybe him having to
come find you in a crack house
when you're supposed to be at the airport.
I'm sorry. I don't know who you are.
Why are you talking?
I'm Charlene. We just met.
We're together. Do we need to do this again?
Hi, I'm Charlene.
- Hi, Charlene.
- Hi.
- Hi, I'm Charlene.
- Hi, Charlene.
Hey, we're together.
What are you going to do, Mick?
Listen to some MTV girl who works in a bar?
What does she know about boxing?
I know they're going to Vegas
and getting paid to train year-round.
Sounds a hell of a lot better than
what you've got him doing here.
You going to let her talk like that
to your mother?
Come on, Micky.
I told you, we're together.
This is my girlfriend. I want her here.
I have done everything.
Everything I could for you, Micky.
This MTV girl comes along...
Stop calling me an MTV girl,
whatever the fuck that means.
- Skank.
- Wild.
I've been doing this over fifteen years.
She comes in, disrespects me...
She don't mean no disrespect, okay?
I had a chance to get paid to train year-round.
Year-round, okay?
That's all she's talking about.
I would hope that you guys
could appreciate that.
I know what you're talking about, all right?
I could have had that.
You know, I had opportunities
like maybe you're going to have.
Now, you want money
so you can train year-round? Yeah?
I'll get you money
so you can train year-round.
- You?
- Yeah, I'll do it.
- Trust me.
- How?
Hey, trust me, all right?
Done.
All right? Charlene?
Yeah? Everyone?
So you put in $200...
Then you get ten other people
to put in $200...
And you've got your $2000.
- Everybody give you $200?
- No, not everybody. Just ten of you.
Ten lucky ones.
- You'll rip us off.
- No, no.
- Give me another $200.
- You give me $200!
No, you get that from ten other people
who you offer the opportunity to.
Right? You understand? No?
He thinks you think
Cambodian people are stupid.
I love Cambodian people!
I mean, look. Look at Karen.
She's my girlfriend.
She's beautiful. I love her.
And Brian. We work on a road crew together.
Not so much lately.
Brian, we work on a road crew together.
You haven't been showing up,
that's what I'm saying.
This isn't any kind of Cambodian thing.
White people do this to other white people.
- It's what makes the world go around.
- I don't think that's helping.
This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity...
I mean, they didn't understand.
They're practically on my game...
Usually they listen to what I say,
but they just didn't understand
the opportunity. I mean, it was awesome.
What were we talking about?
- Before you fought Sugar Ray.
- Right, right, right.
Sugar Ray was too much, too soon.
I needed to build up slow.
- What's this movie about again?
- I told you, it's about crack addiction.
Showing what it really is
so kids can see it for real.
Fuck.
We've got to get Mick's money.
Yeah!
That was awesome!
- Get out of the car!
- Oh, shit!
Put your hands on the roof!
Put your hands on the roof, that's it!
- Empty your pockets.
- Are you a cop?
Get on the fucking sidewalk, move!
Fucking move! Don't turn around!
Don't turn around!
We'll have to take your vehicle.
- How am I going to get home?
- That's your problem.
How much we got here? Count it.
What the fuck?
That's the guy!
He did it to me and he's doing it again!
Get on the ground right now!
Open the door!
I've got to get off the fucking street!
I'm trying to get off the fucking street!
It's Dicky. The cops are fucking punching him.
They're beating him. He needs help.
Stay here. Don't get up. Stay here.
Listen to him. Stay right here.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Hey what the fuck?
Come on.
Just put him in the car.
You don't need to do that.
Want to get involved?
Now you're involved.
He's a fighter.
Break his fucking hands
Micky your hand...
Your hand...
Separate cars, separate cells.
I don't want them making up
some bullshit defense story.
Come on, folks, time to go home.
Let's go.
- Hey, Dicky!
- What the fuck, man?
- Dicky!
- Jesus Christ.
His hands...
Welcome back, Dicky.
That's 27 arrests.
Ward: One count of disturbing the peace,
released on your own recognizance.
Eklund: Three counts of assault
and battery on a police officer,
two counts of resisting arrest,
two counts of larceny from a person,
two counts of impersonating
a police officer.
Bail set at $25,000.
Case continued two weeks from today.
I'm wondering about the File 357.
I need a copy of the discovery report,
as well.
- You're going to say it was self-defense, right?
- What?
You're going to say it was self-defense, right?
You came outside, you seen them beating on me.
I didn't do nothing.
I was just waiting outside like anybody else.
Mick, I was doing it for you.
- You did it for me?
- Yes.
Do me a favor. Don't do fucking
nothing for me no more, okay?
- I'm fucking done lying for you.
- What are you going to do without me, huh?
Huh?
This ain't how it was going to go down.
They should have just put me in the car, huh?
Mick, come on! Mick!
Dicky, hey! What's up, Dicky?
Hey, that's the man!
- Hey!
Hey, you knocked out Sugar Ray!
Dicky! Dicky! Dicky!
Who is it?
I don't want to see you, Micky.
Charlene...
I can't take it.
I'm not going to let you
or your family drag me down.
I'm quitting, Charlene, okay?
I'm done fighting.
I don't need it anymore.
- That's fucking stupid.
- What? Why?
Because it's sad that you let them take it
away from you with their stupid bullshit.
What else I can do, Charlene?
There's a lot you can do, Micky.
There's this guy that your dad wants you to meet,
you just don't think you can do it without Dicky.
Charlene...
- Don't call.
- Come on.
Don't call me, okay?
Hey, Dicky, you hurt bad?
Poor fucker.
Hey, Micky, bring another bucket, huh?
Good.
And this Friday,
an HBO original documentary.
Right here in Lowell, Mass.,
the story of Dick Eklund,
the once promising boxer who turned criminal.
Oh, look who it is.
That's...
That's Dicky's brother.
- Hey, Micky.
- Regular.
Hey.
- Hey, what's up, man?
- Look who's here.
- Good to see you, bro.
- How you doing?
How you feeling?
How's the hand?
- Uh, it's getting there.
- Looks better.
Why don't you come down to the gym?
We'll work out, if you want.
- You fat fuck, you're getting big.
- Yeah, I know. It's just...
Roofing for my father and
spending more time with Kasie.
By the way, this movie on HBO, man.
What are you boys looking at?
The movie's not about him.
It's about his crazy brother.
I should go.
- Come back to the gym, Mick.
- Bye, Mick.
Don't go watch that crazy shit on TV.
Don't.
Going to Hollywood...
Let's get this started!
Lowell was the birthplace of
the Industrial Revolution in America.
- Oh, that's...
- These people came to find...
I used to live over there.
This town's got good memories, right?
- Check it out.
- Fuck yeah.
This house right up this way,
the white house...
- Oh, yeah!
- First time I got my crack over here.
Did you ever know they
smoke crack at the white house?
The first time I did crack or whatever,
I was about twenty-three.
A friend of mine gave me a gram or whatever.
Fuck I wish that never happened.
Before that,
I'd be doing the silver mittens and stuff.
I was the only kid.
I'd be twelve. I'm shit-faced.
I'll tell you how crack was.
It enters your lungs.
When it enters your lungs,
- I want to watch Daddy.
- Oh, my God.
- No, sweetie. You go back upstairs.
- But I want to watch Daddy on TV.
No, you can't.
You can't watch Daddy now, all right?
You go back upstairs and go to bed, okay?
Okay, this is my boy, here. Check it out.
What... What can I sell you today?
A python?
Yeah, check it out, man.
They're going to buy me some.
It's been a while.
I'll take anything right now.
Never thought I'd kiss a fucking snake.
I always dreamed about it, but...
You do a lot of shit when you're high, right?
Heck, yeah.
Put it all on the map.
You knocked Sugar Ray Leonard down,
didn't you say?
Yeah, he knocked him down,
but I don't think it was a knockout.
- I think he slipped.
- He knocked him down.
- He didn't slip.
- He slipped.
- Oh, Jack...
- Come on.
That's a fucking lie!
They say he's in trouble with drugs...
What are you doing?
Are you talking shit about the family?
- No, not at all.
- Yeah. I heard you say.
We're not like that.
This is not what Lowell is all about.
I thought he could make a comeback
and make us proud, but he didn't.
- I don't know what Dicky was thinking.
- Very disappointing.
You brought the city of Lowell
back thirty years. We're not happy.
- Hello?
- Jimmy.
Hey, will you do me a favor?
Make sure Kasie's not watching HBO?
Actually, we were watching it right now, Mick,
but don't worry about it.
I got it...
I want her to see it.
Let her see who her uncle is.
- What?
- Who you are.
Who I am?
What are you talking about?
- Kids need to know the truth, Mick.
- Laurie, turn it off, please.
She does not need to see this.
She doesn't need to see it. She's a kid.
If you're on crack,
you feel so much lighter.
You know, you feel young.
And everything is so funny.
Everything is just...
Everything is...
It wasn't funny.
And then it fades,
then you've got to get high again.
Your part of the movie's going to end
with you going to jail.
We know Dicky.
We're going to take care of him, huh?
You guys can't talk to him.
Turn that shit off.
Turn this off, all right?
Turn it off.
Will you turn this off?
I'm turning it fucking off.
Hey, that's my life.
That's my fucking life up there.
- I want to watch this.
- I don't care. I will fuck you up.
You fucking want some?
Don't fucking try me.
I still fucking won it, okay?
You fucking want some?
That's my son there.
You're laughing at him?
That's my son, he's crying, he needs me,
and I'm fucking stuck in here?
Micky, are you watching this?
What are they doing to us?
I don't know what to tell you.
You're pretending like you don't know what's going on.
He's been doing this for years.
Yeah, I know it's horrible, Mom.
What do you think?
- You think they set him up?
- Mom, what do you think he was doing?
You know, they gave him money,
gave him drugs for the movie, right?
Micky?
- You got a new bag, huh?
- Yup.
- New bracket, too?
- What happened to the peanut?
- Don't know.
Like a beach ball.
Good job.
- Mick, Sal Lanano.
- Hey, Mick. How you doing?
- You own the cab company. Good businessman, right?
- He's very organized.
- How's the hand?
- It's good, you know?
It's getting better. Stronger.
You know, I made a few calls already.
I just talked to Buddy Tags.
He said he can set up something local.
You know, something to start back with.
- Get your confidence back.
- That's it. You've got to get your confidence back.
That's all.
Your dad wants Sal to manage you,
and he wants me to train you,
but he'll only do it on one condition.
- No crazy time nonsense.
- That's how it's got to be.
- No Dicky, no Alice.
I get it. I get it. I'm good. I understand.
Look, I appreciate the opportunity.
Can't take the bullshit, Mick.
No offense, George.
None taken. I mean, I'm going to be
the one that gets his balls cut off anyway.
Yeah, you laugh.
- You traitor!
- What are you doing?
What the hell's the matter with you?
Did that hurt? I hope it hurt!
- Sal Lanano is a good man!
- A good man?
- He's a legitimate businessman!
- Legitimate businessman?
- What?
- Oh, my God, you know what that sounds like?
- He's a crook, George!
- He owns a taxicab company!
- He's organized!
- Oh, my God, he's a cab driver.
- He knows everything about boxing, right?
- Yes.
I don't think so! I think he's going to
steal your son's money and rob him blind!
Why would you think that?
Why would you even think that?
- Why can't you trust anybody?
- I know people.
I know, George. You think I don't
know anything. But I know people.
- I know you know things...
- And that Sal Lanana banana fucking thing...
- We don't need that in our lives!
- We haven't made one dollar with these kids.
- You betrayed me. You betrayed me.
- Oh, bullshit, I betrayed you.
- You're always have to say...
- He's a fucking crook!
What's Micky supposed to do?
Dicky's in jail.
We're not talking about his trainer, sweetheart.
We're talking about his manager, that's me!
Yeah, but Mom, maybe Micky should
try something different...
What are you doing,
opening your mouth in my kitchen?
You owe me $200.
I said I was going to pay you next week.
I don't want another word out of you.
That was last month you told me two weeks.
Do you take sides against me in my own house?
You owe me money?
Mom's been great to Micky, Sherri.
Really, who's going to look after Micky
better than his own mother?
It's that fucking girl, Charlene.
We've got to get rid of her, Mom.
We've got to get rid of her.
It's that girl, Charlene. She's got to go.
You're going to get Charlene involved in this?
Is that what you're all telling me?
- Huh?
- I know where she lives.
What are you picking on her for?
- She lives in that yellow house on Steven Street.
- Yeah, the puke yellow.
I'm going to talk to Micky.
Sort this out for myself.
Yeah, sure. You go handle it with
your vigilantes. This is wrong, Alice!
- I got it.
- Get out of my way!
Get in the car.
Micky, are you in there?
Up in there on the second floor.
Micky!
Where the hell are you, huh?
Are you up there? Come on down.
Where are you?
Holy shit, Micky.
Your mother and your sisters are here.
No, no.
Do not go out there, please.
No, I'm not hiding
from your crazy fucking family.
Hi.
Well, well, well. Look at this.
Look at what?
Why are you hiding from us, Micky?
- He's not hiding.
- I wasn't talking to you.
I was talking to my son.
- What are you doing next to her?
- I'm right here. I ain't hiding from nobody, Alice.
Well you're not helping yourself with
your father's scumbag friend, Lanano.
What are you going to do?
Turn your back on Dicky next, huh?
All we ever wanted for you
was to be world champion.
Micky's a grown man.
He can think for himself.
- Shut your mouth.
- Skank!
Don't call me skank. I'll rip that
nasty hair right out of your fucking head.
- I'm his mother and his manager.
- You're not my manager anymore.
And I'm not waiting for Dicky, okay?
I'm not getting any younger.
- Who's going to look after you, sweetheart?
- How about me?
I know you don't understand it
but I had nine kids,
and I love every one of you the same.
You've got a funny way of showing it,
letting him get beat up,
- letting him get his hand broken.
- You're crazy.
What did I just say to you?
Let go!
Fuck!
Get the fuck out of here! Now!
Fuck you, Charlene!
- Skank!
- I want them the fuck out of here.
- You're fucking dead.
- Fucking bitch!
Gail! Oh, my God.
What did she do to your nose?
Let's get the hell out of here.
What's happening to everybody?
I don't understand, sweetheart.
Why do you think I spell my name with an "E"?
Because I don't.
- "No E" Micky Ward.
- Hey, somebody push that.
- Where are we going?
- To the ring. The ring's across the street.
- The ring's across the street?
- Yeah.
Smaller venue. They've got
no dressing rooms over there.
It's a starter, Micky.
Hey.
Good luck.
That's it. That's it.
Yeah!
Visit for Dick Eklund.
Dicky!
Heard you won a bunch of fights, Mick.
That's good.
I know you know what I'm doing.
I'm sure Alice and everybody else told you.
I just wanted to tell you to your face myself.
I've got a new manager and
Mickey O'Keefe's my trainer now.
It's going good.
Yeah. They've got you fighting Alfonso Sanchez.
- On HBO.
- Bet you're proud of that.
- Fucking right.
- HBO is the best at the Mexican fight. Wake up.
I didn't think they were
going to be invested in me.
- I've got a shot. I'm going to take it.
- Wake up.
They don't care if it kills you.
Mike Toma did it. He's using you.
Like a stepping stone for Sanchez.
- Why don't you see?
- Oh, I see.
How could I stand a chance without
the great Dick Eklund in my corner, right?
You didn't give a fuck if I got
killed by Mungin,
now, all of the sudden, you're worried
Sanchez is going to hurt me?
Why?
Come on, Dick. Because you're stuck in here
and can't be the center of attention no more?
- You need it that bad?
- It's a Mexican fight.
He fights you,
hits like a fucking mule, all right?
Fifteen counts undefeated. You crazy?
And that taxicab idiot, Lanano?
He went right for it.
He's a paper gangster.
He's using you to steal money.
Why can't you just shut up
and be happy for me?
I've spent the last ten years of my life
in bad fights set up by you and Alice.
I've finally got a good thing going for me,
and you can't be fucking happy for me? Why?
What's your plan?
How are you going to fight Sanchez?
I ain't going to talk about that.
What's your plan?
- I'm not here to talk about that.
- Bullshit. Yes you are.
You watch the fight and you'll see the plan.
I can't watch it. They don't let us.
It's too fucking violent, you know?
Two minutes, Dicky.
They let us watch a stupid documentary about crack,
but I can't watch my own brother fighting.
Hey, Mick. What is it?
You scared? You embarrassed because you don't
even have a plan? I'm your brother. Just tell me.
- You're going to shit on it no matter what I say.
- I'm not going to shit on it. Just tell me.
Go toe-to-toe, overhand right in middle rounds.
He's weak against overhand right.
- Who came up with that? Fatty fuck O'Keefe?
- Fuck you, Dicky.
You've got to run against this guy.
Let him burn himself out.
Take it to the body, right?
Get inside, switch stances
like you're going to work his right.
Hit him on the left.
You ain't me.
Okay, you can't be me.
You had a hard enough time being you
when you had your fucking chance,
and that's why you're in here, all right?
I'll fight Sanchez the way I fight.
I'm talking about the way you fight,
you moron!
- You know I'm right. He knows I'm right.
- All right.
Blow to the right.
Ward just in.
29 wins, 7 losses so far.
Twenty KOs. He's been a little better
since he refocused himself on the sport,
as J.B. pointed out.
Now here's Ward's opponent, Alfonso Sanchez,
out of Tijuana, Mexico.
See the record, 16 wins, 15 KOs,
8 first-round KOs.
There's Mike Toma, the promoter of the fight,
who has a lot invested in Sanchez.
He says that Sanchez is one of the most
talented young prospects
in the sport of boxing.
This is really one of the saddest
kinds of fights in boxing.
Micky Ward is 31 years old.
He's here because he needs the money.
- He's taking a beating.
- My point is that
he doesn't really have to sit here
and take this beating.
- He can do something about it.
- Which is what?
- Have his corner throw in the towel?
- Or fight back.
You can see his power.
Every time he hits Ward, he backs him up.
- Unless the referee thinks he can't...
- The referee should just stop this fight.
We know that Micky doesn't want to be here.
- I wouldn't make the crowd...
- No, he's fighting scared, Dick.
Running away, not hitting back.
Oh, Jesus. He's going to get hurt.
Doing the same old shit.
Never seen such an embarrassing performance.
He's doing what I told him, Mom.
He's doing what I told him.
Don't worry about it.
Micky Ward showing nothing but respect.
What are you running around for?
Stop running around.
Shut the fuck up, Sal.
Shut the fuck up!
I don't know what you're doing, Micky.
You want to fucking tell me?
Because I don't know what you're doing.
We'd have lost all five rounds.
Is that what you want?
This is dreadful, dreadful stuff.
You've got to show me something soon,
Mick, or I'm going to stop the fight.
They're going to stop the fight, Micky.
He's got to go inside, Mom.
He's got to take it to the body.
He's got it.
- Don't stop the fight.
- They're going to stop this fight.
You've got to do something, baby.
You've got to do something.
Try what we talked about, Micky.
We had a plan, and you're not doing it.
- Let's go.
- All right, Micky.
You've lost the first five rounds,
what's the next strategy going to be?
Double right hand by Sanchez,
then a triple left hook.
Couple of the left hooks landed flush
on the cheek of Micky Ward.
Ward tying Sanchez up.
Very curious performance by Micky Ward.
Ward seems to be trying to land one big shot
to either change Sanchez's mind...
And he's beginning to open up, taking
advantage of opportunities to get close to Ward
and throw against a fighter who is
not defending himself by punching.
Sanchez is going to try to end this fight.
What are you doing? Come on.
Come on!
He's down on an uppercut.
Nicely thrown left uppercut inside.
Very good. And right after Ward
threw a pretty good right hand.
Mick, you all right?
This is a fight that should be stopped.
- Come on, head, body, head.
- Ugh.
- This is not professional.
- That's exactly what I'm saying.
I sure wish they paid me to watch this.
Come on, Mick!
Head, body, head.
That was a good body shot by Ward.
- Maybe he'll turn it around.
- I'm talking about his body shot.
Sanchez dropped by that shot!
Oh, my God!
What a punch!
The most unlikely knockout
you have ever seen!
That is a kidney shot,
The kind of kidney shot that's not as severe...
Yeah!
I still don't believe what I just saw!
Micky! Micky! Micky!
Micky won!
Now did Micky Ward just make idiots of us all
with a spectacular piece of strategy?
- Take another look.
- Amazing.
A big win in the career of Micky Ward
of Lowell, Mass.
Unbelievable defeat at the hands of Micky Ward,
who had all but given away the first
half dozen rounds in the bout.
I think what Micky did was he recognized
that he'd hurt the guy with the body shot.
Micky's a better fighter than that
to not be running from that guy like that.
Theater of the unexpected.
Hey, you never know
what can happen, right?
Never give up in this game, right?
Never give up.
You can't make it up, folks.
You know what Micky just said?
He said you can't give up in this game.
Well maybe Micky Ward heard me say
he should stop this fight,
- and he went out and stopped it.
- Yeah.
I can't believe it.
I'm looking over and I'm thinking
to myself like they were thinking:
This thing is over.
But I tell you what.
Even look at the commentators.
They started to take their headsets off
before he was even counted out.
- They just wanted to get out of there.
- Mick. Mick...
I just spoke to Mike Toma again and
he just told me something very interesting.
He just told me, had Sanchez won tonight,
he would have gotten the title shot.
- Holy Christ, that's beautiful.
- Why? Why is that beautiful?
- A title shot.
- Micky gets the shot.
- Are you sure about that?
- You've got to be very clear about this,
- because this is my kid's future.
- I just spoke to the guy.
- Mike, come here. Look, tell these guys.
- Hey. Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Not a stepping stone anymore.
I always knew you had the talent.
That was a hell of a strategy,
wearing him down like that
and taking it to the body.
Thirty years in the business,
I've never seen a knockout like that.
Larry Merchant was writing your obituary
and Sanchez drops like he was shot with a gun.
Where did you get that?
That's the first thing my brother taught me.
Tap them to the head, dig into the body.
- That's a hell of a body shot.
- Thank you.
You ready for a title shot?
- Yes!
- That's what I was talking about.
- He's ready. You're ready, aren't you?
Shea Neary in London for the title!
Are you kidding me?
We've got some celebrating to do.
- Yeah, I think so.
- Thank you so much.
You're going to have
a great champion, my boy.
It's what your brother
would have always wanted.
He's not even going to be there.
- Hey!
- Daddy!
- Hey there, buddy.
- Daddy, Daddy!
Good to see you! Oh!
That's a good hug!
That's a good hug! Oh yeah!
- Sweetheart!
- Hi, Mom.
Oh, you look so good.
Oh, my God.
- You have clean teeth.
- I do! Look at my teeth!
I got new teeth. Everything.
How do you think I look?
- Good.
- Yeah?
- Are you going to carry me?
- No.
And more cake. Ice cream...
- Ice cream with cake.
- Ice cream with cake and cake and cake.
Ice cream, cake and cake.
Quacker!
Mom.
- They gave you some new teeth, huh?
- Yeah.
- Hey, George. They let you out of the house now?
- Ha, yeah.
- Run him out of the house, Mom?
- Hey, look. I want you to meet Sal Lanano.
How you doing, Dicky?
Let's spar, huh?
Hi, Charlene.
- Welcome back!
- Shh! It's supposed to be a surprise!
I'm running late.
- Hey.
Mick, I can't even tell you.
Being back in this smelly-ass locker room...
Getting back with you is what got me through.
You look good. Your eyes are clear.
- Yeah?
- You know...
Alice says prison might have been
the best thing for me.
It got me clean. Got me clear up here.
It's a beautiful thing, Dick.
I've got to talk to you about something.
Yeah.
The old locker, huh?
I made a promise to them
I wouldn't work with you again.
Huh?
I had to, after everything that happened.
I'm sorry.
You sticking to that?
I'm glad you're back.
You look good.
I don't know what else to say.
- Mick, you fucking kidding me?
- No, I'm not.
- Hey, Micky.
- Micky, come on in.
You're too loud.
You've got to do this at home, please.
- What are you talking about?
- Mom, please.
All right, girls. Let's pack it up.
- Why?
- Let's get it put away.
If that's what Micky wants,
we're going to put it away.
- There's your brother.
- Dicky!
Hey there. Hey there.
It's nice. It's nice.
- Been working on it for two weeks.
- Hey, Sherri, come on. Stop.
All right, girls, come on. Let's go home.
It's not the time to do this, obviously.
- What's going on?
- We ain't going to work together.
They don't want me to work with him.
What are you talking about?
That's not right.
Micky never would have
won Sanchez without Dicky.
- That's fucking bullshit! Take it back!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
- Don't you fucking talk to my mother like that.
- Fuck you!
Why don't you ask Micky?
We're going to train. They've got to go.
They've got to go, Mick.
Come on.
- You all right?
- Ask him, George.
Ask him if he would have won Sanchez
without his brother.
No, I wouldn't have won Sanchez
if it wasn't for Dicky.
- How can you say that to O'Keefe?
- Because it's true.
I went in with our game plan and it wasn't working
so I went back to what I learned with Dicky.
And I wouldn't have won without you,
either, O'Keefe, okay?
I mean, you know that.
We worked hard. You got me ready.
You got your confidence
and your focus from O'Keefe,
and from Sal,
and from your father, and from me.
- Dicky is a junk bag.
- Hey!
He's a junk bag!
- Fuck you, Charlene.
- Oh, fuck you!
I'm sober.
Oh, yeah. And I'm sure you're going to need
something for something now that you're out.
- "Oh, my back! Oh, my back!"
- Fuck you!
- What are you always picking on me for, huh?
- No, fuck you!
And what about O'Keefe?
We're in the same boat.
One day at a fucking time, right, O'Keefe?
You and me.
It's all right for him to be here?
Why am I the fucking problem?
- I'm his blood! I'm his family!
- You're the problem!
I'm the one fighting, okay?
Not you, not you, and not you.
- I know what I need.
- And you need Dicky?
I want Dicky back.
And I want you, Charlene,
and I want O'Keefe.
I want my family.
What's wrong with that?
- Not the deal we made, baby.
- She's right, Micky.
- That's not the deal.
- It wasn't the deal.
Come on, you can't do this to us.
You sound like them now.
- I sound like them now?
- Yeah, you sound like them.
- We sound like them?
- You can't do this to us. You can't do this to us.
You sound like them.
You should fucking listen to yourself.
You sound like them, just like them.
Maybe this is where you belong.
- That's the way you love him?
- Charlene!
- Come on!
- You want your brother? Good luck.
- O'Keefe, come on...
- Micky.
Micky...
Come on,
everything happens for a reason.
You know, maybe it's for the best.
God has a plan.
Want to spar with your brother?
Dick Eklund, Pride of Lowell.
Watching that for years, huh?
Whoa, hey, what the hell are you doing?
- Micky, for crying out loud!
- Daddy, Daddy, Daddy!
Take that baby out of here.
I told you take him away ten minutes ago!
Sweetheart, are you all right?
You okay? Your back?
What are you doing?
What's the matter with you?
Will it be my fight, Alice? Huh?
Just once? Maybe just
this one time, not for Dicky?
Huh?
I know you think he's coming back,
but he's forty years old and he doesn't have
a tooth in his head that's his fucking own.
Let your brother talk
for a minute here, all right?
- What are you saying, sweetheart?
- Shut up before I bust your fucking head open, Dicky.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- What are you going to do?
- You want me to bust your fucking head open?
- Come on! Come on! George!
- Please! Please!
- Dicky!
What are you saying, sweetheart?
Tell me what you're saying.
This is supposed to be my fight.
- This is my shot at a title.
- It is your fight.
I won't get another one after this.
Am I being selfish?
Am I saying "Micky! Micky! Micky!"?
Because you know what?
If I am, I'm sorry.
I thought I was fighting for the championship.
And I thought you were my mother, too.
I am your mother.
Mick, I'm sorry. I had no idea
you felt like that, all right?
If I made mistakes,
I'm going to be better.
I don't want to hurt you.
I am so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Dicky!
Stay with him.
- Dicky!
- Got to do something.
Dicky, wait. Come on.
Micky wants you. I want you.
- I've got to do something.
- I know what that means. Don't do this!
Hey, Jim.
- Smart.
- Hey, Dicky.
- Hey, Dicky's back!
- Yay!
- Hey!
- Dicky!
- Look at you!
- Look at my boy, huh?
Come over here.
You look good. Welcome back.
- Yeah, you're looking good.
- You look great.
Good to see you.
- Welcome home.
- Hi, honey.
What's up, man? You're looking good.
So, want to head up there?
Dicky's back!
Go upstairs, take a while, huh?
- Throw a little party for you, babe.
- Hey, come back!
- The fuck was that all about?
- What the hell was that?
Charlene, it's Dicky.
Get off my porch, you piece of shit.
How fucking dare you come?
Cock sucker!
Fucking boy!
Fucking ass!
Fucking sick!
You're a fucking asshole, Dicky.
I want you off my fucking porch.
Huh? Why don't you just fucking
come down here and talk to me, huh?
You're such an asshole,
coming to my fucking house.
- You piece of shit, standing on my porch!
- Sorry, sorry.
It's not fucking ladylike to be shouting
in the street like this, all right?
- You're such a fucking cock sucker, coming over here.
- Please!
- Oh yeah? You think I fucking care?
- Come on. Just fucking...
Get off my fucking porch, Dicky.
What kind of dog is that?
Is that a cocker spaniel?
All right,
I know you can't fucking stand me.
- Really, what makes you say that?
- I got news for you, all right?
My brother loves you,
and you can't just run away because of me.
You don't deserve that, all right?
So I will quit if you want me to quit.
- You're full of shit.
- I swear to God.
I will quit if it means
you'll come back, all right?
But I want you to
think about something.
Micky has a chance to do
something that I never did,
that in my time, I never had.
Oh... "Yeah, my big chance was with
Sugar Ray Leonard. I'm so great."
"I'm the Pride of fucking Lowell.
Oh yeah, I fought Sugar Ray Leonard."
- I've heard it.
- I came to make things right with you.
Okay, let's make things right.
Number one:
You didn't knock down
Sugar Ray Leonard. He tripped.
I was in the ring. Don't you think I know
what really fucking happened that day?
- What have you ever done with your life?
- I like my life.
- Yeah? What have you ever done with it?
- I like my life now, Dicky.
What have you ever done with your life?
You're a college dropout, Charlene.
You're just a little bar girl. Your life sucks.
All right.
I drink too much.
I worked in a lot of bars.
And I ruined a lot of opportunities,
but I'm trying to do better here.
- So is Micky.
- So am I.
And he needs me, you heard him.
And I know he needs you.
What is that blue shit on your arm?
It's icing.
Okay.
I'll see you in Micky's corner.
Otherwise, go fuck yourself.
- It's a deal.
- All right, it's a deal.
We worked it out for you. Ask her.
Good. Go get O'Keefe back, too.
I will.
Hey, Mick.
Do you think I knocked down
Sugar Ray Leonard?
You went ten rounds. One of the best
to do anything to hurt him.
You're my hero.
I was.
I was...
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah?
There's a press conference downstairs.
- Come on. Let's go.
- Guys...
Neary: Ten stone, six pounds.
Ward: Ten stone, six pounds.
Hey, Micky. Micky Ward!
We have a question over here.
How have you been training?
- I train. I train hard.
- Shea's 22 in 0. Never been knocked down.
Well that's going to change tomorrow.
In fact we expected a much better fighter.
I'm just grateful to be here and have
the opportunity. Thank you, guys, for the shot.
Shea, who do you respect as a fighter?
And who would you like to fight next?
I plan on moving
right through Micky Ward tomorrow,
moving on to other big fighters,
like Gatti.
I believe Gatti and I would
make a great match.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
twelve rounds of boxing
for the WBU Welterweight
Championship of the World!
Don't listen to them, Mick.
And there is Micky Ward
of Lowell, Massachusetts entering the ring.
It's his first fight outside the United States.
Micky Ward, 30 wins, 7 losses....
He's back and better, recently.
Twenty KOs.
And now Ward awaits his opponent,
Shea Neary.
Neary regards himself as
the European Arturo Gatti,
meaning that he is a head-on
high-contact fighter
who throws seventy punches per round.
Neary is from Liverpool and should
have a huge following her tonight.
Accompanied by "Paint the Town Red"
by the Mahones.
Neary is the current
Welterweight Champion of the World.
He is a very tough young man.
Beyond dedicated. Lives a spartan existence.
And according to his promoters,
there's nothing but eat, drink, think,
fantasize and dream of fighting.
Shea Neary has had 22 professional fights
and won them all.
Seventeen KOs.
Start when you hear the bell.
Shake hands.
Both of you. Shake hands.
As close as we just saw them in the middle
of the ring, forehead to forehead.
That's how close we expect them to be
for as long as this fight goes on.
Ward is a long ways from home.
Don't coast in a foreign country.
Well the big challenge for Ward is to get off
to a faster start than is customary for him.
Micky Ward a notoriously slow starter
in big fights.
Shea Neary an ultra-fast starter.
And that's the question that hovers
over round one. Get ready for the fight.
Already Shea Neary starts
taking it to him on the ropes.
And Neary going to the body,
which is Ward's specialty.
- Whoa!
- Neary bangs Ward to the body.
- And a big uppercut by Neary.
- Neary leads off with a good left jab.
Keeps opponents off balance,
jabbing here and there.
That was a good left hook by Neary
as he stepped in on Ward.
Ward not able to deal with him very well
when Neary stands at range like this.
- Come on!
- That's it! Get him!
My, is it tough for Micky Ward.
Neary digging his own right hand to the body.
They trade shots at close range.
Ward is trying to match Neary blow-for-blow,
and now Neary starts to come on
and take the last thirty seconds to the round.
- How about that!
- Break!
Tremendous barrage in the first minute.
Just look at this. Unbelievable.
What a great round one!
Ward is going to have to
pick up the tempo
and beat him with volumes of punching.
No doubt Neary is a better boxer.
Four hard right hands
Neary has belted in the last minute.
Quicker than Ward, more assertive than Ward.
Surer of what he wants to do.
They're standing and trading shots
at the center of the ring.
Ward's going to have to step it up
a little bit more than he is right now.
Micky Ward's corner taking
a really deep look at what's going on now,
and his family at ringside
well aware he's stepping up in class.
Ward has to got to be more aggressive.
He can't just try to wait until
everything is perfect.
Despondence over Micky Ward
is increasing as the fight goes on
because his plan was the right one
and he's executing it.
Punches like these make it seem
that it's now Neary's fight.
Ward hasn't been in this kind of war
with as strong a fighter as Neary.
They are trying to hurt each other
with only punches.
They've tested each other's will,
now they're testing each other's skill.
And Ward fumbled there
by a right cross from Neary.
- Ward hurting now, his legs are gone.
- Neary goes to the body as he tries to finish Micky.
- Vicious body shots from Neary.
- And Ward doesn't even try to move off the ropes.
I don't know if he can, Jeff.
He's waiting for Neary to punch himself out.
Down goes Micky Ward, and he may be out.
Come on, that's it!
That's my boy!
Forward! Forward!
Come on!
- Ward is out on his feet!
- Loser! Go back to America!
This could be it for Micky Ward.
Dicky, get him a fucking stool
Where's the stool?
Charlene, will you get the fuck
out of here with your high heels?
His brother's got Ward jumping
to wake up his legs.
I think this could be Ward's last chance
to turn this fight around.
It's Micky Ward against the aggressiveness
and clean punching of Shea Neary.
If you don't have your defense up
you can really get hurt.
He's making it very difficult for Micky Ward.
I don't think he's going to give it to him,
at this rate.
This is a survival move.
Are you like me? Huh?
Just good enough to fight Sugar Ray?
I never had to win, did I?
You've got to do more than that.
You've got to win a title.
For you, for me, for Lowell.
This is your time, all right?
You take it.
I had my time, and I blew it.
You don't have to, all right?
Now fucking get out there.
Bring that fucking anger.
All the shit you've been through
over the fucking years,
put it in the ring right now.
This is yours. This is fucking yours.
- Okay.
- Fucking head, body, head, body.
- Say it back to me.
- Head, body, head, body.
You can do it.
Stay off the fucking ropes.
If I'm in Micky Ward's corner tonight,
I'm thinking if he doesn't pick things up
this round and get going,
he'll just get totally wiped out.
Get off the ropes!
Get off the ropes, Mick!
Once again, Ward against the ropes
as Neary is free to attack.
What are you doing?
Come on, Mick...
Sometimes if you want to win,
you've got to be something that you're not.
Off the fucking rope, man!
That ain't it!
Neary continues to pound away.
Don't take no abuse!
This is your time, Micky!
It's all for you!
- Two big misses by Neary.
- That's it! That's it!
Ward seemingly getting his legs back.
Now he backs Neary up.
Ward trades his way back.
Ward nods as if to say "Come on!".
"Come on, let's fight!"
Closer and closer to Neary's ribcage.
This is becoming Micky Ward's fight.
And a left hook to the body,
and an uppercut lands,
and now he backs Neary up.
Ward hits Neary with a body shot.
Four left hooks in the body.
Neary on his butt,
first time in 23 professional fights
that Shea Neary has gone down.
This is it! This is it, Micky!
23 seconds remain in this round
as Micky now wipes off Neary's gloves.
Ward lands a huge left hook
as Micky Ward works away.
Blows to the body with the left hook.
There's the uppercut again!
Gonna stop it right there.
"Irish" Micky Ward with a big
eighth-round TKO!
He's done it again.
They grinding gutting Micky Ward
pulls out another big victory.
You're the champion of the world, Mick!
You're the fucking champion of the world!
You fucking did it!
My boy's the champion of the world!
I love you!
This town always said
you're a fucking boxer, right?
You thought it's a piece of shit.
- He put Lowell back on the map, you know.
- We did.
- I tell you. No, hold on.
- We.
Who used to be the Pride of Lowell?
Right here.
Who's the Pride of Lowell now?
Right there.
That's how it's meant to be, you know?
Hand it down to him.
Nothing better than that.
Nothing better than that...
He did it.
I've got to go.
Sync, corrected by icephoenix
www.addic7ed.com
Oh, Boo Boo. Quacker!
- Quack! Quack! Quack! Quack!
- Boo Boo...
Boo, where's your teeth?