MAN:
It's a beautiful day.
["BLESSED ASSURANCE" PLAYS]
It's God's good day.
It's a beautiful day.
You know, standing up for God,
it's not an easy thing.
Nobody said it was easy.
It is not easy.
But Jesus, Jesus saved my life.
He saved my life.
I relate it to David,
the psalmist, who said:
Thou hast picked me up
from the dunghill
and placed my feet on a solid rock.
And Jesus,
Jesus, he lifted me up
from a horrible pit as well,
and he washed my heart clean,
and he cleaned me up
from all my sins
and all the evil that I did.
I'm all cleaned up,
and it's a wonderful feeling.
It is wonderful.
And he gave me this message.
He gave me this message to give to you today.
And today, he says:
Go, ye, unto all the world
and spread the gospel,
for he who believes
and is baptized will be saved.
Amen. Amen.
♪ Blessed assurance ♪
♪ Jesus is mine ♪
BILL: As you are buried
with him in baptism,
so you are raised with him by faith
in our Lord, Jesus Christ.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Amen, sister.
♪ Purchase of God ♪
[SOBS THEN LAUGHING]
♪ Born of his spirit ♪
♪ Washed in his blood ♪
[MAN LAUGHING]
♪ This is my story ♪
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
♪ This is my song ♪
Hallelujah.
♪ Praising my savior ♪
♪ All the day long ♪
BILL: Our Lord, Jesus Christ.
♪ This is my story ♪
♪ This is my song ♪
[GASPS THEN WHOOPS]
Again!
♪ All the day long ♪
Corinne?
Yes.
As you are buried with him
through baptism...
Hallelujah.
...so you are raised with him by
faith in our Lord, Jesus Christ.
♪ Burst on my sight ♪
♪ Angels descending ♪
♪ Bring from above ♪
♪ Echoes of mercy ♪
♪ Whispers of love ♪
♪ This is my story
This is my song ♪
WOMAN:
Corinne. You've got chores to do.
CORINNE: He taught them
how to swim and dive.
[PIG SQUEALING]
♪ Praising my savior ♪♪
CW:
Hey, honey.
Oh, please, you're a lot of help.
[LAUGHS]
I was hoping for a little help
myself. I got this problem, lady.
Oh, yeah? Somehow your
problems become my problems.
Shoo. I got a runt in the oven.
I've got work to do.
You do?
Yeah, I do.
Me too.
Ha, ha.
Mm. That tickle?
Stop it, don't tickle there.
[LAUGHING]
I told you don't do that.
Careful, honey. Careful, honey.
Careful, honey.
Ooh. Ooh, ooh.
Ha-ha-ha.
[♪♪♪]
CW: Hop on there, squirt. There you go.
And get that other one. There you go.
Now, arms real straight.
Now, pick her up
and walk. Look at that.
Oh, boy. I got you.
You're like a gigantic monster girl.
Yeah.
Going into town to
cause damage. Ha, ha.
Big trouble.
[CORINNE GROWLS]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[DOOR OPENS]
Hello.
Good afternoon, ma'am.
Let me introduce myself.
Name's Bobbie Lee Moore,
Syracuse Accordion Company.
I'd like to show you an instrument to
bring magic into your little one's life.
How'd you like to play the squeezebox?
This here is the Titano
Palmer-Hughes Grand.
It has all the features
of a full-size accordion.
Forty-one full-length black
and mother-of-pearl keys,
all your sharps, all your flats.
[PLAYING]
Now it's your turn.
KATHLEEN: I'm sorry, but
she's not really musical.
I wouldn't wanna waste your time.
Not to contradict you, but maybe
she hasn't found her instrument.
[PLAYING "MARY HAD
A LITTLE LAMB"]
[PLAYING "YANKEE DOODLE"]
SALESMAN: Wow.
Look at the way you squeeze that box.
What do you think of
the Titano Palmer-Hughes Grand?
It's practically bigger than she is.
She can barely stand up straight.
[SIGHS]
SALESMAN:
Okay.
[GASPS THEN GROANING]
Mama.
KATHLEEN: Oh, darling.
I love you. I love you.
Everything is going to be all right.
[SOBBING]
[♪♪♪]
We'll see you in church on Sunday?
Yes, ma'am.
PASTOR BUD: Oh, it's hot today
here in Vacation Bible School.
Just nod your head
if you're hot today. Yes?
Do you know the Lamb of God?
Do you know that he is knocking
at the door of your heart?
So gentle the way he does it.
Just... so soft.
Gently. Tap, tap, tap.
Can you hear it?
[PASTOR BUD TAPPING MICROPHONE]
Can you hear him there?
Jesus is a gentleman, children.
He's not gonna come barging into
your heart without an invitation.
Won't you open the door for Jesus?
Want you to take
that chain off your door
and lift up that latch
and open that up.
Who's there? It's Jesus.
And he's waiting for you, children.
You're welcome here, dear Lord.
All right, let us
bow our heads and pray.
With everyone's eyes closed now,
no one looking around,
raise your hand
if you made a decision today.
Yes, Pastor Bud,
I opened the door.
I didn't leave Jesus out in the cold.
I wanna go to heaven.
[CHILD SNORTS]
No pig snorting, please.
Little children, this is the time
now to make the decision.
I see you. Does anyone else
think this is the...?
I see you, dear.
Is there anybody else today
who will raise your hand and say:
"This is my day."
To say, "I've been saved."
I see you, dear child.
I see you, sweetheart.
I see you, I see you.
Tim, Corinne, Shelly.
I'll speak to you up here.
Everyone else, as you head out,
do be careful on those steps.
Won't you?
Happy summer.
["HOW GREAT THOU ART" PLAYS]
Now,
I want you to know
what a great day it is
in heaven right now.
Do you know why?
Because we asked Jesus into our heart?
Hearts, moron.
Because you made
the best decision of your lives.
Put your hands together.
You've made the best
decision of your lives.
Don't be ashamed of Jesus, children,
and he won't be ashamed of you.
I want you to tell your mama
and your papa
that your names have
been written in the book of life.
[KATHLEEN SIGHS]
Oh, Kathleen, Kathleen.
All right.
Is it hot enough for you?
I might join my girls
at the pool this afternoon.
Oh, Bathsheba bathing, well...
You like to swim, Pastor Bud?
Oh, I never learned to swim, l...
His power is perfected
in my weakness in that way.
I used to be a lifeguard.
You didn't.
I could teach you.
No.
I could.
I could teach you, yes, I could.
PASTOR BUD: No, I would
just sink like a stone.
You know, the baptism tank,
that's as deep as I could go.
KATHLEEN: Ha-ha-ha.
PASTOR BUD: Never mind about that.
Corinne has some wonderful
news to share with you.
Really, sweetheart?
And Kathleen?
Yes.
I know this has not been
an easy time since you
lost your baby, I know that.
But the Lord can make good
things come out of tragedy.
Your family will be strong now with
God at the center. You know that.
All right, you tell your mama
the good news.
Bye.
Come on, Pookie.
Come on, Wendy.
Let's go swimming, huh?
Okay, so, what's the wonderful news?
Hm?
What is it?
She got saved today.
Saved from what?
I just raised my hand, that's all.
Pastor Bud says Jesus knocks on
our heart, but we don't listen.
Maybe he should try
the doorbell instead.
[♪♪♪]
KATHLEEN: Sally saw you.
CW: What? Sally saw me what?
What, what? What did Sally see?
KATHLEEN: I can't trust you.
CW:
You can't trust me?
KATHLEEN:
You're making me crazy, all right?
You're making me crazy. I am home.
I am the one who's home here.
I'm taking care of these children.
I'm in this crap house.
CW: I'm the one who's out working,
buying your wigs and your car
and your other crap. So, what
is the issue? What did I do?
KATHLEEN: I have made every house
that we have lived in a home.
CW:
Yeah, well, are we...?
KATHLEEN:
Follow around all your crap.
CW:
Yeah, yeah, it's all about me.
What?
CW: All alone.
Yeah, you made us a house, sure, sure.
CW: What is the problem?
What do you want me to say?
KATHLEEN:
Right now, what isn't the problem?
[♪♪♪]
Yeah.
You see how big that guy was?
Jesus Christ.
Hey, guys, I'll catch you in a second.
All right.
Hey. You're the writer,
aren't you?
I write. I mean...
Yeah, you're Corinne Walker, right?
Yeah.
I was just on my way to practice.
Do you know The Renegades?
Uh, of course.
Everyone knows The Renegades.
I'm Ethan.
I know.
So, what are you doing?
Um, I'm waiting for my sister
to finish practice.
I meant, what are you writing?
Oh.
Some words and thoughts.
Thoughts on what?
Mm, disappointment.
Oh.
We should write a song together.
For The Renegades?
Sure. Yeah. But, um...
I'm not musical.
Maybe you haven't found
your instrument yet.
[VEHICLE APPROACHING]
[DOOR OPENS]
[WHISPERING]
Tell her she looks pretty.
Just tell her you love her.
Where you going, wildcat?
Hm? Where do you think you're...?
Move it.
No. Mm-mm.
You're gonna have to get through me.
Ow!
That hurt.
Oh! Don't you dare.
Give me. Give that to me or I'm
gonna kill you. Give me that.
Mine.
[KATHLEEN SOBS]
Damn it!
Oops.
♪ I was anything but free
I was any... ♪
What'd you say, free or me?
Free.
Free, okay.
Free, yeah.
♪ I was anything but free ♪
♪ As far as I could see ♪♪
[IMITATING DRUMS]
Do the drum solo right there
and come back.
I like The Renegades.
I've been to concerts.
I love your music.
Thanks.
WENDY:
Corrine.
I'm the only freshman
to make it on varsity.
Ah.
You're looking at the first guy out in dodge ball.
It's like, every time...
It's instant. It's...
Me too.
I'm always out first. Every single time.
Yeah?
Knew there's a reason
I loved you so much.
I heard what you said.
You said "I love you."
No, I said I liked her
so much, because...
Yeah, okay.
Get lost, Wendy.
Yeah, Wendy.
Go shoot some hoops or something.
No, I run track.
Well, I'm a track monster.
Ew, that's gross.
You guys are disgusting.
Ew.
You guys are full of shit.
All right.
Harmonize with me.
Come on, come on.
[♪♪♪]
♪ I went walking down the road ♪
♪ The road for the blind ♪
♪ For a long, long time ♪
I got you. I got you.
I got you.
♪ I walked alone ♪
[BOTH GRUNTING]
♪ Down that lonely road ♪
♪ No place to go ♪
♪ I was the sea ♪
♪ As cold as I could be ♪
♪ I was anything but free ♪♪
ETHAN:
♪ I could show you how to fly ♪
♪ Charge you by the night ♪
♪ I could take you for a ride ♪
♪ A jog around my mind ♪
♪ You turn the other way ♪
♪ I can tell you're afraid ♪
♪ Put up your guard ♪
♪ It's all up to you ♪
♪ It's all up to you ♪♪
[AUDIENCE CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
[FLY BUZZING]
[ETHAN PANTING
AND MOANING]
[PIG GRUNTING]
[SNORTING]
Oh, honey.
[♪♪♪]
MAN: ♪ Every time I see
your smile I run to you ♪
♪ Every time I hear your voice ♪
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
♪ I dream of you ♪
Hey, honey.
♪ Lady, lady, lady, lady ♪
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
♪ I'm gonna let you
Be my girlfriend ♪
♪ Maybe, maybe, maybe, maybe ♪
[CROWD WHISTLING
AND CHEERING]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
♪ Because when you're there ♪
[SOBBING]
♪ I just don't care
I'm here for you ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
Break it.
[SIGHS THEN GRUNTING]
Oh, damn it.
Fuck.
Thought you wanted to be a rock star.
I did, yeah.
A different kind though, huh?
Whoo!
ETHAN: Abigator, did you
help Mommy with her hair?
[CRYING]
Oh, it's okay.
See? She hates me.
CORINNE: She doesn't hate you.
I work too much.
You see? Right there.
Wendy told me the Jesus
people are in town.
Her friends get high
and go talk to them.
Oh. Jesus freaks
in Ellenville, huh?
[GIGGLES]
[CHUCKLES]
You know, I haven't opened
a Bible since I was a kid.
Listen, I told you
things would get better.
And they will.
Just wanna get some practice time in.
And if I didn't have a baby
to take care of, I'd write a novel,
but this is our life.
At least we have Abby-Fat-Legs.
Ooh, ooh.
You little pork butt.
Look at you. Pbbt. Mwah.
Aah.
Ow.
This is for Abby-Fat-Legs.
Right here.
♪ Traded my guitar
For a chubby baby ♪
♪ Work with them stones
Bring home that gravy ♪
♪ Hair once on my head
Moved down to my chest ♪
♪ You sit at home all day long ♪
♪ With a baby
Sucking on your breast ♪♪
[CRYING]
CORINNE:
Shh.
She needs her own space.
Get a cooler and put her in there.
Just use it as a playpen.
CORINNE:
Mike, I need that cooler.
Not that one, take that one.
That one.
ABIGAIL:
Mama.
[CRYING]
This is a nice bed, huh?
Yeah. Yeah.
This is the last gig
Abby and I are coming to.
MAN 1 : Yo, what up?
MAN 2: Look here.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
MAN 1 : What's going on, man?
MAN 2: Party time.
Check out my poopy pants, yeah.
MAN 1 :
Suck it, bitch!
We're The Renegades!
Suck it!
ETHAN:
Hey, dickhead!
You wanna get us pulled over?
My kid's in the bus.
Fucking cut it out!
MAN 2: Hey!
Hey, fucking cut it out!
MIKE: Oh, no.
ETHAN: Oh, shit!
Ethan.
[CORINNE SHRIEKS]
[♪♪♪]
[MIKE GRUNTING]
MIKE: Where are my drums?
ETHAN: Let's go.
[CORINNE SHOUTS
INDISTINCTLY]
CORINNE:
Abby! Where's...?
Grab the cooler.
ETHAN:
Go, get out.
CORINNE:
Abby!
ETHAN:
You got the cooler?
CORINNE:
Abby!
Ethan! Where is she?
Where is she?
Abby!
ETHAN:
Where's the cooler?!
God!
God, please!
[PANTING]
God saved her, Corinne.
God saved us.
Okay, let's find out
what God has to say.
Well? Read it.
"I will dash your infants
against the rocks."
What?
It's right there.
That's fucked up.
Let's start from the beginning.
[♪♪♪]
[YELLS]
[ALL CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING]
BILL: Praise God.
NED: Praise God.
BILL:
Hallelujah.
This is one fish the Lord has been
trying to hook for a long time.
[MEN LAUGHING]
Oh, yeah, that was wild, you know?
I was just so... Ooh.
I was thinking about
the baby in my womb
and how far God's brought me.
BILL: Praise God.
And my big old happy family.
Aah! What is that?
BILL: They're all God's creatures, Corinne.
They're all God's creatures.
I've been trying to get her in this lake.
She says, "Ooh, not in this ucky lake.
It's not sanitary."
[ALL APPLAUDING]
Come over here.
Newly. Newly.
[SHRIEKS THEN SCREAMS]
Hold on. I'm getting out of here.
Yuck, yuck, yuck.
CONGREGATION:
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My savior God to thee ♪
♪ How great thou art ♪
♪ How great thou art ♪♪
Thank you, Jesus.
How you guys doing?
MAN 1 : Hallelujah.
How are you? Praise God.
[ALL CHEERING]
MAN 1 : Praise God.
Praise the Lord.
Another Sunday
and the saints have gathered.
ALL:
Amen!
BILL: Do not neglect the
assembling of yourselves
as is the habit of some,
but all the more
as the day draws near.
Hebrews 10:25.
And we have assembled ourselves
here today, brothers and sisters,
in God's cathedral.
So beautiful.
BILL: In the splendor of his creation.
Mm.
Martin Luther says
that God writes the gospel
not in the Bible alone,
but also in the trees.
Yeah? In the flowers,
in the clouds, in the stars.
MAN 2: Hallelujah.
BILL: Don't they proclaim
the name of God?
Amen.
BILL: Amen. Amen.
Now, you all know
about Nancy and Al, right?
Yeah.
Uh...
Nancy has decided to take
the kids and move to Buffalo.
It's devastating.
They come in for counseling?
I met with them a few times, but
the damage had already been done.
Their marriage was weakened
by, um, sexual, um, issues.
What kind of sexual issues?
I don't wanna go into that right now.
Brothers, God has put it on my heart to
speak freely with you tonight, okay?
You need to attend
to your wives' needs.
We've got a set of tapes.
Christ-Like Sex
by Dr. Frank Barnes.
MAN [ON RECORDING]: When it comes
to satisfying your wife, brothers,
clitoral stimulation
is part of God's plan.
You'll find the clitoris located
toward the top of her labia,
but below the pubic bone.
Let her be your guide
to what feels good.
Amen.
She will indicate this
with body movements
and various sounds.
It is advisable to apply
one tablespoon of oil or lotion.
Direct contact without lubrication
won't please your bride.
Okay.
That's pretty right on.
That's it?
There's more. Um...
There's seven tapes.
[PLAYING "NEARER MY GOD
TO THEE"]
♪ Nearer, my God to thee ♪
[MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY]
♪ Nearer to thee ♪
♪ Even when it be ♪
♪ A cross ♪
♪ That raiseth me ♪
[COUGHS]
♪ Still all my song ♪
♪ Shall be ♪♪
ETHAN:
God bless you, Mama.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
[LAUGHS]
Stay for lunch.
I can't. Ned's waiting for his lunch.
It's daytime.
So? Who cares?
What about you?
How many times a week?
A week?
Mm-hm.
Like once a week.
Honey...
Maybe.
Maybe?
Honey, you...
You cannot let sexual
chemistry burn out.
You cannot.
What if it does?
You have to spice it up.
Show him how much you admire him.
I like to draw Ned's penis.
No, no.
It's beautiful. It's beautiful. It's art.
Ha-ha-ha!
I'm drawing Ned's.
And you're gonna draw Ethan's.
Listen to me.
He is gonna be so flattered.
Ned loves looking
at his penis drawings.
And he has such a...
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Ah...
I call it Shamu. Stop it.
Ha-ha-ha.
They're so weird.
It's God's design.
Yeah, but it's a strange design.
Listen, the human body
is beautiful, period.
It...
It brings glory to God.
[SIGHS]
Sham...
[LAUGHING]
What?
Ouch. Ouch.
Listen, nothing a little olive
oil can't take care of.
Let me see yours.
It's a little crooked.
Well...
it's long.
Okay.
Hi.
Wendy.
What did you do to your hair?
Yeah, I fucked myself with Sun-In.
But it's cool because
I have Mom's wig.
Uh, listen, Rich kicked me out.
And I don't really have
anywhere to go.
So...
Sleep over?
Your girls are gorgeous.
Hey, you could be a beauty queen.
You could be Miss USA.
We're all beautiful in God's eyes.
Hold it down in the front.
I am holding it down.
Man looks at the outward appearance,
but God looks at the heart. Right?
GIRLS:
Mm-hm.
We pray for you every day.
Don't we, girls?
GIRLS:
Yeah.
We ask God to open Aunt Wendy's eyes
and to save her from hell.
Thank you.
I really... I really appreciate that.
[CHANTING IN UNINTELLIGIBLE LANGUAGE]
What was that?
It's the gift of tongues.
It's a prayer language.
A prayer language?
Uh-huh.
That's beautiful. What...?
How does it work?
Scripture says, he who speaks
in tongues edifies himself.
[SIGHS]
It builds me up.
It's like charging my battery.
Can you do it any time you want?
Any time I'm in the spirit.
So do you know what you're saying?
I have no idea.
You don't?
No, l...
I just know it's what God
wants me to say.
It's so holy.
You sounded like an angel.
What does it feel like?
What does it feels like when...?
Uh...
It settles things in your spirit.
I want it.
You get everything.
You do. I want it.
[SIGHS]
It's gotta... It's what...
That's what I need.
That's exactly what I need.
I want it. I'm gonna get it.
I wanna get it. Ha-ha-ha.
Daddy, veggie burger?
Uh...
It looks delicious.
Jesus, you could feed this
to the geese.
ETHAN: They are very high in protein.
Yeah, I bet.
ETHAN:
Very low in cholesterol.
Get used to the taste.
CORINNE: Good for you.
Yeah, not anymore.
CORINNE: Cheese.
What's good for me is seeing my girls.
Isn't he sweet?
I am so pissed off
at that stinking asshole.
If I see him, I'm gonna crack him.
Daddy, Daddy, Dad.
Your vocabulary.
Sorry.
I'm ticked off at Rich and the
way he's done my Wendybug.
Thank you.
CW: You're better off without him.
I know.
Corinne will help you
get back on your feet.
What do you say, squirt?
Why is Aunt Wendy so nice
when she doesn't know Jesus?
Well, because, hon, it's not enough to
just be nice or just do good things.
A man is justified by faith
apart from works of the law.
God will justify
those circumcised by faith.
What's "circus sized"?
That's when you get cut off
from the circus.
WENDY: I'm nice to you
because I love you.
So that's it. I love you.
I don't have to have a reason.
Kids are the best things in life.
Losing your baby brother,
heh, that destroyed my marriage.
God, I regret that.
Ease off the clutch and press the gas.
Ease and press.
It's like making love, you know?
Come on, rev it up.
You can do it.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Oh.
Oh, oh, oh.
Okay.
[SIGHING]
Satan's doing a real number on you,
but you know what?
I'm gonna bind him.
Okay.
I'm gonna bind him right now.
Satan, you have no power over us.
No, you don't.
We are children of God, Satan,
and we reject your fiery darts.
We reject your lies.
Yes.
We denounce you.
You're a fallen angel doomed to hell
forever and ever.
Amen.
Get thee behind us, Satan.
Get thee behind us.
Yeah, get lost, Bub!
Get lost!
Bub?
Bub. Yes.
You know, Satan is Beelzebub.
The Lord of the Flies.
The book.
Get lost, Bub.
That's great.
[SIREN WAILING]
Oh, no.
What do I do? What do I do?
Pull over. Pull over.
It's not Satan, but it's just as bad.
Pull over.
Another very important driving lesson:
Charm the cop.
[IN FOREIGN ACCENT] Hello, Mr.
Policia. Hello. Oh.
What a beautiful mustache
you have. It's so manly.
Very beautiful.
You're a long way from home, ma'am.
Yes, I am, but I so loving America.
I'm stopping you for doing
15 miles an hour over the limit.
That's a direct threat to your safety.
I had a wedgie.
A what?
A wedgie.
Do you know what this is, the wedgie?
My underwear inside
my pooskie-nooskie.
Oh, my...
Oh, it split my kaka in half.
Backwards, forward.
I was squirming, my friend,
not know what to do.
License and registration, please.
CORINNE: Yes, sir.
Shoot. Take this. Here it is.
And where's my registration?
Here.
It's a learner's permit, sir.
Keep your mind on the road,
Miss Miller.
You know, the Bible says
we need to keep our minds
set on things above.
But I can do that
and concentrate on the road
at the same time, and I will.
And I hope your problem
got solved, ma'am.
Oh. Thank you, yes.
Everything down there very beautiful.
I just pluck it out.
Okay.
CORINNE: Thank you.
ANNIKA: Very deep caverns there.
Bye-bye.
CORINNE: Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
ANNIKA: Bye-bye.
A wedgie?
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Yes, I had a wedgie.
I'm gonna give you a wedgie.
[LAUGHING]
Stop. Stop.
[PLAYING "I'VE GOT A RIVER OF LIFE"]
♪ I've got a river of life
Flowin' out of me ♪
♪ Makes the lame to walk
And the blind to see ♪
♪ Opens the prison doors
Sets the captives free ♪
♪ I've got a river of life
Flowin' out of me ♪
ALL: ♪ Spring up, O
well Within my soul ♪
♪ Spring up, O well
And make me whole ♪
And give to me ♪
♪ That life abundantly ♪♪
[ALL CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING]
I like that.
That one always makes me
wanna dance for the Lord.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Uh, listen, before we start,
I wanna welcome, uh...
Sorry, where did she go?
Corinne's sister, Wendy.
Let's give a warm welcome.
[ALL APPLAUDING]
Uh, now, let's give
a hot hand clap for Jesus.
[ALL WHOOPING
AND APPLAUDING]
Listen, before we start,
I wanna, uh...
I wanna open up the floor
to the body of believers.
If anybody has anything
they wanna share.
Anything that's on their hearts.
To edify the saints. Anybody?
No?
Okay.
CORINNE:
Yeah, um...
I was praying with a sister
for her rebellious child
and, um...
after we asked God for help,
we thanked him
for answering our prayers
because he will answer it, you know?
As we're told in Thess...
Thess... Thess...
My, that is a tongue twister.
In, uh, Thessalonians, um...
Hold on.
As we're told in Thessalonians,
uh, you know,
God wants us to come to him
with all our needs and all our desires.
If you want the Ganders
to have a winning season.
If you want it, you know...
It'll take a miracle.
But I'll pray anyway.
And then I'll thank him when
they choke in the fourth quarter
like they always do.
But that's faith, isn't it?
Isn't that what makes us
different from the world?
That we believe
even though we don't see?
Faith is the substance
of things hoped for,
the evidence of things not seen.
You can sit down now.
That's what it says in Hebrews, right?
Thank you.
Uh, I see you have been
hitting your Bible studies.
God bless you.
Power of the holy word.
Uh, I don't know
who you were praying with.
And you know what?
I don't have to know.
It's okay, but I just wanna say, if
that woman wants to come to me directly
uh, or any of the elders
of the church,
we'd be privileged to sit down
and pray with her, okay?
Um, does anybody have a burden
on their heart they wanna share?
Ned, go ahead.
What's on your mind, brother?
NED: Uh, a couple things.
Sister?
Yeah. I'm sorry.
You came very close
to preaching just now.
We have to be so careful not to appear
as though we're teaching the men.
No. I didn't mean to.
I know. I know.
And you were so sincere
and I know your heart.
And I know you wanna
submit to God in all ways.
Of course, that's all I wanna do.
I know. I know.
Okay, of course.
Good.
Okay.
Hmm. Come on.
Come on, Holy Spirit.
Come on.
I will love you, Father God.
Oh, Holy Spirit.
Thank you, Lord.
Oh. Father God.
Come on in.
Come on.
[SPEAKING GIBBERISH]
Come on, Lord.
Come on, Holy Spirit.
Just wash down on me, Lord.
Just...
♪ Come in thy strength
And thy power ♪
Get thee behind me.
♪ Come in thine own
Gentle way ♪♪
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
[SPEAKS GIBBERISH THEN GROANS]
Try later.
Wend?
Yep.
I have a system.
Okay, what's your system?
Look at the edges.
Right.
Half.
Mm-hm.
Right.
Thirds.
Oh.
Look.
Okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
Half.
Half, thirds.
I'm doing it with the wrist.
Half. Ow. Ha-ha-ha.
I'm doing the towels.
LILY:
Hi, Brownie. Hi, Spotty.
What you doing, Spotty?
What you doing, Brownie?
Mm. Are you hungry?
Are you hungry?
You have a stomachache?
You say "yes."
You say "no."
Oh, my God. What is this?
My undies.
Ha-ha-ha. What is this?
Why?
How do you...? What is...?
How do you wear this?
What is this? Ha, ha!
How do you fold this thing? Ha, ha!
Half. Half.
Thirds.
Okay.
Okay, half. Half.
We're going into origami territory.
Hold on, what could this be?
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
ETHAN: Hey, Lily, what are you doing?
What are you...?
Hey. Come on.
Come on, honey.
Come on.
Wendy!
Hey!
Okay, okay.
Get that out of my house!
CORINNE: What is this?
Give it to me.
Do you see this?
Look at me, hon.
No, no, no.
We're answerable to God.
I'm not giving it back.
It's not yours. It's not mine.
I don't use that.
Who has drugs but doesn't use them?
I'm holding it. I'm a safe house.
We gave you a safe house.
Come on.
Don't look at me like that.
Come here. You put it in your mouth?
No.
You sure? Drink.
LILY: Mm-hm.
ETHAN:
Let's do it.
CORINNE:
Drink, okay? Drink.
What are you doing?
CORINNE: Face.
Get right with God, Wendy.
Shit.
It's not for me!
What? Peace, righteousness?
Eternal life?
Which one is not for you?
I don't want your life, Corinne.
I'll take my fucked-up one instead.
[♪♪♪]
Scrub, scrub.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[TRUCK PULLS AWAY]
[PLAYING "HOLY HOLY HOLY"]
LUKE:
That's a nice dress.
Yeah?
Yeah.
It's new.
Yeah? I like the flounce.
You notice these growing
up in a house of girls.
I imagine you would.
Corinne.
Ha, ha. Yeah?
Could I borrow you for a sec?
Sure.
Okay.
I so don't mean to pick on you, but
scriptures tell the older women
to teach the younger women.
Sure. What's wrong?
[WHISPERING]
Your dress.
My dress?
What? It's a maternity dress.
I know.
It caught Luke's attention.
[SIGHS]
You don't wanna
make a brother stumble.
No.
It's true.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Pray about it. I just...
I don't think
you should wear it again.
[♪♪♪]
Why don't we believe in tongues?
Because we don't.
Look, it's...
I mean, it's nonsensical.
It's probably voodoo.
You don't believe every spirit,
you test them.
You see which ones are of God.
Annika prayed for me in tongues.
She called it a prayer language.
I thought it was so beautiful.
Does Ned know about that?
What difference does it make?
She's worshiping God.
It makes her feel closer to him.
There can't be anything wrong with...
Corinne.
Intelligent people
don't mutter to themselves.
The deceiver comes disguised
as an angel of light.
You know that.
Did you understand her?
No.
There you go.
God is not a God of confusion.
Just because something sounds
beautiful doesn't mean it's good.
Polish gibberish.
You okay?
[COUGHING]
Can I fix you something?
No, I'm...
I can't keep anything down.
I don't want any.
Aw, but you have to.
You have to, so imagine
if you could eat anything
in the world right now,
what would it be?
I would have, um...
A white bread bologna sandwich
with iceberg lettuce and Miracle Whip.
I don't have any of that.
Oh...
We're a strictly whole wheat
and legume family.
But I'm gonna go get it.
You will?
Yeah.
Our bodies tell us what we need.
Okay, let's go.
Nika. Nika.
Yeah?
And can you get a cupcake
with pink frosting?
Just a really big one.
A big one? Ha, ha.
Yeah.
ANNIKA:
Ready? Unh.
Mm.
Feels nice.
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[OLYA FRYZ'S "POSADZHU
YA HRUSHECHKU" PLAYS]
[GASPS THEN GRUNTS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Wow, you really do appreciate
a good foot rub, huh?
[CHUCKLES]
[GUITAR PLAYING]
CORINNE: There are ways of dealing
with a backslider. Compassion.
Other times, you snatch them back,
and there's a time to let them go.
I don't understand that.
Okay, well, I think
for the first part, it's...
With believers that haven't matured,
be tender, treat them with kindness.
Can't expect them to eat
the meat of the word right away.
Baby believers need, um...
Mm-hm?
Need to drink milk.
What does it mean to snatch
someone from the fire?
Is that a metaphor?
Or does that mean hell?
I think it's both.
You know, temptation is consuming.
Like fire.
You know, it can devour us.
Mm-hm.
Um...
Do you know you have a lisp?
Yes, I do.
[LISPING] Yes, you do.
[LISPING]
Absolutely.
[LAUGHS]
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Um... "With some, you
must deal with mingled fear and pity,
hating even the garments
soiled with sin."
Hate.
LUKE [IN NORMAL VOICE]: Yeah.
CORINNE: That's a strong word.
Hey, that reminds me.
Did my work pants get washed?
I don't know.
All right, well,
maybe I'll go check on them.
LUKE:
Is that 9:17?
I may just go to bed while I'm at it.
I don't know, I lost... Sure.
ETHAN: Do me a favor? Um...
Yeah.
Lock the door when you're done.
Okay.
Yeah.
Night.
ETHAN: Yeah.
Take care.
LUKE: Good night.
ETHAN:
Love you.
Hey, don't keep her up too late, bro.
She needs her rest.
I get it. She's a miracle
happening right before our eyes.
Mm-hm.
Every woman deserves
to look like you do.
Oh. Like a hippo?
That's the truth.
Pregnancy is the lady hippo's
crowning glory.
Taking my breath away all night.
CORINNE: Oh, so sweet. So...
♪ Kumbayah, my Lord
Kumbayah ♪
♪ Oh, Lord
Kumbayah ♪♪
Do you know "kumbayah"
means "come by here"?
In Hawaiian.
The missionaries brought it back.
Father God,
how grateful we are
that you will indeed kumbayah.
You won't see our
righteousness as filthy rags
but because of Jesus,
you no longer see our hearts
as corrupt and wicked.
I know we wearily try your patience,
but you are gracious
and withhold the rod of judgment
we so richly deserve.
We are healed by his stripes
and all our iniquities
are laid upon him.
Worthy is the lamb that was slain
for such a degenerate
and undeserving people.
[SIGHS]
Amen.
ALL: Amen.
Thank you, Deborah.
[CHATTERING]
WOMAN 1 : Do you think I should
cancel that singles retreat?
DEBORAH: Oh, no.
I don't think there's a lot of turnout.
DEBORAH: We'll pray about it.
WOMAN 2: Yeah.
Deborah loves the Lord
and she means well,
but her sermons are starting
to make me feel suicidal.
She uses a lot of W words.
Eleven W words
in the last three sentences.
Look at her dress.
[INHALES SHARPLY]
What's wrong?
A headache.
I've been getting whoppers lately.
We should have prayed
for you instead of Hawaii.
Hey, everyone. Rebekah's made
carob brownies. Come on.
You know what carob tastes like?
Chocolate?
Disappointment.
[LINE RINGING]
He can hold up the whole
world with his pinkie.
[PHONE RINGING]
I mean, that's crazy strong.
How strong is your dad?
Hello?
ETHAN: Stronger than Mom for sure.
NED: Corrine. Hi, it's Ned.
Hi, Ned.
ETHAN: That's right.
Uh...
[BABBLING]
[GABE GIGGLES]
NED: We just got back
from the emergency room.
Aw. What's wrong?
Uh...
Annika had a seizure today.
Worst thing I've ever seen.
The poor kids were screaming.
Um...
ETHAN & GABE:
Big.
We got her to the emergency room.
ETHAN: There's nothing
that our God can't do.
Well, what's wrong with her?
Uh, could you put Ethan on the phone?
No, Ned. No, I won't.
Tell me, what's going on with Annika?
It looks like she has a brain tumor.
ETHAN: Let's do it.
Probably malignant.
ETHAN: Let me see your hand.
But, you know, operable.
Okay.
Okay, Ned. Um...
I'm gonna be over in 20 minutes
to help you out.
ETHAN: There's nothing.
GABE: Nothing.
ETHAN, GABE & LILY:
Nothing
that our God can't do.
ETHAN:
That's right.
Are you wearing a padded bra?
Yes. Ha, ha.
I like it.
Ha-ha-ha.
It's so soft.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Good. Okay.
I'm glad.
Oh. Okay.
So, you know, it's times like this
I wish I had a prayer language.
So the Holy Spirit would pray for me.
Yeah. Mine dried up a few days ago.
I don't know why.
Okay. Um...
[SIGHS]
Father God, um,
Annika is your little lamb.
She's your precious daughter
and she's scared.
Ooh.
Heh-heh.
That's all me, baby.
That's all you.
Okay, shh, listen.
And she's scared.
Uh, bring her through this valley.
Lord, hold her close.
Um...
Give her peace that passes
all understanding.
Um...
Thank you for your healing.
Thank you for this healing,
thank you for making her whole.
Yeah?
We pray this in the name of the savior
and give you all the praise and glory.
Amen.
PS...
Get lost, Bub.
Ha-ha-ha.
I feel him.
Yeah.
God's here.
ALL:
♪ God is so good ♪
♪ He's so good to me ♪
PASTOR:
God answers prayer.
ALL:
♪ God answers prayer ♪
[PRAYING INDISTINCTLY]
♪ He's so good to me ♪♪
ETHAN:
Right here, right now, Lord.
Right here, right now.
They got it all. She's gonna live.
ETHAN: Praise God.
Thank you, Jesus.
Whoo!
ETHAN: This is good.
BILL: Praise God.
ETHAN:
Thank you, Jesus.
They're telling me that she's
not gonna be herself, though.
BILL:
What does that mean?
NED: It can mean a lot
of different things.
BILL:
A lot of different things?
NED: I guess part of her brain was
damaged when they removed the tumor.
BILL:
Our God is the God who delivers.
And he has delivered our sister
from the shadow
of the valley of death,
and so we thank God tonight.
We rejoice with Ned and Annika
and their beautiful kids.
Ned.
The Lord God has been
your strength and your shield.
Jehovah-jireh. Amen?
ALL:
Amen.
BILL:
He has provided for you.
His ways are not our ways.
But we trust in his infinite mercy,
his loving kindness.
Uh...
Last night, our son Joel
looked up at me and he said:
"Blimey, Da, I'm knackered." Ha-ha-ha.
[BILL CHUCKLES]
It just...
That just cracked me up
because, you know,
of course, Annika was the one
who taught him to say that.
See, Annika loves the Lord,
but she also loves drama
and art and nature.
And she has this uncanny
ability to find the good
in what other people might
call misfortune or tragedy.
And I just want you all to know
that Annika and I are content
to walk the path the Lord has us on.
It is not a path we would have chosen
for ourselves, but his will, not ours.
God has called all of us to life
and life more abundant.
And that's the life that
Annika has always lived.
And l...
I love you with all of my heart.
Thank you, everyone.
♪ When peace like a river ♪
♪ Attendeth my way ♪
♪ When sorrows
Like sea billows roll ♪
♪ Whatever my lot ♪
♪ Thou has taught me to say ♪
♪ It is well, it is well ♪
♪ With my soul ♪
♪ It is well ♪
ALL:
BILL:
♪ With my soul ♪
ALL:
BILL:
♪ It is well ♪
ALL:
♪ It is well with my soul ♪♪
You have anything
you wanna do for God?
What? Oh, my gosh.
[ALL LAUGH]
Can you go like this at the same time?
All right! Ha-ha-ha.
Give these guys a big hand.
Amen.
You guys are amazing.
Here we go, buddy.
Oh, my gosh.
Don't break your legs.
Um... Wow, how do you follow
an act like that?
Good night.
I don't know about you guys,
but that kind of faith humbles me.
You know what I mean?
It makes me ask myself
is my faith now the same faith
that I started out with?
You know what I mean?
God says in the book of Revelation:
Because you are lukewarm,
I will spew you out of my mouth.
[♪♪♪]
You ever take a big old swig of...
Swig of day-old coffee?
You get up in the morning,
you need something hot and bracing.
You get something that tastes like
yesterday's newspaper, all bleh.
Damp and moldy?
Well, God is asking
the same thing of some of us.
He says, "You know what, guys?
Give me hot coffee
or give me cold coffee,
but none of this in-between stuff."
We can't serve God and serve
the world at the same time.
Just can't do it.
It's like serving two women.
How's that sound, guys?
Ha!
Hard enough to keep one wife happy,
no offense to you, sisters.
But you do keep us hopping.
Uh, Deborah now tells me
that the hair in my ears
is unattractive.
I need to keep it trimmed.
Did you guys know about this?
And the...
And the hairs in your nose too.
This is... This is awful.
I'm falling apart here, I tell you what.
And this middle-age stuff, it is...
It's not for sissies.
No way. And, uh...
Oh, now, they got
these things called skin tags.
That's what they call them?
Say that. Isn't that delightful?
That sounds so good, skin tags.
It's one of these things right here.
You see that?
I'm like a horror show.
[♪♪♪]
But Deborah, she still loves me.
She still loves me.
[BILL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
God is the same way.
He's saying:
"I love you so much that I want your
whole heart, I don't want a part of it.
I don't want it on your good days.
I don't want it when you feel like it.
I want it every day
in every way."
Amen? Amen.
Dear Lord,
GABE: Dear Lord,
thank you thank you
for this spaghetti.
For this spaghetti.
It's so yummy
and it is so good
Mm-hm.
That God didn't put mushrooms
and meatballs in it.
[LAUGHS]
Amen. Amen.
Thank you, Lord.
Hey, hon, could you pass me the...?
Hm?
Can you pass me the butter?
Yeah.
What do you think?
I tried a new recipe.
Hm?
Good. Mm-hm.
Yeah?
On a scale of one to 10?
Is there a knife?
Hm?
Scale of one to 10?
Ten.
Thank you, ladies.
It's good.
LILY: Ten.
Thank you.
ABIGAIL: Ten and a half.
CORINNE:
Mm. Mm.
Hey.
CORINNE:
Do you need anything?
Just wanted to be
with you for a minute.
I guess.
Kids always around wanting you.
Why do you turn your head
when I kiss you?
No, I don't.
See? You do.
Why do you do that?
I'm not sure.
Try not to.
Mm. I'm starving.
We should go get something to eat
after we're done here.
Yeah, if we're not too tired.
We gotta eat.
Yeah.
We can go to Tony C's for a chili dog.
Not very romantic, a chili dog.
It can be.
You could try, Corinne.
At least I try.
Mm. Here we go.
[KICKING BALL]
Good job, Gabe.
[COUGHS]
You know what the problem is?
They can't tell who's on what...
Whose team.
Problem is, he needs to spend time
on his memory verses.
Girls could recite chapters at his age.
Girls? Well, the girls.
He's a boy. It's different.
All the more reason
to train him in the way.
He's fine.
I love him just the way he is.
I don't? God doesn't? Why do you twist
everything around all the time?
Why make simple things complicated?
Enough.
Corinne.
Come back.
Excuse us.
Please.
We can talk...
Stop it.
Would you please stop this?
Just open the door.
Open the door.
[SIGHING]
Can we talk?
This is so embarrassing.
So obdurate.
What?
I said that was embarrassing.
Gabe's teacher was sitting
behind us. You didn't see her?
No.
I only see you.
Really?
What do you see when you look at me?
Hm?
The mother of your children?
A virtuous woman?
Handmaiden of the Lord?
I see a new creature in Christ.
Yeah, right, that's me.
Popped right out of Zeus'
forehead, fully grown.
I don't even know what that means.
No shit, you don't.
Of course. You don't
understand anything.
You don't understand literature
or intelligent conversation
or how to make love.
I just do it myself these days,
did you know that?
It takes me 30 seconds to do
what you couldn't get done
listening to step-by-step instructions by Dr.
Fuck Barnes talk about...
You are my wife! Stop it.
Stop it. Stop it.
Let go! Aah!
Let go!
Stop it!
Just stop! Stop!
Aah!
[IN STRAINED VOICE]
I can't breathe.
[MUFFLED YELLING]
[BOTH SOBBING]
Satan, get out of this car.
Out.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
Mr. and Mrs. Miller, the
doctor's ready for you now.
Just follow me.
MAN: Come on in.
CORINNE: Hello.
I'm Dick Adams.
I'm Corinne.
Hi. Nice to meet you. Hi.
Hi, hi, Ethan.
I'm Dick Adams. You guys
are in Bill's church?
He has told me that you
have been a backbone
of that congregation for many years.
Bill discipled me, taught me the word,
I thank God for Bill every day.
That's great. God bless you.
Do you feel the same way?
Bill's amazing. Mm.
What, pulls rabbits out of hats?
Gets coins from behind your ear?
[ETHAN LAUGHS]
[CHUCKLES]
He's been a blessing.
I'll be straight with you people.
I consider myself a prophet of God.
And God is giving me
a word of wisdom right now.
If you don't mind, I'd like to speak to
your wife by herself, to start with.
Okay, there's a waiting room out there.
There's coffee, help yourself.
Well, you know,
I'd prefer to stay if I could.
Corinne and I don't really have
any secrets from each other.
Well, maybe yes and maybe no.
God sees things that we do not.
Bill thinks that Corinne
is in a dark night of the soul.
I don't want her to
go through that alone.
We have to have pity and fear,
hating even the garments
soiled with sin.
Ethan, this isn't going to work.
Look, Bill says that...
No, no, no, she's quite right.
It's not gonna work
if there's no repentance.
Is your marriage worth
an hour of your time?
I know you take your wedding
vows that seriously.
It's fine. It's... It'll be okay.
She's my sister in the Lord.
I'm gonna treat her with kindness, I promise.
It's okay.
All right, I'll be right outside.
Great.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Your husband is quite a guy.
He was protecting you just like
the Lord has charged him to do.
But we are waging
a battle here for your soul.
We want you in heaven
with him and the kids.
And not outside with the dogs.
Inside with you
or outside with the dogs.
Why are you here?
I'm here because...
[SIGHS]
I'm here because my husband of
15 years asked me to come.
There's a fiery lake waiting for you
with whips that'll cut your flesh
and brands that'll sear your skin.
And do you get to watch?
This is not a joke, Mrs. Miller.
You are crucifying Christ
all over again.
I see right into your soul.
A year ago about this time, I stopped
at a McDonald's for an Egg McMuffin.
And as I was finishing up, I
happened to see a city councilman
whose affair with his secretary
was common knowledge.
Even his wife knew.
And I took my last sip of coffee,
and God says to me, "Rebuke him.
Tell him to repent."
Now, I did not wanna rebuke
this guy, to be honest.
But God does not
take no for an answer.
So I stand up.
I walk over there
and I lay it out for him.
I said, "God wants you to repent from
your sin or he will deal with you."
And that man looked back at me
with eyes as cold as any devil's
and told me to go fuck myself.
Well, I shrugged.
I'd done what God told me to do.
And I walked out. Later that day,
that city councilman skidded
on a slick road over a cliff, dead.
I look at you
and I'm eating my Egg
McMuffin all over again.
You are worshiping
at the altar of yourself.
[SNIFFS]
LIAM: Oh, you gotta sniff this one.
I love it. Toni Morrison.
Morrison? I don't know Morrison.
Yeah. Fantastic.
Is it good? Mm.
Oh, yeah.
I ca... Do I know you?
Uh, what's your zip code?
It's 12408.
Yeah, well, I'm your mail carrier.
My mail what?
Mailman. In America,
you call it your mailman.
Yeah.
Yes, of course.
Yes, of course, I just didn't
recognize you without your...
My stuff. Yeah, well...
If I was smoother, I'd pretend
I didn't recognize you either.
But I have to admit, I have.
Yes, now I remember,
you come very early.
The word is out, alas.
No, your route in the morning, that
you deliver my mail very early.
Oh.
Ha-ha-ha.
Come on, I'm pulling your leg.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Thank you very much, that's lovely.
I'll give it a peruse. Thank you.
You're welcome,
okay. Um, bye.
See you.
Yeah.
["SWEETEST NAME I KNOW"
PLAYS]
♪ The sweetest name I know ♪
♪ Jesus ♪
♪ Oh, my Jesus ♪
♪ Lover of my soul ♪♪
Praise God, Jesus,
the sweetest name I know.
Uh, before we go, what can we pray
for tonight as a house church?
Anybody have a burden on their
heart that they wanna share?
You've carried it long enough.
Anybody?
God is revealing to me how
much I'm walking in the flesh.
I really lost it a couple weeks ago
and I know that Satan
can't possess a believer,
but I was out of control.
And I really need his spirit
to fill me up.
A broken and contrite heart, O God,
thou will not despise me for.
We'll intercede for you, brother.
Thank you. Anybody else?
Anybody?
JOANNE: Please pray
for Luke and for me.
We can't get pregnant.
We wanna raise a son or a daughter for
the kingdom, but God is saying no.
Uh, it's hard to, um,
ahem, say not our will,
but thy will be done.
Jesus in the garden, sweating blood,
begging, begging the Father
God to save his life,
and that is the same Jesus
that intercedes for us.
That's the same Jesus that says:
"Come to me, you who are
weary and heavyhearted,
I will take your burden
from you."
Jesus is asking us
to come to him tonight.
Everyone in this room tonight,
I bring to the throne of God.
[♪♪♪]
I ask his tender mercies upon you
and his gentle watch-care.
I ask his angels to watch
your comings and your goings.
May you reside in the
shadow of his wings.
Amen? Amen.
["CREATE IN ME
A CLEAN HEART" PLAYS]
Lord, help me.
Because I can't feel you.
I feel nothing.
Draw near to me, Lord.
Come on.
Where are you?
Huh? Where are you?
♪ Cast me not away ♪
I'm gonna do this unless you stop me.
♪ Take not thy Holy Spirit ♪
[DOOR CLOSES]
♪ Restore unto me ♪
You should just stay home next time.
You obviously don't wanna be there.
♪ Renew a right spirit within me ♪♪
You're leaving me, aren't you?
You sure about this?
CORINNE:
No.
Are you still gonna come
and hear us sing at church?
I said I would, didn't l?
You said a lot of things
you didn't mean, Corinne.
♪ My hope is built on
Nothing less ♪
♪ Than Jesus' name and ♪♪
[DOOR CLOSES]
Fuck you, goddamn it.
Hello again.
My lucky day, huh?
Running into you again.
Checked out a lovely
new collection of Philip Larkin.
Who's that?
Some son of a bitch
who likes schoolgirls.
But he's a poet
who'll break your heart.
You know, it doesn't
seem possible, does it?
People who are perverts
but have the tongue of angels.
You know, that's
in First Corinthians. Um...
Though I have the tongue
of angels and have not
Love.
Love. Yeah.
Do you know the Bible?
If a man knows Shakespeare,
the Bible, something about art,
a man is educated,
as they say.
Heh.
Where are you from?
I'm from Dublin, Ireland.
Oh.
I've been here 20 years.
Twenty years?
Yes, 20...
PERSON:
Shh!
[WHISPERING]
Twenty years. Shh.
[WHISPERING] Why is
your accent so thick?
Is it that thick?
Ha-ha-ha.
I thought it'd gone.
I thought I sounded American.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
I'm Corinne Miller.
I'm Liam Donovan.
It's really nice to meet you.
You too.
So, listen, we must
talk more about books.
Oh, yeah, I'd like to.
Sure.
And I'll tell you what I learned in
a long walkabout with an aborigine
out in the outback.
Mm.
Ominous.
Mm. Heh.
See you.
[LAUGHS]
CORINNE: Hello.
MAN: Hi.
The pearl accordion
with the gold keys, uh...
In the window?
Can I take a look at it?
Sure. Do you play?
If the price is right.
[LAUGHS]
Oh...
It's a big accordion.
Let's see.
You want to put it right on?
It's just... Yeah.
[ACCORDION GROANS]
[SHRIEKS THEN LAUGHING]
Ooh.
I don't think I know that song.
KATHLEEN:
Nice heavy curtains.
This will keep anyone
from peeping in at you.
They're just ugly.
You're a single woman now, Corinne.
You need to start being careful.
Start being careful?
When have I ever not been careful?
Besides now?
Oh! Goodness sake.
You know, Ma, leave them.
Leave them. I love the light.
Shades will suffice. It's fine.
It's dangerous.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
WOMAN: Hi there. Um...
Hi.
I'm Faye Colbert, and I just wanted
to welcome you to the house.
Oh, thank you.
Extra doughnuts nobody ate at
the Speedee Lube this morning.
I just hate to see them go to waste.
Thank you. Aw...
Also, I wanted to give you
a heads-up.
This floor is full of
a lot of religious nuts.
They'll come ringing your doorbell
with all their assorted
Watchtowers and the like.
You let a Jehovah's Witness in once
and they will come back
again and again.
Well, they have a, uh...
They have a quota they
have to make every month.
They... And they
hound you to death.
We had two Mormons
knocking on doors last month too.
They were nice-looking guys.
They had the dress shirt, tie.
Creepy though.
Smiling to beat the band.
They're false prophets.
Sign of the end of times,
that's what my pastor says.
That, and earthquakes.
And it's no coincidence
that all the earthquakes
happen in California,
what with San Francisco and...
The kind of people who live up there.
The Mexicans?
Well, those too, of course.
They're Catholic, they breed
like there's no tomorrow.
Listen, I just told Corinne you have
got to put a chain on that front door.
Do not neglect welcoming of strangers.
You might be entertaining
angels unaware.
More likely Charles Manson,
darling, than an angel.
Ned, it's Corinne.
Can you hold up the phone for Annika?
Thanks.
Nika, it's Corinne.
Listen to this.
[PLAYING "POSADZHU
YA HRUSHECHKU"]
Nika?
[SIGHS]
CORINNE:
Hi.
What's this?
It's Daniel in the lions' den.
Ooh, it is.
Gosh, this is wild.
They said I did it wrong.
Why?
Because there's no TVs and
remote controls in Bible days.
Well, you know what?
I think you have an extraordinary imagination.
I think you have
a very large imagination.
And I think that my son is an artist.
My son is an artist, okay?
I'm gonna take you somewhere
special today, okay?
Will you hold that
so it doesn't get wrinkled?
[ENGINE STARTS]
I think it's wonderful.
Look, she's naked.
CORINNE: She's definitely
not wearing clothes.
There's a tube by her
and it looks like...
CORINNE: She looks frightened.
I don't see their mama anywhere.
ABIGAIL & GABE:
No.
LILY:
They do look scared.
I think that's why they're scared.
Because their mama is gone?
Yeah.
ABIGAIL: Oh, look, what's in it?
LILY: There's pink stripes and stuff.
GABE: How could they
catch a jaguar's, um...
hair?
It's so tall.
CORINNE:
Ooh.
GABE: If you look very closely,
there's webs in the...
In the end of the arrow.
CORINNE:
Look at her.
Gosh, the human body
is so beautiful, isn't it?
GABE:
Whoa.
This lady is so voluptuous.
She better go to Weight Watchers.
LILY: Yeah.
[ABIGAIL & CORINNE CHUCKLE]
GABE:
Yeah, she's a big old target.
Smaller than a giant
but bigger than a human.
Hey, how are you?
Didn't expect to see you here.
I've been delivering your mail
to another address.
Sorry if I'm speaking out of turn.
I plant these rows every spring.
I think the kids would be so
sad if they weren't here.
You deliver my mail this morning?
I did.
It was only bills, I think.
But I did knock on your door
because I brought you this.
The Collected Poems
of W.B. Yeats.
Are you loaning this?
I am. Yeah.
Okay.
I'm only asking one small favor.
Uh-oh.
Just indulge me.
Let me read one aloud.
What, now?
Yes, now. You wouldn't be
the first one I've read to today.
There's an 82-year-old lady
who receives nothing but
junk mail and my daily poem.
That's lovely.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, okay. Heh.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Never give all the heart, for love
Will hardly seem worth thinking of
To passionate women if it seem
Certain, and they never dream
That it fades out from kiss to kiss
For everything that's lovely is
But a brief, dreamy, kind delight
O never give the heart outright
That's Yeats?
It is.
You have the look of a woman
who gives all her heart.
It's hard to give less, you know.
Mm. I hope you've planted some of these
flowers where you can see them too.
[LIAM WHISTLING]
[NOISEMAKERS TOOTING]
[CORINNE & WENDY CHEERING]
Here we go.
I want Mommy to have the first piece.
WENDY:
No, silly.
The birthday boy gets the first piece.
KATHLEEN: Make a wish, darling.
I want you to give each other bites
like in your wedding picture.
Well, wedding cake isn't
the same as birthday cake.
I'll tell you what, you can help me
cut my cake next time I get married.
How's that sound? Yeah?
Good.
Don't hold your breath there, Gabe.
WENDY: Hold your breath, Gabe.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
Didn't you bake
their wedding cake too?
God, that was a delicious cake.
CORINNE: It was yummy, Mama.
WENDY: Yeah.
Nobody bakes like you.
GABE: Yeah.
She put 20 pounds on me.
Heh, heh.
CW:
I would have guessed closer to 40.
GABE: Why would you guess closer to 40?
Because he's fat.
Daddy. Stop.
Oh. Come on, I'm kidding.
I'm half-kidding.
I was kidding, pretty much.
Guys get big, some guys.
I got the same waist size
as high school.
WENDY: Daddy.
Mom, Dad,
can I take your picture together?
Like in the wedding photo?
I wanna take the picture.
Can I take it please, Mama?
He's the birthday boy,
give him the camera.
If it makes you happy...
Ethan, let's do the reenactment.
Come here, big boy.
CORINNE: Reenactment.
CW:
Okay, okay, okay.
You got that camera ready?
ALL:
Oh...
You got it in focus?
Oh, boy.
Yeah.
Just like that?
Just like that.
Now if I remember correctly,
this is the part where your Mama
looked at me with her big blues.
And I smeared the cake in her face.
No, you didn't.
I didn't?
GABE: I'm gonna take a picture.
And fire!
Don't you dare. Don't you dare.
GABE: Ready to take a picture.
[LAUGHS]
Got the camera ready?
Yeah.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS]
I took... I took the picture.
ABIGAIL:
Oh, no.
ABIGAIL, LILY & GABE [CHANTING]:
Kiss, kiss, kiss.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
I thought you'd smash it on her face.
I'm gonna smash it on your face.
ETHAN: Pick it up. Excuse me.
Yeah. I'm gonna
smash it on your face.
Did you turn into an ornery boy
now that you're 7 years old?
No!
Yes!
This is your big birthday bite.
Here it is.
Uh-oh. Hello, Gabe.
Aah! Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Gabe, Gabe, Gabe.
Okay. I won't.
I won't. Ha, ha.
Happy birthday, my angel.
[CORINNE KISSING GABE]
[GABE CHUCKLES]
GABE: Anybody take a picture of me?
CORINNE: Happy birthday.
DICK: Kathleen, did you bring
ice cream for the cake?
GABE:
I thought you'd really do it.
Coming right up.
LIAM: "They flew over the Charles River.
'Better, ' quacked Mr. Mallard.
'That island looks like a nice place,
a little way from the Public Garden.'
'I like this place, ' said Mrs. Mallard,
as they climbed and waddled along.
'Why don't we build a nest and raise
our ducklings right in this pond?
There are no foxes, no turtles,
and the people feed us peanuts.
What could be better?'
'Good, ' said Mr. Mallard,
delighted that at last, Mrs. Mallard
had found a place that suited her.
'Look out, ' squawked Mrs. Mallard,
all in a dither.
'You'll get run over.'
When she got her breath back, she
added, 'This is no place for babies,
with all these horrid things
rushing about.
We better look someplace else.'
["I NEED THEE EVERY HOUR"
PLAYS]
So they flew over Beacon Hill
and round the State House,
but there was no place there."
Looking for a place to live.
"They looked in Louisburg Square.
There was no water to swim in."
♪ I need thee every hour ♪
♪ Stay thou nearby ♪
♪ Temptations lose their power ♪
♪ When thou art nigh ♪
♪ I need thee ♪
♪ Oh, I need thee ♪
♪ Every hour, I need thee ♪
CORINNE:
What are you doing here?
♪ Oh, bless me now, my savior ♪
Hey, where'd you
come from? Hm?
♪ I come to thee ♪
♪ I need thee every hour ♪
♪ In joy or pain ♪
♪ Come quickly and abide ♪
[DOG BARKING]
♪ Or life is vain ♪
♪ I need thee ♪
♪ Oh, I need thee ♪
♪ Every hour, I need thee ♪
♪ Oh, bless me now, my savior ♪
♪ I come to thee ♪♪
♪ And he walks with me ♪
♪ And he talks with me ♪
♪ And he tells me I am his own ♪
♪ And the joy we share ♪
♪ As we tarry there ♪
♪ None other has ever known ♪
♪ And the joy we share ♪
♪ As we tarry there ♪
♪ None other has ever known ♪♪
My children have the voices
of angels, don't they?
Do I hear an amen?
He walks with me and he talks with me
and he tells me I am his own.
What more could anyone want, right?
Taking a stroll with God
in the garden.
Having a chat with the creator.
Asking him questions
and getting the answers.
I mean, you couldn't be
any more safe or secure.
There's no higher ground.
Call upon the name of the Lord
and you will be saved.
We call him so many things.
We call him, uh, El Shaddai.
Lord. Father God.
Jesus. Holy Spirit.
Heavenly Father.
Adonai. Jehovah-jireh.
The ancient Hebrew alphabet
contained no vowels
so God's name was rendered
only in consonants.
And the vowels
had to be provided orally
when a word was spoken.
But the rabbis didn't wanna
use God's name in vain,
so his name was never spoken.
So all we're really left with
is just this string of consonants,
you know, an unspeakable name.
Bill, just one...
Just a minute, pastor,
please, just one.
You know, when I was
a little girl, my pastor told me
that Jesus was knocking
on the door of my heart.
And so I listened real hard,
and I thought I heard him.
I did. I raised my hand
and I told everyone
that Jesus was standing there,
and he wanted me.
He wanted me.
Tap, tap, tap.
So I invited him in.
"Welcome," I said,
and I gave my heart outright.
And I'm standing here today,
and I'm telling you,
I'm telling you today
that I'm still waiting for him
to make himself at home.
You know, I call and I call.
And there have been times
where I know he answered me.
I'm... Times where I'm sure of it.
But other times,
I've got the porch light on,
and he doesn't come.
And I feel like I live
in an empty place.
And I told God, I told him:
"You know what?
I'm not gonna let go."
I won't let go until he blesses me.
But I'm wrestling something
nameless, you know,
without form and void.
And I just want it to be solid so bad.
I need all of this to be real, and I
don't always know how to make it real.
I don't know how to make
it real, so I am...
Forgive me.
Okay?
I admire your faith.
I admire your faith, I really do.
Thank you.
BILL: Thank you, Corinne.
Let's all turn to number 77
in our hymnals, please.
[PIANO PLAYING "HOW GREAT THOU ART"]
♪ Oh, Lord, my God ♪
♪ When I in awesome wonder ♪
♪ Consider all ♪
♪ The worlds thy hands hath made ♪
♪ I see the stars ♪
♪ I hear the rolling thunder ♪
♪ Thy power throughout ♪
♪ The universe displayed ♪
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My savior God to thee ♪
♪ How great thou art ♪
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My savior God to thee ♪
♪ How great thou art ♪
♪ When through the woods ♪
♪ And forest glades I wander ♪
♪ I hear the birds ♪
♪ Sing sweetly in the trees ♪
♪ When from the mountain ♪
♪ From lofty mountain grandeur ♪
♪ I hear the brook ♪
♪ And I feel the gentle breeze ♪
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My savior God to thee ♪
♪ How great thou art ♪
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My savior God to thee ♪
♪ How great thou art ♪
♪ How great thou art ♪♪
MAN 1 : Thanks, God.
MAN 2: Thank you, Jesus.
MAN 3:
Amen.
["HIGHER GROUND" PLAYS]
♪ I'm pressing on ♪
♪ The upward way ♪
♪ New heights I'm gaining ♪
♪ Every day ♪
♪ Still praying as ♪
♪ I'm onward bound ♪
♪ Lord plant my feet ♪
♪ On higher ground ♪
♪ Lord, lift me up ♪
♪ And I shall stand ♪
♪ By faith on heaven's table land ♪
♪ A higher plain ♪
♪ Than I have found ♪
♪ Lord, plant my feet ♪
♪ On higher ground ♪
♪ My heart has no ♪
♪ Desire to stay ♪
♪ Where doubts arise ♪
♪ And fears dismay ♪
♪ Though some may dwell ♪
♪ Where these abound ♪
♪ My prayer, my aim ♪
♪ Is higher ground ♪
♪ Lord, lift me up ♪
♪ And I shall stand ♪
♪ By faith on heaven's table land ♪
♪ A higher plain ♪
♪ Than I have found ♪
♪ Lord, plant my feet ♪
♪ On higher ground ♪
♪ I want to scale ♪
♪ The utmost height ♪
♪ And catch a gleam ♪
♪ Of glory bright ♪
♪ But still I'll pray ♪
♪ Till heaven I've found ♪
♪ Lord, lead me on ♪
♪ To higher ground ♪
♪ Lord, lift me up ♪
♪ And I shall stand ♪
♪ By faith on heaven's table land ♪
♪ A higher plain ♪
♪ Than I have found ♪
♪ Lord, plant my feet ♪
♪ On higher ground ♪
♪ On higher ground ♪♪