www.titlovi.com
Mother! Mother, can I sleep
over at Hutch's tonight?
Mrs. Hutchinson gave permission.
Not tonight, David. Your
father and I are going out,
and I need you to
look after your sister.
Aw, shucks. Now move out of
the way so Mother can park.
Sherry Seeger says they only
cost five or six dollars.
Please, Mother. Please, can I?
Oh, Sybil, thank heavens. Well, I
knew you were going to the grocery.
David, please help Sybil unload the car.
How come Janice doesn't
got to? Doesn't have to.
Because Janice is carrying
in all her belongings...
and marching straight
upstairs into a bath.
Your father and I have an engagement tonight,
so I want you to have a nice early dinner.
And help Sybil. Yes, ma'am.
Sybil, did Mr. Whitaker call while I
was out? Not since you’ve been gone.
How do you like that guy?
Mother, can I please get them?
Janice, I said we'd discuss it with
your father. Now hurry on inside.
David, put your bike away
and help with the groceries.
Where's your jacket? It's inside.
Well, hello, stranger.
Aren't I seeing you in about
three hours' time? You are.
But I just left the caterers
and I had to dash over.
Oh, you have the samples? You bet.
Oh, come inside. You
just caught me actually.
I could only stay a second.
I still have loads to do.
David, what did I tell you?
I'm getting the last bag.
And imagine with the
table setting I showed you.
The aqua trim. Is that smart? Oh, yes.
You like? Mm-hmm.
Well, I'll call the caterer in the morning,
you confirm with Dorothy on the deposit...
and, honey, we're in business.
Magnatech '57, here we come. You betcha.
Thanks for stopping by,
El. I'll see you at 8:00.
You know Frank--
on the dot.
Mother? Mm-hmm.
When you were a little girl,
you looked just like me, right?
Mm-hmm.
So, when I grow up, does
that mean I'll look like you?
I s that what you want,
darling, to look like me?
Yes, I hope I look
exactly as pretty as you.
What a lovely compliment coming
from my perfectly lovely daughter.
7:15.
Where on Earth is your father?
Sybil, did I leave my
gloves on the hall table?
Yes, I see them.
It's nearly 20 after and Mr.
Whitaker still hasn't phoned?
I'm at my wits' end.
Oh, thank you, Sybil.
I tried phoning the office even
though I knew no one would be there.
I certainly hope that's
him, because if it isn't--
Whitaker residence. This is the
Hartford Police Department...
calling for a Mrs. Frank Whitaker.
Who is it? The police department.
Hello?
Yes, am I speaking with a
Mrs. Frank Whitaker? Yes.
One moment, please.
Cathy? Oh, Frank.
Are you all right? What
happened? Everything's fine.
It was all just
a big mix up--
the whole thing.
But you have to come get me. They
won’t let me leave on my own.
Oh, Frank, don't worry, darling.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
Is there anything I
can do, Mrs. Whitaker?
Just keep an eye on the children,
please. I don't think I'll be very long.
Big time faggot. Family
man. Never can tell.
Say, get a load of this one. You
don't see that every day of the week.
This is your copy,
ma'am, and your receipt.
Thank you.
Oh, Frank.
I tell you
one thing--
if it hadn't been for
that snivelling junior cop,
they would have never gone through
this whole charade in the first place.
Instead of trying to save face-- I saw that
guy that they were after, that loiterer.
But they wouldn’t listen to me.
So, there were drinks after work?
What do you mean? They said something,
intoxication level, something--
Christ, I had one lousy cocktail with
Bill after work going over the portfolio.
Should I be arrested for that
too? No, of course not, darling.
The whole thing has just
put me in a foul state.
He's fine. Oh, the car's fine.
Frank says it was the
bumper that got hit.
But you know me, I can't
tell the difference.
Oh, I'm just sorry we had to miss it.
She was fine.
Said it was all a dreadful
bore, what with Mona Lauder...
and her gossip. Cathy,
I'm sorry.
Darling, you've nothing to be sorry for.
It was all just a
silly, wretched mistake.
Ohh.
I'm so tired.
Of course you are.
You sleep now.
The bus is here. Have
a good day at school.
Bye.
I thought you were going to
have another piece of toast.
It's late. I should
be getting down there.
Can I at least fix you lunch? No, thank
you, dear. I've got lunch meetings all week.
It's portfolio season.
Sybil, if that’s the milkman,
his check is in the drawer.
I'm just glad you're
feeling better, dear.
Thank you, darling.
Pardon me, ma'am, sir.
Mrs. Whitaker, this is Mrs. Leacock.
She said she had an appointment
with you this morning.
Oh, jiminy, I completely forgot
the time. Please forgive me.
I do apologize, Mrs. Whitaker,
but candid views are always the best.
Good-bye, darling.
Good-bye, dear.
Mrs. Leacock. Pleasure, Mr. Whitaker.
Your husband's a very
charming man, Mrs. Whitaker.
Thank you. We're rather
fond of him ourselves.
Now, please, won’t you come
in? Make yourselves at home.
I suppose I still can't imagine...
why you would want an interview with
someone like me in the first place.
Readers of the Weekly
Gazette, Mrs. Whitaker--
women just
like yourself--
with families and homes to keep up.
A good society paper...
need not be a gossip rag.
You are the proud wife...
of a successful sales
executive-- planning the parties,
and posing at her husband’s
side on the advertisements.
To everyone here in Connecticut,
you are Mr. and Mrs. Magnatech.
Thank you. I 'm very flattered.
But, really, my life is like
any other wife or mother's.
In fact, I don't think I've,
I've ever wanted anything--
What is it, dear?
I think I just saw someone
walking through our yard.
What on
Earth--
Oh, my-- Mrs. Whitaker, perhaps
you should call the police.
Excuse me.
May I help you?
Who are you?
I'm sorry, ma'am. My name is
Raymond Deagan-- Otis Deagan's son.
I was just taking
over some of his--
Oh, you're Otis's son.
Yes.
I-I'm terribly sorry for
speaking to you in that manner.
I-I didn't know who was in my yard.
Oh, no need. How is your father?
I know he was in the hospital.
Yes, well,
my father's passed away, I'm afraid.
Oh--
Oh, I-I had no idea.
I'm, I'm so very sorry.
Please, accept our deepest condolences.
Your father was a
wonderful, dedicated man.
Thank you. Mrs. Whitaker?
The caterer's on the
line. Oh, thank you, Sybil.
I beg your pardon. Would you excuse
me for just a moment? Of course.
Mrs. Leacock, I'm terribly sorry.
I’ll just be one minute
more. That's fine, dear.
Good morning, Magnatech International?
How may I direct your call?
Good morning, Mr. Whitaker.
Good morning, Kitty.
Lovely dress you're
wearing. Thank you, sir.
Good morning, Marlene, Stan.
Good morning, Mr. Whitaker. How's the
second-best golfer in Hartford this morning?
Somebody break the books already?
Don't tell me our wives'
party budgets finally came in.
It's almost as fatal. Millstein called.
Looks like New York just shaved
a week off portfolio deadline.
You've got to be kidding
me. I wish I were.
What are they trying to
do, strangle us to death?
Does Doug know? Yeah, I
called him first thing.
All right. Get Doug and the others.
Call a portfolio
meeting for lunch today.
Marlene, see if you can reschedule
the production review for dinner.
And, uh, could you get my
wife on the phone, please?
Thanks, Stan.
Mrs. Whitaker is on line one.
Oh, Frank. I'm sorry.
No, no, I understand.
I just wish you wouldn't overwork
yourself, especially after--
I know.
I will.
See you then.
Good-bye, dear.
I'm terribly sorry about
all the interruptions.
Now, where was it you wanted me?
Just one more at the fireplace.
That's it.
Now smile. Isn't that darling?
Hold it.
Well, I guess that about wraps it up.
Bob, Rick. Gentlemen.
You're sure you’re all
right getting home, sir?
Thank you, Davis. But as 2nd in
command of the U.S.S. McMillan,
I do feel equipped to locate
my own car without cover.
Very good, sir. Bright and early.
Sir, can you spare some change, please?
Spare change? Anything would help.
Spare change?
Where ya headed, tiger?
Look out, Jake!
Oh, for heaven's sake.
David, that is the third time I've told you
to turn off that infernal racket and go to bed.
Can I please just this once?
No, you certainly may
not, and that is final.
Ah, geez. That is not the kind
of language we use in this house.
Now march.
And don't forget to wash your teeth.
Hi.
Feeling better now?
Mrs. White?
The picture? Yes.
I thought you really enjoyed the
scene in the gentlemen's lounge.
How about a drink?
Sure. I know just the spot.
I'll bet you do.
Identification, please.
Huh? Identification--
Driver's license.
Thank you, sir. Have a pleasant evening.
Yes, sir. What can I
get you this evening?
Uh, just a scotch--
neat, please.
Yes, sir.
There you are, sir.
One more of the same.
"So, does the fabled maxim hold that behind
every great man there resides a great lady?
"In this case, wife, mother
and Mrs. Magnatech herself,
"Cathleen Whitaker proves that it does.
"A woman as devoted to her family...
as she is kind to Negroes."
To Negroes? Let me see that. What
on Earth is that woman thinking?
Cathy? Oh, she's been liberal ever since
she played summer stock at college...
with all those steamy Jewish boys.
Why do you think they
used to call her "Red"?
Oh, for heaven sakes. Let's go inside
before Joe McCarthy comes driving by.
- Uh
-oh. Oh, I love that scarf..
Oh, I'm sure it just blew
behind the house somewhere.
For heaven sakes. This
really isn't your day, is it?
No. Did they really call you "Red"?
Oh, Nancy. Honestly!
Would anyone like another daiquiri?
Better not.
Oh, no, one's my limit.
El? Mmm.
All right, girls. No more
beating around the bush.
Nancy. Oh,
I-- I can't.
Oh, come on. It can't be that bad.
Um,
well, uh--
Mike
insists on--
He insists on once a week.
- Ah, you got off easy.
- Once a week?
Oh, you're lucky. Ron's
more like two or three.
Three, really? And how.
That's nothing. Girlfriend
of mine-- Shirley Dawson.
Her husband-- every
night of the week.
Plus, three more times on the weekend.
Can you imagine?
It was lovely, Cathleen. Thank you. Bye.
Bye, girls. The chicken was divine.
Oh, thanks, El. I'll call you tomorrow.
All right. Bye-bye.
Could this
possibly--
Oh, I'm sorry. No. You found it.
Yeah, I found it hanging off
one of the birches out back.
It was so windy.
I was going back into the house
and it just sailed off my neck.
I had a feeling it might be yours.
Who else could have been so
absentminded? No, no, it's the color.
It just seemed right.
Well, thank you, Mr.
Deagan-- for finding it.
Please, call me Raymond.
Thank you, Raymond.
Everything looks
wonderful, by the way. Good.
I think we got everything
pretty much under control.
Well, it can't have been easy...
taking over for your father so quickly.
Well, between Pop's
business, my, uh, shop...
and taking care of my little girl,
doesn't leave much time for reflecting.
I didn't know you had children.
Just the one-- Sarah's her name.
And how old is Sarah? Eleven.
Well, I'm sure she's a lovely child.
You and your wife must be very proud.
Well, um, Mrs. Deagan, my wife, uh,
passed away when Sarah was about five.
Oh, Raymond, I'm so sorry.
Thank you.
Sarah and I,
we do just fine.
You know, I got a
picture of her somewhere.
There she is. That's my Sarah.
Oh, she's darling.
Look at those eyes.
Now, what's this I hear about a shop?
Oh, yeah, the plant shop. It's just
a little place down on Hawthorn.
Started out as a
service for gardeners...
till I opened the store
about six years ago, and, uh--
Well, it's the only thing that
business degree's been good for yet.
Why, that's marvellous, Raymond.
You should be very proud.
Well, I am.
Uh, if you’re ever in the
neighbourhood, be sure to stop by.
I certainly will. All right, then.
Thank you. You’re welcome.
If that’s
your father--
Don't worry Sybil, I'll get it.
Hello?
Frank, you haven't left yet?
Oh, no. Not again.
All right.
Good-bye, dear.
He isn't coming home again?
No, he's going to be late.
Father never wants to come home.
Janice, he most certainly does. He's just very
busy at work and under a great deal of strain.
Yeah! Shut up.
Janice, that's enough.
Sybil, you know what?
Wrap up Mr. Whitaker's plate. I'm
going to run down to the office...
and take it to him myself.
All the way downtown?
It's not so very far.
Anyway, the children are fine.
Knowing Mr. Whitaker, I'm just saving
him another night of pretzels and coffee.
Thank you.
I'm just dropping something off
for my husband on the 12th floor.
Mr. Whitaker. Thank you. All right.
Frank?
Oh, Frank.
Cathy.
Mr. Maynard...
Left an estimate for the roof.
I put it in the kitchen.
Twelve hundred
something. Cathy--
I can't.
I
don't--
What?
Eh, you
see, uh--
Once,
a long time ago,
a long, long time ago,
I had, um,
um,
problems--
I just figured
that was--
that was it.
I-I never imagined--
You had problems?
Y-Yes.
You, uh, never
spoke to anyone--
a-a doctor? No.
No one?
I don't understand.
Neither do I.
What if--
I mean,
there must be
people who--
I-I don't know.
Because--
Otherwise, I don't
know what I-- Cathy.
All right.
Thank you.
Mr. and Mrs. Whitaker,
this is Dr. Bowman.
Mr. Whitaker,
how do you do? Hello.
Mrs. Whitaker, how lovely. Thank you.
I suppose we may as well get started.
Actually, uh, Mrs. Whitaker,
I think it might be best...
if your husband and I
conversed in private.
In private. Yes, of course.
I think it would be
best. Certainly, Doctor.
I'll see you later.
I'll see you later, dear.
Today, the general attitude
regarding this sort of behavior...
is naturally more modern,
more scientific than
it ever has been before.
But for those who do seek treatment,
who possess the will and desire...
to lead a normal life,
there still remains only a scant...
five to thirty percent
rate of success...
for complete heterosexual conversion.
For many, it's the treatment itself...
that often changes the patient's mind.
What does it, uh, comprise of?
- The treatment.
- The treatment's comprised of psychiatric sessions...
twice a week, sometimes more.
Just talking? Yes.
Though some patients have explored
additional, more behavioural methods.
- Behavioural?
- Electroshock aversion therapy for instance.
Or hormonal rebalancing procedures.
I know this can all seem
rather daunting at first.
I suggest you take some time.
Think over the various
options we've discussed.
Discuss it with your
wife. No, I already know.
I want to begin treatment.
I can't let this thing...
destroy my life,
my family's life.
I, uh-- I-I know
it's a sickness,
because it makes me feel...
despicable.
I promise you, Dr. Bowman,
I'm going to beat this thing.
I'm gonna break it.
So help me God.
Why don't you confirm those
times we discussed with Rosalyn.
I'll see you here same time
next Tuesday. Thank you, Doctor.
Mr. Whitaker, Mrs.
Whitaker. Thank you, Doctor.
Frank? What?
I'm just proud of you, that's all.
Don't say that. Well, I am.
He seems a very decent man,
Dr. Bowman. Don’t you think?
Frank? I don't know, Cathleen.
I suppose he's decent.
But you must have liked him
enough to want to see him again.
Who else am I going to see?
Well, I'm sure there are numerous doctors
in Hartford or Springfield if you--
Look, I just want to get the
whole fucking thing over with!
Can you understand that?
Frank, please don't.
I-I'm sorry.
All right, Cathy, I'm so sorry.
Good morning, Mr. Whitaker. Morning.
Morning.
Good morning, Mr. Whitaker. Hi, Kitty.
I hope you have a pleasant
day, sir. Thank you.
Good morning, Mr. Whitaker. Marlene.
I found this in the
cupboard, sir. What's that?
Your office lamp-- the
one that was missing.
Ah-- Should I have
it repaired, sir?
Yes. Yes, thank you, Marlene.
Mr. Whitaker, Mr. Fine's been waiting.
Frank? Uh?
I didn't see you sitting there.
Everything all right?
Oh, with me? Of course.
What's up? Just picked up
the galleys from the printer.
How do they look? Great, just great.
Just leave them there. I'll
take a look first chance I get.
Sure.
You'll let me know what you think?
Of course I will.
You're first on my list.
What's it gonna take to get
you back on that course anyway?
We haven't seen you for weeks. I know.
Sunday. No excuses.
All right. I'll hold you to it.
Thanks again, El. You sure
that's all I can give you?
Oh, yes. The caterer should have everything.
I just thought a few extras would be nice.
Oh, don't forget. The art show is
Saturday. Start working on Frank tonight.
I swear he's the kind of man
you have to pin messages to.
Though I'm sorry to say,
Mona Lauder will be attending.
Turns out her uncle's in town, some
hotshot art dealer from New York.
I think I met him at
one of Mona's soirees.
A bit flowery for my taste.
How do you mean? Oh, you know,
a touch light on his feet.
Oh, you mean-- Yes,
darling, he's one of those.
Of course, I could be mistaken.
Just an impression I got.
You don't care for them particularly?
Well, no, not particularly.
Not that I actually know any.
Call me old-fashioned, I just like
all the men I'm around to be all men.
Say, why the third degree?
It's not the third degree.
I'm just interested,
that's all, in your views.
I read an article in a magazine.
What? Nothing.
I'm just delighted to see you taking
interest in yet another civic cause.
I can see it now.
"Cathleen Whitaker and her
kindness to homosexuals."
Ugh. That word.
See you Saturday-- and
bring Frank. I'll try.
Then Billy Hutchinson stole
a pass at the ten-yard line.
Ran it all the way for a touchdown.
You should a seen it, Pop.
Father, want to see my
routine for the ballet recital?
Hey, I was talking to Pop. Children, give
your father a moment to eat his dinner.
Would you like another lamb chop, dear?
Oh, I'm fine. Are you sure?
I have plenty in the
oven. No, thank you.
I'm, I'm fine.
We're playing Lincoln on Saturday,
Pop-- if you’re not working.
That reminds me. This Saturday is the reception
for the modern art show I told you about,
the one that Eleanor's
group is sponsoring.
Oh, God. I know how you hate these
things, but I simply have to go.
- Eleanor pleaded with me to ask you.
- Wait, what about me?
No one cares one bit
what I'm doing Saturday.
David, I'm sorry.
But this Saturday your mother has an
engagement that simply cannot be changed.
Well, Pop could come.
Couldn’t you, Pop? We’ll see, David.
Janice, could you
please pass the butter?
Thank you.
President Eisenhower was determined
to keep the troops there until--
...satisfactory or
unequivocal assurances that--
Frank?
Hmm?
Did you see him?
Yeah.
You didn't say a word.
So how did it go with Bowman?
Did you feel--
It was fine.
And there's nothing else you care to
share with your very own adoring wife?
Cathleen, what I discuss
with this doctor--
it's private, all right.
- That's part of it.
- Oh, I understand, darling.
I do.
Oh-- Frank, wait till you
see the hors d'oeuvres.
The caterer's doing, just
such a marvellous job.
I think you’re going to be so
pleased this year, darling. I really do.
Eleanor, darling, I'm so sorry I'm late.
Cathleen, darling. Hello, Mona.
Uh, I want to introduce you
to my uncle, Morris Farnsworth,
that wickedly successful
Gotham art dealer...
who was kind enough to attend
our provincial little gathering.
Morris, darling, allow
me to introduce you...
to my dear little
friend, Cathleen Whitaker,
whose face and civic fancies
are hardly strangers...
to the society pages of Hartford.
Oh, Mona. Really, you must
ignore her, Mr. Farnsworth.
Charmed. I do hope you enjoy your stay.
Morris was just telling us
the most delightful tale...
all about a forged Rembrandt.
Cathy, don't let us keep you. I know you
want to see the show. I am dying to see it.
Oh, yes, dear, simply charming.
Eleanor, you should be
so proud. Thank you, Mona.
It was lovely to meet you, Mr.
Farnsworth. Likewise, my dear.
Wife of Hartford executive...
communing with Picasso?
Mrs. Leacock, it's
lovely to see you again.
And how is that charming
husband of yours?
Oh, he's very well. Thank you.
Um, would you excuse me just a moment?
Oh, certainly, dear. Thank you.
Raymond, what a tremendous
surprise finding you here.
Mrs. Whitaker, hello.
Is this your daughter?
Yep, this is my Sarah.
Hello, Sarah. Hello.
-Bobby, get over here!
- Say, Sarah,
isn't that Hutch and his little
brother I see playing out front?
You remember them, don’t you, baby?
Oh, sure you do.
The day we went to the Hutchinson house.
Oh, yeah.
What do you say you go out and see
if they’d like to play for a while?
Ah, go on.
For Daddy?
Attagirl.
Oh, Raymond, she's lovely. Thank you.
Well, how on Earth did you
find out about this show?
Well, I do read the papers.
W-- No, of course you do.
I just meant that it's-- it's
such a-- it's a coincidence.
I know. I was just teasing you.
Because, you know, I'm not prejudiced.
My husband and I have always believed
in equal rights for the Negro...
and support the N.A.A.C.P.
I'm glad to hear that.
I just wanted you to
know. Well, thank you.
Oh, not at all.
Go!
Straighter, Tommy! You
got to throw it straighter.
And hard. One, two, three, go!
It's too heavy..
What? On the back. Your airplane.
Who asked you? Come on, Bobby.
So, what's your opinion on modern art?
Uh, it's hard to put into words really.
I-I just know what I care
for, and, and what I don't.
Like this-- I don't
know how to pronounce it.
"Mira"? Miró.
Miró.
I don't know why, but I just adore it.
A feeling it gives.
I know that sounds terribly vague.
No, no, actually it confirms something I've
always wondered about modern art, abstract art.
What is that?
That perhaps it's just picking
up where religious art left off,
somehow trying to show you divinity.
The modern artist just pares it down to
the basic elements of shape and color.
But when you look at that Miró,
you feel it just the same.
Why, that's lovely, Raymond.
T o tell the truth, I've always
preferred the work of the Masters.
Rembrandt,
Michelangelo--
Would you excuse me a
moment? Oh, certainly.
Cathleen-- Oh, El, honey,
everything looks just marvellous.
Cathy, who on Earth is that man? You
have this whole place in a clamour.
For heaven sakes why? Because
of that ridiculous story?
Who is he?
He's Raymond Deagan, Otis Deagan's son.
Your gardener? He passed away and
Raymond's taken over his business.
You certainly seem on
familiar terms with him.
Oh, "familiar terms"--
What does that mean?
He happens to have some very
interesting views on Miró.
Oh, jeepers, look at the time. I have to fly.
I'm having the carpets cleaned for tomorrow--
What time are the caterers
showing? They said 4:00.
I'll come early, for moral
support. You're a doll.
So glad you could make
it. Come in. Come in.
Not to say that I'm against
integration, mind you.
I do believe it's the
Christian thing to do.
But I still say what
happened in Little Rock...
could just as easily have
happened here in Hartford.
- Nonsense.
- Well, why is that?
Well, for one thing, there's no
Governor Faubus in Connecticut.
But the main reason,
there are no Negroes.
No, but there are some...
rather dangerous pro-integration
types right here in Hartford.
Dangerous? Oh, yes.
Some very attractive ones, in fact,
noted, I'm told, for
their kindness to Negroes.
Oh, Dick, stop. Where on
Earth did you hear about that?
Shirley read it to me.
I should have known.
- What's all this?
- Absolutely nothing.
Now, let me freshen those.
Excuse me, please. Thanks.
Oh, by golly, there she is now,
the "purist" gal in the room.
Oh, Stan, liquor brings out the Texan
in you. I hope Eleanor isn't listening.
So what if she is. I still say
Frank is the luckiest guy in town.
Hear! Hear! It's all smoke and
mirrors, fells. That's all it is.
You should see her without her face on.
- Frank!
-No, he's absolutely right.
We ladies are never what we appear,
and every girl as her secrets.
I'll say. How about this girl
getting her husband another drink?
Darling, don’t you think
you've already had enough?
No, I don't think
I've had enough--
I'd just like to take a moment to raise a
glass to our marvellous host and hostess...
and another glorious annual
party at the Whitakers.
To Frank and Cathy, truly
Mr. and Mrs. Magnatech.
Hear! Hear!
My goodness. Thank you very much.
Now, who can I freshen
up? Ron? No, I'm fine.
Me. Oh, I think you’re fresh enough.
All right.
Here, Mrs. Whitaker,
let me take that for you.
Thank you, Sybil.
Cathy? Hi.
Honey, is everything all right?
Why? What do you mean?
Frank-- I've never
seen him so soused.
Oh, he's been working so hard
lately. He's under tremendous strain.
You sure that's all? Oh, yes.
You'd tell me if there was
anything more? Of course I would.
Well, Cathy,
I think we just threw ourselves one class
-"A" swanky function.
It did turn out nicely, didn't it?
Cathleen, darling, you've simply
outdone yourself once again.
Thank you so much.
Frank?
Well, if I do say so myself,
it was a lovely party,
all considering.
I just wish...
it didn't have to turn ugly...
in front of our friends.
Honestly, Frank, if
you didn't insist on--
What is it?
Oh, Frank.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, Jesus! What's
happening? I can't even--
God! Frank, it doesn't matter.
The important thing is to
keep, to keep trying. Don't!
What?
Because--
I'm sure, you know,
Dick Dawson wouldn't mind lending
his services every once in a while.
Oh, Frank.
I mean, you wouldn't mind
that so much, would you?
A good-looking guy like Dick.
Maybe even Stan would pitch in.
Frank, you're the only
man that I've ever wanted.
Just let go. Frank,
Frank, you're--
You're all men to me. You're all man.
Stop it!
Cathy. Cathy, I'm sorry. Oh.
I'm so sorry. I didn't mean to.
It's all right. I'm-I'm all right.
It was an accident. Are you bleeding?
Oh, just--just
the littlest bit.
Perhaps, um, you could
get me some ice, dear.
Some ice? Yes.
Cathy--
I-I know.
Uh, um, it's all right. I'm all right.
Hey, there, hon. Listen. I can't stay.
I'm meeting Stan for lunch at the club.
Oh, that sounds like fun. Can't believe
I let you get away without these.
It's cute, your hair that way. Oh, yeah?
I experimented. Oh, it's adorable.
Thanks. Oh. Whoopsie.
Thanks.
Cathy. What?
What happened to your head?
Oh, nothing. I--
I hit the door.
It was the silliest thing.
Cathy. What?
Did something happen
between you and Frank?
What do you mean?
Cathy, I'm your best friend.
Nothing happened.
Nothing at all.
Oh, Cathy.
Eleanor.
Cathy, I'm your dearest and
closest friend in the world.
You call me--
day or night.
You hear?
Mrs. Whitaker?
Is there anything I can do?
You sure?
I'm-- I'm fine.
I just,
um--
I-It's a difficult
time with my husband.
Oh. It happens with married people.
I know it does. I’m just--
It’s just embarrassing.
Please forgive me. Forgive you?
Mrs. Whitaker, listen.
I have to pick up some shrubs
from a farmhouse just out of town.
Which means I gotta get a move on.
Why don't you come along for the ride?
Some fresh air, change of scenery...
might help you take your mind of things.
Ooh. Oh,
no. I, uh--
I couldn't.
Uh--
Thank you, Raymond, for offering.
You're very kind.
You sure? Mrs. Whitaker?
Oh. Yes, Sybil? It's
Mrs. Barker on the phone.
I'll be right there! Oh.
Mm. I have to get back.
Okay.
Oh, not at all. Um, well, I-- I was
planning on picking them up at 5:00.
You'd like to switch for Thursday?
I don't see why that would be a problem.
Um, No. I'm glad I could be of help.
Certainly.
Bye now.
Raymond. Mrs. Whitaker.
Hi. Hello.
Oh, wouldn’t you know it. I just received
a call and suddenly everything's changed.
Anyway,
I--
You changed your mind.
Well, good.
Thank you very much,
Mr. Deagan. Thank you.
Oh, it's lovely. What is it?
Hamamelis-- well, flowering witch
hazel. Fairly rare in these parts.
It's beautiful.
You were right. What a
perfectly lovely spot.
Is that a path?
I think so.
Let's have a peek. All right.
Sometimes it's the people
outside our world...
we confide in best.
But once you do...
confide, share with someone,
they're no longer
really outside, are they?
Oh. Look!
How lovely.
Did he cause that?
He didn't mean to strike me.
I am so sorry.
No. Heaven knows we
all have our troubles.
I'm sure you,
yourself--
What?
I don't know. Ever since running
into you at the exhibition,
I kept wondering what it must be like...
to be the only one in a room.
Colored or...
whatever it was.
How that might possibly feel.
I'm sure I've--
I've never--
Well,
I suppose you sort of grow
accustomed to it over time.
I mean, don't get me wrong.
There is a world, even here in Hartford,
where everybody does
indeed look like me.
Trouble is, very few people
ever leave that world.
I only want what every
father wants for his child.
The opportunities growing
up I never had. Naturally.
But I tell you something. If
you’re really interested-- Oh, I am.
You hungry? I mean,
could you eat something?
I suppose I could. Tell you what,
I'm gonna take you to
one of my favourite spots.
On good days, it's got
hot food, cold drink,
and just about discernable music.
It's hard to beat that. There you go.
Say, who's green Edsel? Yoo-hoo.
Yoo-hoo. Here I am.
Oh. There you are, ma'am.
Let me get that for you.
Oh. Thank you very much indeed.
Thank you, ma'am.
Oh, my God.
Let me help you with that,
ma'am. Oh. Thanks very much.
Blues ]
Thank you. I'm hardly
dressed for a restaurant.
You look fine.
Raymond. Don't worry.
This is a very friendly place.
Say there, Esther.
What, you can't say hello anymore?
Looks like you speakin'
just fine for yourself.
Oh, now you just sore because I haven't
been coming around like I used to.
Is that so? Mm-hmm.
Now what do you say about bringing
us over a couple of drinks?
What would you like? Oh,
uh, a daiquiri if they--
One daiquiri and a bourbon on the rocks.
Thank you, doll.
What do you think you're doing, boy?
Thank you.
Well, I hope you’re
finding this very amusing.
What do you mean? This
is a very welcoming place.
How you doing', Gus?
See what I mean?
Thank you.
Thank you, Esther.
Here's to being the only one.
You know, we don't have to stay here.
If you feel uncomfortable-- No.
As long as I stay away from Esther,
I think I'll be fine.
All right then.
«
Thank you, Raymond,
for a lovely afternoon.
No. Thank you, Mrs. Whitaker.
I've had one as well.
Mrs. Whitaker sounds
so formal. Would you--
Would I what?
Ask me to dance?
«
Oh. That looks
wonderful. Now, let's see.
Where should we put it?
Oh. I know. Right there.
Right by the window.
Yes.
Yes. That's lovely. It certainly is.
Oh. Now, let's see.
Where did I put that list?
Although I promised Janice that I
wouldn't be late for her recital.
Can't miss that.
Sybil, I've been meaning
to ask you-- Yes, ma'am?
What's the name of that
church group you belong to?
The one you mentioned to
me. You mean, at Ebenezer?
The Baptist group? Yes.
I believe that's it.
Or was it South Green Baptist during
the fair drive, the Ladies Auxiliary?
Oh. I didn't know
there was more than one.
Yes. I always seem to be
signing up for something.
I think that's marvellous, Sybil, that
you find the time with all you do for us.
I just have so much in the attic
I've been meaning to go through.
I thought you might know of a
church or civic organization...
that could use a donation.
Well, certainly, Mrs. Whitaker, if
that’s what you’re looking for.
Places in need are never hard
to find. I'm sure you’re right.
Oh! My. Hello. May I help you?
Good afternoon, ma'am.
Allow me to introduce myself.
My name's Reginald Carter
and this is Martha Livingston.
We're members of the Hartford Branch...
of the National Association for
the Advancement of Colored People.
Oh, well, certainly, I am
familiar with your organization.
Perhaps you'd be interested in reading
over our complimentary brochure.
Mm. Yes. I would. If you
wouldn't mind signing our roster--
I'm running so terribly late as it is.
Sybil, would you mind
signing for me? Yes, ma'am.
Thank you.
«
Mother! Hello, dear.
- Did the recital just begin?
- Shh!
So where are the other
little girls from your class?
Over there.
Janice. Janice!
Sybil?
Hello. Cathy?
El? Oh, Cathy. Thank heavens you're
home. I've been trying you all day.
El, what is it? So you haven't
heard? You haven't heard a thing?
No. What happened? Oh, Cathy.
There's been talk. Vicious talk.
What do you mean? About what? About you?
Oh, for heaven sake. What
now? Honey. It's Mona, Cathy.
She's-- Well, she's just
been on some kind of rampage,
swearing up and down that she saw you and
a colored man somewhere out on Franklin.
Getting out of a truck
or some such thing.
The same colored man she claims
you were talking to at the art show.
Eleanor, that's--
that's preposterous.
I mean, yes, I've spoken to Mr. Deagan on
occasion, but this makes it sound like--
I know. You have no idea what
it's been like around here.
The phone has been ringing off
the hook since 8:00 this morning.
- Eleanor, the entire situation is so absurd.
- Darling, I know.
What in the world am I supposed to do?
I suppose you could start by
getting yourself another gardener.
Frank? What on Earth-- Eleanor, could
I call you back? Frank just walked in.
Of course. You go ahead.
I'll call you later.
Frank?
What are you doing home?
Is everything all right?
Just tell me one goddamned thing. What?
Is it true, what they've been saying?
Frank, I can't
believe you even--
Because if it is, even in the
slightest, I swear to God, Cathleen--
Frank, I am sorry you even
had to hear such nonsense.
Yeah, well, Dick Dawson didn't seem
to think it was such nonsense...
when he snuck away from
his desk to phone me today.
Good heavens. He says the
whole friggin' town's talking!
Frank, please. Sybil will hear you.
I sent her out!
Christ, Cathleen, do you even have the
slightest idea about what this could mean?
Don’t you realize the
effect it's gonna have on me...
and the reputation I have spent the
past eight years trying to build...
for you and the children
and for the company?
Frank, I swear to you, whatever
Mona Lauder saw or thought she saw...
was entirely a figment of that
woman's hateful imagination.
Yes. I have spoken to
Raymond Deagan on occasion.
He brought his little girl to Eleanor's
art show. But-- But, apparently,
even here in Hartford, the idea of a white
woman even speaking to a colored man--
Oh, please! Just save
me the Negro rights!
You know what that woman is capable of!.
And besides, I-I've
already given him notice...
and we-- we won't be
seeing that man again.
Fine.
Is that why you came home--
because of what Dick said?
Did something happen at work?
Frank.
Tsk. I guess you could call it
some sort of early Christmas bonus.
What do you mean?
A month of rest and relaxation.
Can you imagine? During the
busiest season of the year.
What a goddamn honour.
But when you consider the
bang-up job I've been doing...
ever since good ol' Dr.
Bowman came on the scene--
and for being-- What
did Millstein call it?
"Years overdue."
They do owe you a vacation
after all you've given them.
Palm Springs is supposed to be nice.
So says the word on high.
I know it may not seem like it now,
but a little time away, a vacation,
might be the best thing...
for both of us.
Frank, what a wretched day
it must have been for you.
Say, what do you know? Pop's
home. What you doing' home, Pop?
David, your father has work to do.
It's best you help yourself to a glass
of milk and get started on your studies.
Yes, Mother. Say, Pop--
Mind your mother, David.
Yes, sir.
Uh, say, Mr.
Deagan-- Yes, Jake?
There's a lady on the phone
for you. I'll be right there.
- Hello.
Thank you for meeting me. I
realize you have a busy schedule.
Worked out fine. I was glad you called.
Are you sure everything's all right?
Uh, is there something
I can do for you folks?
Can we leave here? Of course.
What is it? What happened?
I wanted to see you
in person, Raymond. I--
I just--
I can't.
Can't what?
It isn't plausible for
me to be friends with you.
You've been so very kind to me and I've been
perfectly reckless and foolish in return,
thinking--
Thinking what?
That one person could
reach out to another,
take an interest in another...
and maybe for one fleeting instant...
could manage to see beyond the surface,
beyond the color of things?
Do you think we ever really do...
see beyond
those things--
the surface of things?
"Just beyond the fall of grace,
behold that ever-shining place."
Yes. I do.
I don't really have a choice.
I wish I could.
Good luck to you, Raymond.
Mrs. Whitaker. You! Boy!
Hands off!.
- Yeah! You!
- Raymond, please don't.
You're so beautiful.
Come on, dear.
Oh! It is them! It is!
Thank you, Mother. Thank you, Father.
Mwah!
Oh-ho. Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
Now I'll be as good as all
the other girls in class.
Here you are, darling.
Just the way you like it. Ahh.
Hey, Pop. Look at this steam engine.
Wonderful. Oh. My goodness.
I knew I was forgetting something.
A little something
for Mr. and Mrs. Claus.
Well, what have we here?
"Bermuda."
"Acapulco. Rio.
Miami." Take your
pick. It's your choice.
Mother, will you help
me lace up my slippers?
In a minute, dear. I don't know.
Stan is always raving about Miami.
Oh, Frank. Miami would be a dream.
El says it's just
darling. Everything's pink.
Oh, really? Hmm.
Maybe we oughta consider Bermuda.
Oh, Frank! I do love you, darling.
Mwah. I do.
«
I must say, you look
extremely fetching...
all gussied up in
your white tux and tie.
Well, it's a good thing, since
I can hardly breathe in it.
Oh. It's not that bad.
You like my dress? Why, yes.
Very much. Didn't I say?
You did not. Well, it's
a ravishing dress...
with a ravishing girl to go with it.
That's more like it.
Very nice.
Right this way, sir.
Hilda, we're over here.
Ah. Excuse us. No problem at all.
«
You have a lovely family. Thank you.
Have a Happy New Year. Happy New Year.
Oh, Kenny, be a darling and
pour the champagne. Sure, Mother.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the time has come...
for the countdown into the new year.
Must be almost time. All together now!
Five, four, three,
two, one.
Happy New Year!
Happy New Year, darling. «
Happy New Year to you.
- Where do you wanna go?
- Mm. The table.
All right. Mary. Did you see Kenny?
Martin! Martin!
Martin!
Oh! Caroline.
You know you’re not
supposed to go in there!
Now what did I tell you
about going in that pool?
You know you're not
supposed to go in there!
Donna!
- Hello there.
- Well, hello.
Nice swim, darling? Ahh.
Isn't the sun just marvellous? Mm-hmm.
Donna. Time to get out. What? But why?
Because I said so.
- Here comes Kenny.
- I was looking for you on the other side.
I tell you, we're gonna
have to start meeting points.
That does it. I've had quite enough
fashion advice for the afternoon.
I do believe it's time
for my Miss Mitchell.
Oh, heavens. What?
I think I left it upstairs. So
silly. You want me to go get it?
No. You just sat down.
Oh, no. I don't mind.
You sure? Yeah. I have
to get a paper anyway.
Thank you, darling.
I think it's right
there on the nightstand.
Hey, Hutch. Look. What?
Hey, fellas!
Look who's coming. It's daddy's girl.
Hey there, daddy's girl. Where
do you think you're going?
Home. Home to see your daddy?
Yeah. And his white girlfriend.
Hey! Where you going?
We just wanna play.
Uh-oh. Wrong turn, daddy's girl.
Hey, daddy's girl. Over here.
Yeah. She made a wrong turn
all right. Just like her daddy.
They're here! I see
their car! They're here!
Welcome home, Mr. and Mrs.
Whitaker. Oh, my goodness.
What a lovely greeting.
Hiya, Pop. Hey, Mother.
Hey. So, Mother, was it dreamy?
Oh-ho. Listen to you. "Dreamy."
Did you have a nice time, Mr.
Whitaker? Yes. It was very relaxing.
Say, Pop-- David, help Sybil
with the luggage please.
Pop, you'll never guess what
happened at school this week.
Try and guess. David. Uh, I give up.
I'm helping, Mother. Billy
Hutchinson and these two other boys...
all got expelled from school.
I think you mean "suspended."
No. Expelled. I swear.
For throwing a rock at a
girl's head. That's terrible.
- A little girl at school?
- No. She was a Negro.
What? Who told you such
a thing? Tommy Hawkins.
He saw it, so he had
to tell the principal.
Sybil, is this true? Yes,
ma'am. I'm afraid it is.
What on Earth has gotten into this town?
It was just a couple of foolish kids.
Yeah. Hutch said that they were
just trying to teach her a lesson.
Well, I think it's dreadful, and you're not to
play with that Hutch boy again, understand me?
-Yes, ma'am.
- David, while you’re up,
how about flippin'on
the set for your old man?
Sure, Pop.
- Mother, how do you spell "skirt"?
- Uh, just a minute, dear.
Mother's making a call.
Oh. Yes. Hello. Um, I was wondering
if you could help me possibly.
I just received your brochure,
which I found extremely informative,
and I was curious about what was
entailed, precisely, in your--
in your volunteer program in terms
of particular skills and so on.
You see,
I-- Oh.
Oh, yes. I can hold.
Father's home.
Frank. What happened to the match?
Oh, my, um, shoulder.
It started acting up.
I-- I just couldn't
sit there any longer.
You didn't say anything. Father,
I did the splits today. Wanna see?
Janice, your father just
walked in the door...
and you have schoolwork to finish.
Yes, Mother.
You know, Frank, you
never had that physical.
And I think you're due for
one. Can I call Dr. Ellis?
You know, it's been three years.
Oh. Did I tell you that the paediatrician
thinks that Janice is going to need braces?
Father, do I have to? Apparently,
our little girl has an overbite.
Pop, you'll never guess what
I'm doing. Where is your coat?
It's in the garage. I'm waxing
Pop's car. And what's it doing there?
It's gonna look swell, Pop.
How many times do I have to tell you
children you are not permitted outdoors...
in this kind of weather unless
you are properly dressed?
Yes, ma'am. Because I give up.
If you wanna go and catch your
death of cold, then so be it.
You try talking some sense into them,
Frank, because whatever I say doesn't--
Frank?
What's the matter?
God.
David, Janice, go
upstairs to your rooms.
Now.
Now!
Frank.
What is it?
Cathy,
something's happened.
What?
I've fallen in love with someone...
who wants to be with me.
Oh, Cathy,
I-I-I
just-- I--
I never knew
what that felt--
But I know that
sounds so cruel, but--
Oh, God. Cathy, I tried.
I tried so hard to make it go away.
It-- It-- I thought
that I could do it...
for you and for the kids.
But... I can't.
I just--
I can't.
I, um, assume then, you'll be...
wanting a divorce.
Cathy.
Eleanor.
Eleanor, it's me, Cathy.
Oh, Cathy.
So you see, El,
why I couldn't tell you
anything-- anything at all.
Oh, you dear sweet kid.
In a million years, I couldn't
have imagined. Not Frank.
I think that's what's
been hardest of all.
The endless secrecy.
Our entire lives just shut in the dark.
Are there savings? None to speak of.
Certainly not with
Frank's job on the line.
Well, honey, if there’s anything
you need, anything at all--
Oh, El. I mean it.
We're here, all right?
Thank you, El,
for always having been.
You know, it's funny. What's that?
This whole time, the only person I was
able to talk to about any of this...
was Raymond Deagan.
- What?
- It's true.
Not in the way that Mona
intended. Nothing like that.
But we would just talk.
And somehow, it
made me feel--
I don't know.
Alive somewhere.
Eleanor, I know it's ridiculous and mad,
but I-- I
think of him.
I do.
What he's doing. What he's thinking.
I--
I do.
El? What can I say?
You're so full of
surprises, I'm speechless.
What do you mean? I'm sure I
must've looked entirely the fool...
crusading away against Mona Lauder
and all her so-called inventions.
Eleanor, how could you say such a thing?
I didn't say a word.
Who am I to tell anyone
how to lead their lives?
Eleanor, nothing happened
between us. I told you that.
Cathy, it's none of my business,
but you certainly make it
sound as if something had.
Mrs. Whitaker? Oh. Sybil.
I'm sorry to disturb
you, ma'am. I-I just--
Yes, Sybil?
There's something I've been wanting
to tell you, ma'am, for some time.
Something I believe you surely Anna
know, even if it isn't exactly my place.
Well, what is it? It's about
the little colored girl, ma'am.
The one that got hit. Yes.
What about her?
I'm sorry, ma'am. It was Mr.
Deagan's little girl, Sarah.
What? Oh, Sybil. No.
The neighbours tell me she's doing just
fine. Oh, that poor sweet little girl.
That-- How in God's name could you not
have told me, Sybil? This was weeks ago!
Mrs. Whitaker, please
don't be cross with me.
I didn't wanna make things any worse.
Sybil, do you know
where Mr. Deagan lives?
I believe he's been at his father's
old place on 12th and Governor.
Twelfth and Governor. Thank you.
Are you going there now?
Please keep an eye on the
children. I shouldn't be too long.
Mrs. Whitaker. What?
Would you like me to go with you, ma'am?
No. No, I'll be fine. Thankyou, Sybil.
Who on Earth?
Yes. Raymond, I-- I just
heard. Just this instant.
I heard and I jumped into my car.
How are you? How is Sarah?
We're fine. Thank you.
Would you meet me around the side?
Sarah, everything's all right. Daddy's
just gonna be out for a minute, okay?
Okay.
Raymond. What she must've been through.
What's being done to the boys? Nothing.
I won't put her through that again.
Not now. Not with rocks coming
through the windows every night.
Raymond, that's hateful. Oh,
it's not whites throwin' them.
It's coloreds. No.
Yeah.
Seems to be the one place where whites
and coloreds are in full harmony.
Anyway, we'll be outta here
soon enough once and for all.
You're moving?
Yeah. Where to?
I have a brother in Baltimore,
says he can find me work there.
So we're packing up the house.
Two weeks, Friday, we'll be on
the 4:30 train heading south.
What about your-- your
business, your shop?
Oh, the business is through.
Nobody's gonna hire me.
So I'm gonna sell the
shop to a cousin of mine.
Yeah. Things are...
pretty well finished for me here.
I've never lived anywhere
other than Hartford.
Perhaps...
sometime in the future...
after you’re
settled, I could--
Perhaps I could come for a visit,
see Baltimore.
You
see, I--
Well, it seems as if
I'm to be single again.
Oh, Mrs. Whitaker.
Please call me Cathy.
Cathy.
No one would know us there.
I'm just not sure that
would be a wise idea.
After,
well,
everything
that's--
What matters now,
what has to matter the most,
is what's right for Sarah.
I've learned my lesson
about mixing in other worlds.
I've seen the sparks fly.
All kinds.
Have a proud life.
A splendid life.
Will you do that?
Good-bye, Cathy.
Hello. Cathy, did I wake you?
I-I'm sorry to call this
late. I hope I didn't, uh--
Uh, no. I was awake.
I, uh, didn't want
to upset the children.
No. No, of course not.
How are they, by the way?
Fine. Just fine. They still
ask when you'll be coming home.
I know.
That's, uh, partly
why I'm calling really.
I got a call from Dick yesterday...
and he said that everything was set,
um, papers drawn up.
And he wanted to know how Thursday
was for you. 3:00 or sometime?
I-- I told him I thought
you had car pool Thursdays,
but I wasn't absolutely
certain, so I said I would check.
You never could remember
my car pool days.
And they've always been the same.
Wednesdays and Fridays,
long as I can remember.
Oh, Wednesdays and
Fridays. Right. Uh--
Same old
absentminded--
What time... did you say on Thursday?
What? The appointment. What time?
Three. Uh, three o'clock.
All right.
Okay. Uh, well... great.
That-- That was
it, uh, really.
I... know it's late.
It is.
So I'll see you on--
on Thursday then.
See you Thursday.
Good-bye, Cathy.
Good-bye, Frank.
Sixty-seven dollars
and thirty-two cents.
Now, what day is today?
Oh, Sybil. You don't need to do that.
It's Friday.
I know it's Friday, but
there's so much to be done now,
I can hardly expect you
to be polishing tables.
No reason not to keep
things up. No reason at all.
I know. Don't forget the grocery list.
Thank you.
I don't know how on
Earth I'd ever manage--
I shouldn't be long, Sybil.
All right, Mrs. Whitaker.
Why are we turning in here?
I'll be right back. Where are you going?
Now stay put, both of you.
All aboard! Southbound train
to New York and Washington...
now departing!
All aboard!
All right. Thanks. I 'l I be seeing you.
Southbound train to New
York and Washington...
now departing.
All aboard!
Ready to go?
That's my girl.
Wesley! Come on! We'll miss the train.
Don't forget to call
your mother tomorrow.
All aboard! Southbound
train to New York City--
- Thank you, sir.
- Here you go. Thanks.
All aboard!
The End @
Preuzeto sa www.titlovi.com