The region where North Korea, China and Russia meet
is known as Yanbian Korean Autonomous Prefecture.
About 800,000 Korean-Chinese known as JOSEONJOK reside here.
Over 50% of Joseonjok population rely on illegal activities
or legally live and work in South Korea in order to survive.
When I was 11 years old, rabies was spread throughout the neighborhood.
I'm telling you, you're left with quite a profit.
Our dog, too caught rabies. It bit it's mother to death first,
Then, what it could kill with it's mouth,
it bit to death.
Eventually when the neighbors prepared to kill it,
it ran off.
-I'll play the number 10...
-Hu!
You have chow.
Kong and chow is 4 points, 8 points,
You're at 16 points.
After a few days, that dog showed up again looking extremely thin.
In his black eyes,
he didn't have any strength.
But he stared at me like that for awhile
and then slowly laid down and died.
I buried that dog behind the neighborhood,
and the dog that was buried in the ground like that
was dug up that night and eaten by the elders.
I have kong.
Oh, you have Kong? Wait please.
I have a higher kong.
Hu
You lose again.
How do I fare so well?
Do I deal now?
- Shit
- Damn.
16 points plus 32 points...
Hey, hey... what kind of calculations are you doing?
Hey!
That bastard, what does he think he's doing?
The reason why I thought of that dog all of the sudden is
because after that, rabies was spread again.
Rabies is spreading.
Yellow Sea
1 . Taxi driver
[North Korean Joseon People Self-Governing, Yanji City]
Damn
What time did you come in?
I'm asking you,
what time did you come in?
4:00
You played mahjong again didn't you?
Didn't I tell you that I wouldn't let you off if you played Mahjong again?
I will tell you again.
If I dig out your eyeballs and all of your organs to sell,
and sell your daughter to animal like men,
it still isn't enough to pay the original amount back.
However, if you keep going on...
Sorry
I'm sorry?
You're telling me you are sorry?
Hah!
Is 60,000 yuan a joke to you?
You are going to repay that through playing mahjong?
Hey you bastard!
Don't wash, just get out.
Make more money.
That son of a bitch.
Shit...
Ma'am!
Go, I have no business with you.
Please find out for me,
I'm sure it has come in this time.
Your wife is having an affair,
Do you think she'd send you money?
Ahjumma, do you want to quit your business?
I got it.
That son of a bitch won't shut up.
Hey, please confirm if money has come in from Korea.
Kim Goo Nam, Lee Hwa Ja should be depositing...
It hasn't come in?
Ok, got it.
They're saying it hasn't come in.
Are you absolutely sure?
Do you think I'd lie that money that has come in hasn't?
There are many wives that have gone to Korea and are having an affair.
Just think that she is rotten and don't come back here.
Don't say that!
That crazy ass!
I am sorry son-in-law.
Give me the money, give me the money.
Give me the money.
You don't have any money?
Boss, this one has no money,
trade me.
You're not leaving?
Go, you gaoli bangzi.
[*Note: A gaoli bangzi is a racial term Chinese use for Koreans.]
Leave, you bastard.
You mother fucker!
Bitch.
Did you have a bad dream?
They say dreams are opposites...
There will be good news then.
Your life savor has turned up.
Mr. Myun!
Mr. Myun, hello
Come here.
This kid...
I got it. You can go.
Go and wait.
When I'm done talking, I'll send him back.
Those morons.
You know who I am, right?
I'm Myun Gah, nice to meet you.
Your hands are really...
Have you eaten?
Let's go eat.
I heard you haven't heard from your wife that went to Korea.
The money that you borrowed to get your wife a visa is still the same?
60,000 yuan?
Aigoo...
Those fuckers want a whole 60,000 yuan?
You must want to kill your wife.
If she doesn't call after getting to Korea,
it's definitely an affair.
Hey, hey, hey... listen to the rest of what I have to say before you leave.
Sit.
Sit down.
You're quite an interesting fellow.
You've got a bad temper but you're not a gangster.
You always get hit, but I don't feel sorry for you.
Weird.
Did you say you were Goo Nam?
Yes.
Goo Nam,
Go to Korea and kill someone for me.
You kid, do you think I'm joking?
You can't get all of that money here.
Do you want to live your whole life being beat like those dogs?
Go kill him or bring him back.
And meet up with your wife.
Don't think and go.
Start fresh.
I knew you wouldn't be able to make a decision.
Contact me quickly.
Before I find someone else.
Are you cleaning chicken poo?
Seung Hee, Daddy is here.
Here Seung Hee. Ah~
Still no word from her mom?
That girl looked bad from the start.
Her eyes are so slanted...
They're split open like a vagina.
Old lady, have you gone insane? Watch what you say.
Is that something to say in front of a child?
Your eyes are slanted too...
You son of a bitch.
You should hurry and make money to go to Korea.
Go and meet a pretty korean girl
and show that bitch that you live well.
I'll take care of the kid so don't worry.
Oh have you come?
Memorize it.
Have you memorized it all?
Tell me.
Seoul, Kang Nam area, Noh Hyun Dong 99-1
Kim Seung Hyun
Don't forget that.
If you forget this, your whole family will die.
It's 3,000 yuan. 500,000 won in Korean money.
That should be more than enough so use it for your expenses in Korea.
Take it.
That's 57,000 yuan.
When you come back after you've finished the job,
I'll tell you the password.
Then it becomes your money, got it?
Oh, right! You have to bring back his finger. A finger.
The thumb.
Hey!
Have a safe trip.
[Liaoning province, Dalian City]
Hey, wake up! Wake up quick!
Get up quick! Hey!
Hey wake up!
Wake up! Go up! Hurry get up!
Get out! Quickly get out!
Hurry, Hurry! You bitch!
Get up, hurry!
Get up! Hurry, get up!
Jump, Jump! You bitch!
Hurry! Bastard, Come up!
- You got it?
- Go! Go!
Go, Go, Go!
[2. Murderer]
[South Kyung-Sang Province, Ulsan City]
[Ul Joo Sushi House Bed And Breakfast]
Ah this lighter...
Hey, give me that light there.
Hey! Give me that.
This is the boat to return.
The date is written.
It's exactly 10 days later.
[January 16th Inchun city Suh Goo Kyung Suh Dong
472-1 Hae Chun Bed and Breakfast]
If you're late, you can't go back to China.
Also...
I don't know what you came to do,
But wear a hat.
You stand out too much.
[Ulsan Public Bus Terminal]
[Seoul Special City]
Seoul City, Kang Nam area
99-1, Kim Seung Hyun
[Catholic Church]
[No Hyun Dong 99-1]
Kim Seung Hyun
[Watch Repair]
[Ahn San Station]
Lamb Skewers
What about alcohol?
Uh...
Have you....
Do you know this woman?
I don't think so.
She said she worked here
about a year ago...
I don't know.
Later when the owner comes,
You can ask him.
She quit really fast.
Did she work 2 months?
I think she said she was going to Gari Bong Dong.
Where?
In Seoul, Gari Bong Dong.
Where is that?
I don't know.
But do you think she'd still be there?
But why? You can't contact her?
Hey, come here.
Of the people here, how many do you think are couples? Huh?
Forget her or act like you don't know her.
Don't go around making trouble.
Joseon people that come here and make a mess get deported.
So quietly earn money and leave.
-Yes, you worked hard. See you tomorrow!
- Go safe, Goodbye.
- Go safe, see you tomorrow.
- Goodbye
Oh, you scared me.
Where are you coming from?
Uh... the second floor..
But why did you take the elevator down?
Are you a Joseon Jok?
- Ahjusshi, what are you?
Hey, Hey, leave him, he's a Joseon.
Don't stay in here because it's cold. Ok?
Yes...
Hey!
Come over here.
Come!
If you don't have anywhere to sleep, go sleep at the sauna across the street.
Take it. Go ahead and take it.
Pull the gate down.
3:10
2:10, 3:10..
2:10
3:10
Bar.. 3:10, Shut Doors
Lights.. Driver...
2:10, bar...
3:10, Kim Seung Hyun...
Shit.
Ah, thumb
Finger, thumb...
Thumb, Finger...
[Gari Bong Variety Market]
[Dong Po Town Welcome]
Do you know this woman?
If you go straight that way,
there's a block with a lot of bars...
You shouldn't do this.
Move over, move over.
I don't know.
Welcome.
I'm looking for a person.
I know her, isn't she Hwa Ja?
There was a customer that came to see her often,
He was the supplier of fish at a Japanese restaurant.
The called each other Oppa/Dongseng
and were quite close.
And then, That guy..
in Gang Nam... some Japanese restaurant...
had an opening so he quit
and went there.
That man comes here often
So try asking him if you find him.
What is his name?
I don't know his name,
Look for a white truck.
A truck that loads fish.
Were they lovers?
I don't know.
Ah, really...
Hey!
Ye..Yes?
You know this woman, right?
Yes, but why?
Where is that bitch?
You know where she is, right?
Ahhh...
Excuse me, Sir?
Mister.
Mister!
Why are you doing this, Mister?
Where is this woman?
Why?
She's my wife.
I want to see her face.
Who are you?
The woman next door...
Do you know where that woman has gone?
A little while ago
she had a big fight with a man...
She's not there anymore?
When was that?
It hasn't been long,
about 1 hour.
1 hour...
By chance...
Did you see the man's face?
I couldn't.
But who are you?
[Mok Po Fishing]
The call could not be answered, please leave a message after the tone.
[Myun Jung Hak]
What?
President Myun, I'm Goo Nam.
Oh, Kim Goo Nam.
Is your work going well?
Sir, something came up for me...
The return boat,
could you delay it a few days?
What do you mean by that?
The boat is to depart tomorrow,
Please delay it for about 2 days.
Are you thinking of something else right now?
Sir, that's not it...
The boat isn't under my control so I can't change it,
but make sure to finish the job.
If you don't, I told you right?
I will send someone to your mother's home right now,
so think carefully before making your decision.
President Myun!
Who is it?
Sir, let me ask you a favor.
When the woman next door comes in...
it doesn't matter if it's the man either...
Whoever comes, hold them there so they can't leave.
I will be here by 4:00 AM.
Please just hold onto them until then.
-You guys worked hard.
-Yea, see you tomorrow.
Hey you son of a bitch, stop right there!
Stop there, you fucking bastard.
Here! Here!
[3. Joseon Clan]
[*Note: Joseon Clan is a North Korean person that crossed over to China and is a citizen of China.]
Yes.
Mm.
If you see the suspect or know him,
Please report to a nearby police station or the 112 call number.
This dawn, the silver medalist of Judo at the Beijing Asian Games,
Kyung In Athletic University Kim Seung Hyun
He was murdered in his own building.
Police say there were 3 men that constantly came to the place a few days before.
And the murdered professor Kim Seung Hyun's finger has disappeared.
They say there is a high chance that
this case a planned murder.
We estimate that these three people are working together.
We will find and arrest the runaway suspect.
It's important to reveal the true criminal.
[January 16th In Chun Suh Goo Kyung Suh
Dong 472-1 Hye Chun Bed and Breakfast.]
[In Chun Gwang Yuk Shi Suh Goo Kyung Suh Dong 472-1]
[January 16th In Chun Suh Goo Kyung Suh
Dong 472-1 Hye Chun Bed and Breakfast.]
[Myun Jung Hak]
The number you have dialed
is no longer in service
Hello?
It's Goo Nam.
I can't get a hold of that dog owner you introduced me to back then.
Hello...
Hello?
Yes boss, it's me.
Mm.
Who is going to that chauffeur's home?
Shit. Just go.
Okay.
The guy that ran away, you don't know him, right?
Yes.
You're not going to find him?
We should find him.
Should find him?
You son of a bitch,
You have done something unspeakable to me.
I could chew you to death.
Hey.
Hey!
Yes.
No matter how much money it takes, find that bastard now.
Before the police.
Yes.
What will you do when you find him?
Kill him.
Pull it all the way down. All the way...
Ahjusshi? Ahjusshi?
Ah, yes.
Ahjusshi, what did you say was missing?
About 200,000 won that was in the drawer and...
Clothes. You're not missing any clothes?
[Hwa Sung]
[Hwa Sung City]
Give me one ticket to Hwa Sung please.
You crazy bitch! What do you take me as?!
You are dead, come here! You're dead today. Come here!
Come here!!
Come here right now!
How are you going to sleep in the car?
I'll just sleep with this.
Should we sing your teddy a lullaby?
Yes.
Are you going to sleep? Okay, let's sleep.
[Stop and Search]
Excuse us.
Excuse us, we are doing a stop and search.
Please show us your ID.
Sir?
Sir??
Hong Shik!
Hey, stop right there...
Hey, stop there! I'll shoot!
Ahh! I'm going crazy!
Shit, what are you?
Stay still. Don't move.
Hong Shik! Hold him.
I'm taking my cuffs out.
-Don't move!
-I'm taking my cuffs out, taking my cuffs out.
Good job, good job, okay, done!
Wait, wait.
You did well today.
Hey Hong Shik! Wait!
Hold onto him for a little bit!
You bastard! Let that go!
Hong Shik, don't move! You can't move!
Let go of that you bastard!
Ah, shoot!!
Hong Shik! Hong Shik!
Hong Shik!
Hong Shik! What's wrong with you?
Hong Shik! Hong Shik!
What's wrong Hong Shik? Are you okay?
You son of a bitch!
Subtitle by
Aldi Arman
Stop right there! You son of a bitch!
Stop right there!
You will be dead when I catch you!
Hong Shik... Hong Shik...
I shot because you told me to, but why did you get shot?
Ah, that shitface..
What's up with those guys?
[Professor Kim Seung Hyun's murderer is a Joseon.]
That chauffeur wanted to make some money,
that's why he used those bastards.
Or, you did that.
Did you do that?
No sir.
Then, did the chauffeur do that?
I think so.
You dumbass.
It's obvious he is trying to do escape.
Even if you have to beat all of the Joseons down,
find out the boat he will be boarding.
Yes.
The police aren't dumb, He will get caught 100%
before he can board the boat.
Find him before that and kill him.
Okay?
Yes.
It's Sang Chun.
Call him.
Yes, I understand.
Hey, grab that bastard!
Begin.
I will tell you. I will tell you.
Shit!
Escort the President here.
About that Joseon guy,
It looks like he was smuggled into the country.
You made all this mess and that's all you're telling me?
So?
There is a broker that handles these types of cases.
If he was smuggled,
there is 100% probability that he has a connection with the broker.
Where is that broker?
There aren't any brokers in Korea.
You bastard, really!
There were a few brokers like that just up to a little bit ago, but
now, there is one person left, Myun Gah, a person living in Yeon Gil (Yanji).
His real name is Myun...
Ah, Jung Hak. He is called Myun Jung Hak.
I think that if we get rid of that broker,
we are losing one other person of this line of work...
Mm.
Even if that Joseon kid were caught...
Myun Jung Hak?
Yes.
You're absolutely sure, right?
First of all,
these people here don't know that Joseon kid at all.
Which means
he was smuggled in.
And if he was smuggled,
The chance that Myun Gah sent him, is 100%.
Then go right now to Yeon Gil (Yanji)
and find Myun Jung Hak.
- When you find him...
- I will take care of it.
Police are not able to find trackable trail.
Professionals say this mountain is a tough one to climb,
And has many escape routes to populated areas.
It's very likely that the suspect has escaped from the searching grounds.
This morning, at a home in the Ahn Mountain in Kyunggi Province,
A mutilated body was found and the police have begun investigations.
The body that was found inside a bag,
has been revealed to be a Joseon woman in her early 30's.
This morning, a Joseon Mr. Choi that resides in Won Gok Dong of Ahn Mountain,
found an abandoned travel bag in a alley near his home.
A mutilated body was found in this bag
and Mr. Choi immediately contacted the police.
The body that was found with the neck, arms and etc dismembered,
has been presumed to be a woman in her early 30's.
Also, the Won Gok Dong of Ahn San has been known for being the Joseon smuggling area.
As the body's identity was found to be a Joseon, an investigation to know her accurate identity is going on.
[Yo Sul Palace]
[Yo Sul Palace][Yo Sul Palace]
[North Korean Joseon People Self-Governing, Yanji City]
Welcome.
What can I do for you?
Give me a room, please.
Yes, please wait one moment.
Is there a special suite here?
There is... but a different customer is occupying it at this time.
Myun Jung Hak?
Why are you so surprised?
Babe, do you want to make some money?
Who are you?
What are you doing? Give me a towel.
We're all done,
What do you want to do with this?
Throw the head away separately
and give the rest to the dogs.
You're boss's name is Kim Tae Won?
President Kim Tae Won...
Maybe it's because it's too late,
He isn't answering.
That psycho bastard.
Hey! You haven't gotten a call from Choi Jung Nam?
No.
Crazy mother fucker.
[Massage]
What about the office?
They're all gangsters.
There he comes.
How is it? Is it right?
Yes. The ownership is under another guy's name, but
it's Kim Seung Hyun's building.
Then Kim Seung Hyun owns a total of 7 buildings.
4 massage clinics,
and 3 room salons.
Hah. A person that calls himself a professor...
He's a total crook.
[South Kyung San Province Busan City]
[Yo Sul Palace]
Why did you do that?
Was it for the money?
I don't know... we don't know.
We just did it because President Myun...
Call Myun Jung Hak.
I do not know... I really don't know..
We only do as they ask us...
Do I look like a moron to you? Huh?
How could you do that to me?
Oh my, I apologize.
The suspect just showed up in Busan
so it's crazy here right now.
After looking it up,
We found that Professor Kim Seung Hyun was quite a famous person over there.
We heard that you were close with Professor Kim...
Yes.
What is your relationship?
We were like brothers.
You made a scary brother.
A few days ago, the suspect of Professor Kim's murder showed up at the building. You knew that, right?
Yes.
There, we saw your company cars
and employees.
We also found that you invested quite a lot in Professor Kim.
A little.
By chance....
Are you searching for the suspect right now?
You still haven't gotten a hold of Choi Sung Nam?
Yes.
The guys that went with him too?
Bastards.
This is driving me insane.
Should I drive you to your home?
Go to the building.
You don't feel anything?
About what?
You were close with that person.
Why did you do it?
[Choi Sung Nam]
Where are you?
President Kim Tae Won?
Who are you?
Oh, I'm Myun Gah,
From Yeon Gil (Yanji), you know me...
Hey! Hey!!
Yes.
I've arrived at the airport with Mr. Choi.
Let's meet. A little later around dinner time.
Are you listening to me?
Has this man gone deaf?
Hey! Hey!
Next to you... Is Mr. Choi there?
What a...
Answer it.
What are you doing?
Yes, boss.
You... What are you doing right now?
We..we just arrived at the airport.
He calls himself a man?
Give it to me.
President Kim?
Mr. Choi will go to you right now,
So listen to what he tells you and give me a call.
Have you or have you not heard me?
What kind of bastard is this?
Hey! Kim Tae Won!
That fucking bastard.
Hey! President Myun!
Oh! You guys came!
-Good to see you!
-Chan Sung! It's been awhile!
What's wrong?
Go and tell him my words clearly.
If he tries anything, I will spread rumors,
Understand?
Yes.
I sent the money.
Oh, it's me.
I sent the money so confirm it.
2 'o clock. I got it.
What did he say?
Tell me.
It's a boat to Dalian,
At 2:00. Busan Pier, Number 6.
Tonight?
That's all?
Aigoo, Ah, hello!
Do I sit here?
Boss is so handsome.
Have you heard everything from Mr. Choi?
What do you think?
President Kim, You should know because you said you heard, but
Of the boats that go from Korea to China,
there isn't a boat that doesn't come across me.
The news say Kim Goo Nam is in the Busan area,
Now why would he have gone there?
That kid can't
not be caught by me.
I understand. Do as you wish.
Huh?
Ah, you will do it?
But I will split your share.
3,000 for the contract fee,
once the deal is done, I will give you the money then.
Ah, why would you be like this?
That is the correct way.
What if you try something else when that time comes?
You know our situation.
That won't happen.
Then I will trust you
and start my work.
Go ahead.
Good.
Okay, We've become one family.
Last time, about your employees, my sincere...
Let's not talk about that, okay?
Is it that guy? That guy is the person?
Why is he frowning like that?
Hyung-nim.
Yea, Mr. Park?
I'm Myun Gah.
Ah, Mr. Park, are you in Busan right now?
I'm going to have to meet with you.
I'm in Korea right now.
Why doesn't this guy answer his phone?
Oh, it's me.
Why can't I get a hold of Young Bae? His phone was on.
Look into it for me.
He says he can't get in contact, right?
You're right.
Last time when Kim Goo Nam came,
Where did he sleep?
Ulsan, why?
Guide me there.
It seems as though the tension will heighten.
The suspect to the cruel Ahn Mountain murder case has been caught.
The criminal is an average fisher in his mid 40's.
The victim is a Joseon woman in her early 30's.
Today at 11:30 AM, the police arrested the 46 year old suspect
of this case, Mr. Bae, and is interrogating him.
The Fisherman, Mr. Bae, has confessed to everything.
Police say it is a passionate crime.
And are investigating the accurate partner in crime.
Living together,
I introduced her to a job,
I gave her money.
But all of the sudden,
She said she was going to China,
to meet her husband.
I was drunk, I didn't know what I was doing...
[Mok Po Fishery]
How do you feel now?
I'm sorry.
The police say Mr. Bae,
dismembered the victim's arms, legs, etc.
The police are investigating the site where he threw the body parts away.
Hello?
Yes.
Sir, I heard your story,
But we cannot give out the name of the victim to just anyone.
My wife's name is
Lee Hwa ja, but I don't know if that is correct...
Sir, this can't be told over the phone. Contact the coast guard or police. And tell them you are family...
The murderer is Mok Po Fishing,
Number is 016,
Sir, I cannot tell you because it is personal information.
Ah, it's about my wife,
please don't be like that and help me out.
Lee Hwa Ja,
Mok Po Fishing.
Teacher, no matter how much you call...
Who is a teacher? How am I a teacher? Shit!
[Ul Joo Sushi]
Is that it?
Mm.
Hey, all of you get out.
[No Trespassing]
Did Shin Young Bae send you?
Hey, get out.
Did you bring the money?
Yea.
Follow me.
Go inside.
I told you to go inside.
-Wait... Wait!
-Close it!
Lock it!
-Ah!
-Fuck!
-You mother fucker!
-Shit!
Ah!!
You shithead!
Go get him!
Hey you son of a bitch!
You guys are friends, why are you fighting so much?
There he is.
Hey, just jump over the gate.
Hey you asshole!
Get out of the way, all of you!
Move out of the way!
You fucktards!
You made such a mess because you couldn't catch this rat?!
Bastard.
Give it to me.
Goo Nam.
You son of a bitch!
That mother fucker.
What are you guys doing?
Go get him!
What will you do running over there? Ah shit.
[4. Yellow Sea]
Why did you go to the Busan Pier?
I was just site seeing.
So what you are saying is that Myun Jung Hak
met with the owner of the bus company?
Yes.
After he met with the owner,
he went straight to Busan with you guys,
Myung Jung Hak did, right?
Yes.
Kim Tae Won would absolutely say that it wasn't him...
I guess we have to find Myun Jung Hak.
Ah, fuck...
Where in the world do we find that bastard?
I'm going to sleep.
Ah damn,
Those cock suckers should do some cleaning.
Wait a minute.
Ah, you embarrassing bastard.
What am I doing right now?
Yea, Mr. Choi?
Bring President Kim over here.
It's an urgent matter.
Shit, I can't tell.
Yes, It's me.
I just confirmed it,
And you were correct.
It's the same person as in the picture.
Hello?
Are you absolutely sure?
Yes, I am absolutely sure.
I could tell with one glance.
Hello?... Hello?
Go ahead.
Ah, yes, also, that woman,
she needs to be cremated right away.
It normally costs about 300,
but I found a place that would do it for 200.
Can you get 200?
Hello?
Go ahead and do that.
Let me talk to my Seung Hee.
You scumbag. Is there something wrong?
Goo Nam?
Don't say anything. Just let me talk to Seung Hee.
Hurry, put her on the phone.
You silly kid, it's so late for her.
Go ahead and talk to her.
President Kim.
Kim Tae Won!
Fill the earth and
subdue it.
The fish in the sea
and birds in the sky
and over every living creature that moves along the ground
Let them have dominion.
The Lord said...
What am I supposed to do if you lose that son of a bitch?
You bastards!
Find that mother fucker immediately.
Find him!
[Catholic Church]
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
You won't believe me, but
The person that killed your husband,
wasn't me.
The one that killed your husband,
was that chauffeur.
I,
Won't be able to go back to China.
I'll die anyway.
Before I die...
The person who ordered this,
why they ordered this,
I'm going to find out.
It is after I meet that man,
I will be able to die.
When I meet that man,
I will kill him for you.
Please answer the questions I ask you.
Welcome.
Sir, please remove your shoes.
Who is the highest person here?
Hey!
Is it here?
What did you say?
It was a few hours ago.
I was looking around Gari Bong
to find Myun Jung Hak,
We found a guy that was saying he was in charge
of the professor's murder...
Ah, what does that mean?
He said he paid people to kill Kim Seung Hyun.
He was bragging to people he was drinking with.
This bastard, I have no idea what you are talking about.
Hey, where is he?
He's in the basement.
- Is this him?
- Yes.
Tell me.
What happened?
I think it's confirmed.
This guy worked as a waiter in Gangnam..
You guys keep quiet.
Quickly tell me.
Before I kill you.
Just...
he kept saying he wanted to kill someone...
Who?
Someone that came by our store often...
It's this guy.
[Kim Jung Hwan]
This guy...
Made you do it?
He kept drinking,
and kept saying it over and over...
I'm asking if this guy made you do it.
Yes, yes.
So what did you do?
My wife...
told me that a friend's lover in Yeon Gil did that line of work...
So, to that person...
You gave the job to that guy?
Yes.
And then?
I don't know either.
Really. I really don't know!
Then... Who is that friend's lover in Yeon Gil?
He is Myun Jung Hak.
Shut up you shitface!
That friend's...
lover, who is it?
Myu... Myun Jung Hak...
Tell Choi Sung Nam to come.
Hello?
What is this?
Tell me.
I'll say it, I'll say it!
Kim Tae Won...
Who?
Kim Tae Won.
Kim Tae Won!
What does he do?
[President Kim Tae Won]
Where are you?
You son of a bitch!
That son of a bitch...
Go and drag this son of a bitch here.
Go over to that side!
Do I have to stab him?
Can't we just bury him?
What if he tries to attack us?
Still... how could....
Are you going to keep saying such things?
Why did you start this if that's how you were going to be?
Just close your eyes and stab him.
Close your eyes.
Get out.
Open the trunk when I say 1, 2, 3.
Okay.
One... Two... Three!
Ah Shit!
-Call him.
-Yes.
I'm sorry.
That dead kid... I'll give you his money,
so let's share the money and separate.
I'm a North Korean too.
I came from Hoon Chun.
I'll kill the guy that told me to kill you.
I'll be sure kill him!
That guy's card,
that guy's business card is in the car. Go look!
Don't come here you crazy ass!
[HK Savings Bank]
[Kim Jung Hwan]
Go rip that guy's clothes and bring it to me.
Wrap it around.
Bandage it!
President Kim.
Give me my money.
I must give it to you, of course.
Give it to me now.
Right now?
The time right now....
Is that so?
Then, let's go somewhere.
Where do you want to go?
Let's go to your house.
That... that...
Shut up you fucking bastard!
If you open that mouth again,
I'll split your head.
That fucking son of a bitch!
That rascal..
[Social Security]
[Kim Tae Won]
That bastard messed with my woman, in my house
That bastard and the bitch... together..
That bastard messed with my woman,
in my house.
That bastard and the bitch... together..
That bastard messed with my woman...
Police say that this suspect that hasn't been arrested yet
could commit an even bigger crime.
A lockdown is ordered for the city of Seoul.
This news just came in.
Just a bit ago,
at a bus company in Seoul,
the body of the bus company's owner,
Mr. Kim was found.
For being the hidden criminal of Professor Kim Seung Hyun,
He was being investigated by the police.
Just a bit ago,
the suspect for Professor Kim Seung Hyun's murder case,
The president of the transportation company
Mr. Kim
was found murdered in front of the company.
At the crime scene,
bodies that seemed to be employees were found.
Also, the body of Mr. Myun,
who is deeply involved in this case, was found...
[HK Savings Bank]
Thank you.
[Kim Jung Hwan]
Would you press your pin in?
Hey, Hey!
Let's depart.
[Ha Jung Woo]
[Kim Yoon Suk]
[Jo Sung Ha]
[Screenplay Director]
[Na Hong Jin]