Everyone has an angel.
A guardian who watches over us.
We can't know what form they'll take.
One day, old man.
Next day, little girl.
But don't let appearances fool you.
They can be as fierce as any dragon.
Yet they're not here
to fight our battles...
...but to whisper from our heart...
...reminding that it's us.
It's every one of us who holds
the power over the worlds we create.
No!
No.
SUCKER PUNCH
We can deny our angels exist...
...convince ourselves
they can't be real.
But they show up anyway.
At strange places.
And at strange times.
They can speak through any character
we can imagine.
They'll shout through demons
if they have to...
...daring us...
...challenging us to Fight.
Female. Age 20.
-You're the father?
-Stepfather.
That's right. We talked on the phone.
Okay, come with me.
We're gonna take her into the theater.
Dr. Gorski's gonna want to take a look
at her.
She likes to see all the new girls.
Don't worry, Dad.
Everything's gonna be fine.
I've got everything under control
around here.
Okay? Come on. Follow me.
So this is what we call the theater.
Liar!
Oh, girls. Yes, go, go.
Hey. Come here.
Girls. Behave.
-Break it up. Break it up.
-Will you stop them?
Lynn.
Amy.
Sit down.
Sit.
Anyway. So the girls use this place
to be social.
Dr. Gorski, she uses it to help them
deal with their issues.
Polish therapy.
It's quite a show, watching them
act out who touched them or beat them.
Dr. Gorski seems to think it helps.
I'm not so sure.
But whether it does or doesn't
won't matter much to you.
Once we take care of
a little bit of business...
...there won't be any of that
for this one.
-Good.
-She'll be in paradise,
if you know what I mean.
And all of your troubles will be over.
Now, I know we said 1400 on the phone...
I'm taking a really big risk here...
...so it's gonna have
to be 2 grand even.
What the hell are you talking about?
We had a deal.
Listen, Father,
I'm not gonna tell you what to do.
Clearly you're a man that can take
care of himself.
I don't know what you did to this girl.
And, frankly, I don't wanna know.
What are you gonna tell the detectives
when they come around?
They're gonna love her side
of the story.
-Yeah.
-Okay.
I'm going to start your music.
You are safe.
It's all safe.
Now relax.
And just let go.
Now, here's the other thing:
I don't have a doctor on staff
who does lobotomies.
-What?
-But...
...there happens to be one scheduled
to come in in five days.
So I'll just forge her signature.
I've done it a dozen times.
It's like we talk about.
You control this world.
I told the police she lost her mind
when her mother died.
The truth is a little more complicated.
Let the pain go.
Let the hurt go.
Let the guilt go.
What you're imagining right now...
...that world you control?
That place can be as real as any pain.
I don't want her to remember a thing.
Don't worry,
she won't even remember her name
when I'm done with her.
Stop.
Get that thing away from me.
Get it away from me.
Where is my mind?
And shut off that damn music.
Undo these straps.
Don't forget my ankles.
Hurry.
Is there a problem, Sweet Pea?
This is a joke, right?
Don't you get the point of this?
It's to turn people on.
I get the sexy little schoolgirl.
I even get the helpless mental patient,
right? That can be hot.
But what is this?
Lobotomized vegetable?
How about something a little more
commercial, for God's sakes?
Sweet Pea,
could you come here, please?
You gotta help me.
I'm the star of the show, remember?
I'll figure something out.
All right, ladies. Wrap it up.
Sweet Pea, I want you
to meet somebody. This--
Don't tell me.
The priest brought you here from the
orphanage to lose your virginity, right?
Oh, let me rephrase that.
To sell it.
Heh, heh, heh. Yeah, that's right.
How original.
The High Roller is coming for her
in five days.
He's gonna, you know,
just do a little flower picking.
And he's gonna pay
a lot of money for that.
Mm. Luck you.
Can you do me a favor, honey?
Can you show this
little baby doll around,
give her a tour
of the establishment, please?
Blue, you saw the show, okay?
I don't have the time.
Let my sister take her.
Rocket.
Show her around, will you, sis?
All right, come on. Let's go.
Don't worry, I don't bite very hard.
Goodbye, my dear.
-Jesus!
-Oh...
You'll get what you deserve
when the High Roller comes!
-Calm down.
-I will not calm down.
-You see what she did? I hope you rot!
-I did. I'm sorry.
This way.
You're gonna be okay. It just
takes a little while to get used to.
So how'd you become an orphan?
Oh, I get it. It's complicated, right?
Well, we all have our stories in here.
Mine's...
...complicated
These are the rooms
where we take the clients.
There's fresh towels
in all the bathrooms and--
Turn that on.
Blue owns the club.
And we, my dear, heh...
...are the main attractions. Ta-da.
The club's a front for his business.
Guns, gambling, medications,
special favors.
He brings in his clients,
and we gotta make them feel, you know...
...special.
New girl.
This is our backstage.
It's just for us, so don't
bring any clients back here, okay?
Or Blue's gonna get pissed.
Uh, cleaning closet.
You'll find all the
mops, brooms, disinfectants.
New girls get cleaning duties.
I don't make the rules.
And if you don't do what you're told,
Blue locks us in here...
...until we become
a bit more cooperative.
Don't worry.
It's not gonna happen to you.
This is the kitchen.
We all work in here.
Time for rehearsal.
-She looked nice.
-She looked stuck-up to me.
No. She's scared.
I feel sorry for her.
Amber, you feel sorry for everyone.
Do you remember when you first got here?
Nobody felt sorry for you.
Well, don't get
too attached to her, okay?
Blue's saving her for the High Roller.
She's no virgin.
Babydoll, that's Amber, Blondie,
and you've met my sister, Sweet Pea.
-Watch yourself.
-Come on, just give her a break.
Yeah, she hasn't done anything
to you guys.
You best friends now?
Will you just let me finish my tour,
please?
Thank you.
Everybody gets a dance, a routine.
We practice, practice, practice,
and the men come and watch us perform.
And if they like what they see...
Well, you'll see tonight.
Good evening, gentlemen.
We've got a great night
in store for you.
I see a lot of new faces out there.
As well as some familiar ones.
So I'm not gonna yammer on too long.
I want you all to sit back,
enjoy the service...
...the scenery.
But most of all, enjoy the show.
Hit it.
Ooh. Au right.
It ain't no big thing
To wait for the bell to ring
The toll of the bell
Aggravated, spare for days
I troll downtown.
The red light place
Jump up, bubble up
What's in store
Love is the drug
And I need to score
Showing out, showing out,
Hit and run
Boy meets girl
Well, the beat goes on
Stitched up tight
I can't shake free
Because love is the drug for me
Oh
Love is the drug
Late that night I park my car
Stake my place in the singles bar
Face to face,
Toe to toe
Heart to heart as we hit the floor
Lumber up, limbo down
The locked embrace, the stumble round
I say go
And I say yes
Dim the lights, you can guess the rest
Oh
Love is the drug
Love is
Love is the drug for me
Oh, catch that buzz
Because love is the drug
I'm thinking of
Oh
Can't you see
Love is the drug
Got a hook in me
Oh, catch that buzz
Because love is the drug
that I'm thinking of
Oh, can't you see
Love is the drug for me
Ain't no big thing
Yeah, no big thing
Whoo!
Can't you see
Love is the drug for me
Oh
Love is the drug
Love is, love is
Drug, drug. The drug is love.
Give me that.
Somebody! Help me!
Shh.
Let her go, pig.
I didn't mean nothing.
Just having a little fun.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Let's just go.
We don't wanna be late.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Two, two, three, four,
arms, six, seven, eight. Stop.
Stop.
Where are you right now?
Are you with us or not?
Sweet Pea, take break.
Yeah.
Babydoll.
Come over here.
Come, come.
Let me look at you.
Hm.
You seem fit enough.
I'm going to play you some music, okay?
I want you to just relax.
Feel the music.
Open your heart to it. Let it in.
And when you are ready...
...I want you to dance.
If you do not dance,
you have no purpose.
And we don't keep things here
that have no purpose.
You see, your fight for survival
starts right now.
You don't want to be judged?
You won't be.
You don't think you're strong enough?
You are.
You're afraid. Don't be.
You have all the weapons you need.
Now fight.
Again.
Stand up
You've got to manage
Hello?
-Excuse me, could you help me? I'm--
-Shoes.
I'm sorry?
Your shoes.
You're tracking snow everywhere.
Oh, I'm sorry. Should I take them off?
That time has passed.
What can I do for you?
Nothing. I just--
Let me ask it another way:
What are you looking for?
A way out, I guess.
You guess?
No, I--
I know.
I need to get out of here.
Freedom.
That wasn't so hard, was it?
I'm going to help you to be free.
What do I have to do?
These are your weapons.
When you take them,
you begin your journey.
Your journey to freedom.
You will need five items
for this journey.
The first is a map.
Then fire, a knife and a key.
You said five things.
The fifth thing is a mystery.
It is the reason. It is the goal.
It will be a deep sacrifice
and a perfect victory.
Only you can find it.
And if you do...
...it will set you free.
Oh, and one more thing:
Defend yourself.
What was that?
Seriously, you're gonna have to
teach me how to dance like that.
That was crazy.
That was so amazing. I'm, like, shaking.
I've never seen Madame Gorski
clap like that before.
Well, get over it.
It's nearly lights out.
She's not easily impressed.
She wasn't impressed.
All that gyrating and moaning.
The dance should be
more than just titillation.
Mine's personal. It says who I am.
What the heck does yours say?
It says I'm gonna escape from here.
That I'm gonna be free.
Well, send me a postcard from paradise.
Are you really gonna try to escape?
Yeah. Before the High Roller comes.
-Can I come?
-Me too.
-Yeah, of course.
-You're not going anywhere, Rocket.
I'm gonna do what I wanna do.
No one's ever escaped from here.
You know that.
Yeah. You know, the last three girls
that tried died.
And the same thing'll happen
to the next fool.
Look, why don't you just
listen to my plan?
Don't wanna hear your plan, okay?
None of us do.
Now, let's get ready, girls.
Rehearsal in 15 minutes.
We're not helping Baby.
-Am I clear?
-What if it's a good plan?
Then she can go through with it.
I'm not letting you get hurt.
-I kept us safe through a lot of shit.
-I know you have.
I'm not gonna get hurt.
I just can't be here anymore.
And if it is a good plan,
we're both going.
No, we're not.
You're on your own.
-Well, I've been on my own before.
-Heh.
Sure you have.
Look where that got us.
Baby saved me from the Cook
the other day.
What?
I was working in the kitchen
and he comes in behind me.
And he pushes me down
and he gets on top of me...
...and I can't even move.
And there she was, just like that.
She had a knife to his throat.
She saved me.
The High Roller comes for me
in three days.
But I'm getting out of here
before he does.
So if you guys wanna come with me,
this is how I plan to do it.
Well?
Okay.
If we can collect all four
of these items, we can be free.
Okay.
-How do we use them?
-Wait up.
First things first.
How do you plan on
getting these things?
Well, whoever has the item we need,
we get them to watch me dance.
While we run around
and pick their pockets?
-Yeah, that's right.
-But we'd be taking all the risk.
We'd be doing the work
while you prance around with an alibi.
No. As long as I'm dancing,
they won't even know you're there.
Okay, so the first thing
we need is a map...
...to figure out
where all the exits are,
where the guards are located.
Blue has that in his office.
It's behind his desk.
Right. Good.
Second thing we need
is something to start a fire with...
...as a distraction for when we escape.
Plus, the fire should disable
all the checkpoints.
And the third thing is a knife...
...in case we run into trouble.
The Cook.
-We can do it.
-Okay.
And the last thing's a key.
Blue wears a key around his neck.
What door does it open?
It's for all of them, I think.
It's a master key.
This plan is crazy.
There's armed guards everywhere, okay?
And if Blue finds out, we're dead.
It's not gonna be,
"Oh, sorry, Blue, we won't do it again."
Because we'll be dead.
We're already dead.
-I'm in.
-So am I.
Me too.
All right.
But I'm only doing this because you
guys'd get caught without me, okay?
And if it gets too hairy...
...if I say it's over...
...we stop.
Okay.
I'll get the map.
I went for a walk
down the railroad track.
Next thing you know, some--
-What do you want?
-She's dancing.
Who is dancing?
Your baby doll.
One pill makes you larger
And one pill makes you small
Baby.
He's coming.
He's gonna start the briefing.
All right, here's the drill:
The Germans are preparing a report
for the kaiser. It's a map...
...that shows troop locations
and trench layouts.
Their field commander's
sending the map via courier...
...back to Germany on a zeppelin today.
How do we intercept it?
You're gonna cross no man's land,
enter the enemy trenches...
...and take the map from
the field commander's bunker...
...before the courier
can reach the zeppelin.
Sounds like fun.
Oh, and I've arranged something special
for Amber.
Give you some cover.
Get you out of there when you're done.
Let's go.
What do you think?
I like it.
German doctors and engineers...
...have worked out how to return
their fallen to the front lines.
They're using steam power and clockworks
to keep them moving.
So don't feel bad about killing them.
They're already dead.
Remember, ladies:
If you don't stand for something...
...you'll fall for anything.
Oh, and one last thing:
Try and work together.
Son of a--
Come on, guys. The bunker's this way.
-Cover!
-Rocket!
Sweet Pea! Help!
Unh. Sweet Pea!
Rocket.
Are you okay?
It's right here.
Rocket. That's enough.
Wow.
-Very good.
-Hm.
-Nice work.
-Thanks.
Very good.
Okay, this gives me an idea.
What about a private dance
for the Mayor.
What?
Nothing touchy-feely, just something
to get him wound up.
Get him ready to spend some money.
All she has to do
is do what she did just now.
That is out of the question.
She is not ready. It is too raw.
Did you just say she's not ready?
She doesn't have a costume.
There is no set.
Honey, she doesn't need that bullshit.
She's perfect.
Perhaps.
But that is not for you to decide,
that is for me to decide.
Oh.
It's my show, and I say she's not ready.
Clearly, I've offended you,
and I apologize.
Thank you.
Here's the thing:
This show might be yours...
...but the girls and you...
...are mine.
Right?
You're mine.
And if you need a stronger reminder
of that, you let me know, okay?
That won't be necessary.
So with or without your blessing,
she's gonna be on that stage tomorrow?
-I'll see what I can do.
-Attagirl.
-Mm-hm.
-All right.
You look fantastic, by the way.
Big show, girls.
Thank you.
-For what?
-The Cook.
-It was nothing.
-Shut up.
No one takes a risk for anyone in here.
So thank you.
You're welcome.
You got family?
No.
Oh, that's rig ht.
I forgot, you're an orphan.
I ran away from mine.
I thought I was pretty smart
at the time, but...
Sweet Pea followed.
Which is crazy, because she never even
had a real problem with Mom and Dad.
She just cares about you a lot.
Have you just ever wanted
to just take something back?
You know, something you said.
Something you did.
All the time.