London - England
- Fuck.
- It's not there.
- It's in the kitchen where you left it.
- How did you get out?
You have a nice family.
They are fine.
Alive, asleep...
Are you gonna kill me?
If I was gonna kill you, I would have done it when
you walked to your car this morning.
And be gone by the time your
body hit the sidewalk.
- Then why are you here?
- To talk.
But Mike, if you make me kill you
you will not go alone.
Sit.
- Are you a good man, Inspector?.
- I think.
- And yet you've killed men.
- Yes.
I'm gonna ask you a question.
How you answer it,
will determin how this night ends.
How does a good man decide
when to kill?
The man you have been
chasing is a killer.
SHANTY TOWN
NIGERIA
Rumor has it that he is working for a group
known only as "The Organisation".
So secret no one knows it exists.
Takes no signs.
Yet it has ties to every government.
It's sole purpose is the training and
conditioning of professional killers.
These men are selected at birth.
Rejects, Orfans.
All of them, unwanted and disposible.
They are made experts in every
aspect of combat.
And programmed for one purpose:
To Kill.
The man you have been chasing the last years,
Inspector,is the very best of them.
Put him there.
You should not have stolen from me, Brother.
Now you must pay.
What happened to his voice?
- A man...
What did you do to his voice?
- Nothing, Ovey.
You didn't find him?
- No a contractor, an american.
Run!.
HEADQUARTER NIGERIAN EMBASSY
NIGERIA
- We have all heard your theories.
- This is not a theory. This is our guy.
No motif, no ferencic evidence,
no witnesses.
He's a...
He's a ghost.
- And how long have you been chasing this "ghost"?
- Three years.
Well, thank goodness you have Interpol
to finance your persistance, huh?
You see, Inspector.
It is unlike any in the third world,
we attempt competent
police work here.
And it is our belief that Juan Abir
was killed by his own brother.
So he choked dow a pound of C4
and knocked on his door.
- Probably.
- General...
This man truly is the best at what he does.
He is likely responsible for over
one hundred deaths.
Let me show you what I mean.
This is Ove.
And these are just the ones we know about.
Are you beginning to get the picture?
They might kill you for that?
For what you are doing to that whisky?
You are brutalising it with ice.
I'm sorry. Aftermath of my pretencious
ex-husband, I'm afraid.
I'm June.
And you are?
- This is where you tell me your name.
- Excuse me.
Afrika-job complete.
The money has been wired to your account.
Nice work.
Regrettably the next target date has been
moved up, at the client's request.
The client wishes it to be public.
I have planned something more...
Subtle.
I've made preperations.
It comes from the russian president, Mikhail Belikov,
recent political shift is in direct conflict with our client's interests
and threatens the control of the russian government.
The client needs it to be public.
Do you accept the new parameters?
- Yes.
- We appreciate you breaking your normal protocol.
The specifics are being uploaded.
I'm sorry. In light of your new political dispositions,
do you think that "hardliners" will continue
- to support you to the election?
- All that needs to be...
CENTRAL STATION
ST. PETERSBURG
We have a problem.
There was a witness at St. Petersburg.
- How reliable are your souces?
- Impercable, as always.
Interpol has arranged a pick-up.
Will you intercept?.
Yes.
- Uploading data.
How much?
PULKOVO AIRPORT
ST. PETERSBURG
Can't be sure.
He never works again so quickly.
But the russians say that Belikov was graised
by a single bullet from 4 km away.
But it definately sounds like him.
What bothers me,
is that he missed.
Yes sir, I know what this investigation
has cost. I understand...
I just need a little more time.
- You have to see this.
Sorry sir, I'm gonna have to call you back.
Ok, he shoots a bodyguard to get a clean
shot at Belikov.
Yet he splits these two civilians
by a couple of inches.
Keep watching. Keep an eye on the bodyguard.
See that?
- Back it up again.
That is an awful lot of arterial spray for a miss.
- You have a call.
This is Whittier.
They found him?
Concierge? Where?
A picture?
Where the hell did they get a picture?
Alright I'm on my way.
They found him.
Contact the russian secret police in St. Petersburg
and tell them that Interpol has juristiction.
We have to keep him under survelliance only.
No one moves until we get there. Noone!
Was the target not at the location?
- The girl was there, but she was no witness.
She had never seen me before.
We will be unable to transfer payment for the
given assignment as the task was not completed.
No he took a direct hit through the nasal cab.
I watched it myself.
Please wait.
Uploading live news feed.
BELIKOV LIVES
Who was the client?
Answer me!.
Who ordered the hit on Belikov?
If you set me up...
I will find you and burn that building to the ground.
Mike Whittier, Interpol.
What's the status on my suspect?
I was told you were coming, Inspector .
I am Captain Gudnayev, St. Petersburg Militia.
Make yourself comfortable.
My men are almost in position.
In position for what?
- We have been informed that the suspect intends to flee.
My orders are to...
- Orders? Orders from who?
Interpol has juristiction here.
The police is responsible for the
extraction.
Kapitein Gudnayev is not directing this operation
I'm afraid, I am.
Chiefagent Yuri Marklov of the FSP.
- The FSP?
Why the hell is the russian secret police
involved in this?.
We're going in...
- Captain, I advise you to get your men out of there.
You have no idea who you are dealing with.
I assure you, Inspector, these men are cuite cabable
of handling this situation.
Shoot on sight.
Do not give that order.
47, It's Diana.
I can get retired for contacting you directly.
The client was Belikov.
Your location has been compromised.
Stay here. Cover the elevator.
Call me on my cell and tell me were it stops.
I've got five dead in the elevator.
None of them our boy.
He's on the third floor.
So he must be heading for the southern shaft.
Freese.
Get down.
- Stay there.
Get down!.
- Stay up.
We had him.
How many men did you lose?
- Sixteen.
No, no, no... Wait... Don't touch that!.
Were do you get your fucking licence?
- I need the room, Captain.
Where does he get all this stuff?
- Can you make it work?
Probably.
Why?
I have been loking for you, Inspector.
I think we started off on the wrong foot.
Who informed you on the whereabouts of My guy?
- I think it's time we had a chat, You and I.
This assassin, my colleague tells me
you believe him to be in freelance.
Your associates tell you that?
- You do not believe he is connected to the CIA?
Why do you ask?
- No reason, it just seems a bit naïve.
Well, it's a theory.
- Yes, a theory.
But a theory shared by Moskow.
In accordance with article 1764.3 of the EU-charter
Any states matter that deals directly with
intelligence will be the soul juristiction of the hosts country.
Ah, the light bulb comes on,
give me a minute, must be the jetlag.
You are telling me to fuck off.
Of course not.
You are a good man, Michael.
One of Interpols best.
But leave this intelligence work to the FSP.
And Belikov?
I'm sorry?
- You know, There are two things wrong with this photograph.
For one, the fotage has been tampered with.
Someone inserted that civilian to cover up
what actually happened.
And the sencond thing?
My Boy doesn't miss.
Delivery.
- You are supposed to leave it at the desk.
Mr Belikov sent them.
Make a sound and I'll end your life.
Do you understand?
Who else is inside?
I know you. From the street earlier today.
- You are coming with me.
No, I can't.
- OK!.
Where are you taking me?
- Somewhere safe.
Get in.
- Fuck You, I'm not getting in there.
Are you going to kill me?
I am going to ask you some questions.
Before today on the street, had you ever seen me?
Why were you there?
My boyfriend... He told me to meet his
driver on the corner.
Belikov?
How?
After I put a bullit through his head.
How was he able to give that speech this afternoon?
Then you have no use to me.
Wait.
There is something.
Dobbles. Mikail has dobbles.
- The man I shot was not an imposter,
Belikov is dead.
Why did you tatoo your face?
Because it's the only place I knew Belikov
wouldn't hit.
Tell me about Udre Belicoff.
Mikhails broder?
He runs slave girls, drugs and weapons.
Both the CIA and the FSP want him dead.
Mikhail has been protecting him.
Get up, You're coming with me.
I can't. He'll kill me if he found out I left
the appartment.
Belikov hired me to kill you
and used you to set me up.
The dead man in the trunck was your driver.
He was gonna use him on You.
You're as good as dead without me.
Where are we going?
I'm gonna finish the job I
was hired to do.
Find out who's behind this.
I need to talk to you.
- I need coffee. Follow me.
We have three roadblocks. Here, here and here.
We completely shot down international airports.
All of our security has been tripled.
He cannot get out of the city.
What about the train stations?
Temporarely closed.
And St. Petersburg station?.
There are no trains leaving Russia
from this station.
Only trains headed for Argentirer.
What makes you think he'll go further into Russia?
- Because I know him better than anyone.
Thanks for the coffee.
Go to the last platform and wait.
Why?
- Now.
Jenkins, anything?
- Nothing.
Stay sharp.
I don't know, sir. It seems odd for him to come here.
- Trust me, this is were he'll be.
Jenkins, bench.
- I've got him, boss.
Still on him, Boss.
Platform 9.
Getting slow?
Tell me why.
Why is there a hit on me?
Stay here.
Let him die with a little dignity.
You think it's done.
It's just beginning.
I told you to wait.
- I know.
I'm sorry.
I know.
Freese.
You are the one who has been tracking me.
You need a hostage.
Take me.
Come on. He hasn't seen
your face, he doesn't have to die.
Take me instead.
Please...
Stop.
She saved your life.
He said your ribs are broken.
- I'm lucky.
You seem awfully calm considering...
- Your assassin is dead.
Why are you covering this up?
You know that's not our killer.
I told you before, Inspector.
This is no longer your affair.
There are to ways in which we can proceed:
One, my men will accompany you to a hospital
and when you and your associate are able to travel,
they will escort you to the airport.
Then I will write a report ecxtoling
Interpol for it's help.
Medals will probably be along.
Or I can report your incompetance.
and disregard for my nation's laws
to your superior.
It will undoubtably find its way to the state procecutor in Moscow.
So, how do you think we should proceed?
How about... Go fuck yourself?
Ik heb er genoeg van, teringlijer.
Hoe wist je dat ik genoeg zuurstof had?
Don't be dramatic.
- Dramatic?
I got rid of the body.
- I was in there for hours.
I brought you breakfast.
I think if I wasn't so mad at you.
- Look at me.
Back at the station you interfered.
I'm sorry. I cannot allow that.
I swear I'll...
- Stop talking.
If you are looking for a reason not
to kill me, I have none.
I'm a hore by choice.
Bennic owns me.
Would you like to know how much he paid for me?
Three hundred... American.
I've tried to escape...
The last time...
It is a strange thing to wish to die.
So are you...
going to kill me?
No.
You don't wanna fuck me
and you don't wanna kill me.
I've never felt so much indifference
in my entire life.
If you ever again interfer with me like that...
- I won't.
Are we clear?
- Yeah.
Eat your sandwich.
I need some sleep.
You know...
- Nika, stop talking or I'll put you back in the trunck.
FSB AGENCY
ST. PETERSBURG
Wait outside
Are we on a secure line?
Yes comrade
I heard you lost him at the station again
If you're trying to make me nervous
Comrade it's clearly working
Just keep it low profile while
we track him down
Don't appear in public
and he won't be able to reach you
Comrade Yuri, all of those bodies you buried
and yet a single man eludes you
The operation will not be a success
until he and that whore are dead!
They are the only ones who can ruin all of this!
Moscow - Russia
For you.
After all these years I'd think
you would trust me a little more than this.
Tell me what you know.
- Officially, nothing.
Unofficially it appears that your employers has
thrown you to the wolves.
Why?
- Apparently, Belikovs political stands and refusal to
cooperate with the hardliners,
has upset a lot of people.
So the order to replaced him
with one of their own.
You and your friend here are the
only ones that know Belikov's a dubble.
What's the CIA's position?
- The company usually likes to be on the side of whoever wins.
Take the envelope from the girl.
Udre Belicoff.
Mikhails younger brother.
Rumour is, you'd like him to disappear.
- That is the rumour.
I'd like to help.
- How's killing Udre Belikov gonna help you?
Let me worry about that.
Oh, that might be worth something.
What do you want for your troubles?
A small favour.
This is a small favour? I don't think I can do this.
Not in your timeframe.
Keep reading.
Tell me this isn't what I think it is.
- OK, it's not what you think it is.
But I'd think the last thing you want, is
for me to get arrested with that file.
I'll try.
Thank you.
- Yeah, Your welcome.
We know Udre has been planning something
with a Russian armsdealer named Price.
The two have never met.
That's your way in.
Intercept Price,
and you got a shot at Udre.
I'll get you his file.
They're meeting in Istanbul in two days.
Good morning.
Have you slept at all?
You know, you can sleep in the bed.
I won't bite you.
Unless you pay me.
It is unpolite to stare.
Are you gonna tell me your name?
- Get dressed.
What for?
- We're going to dinner.
We need to buy you a new dress.
You know you're really quite
charming when you aren't killing people.
This looks nice.
- Yeah.
Don't you think?
Wait here.
Wait. What did you do?
Leave without me?
How do you know I wouldn't just take off?
- I didn't. Come on.
We have dinner reservations at eight.
HEADQUARTER INTERPOL
LONDON
How do you feel?
My pride hurts worse than my arms.
Any word?
The scetch is out to every Interpol-station in Europe.
Trainstations, airports, border-crossings...
What's that?
- This is what I wanted to show you.
Every appearence Belikov
has made in the last 12 months.
This is from his speech he made in
London on May the seventh.
And this is from some shitty bill-in school lunch he had in Georgia.
Look at the date.
May seventh.
How's that possible?.
I can't be sure. But unless he has figured
out how to be in two places at once?...
He has a dubble.
- He is certainly paranoid enough.
That explains the arterial spray.
- I hope he had health benfits.
When I was a little girl, I had this little squarrel.
Black stripes on the back.
Oh, yeah that's right.
His name was Tishka.
I'm sorry sir but this is for another
gentleman.
Table 26.
That's right.
My mistake.
You know what table that is?
- I saw the layout when we came in.
Do you remember everything you see?.
- No, not everything.
What's the soup of the day?
- ...onion with dized tomatos.
The woman sitting two tables behind you.
What is she wearing?.
With the red hair and silk dress?
That is not a woman.
What color underwear am I wearing?
- You are not wearing any underwear.
Nika, ask for the check.
- But I am not done.
Then... Hurry.
You scratch that about me saying
you were charming.
Excuse me, sir.
Surprise.
Thank you for the introducing of Udre Belikov.
What the fuck?
- Let's go.
Now.
That was lovely.
Right up to the time when you dragged me out by my hair.
Undress me.
So good with firearms,
not so good with ladies and their undergarments.
Careful, I'm not wearing any panties.
- Nika, you're drunk.
And this is a very bad idea.
- Oh... You mean this?
Yes, that.
And this?
- Definetely that.
This must be...
Mr. Price.
So... You took it upon yourself to change our appointment.
How forward of you.
- As I told your men downstairs:
I was attacked earlier tonight by some lunatic.
My common sense dictated...
Your common sense should have dictated
you not abuse my good nature.
I was just going over a few of my lines with
some of your competetors.
Lines.
Lines. Do you get it?
Where was I?
He's not Price.
This is the 'Decador', 9mm compaq.
It's...less than 2 kg, selects five singles, fully automatic.
Empty.
And safe.
Or if you are looking for an assaultrifle,
I have the M203, with underbatter grenade launcher.
A lot of third world dictators got a lot of 762 stuff...
It safes them from having to buy ammo.
Everything here is available in bulk, of course.
Prices, not negotiable.
Any questions, Mr Price?
- Yeah.
What about the little one there?
Yeah, I show you.
This is a Makarov.22.
A favorite of the KGB...
Particually effective in the right hands.
But for a real target you need to find a soft spot...
- Hold up.
This is not a Decador, it's a Chinese copy.
In fact, I don't know if it's the drugs,
but you've been wrong about most of these weapons.
If the gun you're holding is as cheap as this one...
even if you could manage to shoot her in the eye,
and I'm not saying you could.
You wouldn't kill her.
Why are you doing this to me?
- I need you to help me with your brother.
Mikhail? Fine.
Fuck him, I do what ever you want.
What the fuck do you want me to do?
- Just this.
You know, it says here: When the male penquin
meets the female penquin,
he knows in the first ten seconds
if he likes her or not.
Are you listening?
- I'm listening.
I read that.
This article is full of shit.
Why do you buy these magazines?
- For the advertisements.
What do you need luggage like this for?
- Because that perfectly holds my sniper 245.
and a gag for irritating talkative little girls like yourself.
Do you want me to stop and get it out?
I don't know.
Do you think we have time for foreplay?
You know, when I was a little girl,
my father raised grapes.
And I told him that I would
own my own wineyard one day.
It looks nice.
We need to get off the road.
Is that his suitcase?
How did we get that?
As a consolation price Captain Gudnayev
send me our boy's stuff from the hotel in St. P..
In case it might help.
- Anything?
Not much.
There is this.
What do you make of this?
Trust onto God and he shall direct your path.
Charms.
I never thought our boy as the religious type.
That's strange.
I have to go.
So much for happy endings.
I don't want you to do this.
- Belikov needs to die.
I don't care about that.
Not anymore.
As long as he's alive,
they will never stop looking for you.
Take this. At the next station,
get off the train as soon as it stops.
Move with the crowd.
But I don't even know your name.
The place I was raised they didn't give us names.
They gave us numbers.
Mine was 47.
That explains a lot.
How will I find you?
- Don't worry. I'll find you.
What are you going to do?
- What I do.
You have no idea of the pain involved in the procedure
They peel back the skin of the face...
and screw a teflon frame to the bones...
to duplicate the facial features.
I wonder, if I had known the pain involved...
would I still have gone through with
this whole double business.
Your drunk.
You don't want to drink
with your new president?
All the evidence has been erased.
Mikhail. Belikov.
This pathetic brother, Udre.
Now I am the one and only.
The one man I have asked you to kill...
The only one who can expose us,
is the only man not in this room!.
Tell me, Comrad.
What excactly have you done to find him?
It seems if we wait long enough,
he will find you.
Us. He will find us.
- The orginisation has sent in their best operatives.
I know.
Do not your incompetence hinder them,
if you want to have this conversation again.
Three hours ago Belikovs brother Udre was
found dead in Istanbul.
Ze wachten in Moskou
op het lichaam voor z'n begrafenis.
Michael, how is things going?
- Belikov's brother has just been found murdered.
It's him, sir. It's our guy.
He's setting Belikov up.
But we're getting pressure from the ministiry and the EU
To drop this investigation.
But the russians will confirm...
- The russians are the ones leading EU on this.
They blatenly deny your ghost even excists.
And a foul paper is with the ministers office
claiming you've overstepped your
athourity.
Who brought those allegations?
- The FSB. Specifically Special Agent Jurij Markov.
I need you to stop.
- No, you don't understand.
The FSB is covering this up.
He killed Belikov's brother. Why?
Why would he do that, unless...
- Belikov announced that attend funeral services...
tomorrow morning for the burial...
- The funeral.
He's gonna take Belikov at Udre's funeral.
This generator produces over 3000 amps.
Much more than what is nessesary...
I wanted you to understand the gravity of this situation.
At 2.30. that radio taped to your
arm will activate.
You'll have 30 seconds to order
the shooting of your friend Belikov.
If you don't, the generator will start.
Your skin will melt, your blood will vayporise.
There won't be enough of you left,
to identify.
- You have gone through a great deal of trouble.
I am just a burekrat.
There is nothing I can do for you, I'm afraid.
I disagree.
This is not a request, this situation is fixed.
And you know both possible outcomes.
Live or die.
Your choice.
Here's something to keep things
in perspective.
I picked it up last night when
I was in your house.
You bastard!.
- If I were you I'd keep that radio dry.
Yell all you like,
the lord himself won't hear you.
There are over 100 specially trained alpha
soldiers in this cathedral.
It will be foolish to attempt
any kind of violence.
A man as highly trained as your
assassin would realize this.
What if he doesn't?
Look around you.
How much civilian blood do you think will be shed?
- We are prepared for that as well.
Gascans are being deployed. If anything should occur,
the civilians will be rendered unconsious.
Now if you will excuse me.
Dames en heren, om te beginnen, wil ik u
en uw familie bedanken voor uw gebeden.
One minute, fifty seconds.
Answer. Answer.
We zijn echt dankbaar.
My brother he was a troubled man.
But he was not always like that.
One minute 25 seconds.
One minute 20 seconds.
Shouldn't we choose to live and die
much like my brother?
Should we do what is nessesary...
What is hard...To save what we love.
One minute.
I for one will not fail again.
Not with this country.
Not with our children's future,
Not with You, My countrymen...
35 seconds.
Come in.
Change target, shoot Belikov.
Are you sure?
Come on!
Fucking, do it now!.
Release the gas.
Lock down the doors.
I sugest you and your men follow me.
- Let's go.
Your man has made a mistake.
There is no exit. He's trapped.
It doesn't make sense.
Why would he...
Trust on to God... And he shall direct you path.
Shit, he set us up from the very beginning.
Where does this key fit?
The last bishop's personal chambers.
The clock tower.
Over there.
He's going into the river like in St. P.
Jenkins, let's go.
He is in the southwest tower. Call
the gun ships. Do not let him escape.
Seems I underestimated you.
- Consistently.
A miscalculation on my part.
Who are you?
Answer me.
Let me help you.
- How would you do that?
By having me killed?.
No for that I am sorry. It was a mistake.
And Nika, was that a mistake? Or did you
destroy her life for your amusement?
Do you think you can take what has cost
millions, years of planning,
for the good of this country?
And destroy that?
Then what? Walk away?
You don't really think they will let you do that.
If you kill me they will never let you go.
They will hunt you for the rest of your life.
You did your job.
And you did it very well.
And for that my boy, you should be proud.
- That's it?
Yes, I'm offering you your life back. That is
why you are here, yes, that is what you want.
No?
- No.
He shot the president!
Interpol, drop your weapons.
We have an arrestwarrent for that man.
Don't move.
Hands on your head.
On your knees.
Don't do anything stupid.
Just one thing:
Knowing how it ends, was it worth it?
Killing Belikov.
- Knowing how this ends... Definetely.
What do you make of that?
Who the hell are you?
- I'm agent Smith, CIA.
I need all of you men to the rear of that vecicle.
- You don't have juristiction here.
We aren't here. That means that when we open
up with... then this will never have happened.
We have reason to believe that you
are involved in terrorist activities.
We're Interpol. And in accordance with section 3,
we're transporting an international criminal.
What criminal?
You know what, I'm sorry man.
My mistake, I thought you were somenone else.
You prick.
- On behalf of the U.S. government I would like to extent your... sincerest apology.
Load up, boys.
We're even.
So now what?
- Now you have to answer my question.
Are you a good man, Inspector?
I think.
And yet you've killed men.
So, Inspector, how does a good man
decide when to kill?
If I think a man means to do me or my family harm
I will do whatever I can to stop them.
But beyond that... It's a crap-shoot.
The key...
You knew I had juristiction.
And would walk you right out the front door.
- I wanna be left alone.
Just like that.
Yeah, just like that.
This is the man you've been looking for.
Ballistics will confirm that he was shot
by your weapon.
The magazine is on the night stand next to your bed.
Don't forget it when you call your superiors.
Did you kill him here?
- It's five.
Wait a few hours until the
girls go to school.
You woa't have to expose them to this.
Explains why you waited so long before you called it in.
I can't go along with this.
- I hope you can.
For both our sakes.
Goodbye, Michael.
I hope I never see you again.
St. Petersburg - Russia
I told you to leave her alone.
You should have listened.