HELP !
[ Grunts ]
SOMEBODY HELP ME !
HELP !
[ Panting ]
OH, HE'S GONNA KILL ME !
HELP !
GOD, SOMEBODY HELP ME !
GO AWAY !
[ Screams ]
HELP !
[ Panting ]
PLEASE HELP ME !
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
HELP !
MULDER ?
LOOK AT THAT.
HUH ?  HUH ?
OH, SHI--
[ Door Closes ]
[ Tapping Pen
Rhythmically ]
MULDER--
DON'T.
DON'T EVEN START WITH ME.
I KNOW WHAT I SAW.
[ Sighs ]
SKINNER WANTS A REPORT
IN ONE HOUR.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO TELL HIM ?
I'M GONNA TELL HIM
EXACTLY WHAT I SAW.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA TELL HIM ?
I'LL TELL HIM
EXACTLY WHAT I SAW.
NOW, HOW IS THAT DIFFERENT ?
I'M THE ONE WHO MAY WIND UP
GOING TO PRISON HERE.
I GOTTA KNOW
IF YOU'RE GONNA BACK ME UP.
FIRST OF ALL,
IF THE FAMILY OF RONNIE
STRICKLAND DOES, INDEED,
DECIDE TO SUE THE F.B.I...
FOR-- I THINK THE FIGURE
IS $446 MILLION--
THEN YOU AND I BOTH
WILL MOST CERTAINLY
BE CODEFENDANTS.
AND SECOND OF ALL--
I DON'T EVEN HAVE
A SECOND OF ALL, MULDER.
FOUR HUNDRED AND FORTY-SIX
MILLION DOLLARS.
I'M IN THIS AS DEEP AS YOU ARE,
AND I'M NOT EVEN THE ONE
THAT OVERREACTED.
I DIDN'T DO THE--
WITH THE THING.
I DID NOT OVERREACT.
RONNIE STRICKLAND
WAS A VAMPIRE.
WHERE'S YOUR PROOF ?
YOU'RE MY PROOF.
YOU WERE THERE.
NOW YOU'RE SCARING ME.
I WANT TO HEAR WHAT
YOU'RE GONNA TELL SKINNER.
YOU WANT OUR STORIES
STRAIGHT.
I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
I JUST WANT TO HEAR IT
THE WAY YOU SAW IT.
I DON'T FEEL COMFORTABLE
WITH THAT.
PRISON, SCULLY.
YOUR CELL MATE'S NICKNAME
IS GONNA BE "LARGE MARGE."
SHE'S GONNA READ
A LOT OF GERTRUDE STEIN.
- ALL RIGHT.
- ALL RIGHT, START
AT THE BEGINNING.
THE VERY BEGINNING ?
[ Drawer Opens ]
FINE.
[ Sighs ]
YESTERDAY MORNING...
WHEN I ARRIVED AT WORK,
YOU WERE, UH...
CHARACTERISTICALLY EXUBERANT.
HOPE YOU BROUGHT
YOUR COWBOY BOOTS !
YOU WANT US TO GO TO DALLAS ?
YEE-HAW !  ACTUALLY
A TOWN CALLED CHENEY ABOUT
50 MILES SOUTH OF THERE.
POPULATION: 361.
BY ALL ACCOUNTS,
VERY RUSTIC AND CHARMING.
BUT AS OF LATE,
GROUND ZERO, THE LOCUS...
FOR A SERIES OF MYSTERIOUS
NOCTURNAL EXSANGUINATIONS.
EXSANGUINATIONS.
OF WHOM ?
[ Slides Clicking Into Place ]
[ Mulder ]
HOW DOES THAT GRAB YA ?
- IT'S A--
- DEAD COW !  EXACTLY.
OR MORE SPECIFICALLY,
A DEAD 900-POUND HOLSTEIN.
ITS BODY COMPLETELY DRAINED
OF BLOOD, AS WAS THIS ONE,
THIS ONE, THIS ONE,
THIS ONE, AND SO ON--
SIX, ALL IN ALL--
APPROXIMATELY ONE A WEEK
OVER THE PAST SIX WEEKS.
- ANY SIGN OF--
- TWO SMALL PUNCTURE WOUNDS
ON THE NECK ?
- NOT WHAT I WAS GONNA ASK.
- TOO BAD.  WE GOT 'EM.
CHECK IT OUT.
THESE MAY BE SYRINGE MARKS,
THEIR PLACEMENT MEANT
TO EMULATE FANGS.
SUCH RITUALISTIC BLOODLETTING
POINTS TOWARDS CULTISTS
OF SOME SORT,
IN WHICH CASE--
WHAT ?
YEAH, THAT'S PROBABLY IT.
SATANIC CULTISTS.
COME ON, SCULLY.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA TELL ME THIS
IS THAT MEXICAN GOAT SUCKER.
EL CHUPACABRA ?
THEY GOT FOUR FANGS, NOT TWO.
- AND THEY SUCK GOATS,
HENCE THE NAME.
- SO INSTEAD THIS WOULD BE ?
- CLASSIC VAMPIRISM.
- OF A BUNCH OF COWS ?
AND ONE DEAD HUMAN.
LAST NIGHT A VACATIONER
FROM NEW JERSEY.
COME ON.
WE GOTTA GO.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
THAT FROM THE BEGINNING ?
LOCK THE DOOR
ON YOUR WAY OUT.
[ Disgusted Sigh ]
[ Scully's Voice ]
THE TOWN OF CHENEY IS TOO SMALL
TO MAINTAIN A MORGUE FACILITY.
AS SUCH, WE MADE OUR WAY
TO THE PEACEFUL SLUMBERS
FUNERAL HOME...
IN ORDER TO EXAMINE THE BODY
OF ONE MR. DWIGHT FUNT,
RECENTLY DECEASED.
[ Man Talking
Quietly ]
[ Scully ]
IT WAS THERE THAT WE WERE MET
BY A REPRESENTATIVE...
OF LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT,
SHERIFF--
LUCIUS HARTWELL.
- YOU THE F.B.I. AGENTS ?
- YES.  I'M--
AGENTS MULDER AND, UH--
[ Snapping Fingers ]
SCULLY.  WHAT DO YOU SAY WE
TAKE A LOOK AT YOUR VICTIM ?
YEAH, BY ALL MEANS.
AFTER YOU.
COME ON, SCULLY.
GET THOSE LITTLE LEGS
MOVIN'.  COME ON.
BOY.
HERE WE GO.
NICE THREADS.
NO EXAM HAS BEEN DONE ?
NO, MA'AM.
HE'S JUST LIKE WE FOUND HIM
IN THE MOTEL ROOM.
ONCE I HEARD YOU FOLKS WERE
INTERESTED, I FIGURED WE'D BEST
LEAVE IT UP TO THE EXPERTS.
YOUR SATANIC CULTISTS HAVE
SOME SHARP LITTLE TEETH.
WHAT SATANIC CULTISTS ?
GO AHEAD, TELL HIM
YOUR, UH, "THEORY."
WELL, MY THEORY HAS EVOLVED.
BASICALLY, I THINK WE'RE
LOOKING FOR SOMEONE WHO HAS SEEN
ONE TOO MANY BELA LUGOSI MOVIES.
HE BELIEVES HE IS A VAMPIRE,
THEREFORE HE--
THEY ACT LIKE ONE.
YEAH.  YEAH.
THAT MAKES A WHOLE
LOT OF SENSE.
- I THINK SHE'S RIGHT.
- WHAT ABOUT THE FANG MARKS ?
WELL, SOMEONE SO OBSESSED
MIGHT WELL FILE DOWN
THEIR INCISORS.
I THINK THAT A MOULAGE CASTING
SHOULD HELP US MAKE
AN IDENTIFICATION.
MOULAGE CASTING.
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
NOW--
NOW, ISN'T THERE SOME KIND
OF DISEASE THAT MAKES A PERSON
THINK THAT THEY'RE A VAMPIRE ?
WELL, THERE IS
A PSYCHOLOGICAL FIXATION
CALLED HEMATODIPSIA,
WHICH CAUSES THE SUFFERER
TO GAIN EROTIC SATISFACTION...
FROM CONSUMING
HUMAN BLOOD.
EROTIC.  YEAH.
THERE ARE ALSO GENETIC
AFFLICTIONS...
WHICH CAUSE A HEIGHTENED
SENSITIVITY TO LIGHT,
UH, TO GARLIC.
PORPHYRIA.
XERODERMA PIGMENTOSUM.
YOU REALLY KNOW
YOUR STUFF, DANA.
"DANA" ?
HE NEVER EVEN KNEW
YOUR FIRST NAME.
- YOU GONNA INTERRUPT ME,
OR WHAT ?
- NO, GO AHEAD.
DANA.
ANYWAY,
THAT'S WHEN YOU HAD
YOUR BIG BREAKTHROUGH--
WHATEVER.
AGENT SCULLY, YOU REALLY
KNOW YOUR STUFF.
SHERIFF, YOU SAY
THIS MAN ISEXACTLY
AS YOU FOUND HIM ?
YES, SIR,
TO THE LETTER.
HAVE YOU NOTICED
THAT THIS MAN'S SHOES
ARE UNTIED ?
- YEAH, THEY SURE ARE.
- MULDER, WHAT'S YOUR POINT ?
THIS MEANS SOMETHING.
DO YOU HAVE AN OLD CEMETERY
IN TOWN, OFF THE BEATEN PATH,
THE CREEPIER THE BETTER ?
UH, YEAH.
- TAKE ME THERE NOW.
- MULDER.
WE'RE GONNA NEED A COMPLETE
AUTOPSY ON THIS MAN,
THE SOONER THE BETTER.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WHAT AM I
EVEN LOOKING FOR ?
I DON'T KNOW.
- HE DOES THAT.
- COME ON, SHERIFF HARTWELL.
MA'AM.
4:54 P.M.
BEGIN AUTOPSY
ON WHITE MALE, AGE 60,
WHO IS ARGUABLY HAVING
A WORSE TIME IN TEXAS
THAN I AM,
ALTHOUGH NOT BY MUCH.
I'LL BEGIN
WITH THE "Y" INCISION.
[ Blade Hits Floor ]
YEE-HAW.
HEART WEIGHS 370 GRAMS.
TISSUE APPEARS HEALTHY.
LEFT LUNG WEIGHS 345 GRAMS.
LARGE INTESTINE,
890 GRAMS.
YADA, YADA, YADA.
STOMACH CONTENTS SHOW LAST MEAL
CLOSE TO THE TIME OF DEATH...
CONSISTING OF...
PIZZA,
TOPPED WITH PEPPERONI,
GREEN PEPPERS,
MUSHROOMS.
[ Sighs ]
THAT SOUNDS REALLY GOOD.
[ Neck Muscles Cracking ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Scully's Voice ]
HAVING COMPLETED THE AUTOPSY,
I CHECKED INTO THE DAVEY
CROCKETT MOTOR COURT.
[ Mulder ]
THE NAME OF IT WAS ACTUALLY
THE SAM HOUSTON MOTOR LODGE.
[ Bed Motor Humming ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Whispering ]
OH, MY GOD.
[ Door Hinges Creak,
Door Slams ]
CHLORAL HYDRATE.
WHAT ?
- WHAT THE HELL
HAPPENED TO YOU ?
- NOTHIN'.
CHLORAL HYDRATE ?
YEAH, THAT THING
THAT YOU DIDN'T KNOW
THAT YOU WERE LOOKING FOR.
CHLORAL HYDRATE,
MORE COLORFULLY KNOWN
AS "KNOCKOUT DROPS."
I FOUND IT IN ABUNDANCE
WHEN I SENT THE TOX SCREEN IN
ON OUR MURDER VICTIM.
- NO, SERIOUSLY, MULDER.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU ?
- NOTHING.
- WHO SLIPPED HIM THE MICKEY ?
- MY "THEORY" ?
YOUR VAMPIRE.
HE FOUND IT NECESSARY
TO DOPE POOR MR. FUNT
TO THE GILLS...
BEFORE HE WAS ABLE
TO EXTRACT HIS BLOOD.
PROBABLY DID IT
TO THE COWS TOO.
WHAT KIND OF VAMPIRE
WOULD DO THAT ?
EXACTLY.
[ Sighs ]
WE GOT ANOTHER DEAD TOURIST.
YOU GOTTA DO ANOTHER AUTOPSY.
TONIGHT ?
I JUST PUT MONEY
IN THE MAGIC FINGERS.
I WON'T LET IT GO TO WASTE.
[ Bed Continues Vibrating ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Giggling ]
[ Giggling Continues ]
THIS ONE'S MY ROOM, MULDER.
DON'T GET MUD EVERYWHERE.
YEAH.  YEAH, YEAH,
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
OKAY.
[ Giggling ]
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
DID YOU ORDER A PIZZA ?
YEAH.  THE GUY IN THERE
WILL PAY FOR IT.
[ Scully's Voice ]
FORGOING BOTH DINNER
AND SLEEP,
I WAS SOON BACK
AT THE FUNERAL HOME...
EXAMINING ONE
MR. PAUL LOMBARDO...
FROM NAPLES, FLORIDA.
HEART.  LUNG.
LARGE INTESTINE.
[ Sighs ]
[ Sighs Deeply ]
AS WITH THE PREVIOUS VICTIM,
IT APPEARS THAT THE SUBJECT...
WAS MOST LIKELY INCAPACITATED
WITH CHLORAL HYDRATE...
AND THEN EXSANGUINATED.
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Sighs ]
THE DRUG WAS EITHER INJECTED
OR INGESTED,
[ Ringing Continues ]
I'M NOT SURE WHICH.
[ Phone Beeps ]
SCULLY.
[ Heavy Breathing ]
HELLO ?
[ Gasping ]
[ Panting ]
[ Sighs ]
WHERE WAS I ?
STOMACH CONTENTS.
[ Sighs ]
STOMACH CONTENTS INCLUDE...
PIZZA--
[ Gasps ]
CHLORAL HYDRATE'S
IN THE PIZZA.
THE PIZZA GUY.
[ Gasps ]
MULDER.
MULDER ?
[ Hissing ]
THAT'S IT ?
WELL, LUCKILY,
I'D GOTTEN THERE IN TIME.
I MEAN,
THOUGH YOU WERE DRUGGED,
YOU WERE, MORE OR LESS,
UNHARMED.
MULDER ?
ARE YOU OKAY ?
WHO'S THE BLACK PRIVATE DICK
WHO'S THE SEX MACHINE
WITH ALL THE CHICKS ?
♪♪ SHAFT ♪♪♪♪
CAN YOU DIG IT ?
THEY SAY THIS CAT SHAFT
IS A BAD MOTHER--
SHUT YOUR MOUTH.
TALKIN' 'BOUT SHAFT.
I DID NOT.
LONG STORY SHORT,
THOUGH MY FIRST FOUR SHOTS
OBVIOUSLY MISSED RONNIE
STRICKLAND ENTIRELY,
WITH MY FIFTH,
I WAS ABLE TO SHOOT OUT
A TIRE ON HIS CAR,
FORCING HIM
TO ESCAPE ON FOOT.
I LEFT YOU BEHIND,
AND I ENTERED THE WOODS
IN PURSUIT.
I ASSUMED THAT YOU
WERE INCAPACITATED.
THEN I HEARD SCREAMING.
WHEN I ARRIVED IN THE CLEARING,
I FOUND THAT YOU HAD CAUGHT UP
WITH HIM FIRST...
AND HAD... OVERREACTED,
AND THAT HIS VAMPIRE TEETH
WERE FAKE.
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA TELL SKINNER.
WELL, I'M GONNA ARGUE
THAT WE CAUGHT A KILLER.
AN UTTERLY
NON-SUPERNATURAL KILLER,
BUT A KILLER NONETHELESS.
AND THAT YOUR ZEAL
TO CATCH UP WITH HIM
WAS AUGMENTED...
BY THE CHLORAL HYDRATE
YOU WERE GIVEN.
- YOU ARE AFRAID
TO TELL THE TRUTH.
- EXCUSE ME ?
THAT'S NOT THE WAY IT HAPPENED.
ARE YOU AFRAID IF YOU TELL IT...
THE WAY IT REALLY HAPPENED,
YOU'LL LOOK LIKE AN IDIOT,
LIKE ME ?
MULDER, WHY DON'T
YOU TELL ME THE WAY
YOU THINK IT HAPPENED ?
STARTING
AT THE BEGINNING.
YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT.
YESTERDAY MORNING BEGAN
LIKE ANY OTHER MORNING.
YOU ARRIVED AT THE OFFICE
CHARACTERISTICALLY
LESS THAN EXUBERANT.
[ Quiet Tone ]
I HOPE YOU BROUGHT
YOUR COWBOY BOOTS.
WHY ARE WE GOING
TO DALLAS ?
ACTUALLY IT'S A LITTLE TOWN
JUST SOUTH OF THERE
CALLED CHENEY, TEXAS.
THEY'VE HAD INCIDENTS DOWN THERE
RECENTLY WHICH I THINK YOU'LL
AGREE ARE PRETTY UNUSUAL.
- LIKE WHAT ?
- I BROUGHT SOME SLIDES WITH
WHICH TO BETTER ILLUSTRATE.
HERE WE GO.
IT'S A DEAD COW.
IT'S ACTUALLY SIX DEAD COWS,
AND HERE'S THE REALLY
INTERESTING THING.
WHY AM I LOOKING
AT SIX DEAD COWS ?
BECAUSE OF THE MANNER
IN WHICH THEY DIED.  ALL SIX
WERE MYSTERIOUSLY EXSANGUINATED.
- AND ?
- AND TWO LITTLE PUNCTURE MARKS
RIGHT HERE ON THE NECK.
LOOK, I GOT A SLIDE
OF THAT.
AND, UM, ONE DEAD HUMAN VICTIM.
LAST NIGHT A VACATIONER
FROM NEW JERSEY.
HIS BODY COMPLETELY DRAINED
OF BLOOD, AND TWO LITTLE
PUNCTURE WOUNDS ON HIS NECK.
OKAY, LOOK, SCULLY,
I DON'T WANT TO JUMP TO
ANY HASTY CONCLUSIONS,
BUT ON THE STRENGTH
OF THE EVIDENCE
THAT WE HAVE HERE,
I THINK WHAT WE MAY BE
LOOKING AT IS WHAT APPEARS
TO BE A SERIES OF VAMPIRE...
ORVAMPIRE-LIKE ATTACKS.
ON WHAT DO YOU BASE THAT ?
UH, WELL, ON THE CORPSES
DRAINED OF BLOOD...
AND THE FANG MARKS
ON THE NECK.
BUT AS ALWAYS,
I-I'M VERY EAGER
TO HEAR YOUR OPINION.
- WELL, IT'S OBVIOUSLY
NOT A VAMPIRE.
- WHY NOT ?
BECAUSE THEY DON'T EXIST ?
WELL, THAT'S ONE OPINION,
AND I RESPECT THAT.
NONETHELESS,
I'M THINKING A MURDER
HAS BEEN COMMITTED HERE,
AND WE CAN GO DOWN THERE
AND HELP BRING A KILLER
TO JUSTICE...
IN WHATEVER FORM--
MORTAL OR IMMORTAL--
HE MAY TAKE.
IT'S NOT THAT MEXICAN
GOAT SUCKER EITHER.
[ Man Talking Quietly ]
[ Mulder ]  UPON ARRIVING
AT THE FUNERAL HOME, I MADE
AN INTERESTING OBSERVATION,
ONE WHICH YOU
APPARENTLY DIDN'T HEAR.
- THAT'S A WHOLE LOT OF CASKETS.
- LARGEST IN-STOCK SELECTION
IN THE STATE.
WELL, WHY WOULD
A TOWN WITH A POPULATION
OF ONLY 361 NEED THAT ?
REPEAT BUSINESS.
[ Chuckles ]
MORTICIAN HUMOR.
EXCUSE ME.
[ Mulder ]
APPARENTLY, YOUR MIND
WAS SOMEWHERE ELSE.
WHOO, BOY.
[ Exaggerated Texas Accent ]
Y'ALL MUST BE
THE GOVERNMENT PEOPLE.
I'M LUCIUS HARTWELL.
HE HAD BIG BUCKTEETH ?
- HE HAD A SLIGHT OVERBITE.
- NO, HE DIDN'T.
AND THAT'S SIGNIFICANT ?
HOW ?
I'M JUST TRYING
TO BE THOROUGH.
ANYWAY, THEN WE WENT
TO TAKE A LOOK AT THE BODY.
HERE WE GO.
NO EXAM HAS BEEN DONE ?
NO, SIR.  THIS IS
JUST LIKE WE FOUND HIM
IN THE MOTEL ROOM, AS IS.
NO EXAM HAS BEEN DONE ?
UH, NO, MA'AM.
ONCE I HEARD Y'ALL
WAS INTERESTED, I FIGURED WE'D
BEST LEAVE IT TO THE EXPERTS.
NOW, UH, THAT CAN'T BE
WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE, RIGHT ?
IT DEPENDS ON WHAT
YOU THINK IT LOOKS LIKE,
SHERIFF HARTWELL.
VAMPIRES HAVE ALWAYS
BEEN WITH US,
IN ANCIENT MYTHS AND STORIES
PASSED DOWN FROM EARLY MAN.
FROM THE BABYLONIANEKIMMU
TO THE CHINESEKUANGSHI,
THEMOTETZ DAMOF THE HEBREWS,
THEMORMOOF ANCIENT GREECE
AND ROME,
RIGHT DOWN TO THE MORE FAMILIAR
NOSFERATUOF TRANSYLVANIA.
MORMO. YEAH.
IN SHORT, SHERIFF, NO, THIS
CAN'T BE WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE.
I THINK WHAT WE'RE DEALING
WITH HERE IS SIMPLY A CASE
OF SOME LUNATIC...
[ Chuckles ]
WHO, UH, HAS WATCHED
TOO MANY BELA LUGOSI MOVIES.
HE WISHES THAT HE
COULD TRANSFIGURE HIMSELF
INTO A CREATURE OF THE NIGHT.
YEAH, OKAY.
WHAT SHE SAID,
THAT'S WHAT I'M THINKIN'.
AND, UH, YEAH.
STILL, THAT LEAVES US
IN SOMETHING OF A QUANDARY...
BECAUSE THERE ARE AS MANY
DIFFERENT VAMPIRES AS THERE ARE
CULTURES THAT FEAR THEM.
SOME DON'T EVEN
SUBSIST ON BLOOD.
THE BULGARIANUBOUR,
FOR EXAMPLE,
EATS ONLY MANURE.
THANK YOU.
TO THE SERBS, A PRIME INDICATOR
OF VAMPIRISM WAS RED HAIR.
[ Chuckles ]
UH, SOME VAMPIRES
ARE THOUGHT TO BE ETERNAL.
OTHERS ARE THOUGHT TO HAVE
A LIFE SPAN OF ONLY 40 DAYS.
SUNLIGHT KILLS CERTAIN VAMPIRES,
WHILE OTHERS COME AND GO
AS THEY PLEASE, DAY OR NIGHT.
IF THERE'S A POINT, MULDER,
PLEASE FEEL FREE TO COME TO IT.
MY POINT IS WE DON'T KNOW
EXACTLY WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR,
WHAT KIND OF VAMPIRE--
OR, IF YOU PREFER,
WHAT KIND OF VAMPIRE THIS KILLER
WISHES HIMSELF TO BE.
NOW, WHY IS IT
SO IMPORTANT THAT
HIS SHOES WERE UNTIED ?
I'M GETTIN' TO IT.
SO WHILE YOU STAYED BEHIND
TO DO THE AUTOPSY,
THE SHERIFF DROVE ME
TO THE TOWN CEMETERY.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Metal Gate Squeaking ]
AGENT MULDER,
YOU MIND ME ASKIN' YOU
WHY WE'RE OUT HERE ?
HISTORICALLY, CEMETERIES
ARE THOUGHT TO BE A HAVEN
FOR VAMPIRES,
AS ARE CASTLES,
CATACOMBS AND SWAMPS.
BUT, UNFORTUNATELY,
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY OF THOSE.
WE USED TO HAVE SWAMPS,
ONLY THE E.P.A. MADE US TAKE
TO CALLIN' 'EM WETLANDS.
YEAH, SO WE'RE OUT HERE
LOOKING FOR ANY SIGNS
OF VAMPIRIC ACTIVITY.
- WHICH WOULD BE LIKE, UH--
- BROKEN OR SHIFTED TOMBSTONES.
THE ABSENCE
OF BIRDS SINGING.
THERE YOU GO.
'CAUSE I AIN'T--
I AIN'T HEARIN'
ANY BIRDS SINGIN'.
RIGHT ?
'COURSE, IT'S WINTER,
AND WE AIN'T GOT NO BIRDS, BUT--
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE ?
A FAINT GROANING COMING
FROM UNDER THE EARTH,
THE SOUND OF MANDICATION,
OF THE CREATURE EATING
ITS OWN DEATH SHROUD.
[ Rain Falling ]
NO.  NO MANI--
MAN-- MAN--
MANDICATION.
MANDICATION, NO.
SHERIFF, I-I KNOW
MY METHODS MAY SEEM
A LITTLE ODD TO YOU, BUT--
LOOK, Y'ALL WORK
FOR THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
THAT'S ALL I NEED TO KNOW.
I MEAN, C.I.A., SECRET SERVICE.
Y'ALL RUN THE SHOW, SO--
IT'S JUST THAT MY GUT INSTINCT
TELLS ME THAT THE KILLER
WILL VISIT THIS PLACE,
THAT IT MAY WELL HOLD
SOME FASCINATION, SOME KIND
OF SIREN CALL FOR HIM.
YOU KNOW ?
[ Horn Honking ]
HOWDY, SHERIFF !
- OH, HEY, RONNIE.
HOW'S IT GOIN' ?
- CAN'T COMPLAIN.
WELL, ALL RIGHT, THEN.
MAYBE AFTER NIGHTFALL,
SHERIFF, BUT HE'LL COME.
OH, HE'LL COME.
[ Mulder ]
SO WE STAKED OUT THE CEMETERY.
[ Animal Howling ]
MULDER.  SHOELACES ?
HMM ?
ON THE CORPSE.
YOU WERE GONNA TELL ME
WHAT WAS SO MEANINGFUL
ABOUT FINDING UNTIED SHOELACES.
I'M GETTIN' TO IT.
SUNFLOWER SEED ?
SORRY.
NO, THANKS.
DO YOU MIND--
DO YOU MIND ME ASKIN' YOU
WHAT YOU WERE--
HISTORICALLY, CERTAIN TYPES
OF SEEDS ARE THOUGHT
TO FASCINATE VAMPIRES.
CHIEFLY OATS AND MILLET,
BUT, YOU KNOW, YOU GOTTA
MAKE DO WITH WHAT YOU HAVE.
REMEMBER WHEN I SAID BEFORE
THAT WE DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TYPE
OF VAMPIRE WE WERE LOOKING FOR ?
YEAH.
ODDLY ENOUGH, THERE SEEMS
TO BE ONE OBSCURE FACT...
WHICH, IN ALL THE STORIES
TOLD BY THE DIFFERENT CULTURES,
IS EXACTLY THE SAME,
AND THAT'S THAT VAMPIRES
ARE REALLY, REALLY
OBSESSIVE/COMPULSIVE.
HUH.
YOU TOSS A HANDFUL OF SEEDS,
NO MATTER WHAT HE'S DOING,
HE'S GOTTA STOP
AND PICK IT UP.
IF HE SEES A KNOTTED ROPE,
HE'S GOTTA UNTIE IT.
IT'S IN HIS NATURE.
THAT'S WHY I'M GUESSING
OUR VICTIM'S SHOELACES
WERE UNTIED.
YEAH.  OBSESSIVE.
LIKE RAIN MAN.
WHEN THAT OLD BOY DROPPED
MATCHSTICKS, HE HAD TO
PICK 'EM ALL UP.
SAME THING, RIGHT ?
WELL, HE DIDN'T
ACTUALLY PICK 'EM UP.
HE COUNTED THEM.
OH, YEAH !
HE DIDN'T HAVE TO PICK THEM UP.
247.  OFF THE TOP
OF HIS HEAD.
IF HE PICKED THEM UP,
HE WOULD HAVE BEEN A VAMPIRE.
YEAH.
I TELL YOU WHAT.
I KNOW I'M IN LAW ENFORCEMENT,
BUT I'D LIKE TO TAKE HIM
TO VEGAS MYSELF.
AM I RIGHT ?
WELL, THAT WOULD
BE ILLEGAL, RIGHT ?
- HE WAS LIKE
A LITTLE CALCULATOR.
- YEAH.
[ Woman On Radio ]
YOU GOT YOUR RADIO ON ?
EXCUSE ME.
HEY, CHARLENE.
WHAT'S UP ?
I JUST GOT A CALL
FROM THE R.V. PARK.
THEY GOT SOMETHING
OF A SITUATION THERE.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU MIGHT
WANT TO HAVE A LOOK.
[ Engine Starts ]
HEY AGAIN, SHERIFF.
HEY AGAIN, RONNIE.
[ Ronnie ]
I GUESS YOU GOT YOURSELF
A RUNAWAY, HUH ?
[ Hartwell ]
YEAH, RONNIE.
I GUESS WE DO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ?
WE OUGHT TO SHOOT
THE TIRES OUT ?
[ Mulder ]
ANYWAY, SKIPPING AHEAD--
WHY SKIP AHEAD ?
WHAT HAPPENED THEN ?
MULDER ?
YOU SHOT OUT THE TIRES.
AND WHAT THEN ?
[ Mulder ]
OKAY, HERE'S SOMETHING
YOU MAY NOT KNOW.
SHOOTING OUT THE TIRES
ON A RUNAWAY R.V. IS A LOT
HARDER THAN IT LOOKS.
I THEN TRIED
A DIFFERENT APPROACH.
WHOA !  HEY !
HEY, HEY !  WHOA !
- HELP !  WHOA !
- COME ON, BIRD-DOG IT !
THATAWAY !
[ Screaming ]
- OH !
- [ Groaning ]
SHEE, OW.
HOW YOU DOIN' THERE ?
ALL RIGHT THERE ?
[ Engine Sputtering ]
[ Mulder ]
FINALLY, WE PREVAILED.
THAT'S THE SAME
AS THE OTHERS.
RIGHT DOWN TO THE SHOES.
[ Mulder ]
WE INTERVIEWED EVERYONE PRESENT.
NO ONE HAD SEEN ANYTHING.
TIRED, FRUSTRATED
AND LACKING A SOLID LEAD,
[ Bed Vibrating ]
I JUST WANTED
TO GET CLEANED UP.
I HAD THE SHERIFF
DROP ME AT THE MOTEL,
WHICH IS WHERE I RAN INTO YOU.
[ Shouting ]
WHAT DO YOU MEAN YOU WANT ME
TO DO ANOTHER AUTOPSY ?
WHY DO I HAVE TO DO IT NOW ?
I SPENT HOURS ON MY FEET
DOING AN AUTOPSY, ALL FOR YOU !
I DO IT ALL FOR YOU,
MULDER !
I HAVEN'T EATEN SINCE 6:00
THIS MORNING, AND THAT WAS
WAS HALF A CREAM CHEESE BAGEL.
IT WASN'T EVEN
REAL CREAM CHEESE,
IT WAS LIGHT CREAM CHEESE !
NOW YOU WANT ME TO RUN OFF
AND DO ANOTHER AUTOPSY ?
WHAT THE HELL
HAPPENED TO YOU ?
[ Mulder ]
FINALLY, YOU LEFT.
[ Scully ]
DON'T YOU TOUCH THAT BED !
[ Door Slams ]
[ Bed Continues
Vibrating ]
[ Knocking On Door,
Door Opening ]
[ Ronnie ]  HELLO ?
HELLO !
OH, HEY AGAIN.
THE LADY OUTSIDE--
SHE SAID THAT, UH,
YOU'D PAY FOR THIS.
SHE ORDERED A PIZZA
FROM YOU ?
EXCELLENT.  HOW MUCH ?
12.98.
I'LL GET MY WALLET.
- HOW MUCH ?
- IT'S 12.98.
- OKAY, HERE'S 13.
- OKAY, THEN.
ENJOY.
[ Door Closes ]
AH, SCULLY.
[ Mulder ]
SO I ATE YOUR DINNER.
AND THAT'S WHEN I SAW IT.
BUT BY THEN,
IT WAS TOO LATE.
[ Falls On Floor ]
[ Phone Beeps, Dialing ]
UH--
THIS IS SCULLY.
HELLO ?
UH-- DE--
- HELLO ?
- [ Mulder Groans ]
UH-- UH--  TH--
CREEP.
UHH-- UHH--
YOU--
[ Hissing ]
OH, MAN !
WHAT'D YOU HAVE TO
GO AND DO THAT FOR ?
YOU ARE IN BIG TROUBLE.
[ Grunts ]
[ Mulder ]
THEN I WAS OUT COLD.
I DON'T KNOW FOR HOW LONG,
BUT WHEN I FINALLY CAME TO--
[ Hissing ]
[ Scully ]
MULDER ?
[ Gun Cocks ]
[ Growls ]
YOU'RE SAYING
THAT I ACTUALLY
HIT HIM TWO TIMES ?
SQUARE IN THE CHEST.
NO EFFECT.
AND THEN HE
SORT OF FLEW AT ME
LIKE A FLYING SQUIRREL.
WELL, I DON'T THINK
I'LL USE THE PHRASE...
"FLYING SQUIRREL"
WHEN I TALK TO SKINNER,
BUT, YEAH,
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED.
[ Mulder ]  YOU CHECKED ON ME,
THEN LEFT TO PURSUE RONNIE
STRICKLAND INTO THE WOODS.
ONCE I RECOVERED,
I KNEW WHAT I HAD TO DO.
HELP ME !  HELP !
I CAUGHT SIGHT OF HIM,
CHASED HIM OVER HILL AND DALE.
AND IN THE END--
[ Shouts ]
MULDER, IT'S NOT JUST ME.
NOBODY IN THEIR RIGHT MIND
WILL EVER BELIEVE THAT STORY.
THEY'LL HAVE TO,
ONCE THEY EXAMINE
RONNIE STRICKLAND'S BODY.
[ Sighs ]
"CASE 0026198.
RONALD LaVELLE STRICKLAND."
PROBABLE CAUSE OF DEATH--
GEE, THAT'S A TOUGH ONE.
[ Grunting ]
[ Stake Clatters On Tray ]
[ Tools Clattering ]
[ Hisses ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Growls ]
[ Knuckle Cracks ]
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Woman ]  ASSISTANT DIRECTOR
SKINNER'S OFFICE.
OH, I'M SORRY.
HE'S ABOUT TO GO
INTO A MEETING.
YES, IT MAY LAST
SEVERAL HOURS.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
MULDER.  PLEASE
JUST KEEP REMINDING HIM
YOU WERE DRUGGED.
[ Whispering ]
WOULD YOU STOP THAT ?
IT COULDN'T HURT.
JUST STOP IT.
SCULLY ?  MULDER ?
I WAS DRUGGED !
[ Sighs ]
I WANT YOU BACK IN TEXAS.
RONNIE STRICKLAND'S BODY
HAS DISAPPEARED
FROM THE MORGUE.
APPARENTLY IN CONJUNCTION
WITH THIS, A CORONER'S
BEEN ATTACKED.
HIS THROAT WAS BITTEN.
THE CORONER'S DEAD ?
NO, HIS THROAT WAS BITTEN.
HE WAS SORT OF... GNAWED ON.
DAYLIGHT'S BURNING, AGENTS.
[ Door Closes ]
WELL--  HE WAS DEAD.
I NOTICED THAT.
WITH A STAKE
THROUGH HIS HEART.
I NOTICED THAT TOO.
SO WE SHOULD FIND RONNIE
OUT HERE BECAUSE ?
BECAUSE TRADITION STATES
THAT A VAMPIRE NEEDS TO
SLEEP IN HIS NATIVE SOIL.
OH.
YEAH.
BUT, MULDER,
HE HAD FAKE FANGS.
WHY WOULD A REAL VAMPIRE
NEED FAKE FANGS ?
I MEAN, FOR THE SAKE
OF ARGUMENT.
NO, FANGS ARE
VERY RARELY MENTIONED
IN THE FOLKLORE.
REAL VAMPIRES AREN'T THOUGHT
TO HAVE THEM.  IT'S MORE AN
INVENTION OF BRAM STOKER'S.
YOU WERE RIGHT BEFORE WHEN YOU
SAID THAT THIS IS A GUY WHO'S
WATCHED TOO MANY DRACULA MOVIES.
HE JUST HAPPENS
TO BE A REAL VAMPIRE.
[ Sighs ]
WELL, SO WHERE
THE HELL IS HE ?
WHAT ABOUT HIS FAMILY,
THE ONES WHO WERE GONNA
SUE US FOR 446 MILLION ?
WELL, AN AUNT
AND AN UNCLE.
THEIR MAIL
COMES GENERAL DELIVERY
TO A LOCAL POST OFFICE.
NO HOME ADDRESS ?
[ Mulder ]
THAT'S THE SHERIFF.
- SHERIFF HARTWELL.
- EVENING, AGENTS.
I HEARD Y'ALL WERE BACK
IN TOWN.  THOUGHT I MIGHT
BE OF SOME ASSISTANCE.
YEAH, A-ACTUALLY
YOU CAN.
YOU CAN STAY BEHIND HERE
WITH AGENT SCULLY WHILE I
CHECK SOMETHING OUT.
DON'T SAY I NEVER DID
NOTHIN' FOR YA.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING ?
WHERE MIGHT YOU BE LIVING
IF YOUR MAIL CAME GENERAL
DELIVERY AROUND HERE ?
THE R.V. PARK ?
YOU'RE GOOD.
THANKS.
YOU'RE VERY WELCOME.
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT VAMPIRES ?
YOU MEAN, ASIDE FROM
THE FACT THAT I DON'T
BELIEVE IN THEM ?
YEAH, ASIDE FROM THAT.
WELL, THEY'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE EXTREMELY CHARMING,
SEDUCTIVE.
NO, I MEAN, EVEN IF
THEY DID REALLY EXIST,
WHO'S TO SAY THEY'D
ACTUALLY BE LIKE THAT ?
AS AGENT MULDER SAYS,
THERE ARE MANY DIFFERENT
KINDS OF VAMPIRES.
YEAH, THERE SURE ARE.
I REALLY NEED TO APOLOGIZE
TO YOU ABOUT RONNIE.
HE MAKES US ALL LOOK BAD.
UH--
HE'S JUST NOT
WHO WE ARE ANYMORE.
I MEAN, WE PAY TAXES,
WE'RE GOOD NEIGHBORS.
OLD RONNIE, HE JUST--
HE CAN'T QUITE SEEM TO
GRASP THE CONCEPT...
OF...
LOW PROFILE.
BUT THOUGH HE
MAY BE A MORON,
HE IS ONE OF OUR OWN.
[ Cracking Sound ]
[ Door Creaking ]
HELLO.
[ Creaking ]
[ On Headphone ]
♪♪ 20th-CENTURY MAN
THAT'S WHAT HE IS ♪♪
- SLEEPING LATE.
- [ Growls ]
RONNIE STRICKLAND !
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT
TO REMAIN SILENT.
ANYTHING YOU SAY CAN
AND WILL BE USED AGAINST YOU
IN A COURT OF LAW.
COME ON.
CUT IT OUT, RONNIE.
[ Ronnie Grunting ]
OH, DAMN.
BACK !
AH, NO !
[ Screaming ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
MULDER ?
[ Exhales ]
SCULLY, WHAT HAPPENED ?
I CAME TO
IN THE CEMETERY.
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Car Door Opens ]
THEY PULLED UP STAKES.
SO THAT'S IT ?
THEY SIMPLY DISAPPEARED
WITHOUT A TRACE ?
AND THAT'S EXACTLY
THE WAY IT HAPPENED,
FROM START TO FINISH ?
WELL, I CAN NEITHER CONFIRM
NOR DENY AGENT MULDER'S
VERSION OF EVENTS...
WHICH OCCURRED
OUTSIDE MY PRESENCE.
AND I CAN NEITHER CONFIRM
NOR DENY AGENT SCULLY'S
VERSION OF EVENTS, BUT, UM--
ANYWAY... I WAS DRUGGED.
THAT IS,
ESSENTIALLY, EXACTLY
THE WAY IT HAPPENED.
ESSENTIALLY.
[ Mulder ]
EXCEPT FOR THE PART
ABOUT THE BUCKTEETH.
[ Child ]
I MADE THIS !