Professor!
Catherine!
Professor...
We found something beautiful!
I don't believe it!
Big, big, big surprise!
Over here!
Taylor!
Dr Langford, hello.
What have we here?
Cover stones.
It's fantastic.
Catherine,
come!
What in God's name is that?
I wish I knew.
There are symbols
painted everywhere.
Names, titles of owners,
lists of offerings.
All major structures at the time...
...were covered with hieroglyphics.
When will
the academic community accept...
...the pharaohs of the 4th dynasty...
...did not build the Great Pyramid?
Look, look...
Inside the most incredible
structure ever erected...
...there are no writings whatsoever.
Doctor Jackson!
You left out the fact
that Colonel Vyse...
...discovered
quarrymen's inscriptions...
...of Khufu's name
within the pyramid.
Uh, his discovery was a fraud.
Well, I hope you can prove it.
Who do you think
built the pyramids?
I don't have any idea. I mean...
Men from Atlantis?
Or Martians, perhaps?
The point is not who built them,
but when they were built.
I mean, we all know...
...new geological evidence
dates the Sphinx...
...back to a much earlier period.
I think we have
to begin to re-evaluate...
...everything
we've come to accept about...
I mean, I've been able to show...
...a fully developed
writing system...
...appeared
in the first two dynasties.
You know, which...
Almost as if it was based...
...on an even earlier prototype.
Is there a lunch or something
that everybody...
-Doctor Jackson?
-What? Yes?
Someone wants to speak with you.
The Air Force?
What's this? What is this?
Step over to the car, please.
Sir?
-We goin' somewhere?
-You'll be fine.
We'll take care of these.
Jackson...
...those your parents?
Foster parents.
What is this all about?
A job.
What kind of a job?
Translation.
Ancient Egyptian hieroglyphs.
Interested?
I'm gonna go now.
Go where? You've just been evicted
from your apartment.
Your grants have run out.
Everything you own
are in those two bags.
You want to prove
that your theories are right?
This is your chance.
What's this?
Travel plans.
Sir?
Mrs O'Neil?
Come on in.
Mrs O'Neil, is your husband home?
Yes.
Might we be able to speak with him?
You can try.
Excuse me, Colonel O'Neil.
We're from General West's office.
Sir?
We're here to inform you
that you've been reactivated.
That guy's a mess.
How'd he get like that?
His kid died.
Accidentally shot himself.
Jesus!
"Clear."
Cold?
Allergies.
Always happens when I travel.
There you go.
Hi.
Doctor Jackson?
Doctor Gary Meyers. How are you?
What is this place?
Nuclear missile silo.
But it's been converted.
-Barbara Shore.
-Hello.
Okay, Jackson.
-Welcome.
-Hello!
This...
Where'd you find this?
Giza Plateau, 1928.
I've never seen anything like this.
Of course you haven't.
No-one has.
There's two lines of hieroglyphs.
The inner track
has the classic figures.
But the outer track is like
the cartouche in the centre.
It's got writing
unlike we've ever found before.
Those aren't hieroglyphics.
It might be some form
of hieratic or maybe cuneiform.
The translation
of the inner track is wrong.
Must've used Budge. I don't know
why they keep reprinting him.
Excuse me?
What... what are you doing?
We... we've used
every known technique.
That's a curious word to use
-"Gebbeh".
Yeah.
Then an adverbial "sedjem-en-ef".
Then "sealed"...
...and "buried".
Excuse me.
What are you... what are you doing?
It's not "coffin".
It's "for all time".
Who the hell translated this?
I... I did.
It should read
"A million years into the sky...
...is Ra, sun god,
sealed and buried for all time".
It's not "door to heaven".
It is...
..."Stargate".
So why is the military
so interested...
...in 5,000-year-old
Egyptian tablets?
My report says 10,000.
Afternoon, Colonel.
Um... do I know you?
Col. Jack O'Neil
from General West's office.
I'll be taking over from now on.
This figure of 10,000 is ludicrous.
Egyptian culture
didn't exist until...
We know. But the sonic and
radiocarbon tests are conclusive.
These are cover stones.
Was there a tomb underneath?
No, no, no, no. But we found
something a lot more interesting.
Excuse me.
This information
has become classified.
From now on,
no information is to be passed on...
...to non-military personnel
without my express permission.
Catherine, what's going on here?
I'm not sure.
Colonel O'Neil?
I think you owe me an explanation.
I was told I had complete autonomy.
Plans change.
Why are you here? Why did they
bring you on this project?
I'm here in case you succeed.
"Searched for cuneiform and
other pre-dynastic hieroglyphics."
"No matches whatsoever.
I've exhausted all sources...
...in comparing
the cartouche symbols...
...against all writing samples
from the period, pre-and post-."
"Still no similarities."
"I'm never gonna get paid."
Uh-uh, uh-uh.
Can I borrow this?
Orion.
Hi.
Right here.
Jackson, I'd like you
to meet General West.
Hello.
Oh, right -General!
So you think you've solved
in 14 days...
...what they couldn't solve
in two years?
Two years?
Any time.
Um...
I have some stuff to look at.
Uh... if you'll just pass 'em down.
You'll have to share them cos I...
Sorry, I don't have enough of those.
But, anyway... Okay, all right.
We're looking at a picture
of the cover stones.
Now, on the outer track...
...these figures
that you had believed...
...to be words to be translated
were, in fact...
Sorry about that.
Were, in fact, star constellations.
These constellations
were placed in a unique order...
...forming a map
or an address of sorts.
Seven points to outline
a course to a position.
And, uh...
...to find the destination within
any three-dimensional space...
...we need six points...
...to determine an exact location.
You said you needed seven points.
Well, no. Six for the destination.
But to chart a course you need...
...a point of origin.
Except there's only six symbols
in the cartouche.
The seventh actually
isn't inside the cartouche.
It's below it here...
...designated
by a little pyramid with...
...two...
...funny...
...neat little guys...
...and a funny little line
coming out of the top.
Anyway, uh...
He did it.
No! That symbol
isn't anywhere on the device.
What device?
Show him.
What is that?
It's your "Stargate".
Come, Jackson.
"Technical personnel
report to command centre."
Monitors up!
Monitors are up.
Mitch, bring up the details
on the centre monitor, please.
I've got details... on.
Hold it!
Wait.
Do you have a?
Oh, here. Sorry.
Hey, hey, hey, don't!
Two figures...
...on either side...
...praying beside a pyramid
with the sun directly above it.
He's right.
It was in front of us
the whole time.
General West...
...Jackson has identified
the seventh symbol.
Go ahead.
Programming seventh symbol
into computer.
Chevron one is holding.
Chevron one is locked in place.
Power output at 23 per cent.
Chevron two is holding.
"Engage."
Chevron two is locked in place.
We're at 35 per cent.
We got a condition red in the gate.
Evacuate all personnel.
Area secure. Heading back.
Seal off the door.
It was under the cover stones?
Yes. My father found it in 1928.
Made out of a mineral
unlike any found on Earth.
Chevron five locked in place.
79 per cent.
Chevron six is holding.
Chevron six is locked in place.
This is as far as we have
ever been able to get.
Chevron seven...
"Engage."
Chevron seven is locked in place.
Send in the probe.
Let's go! Let's go!
Yes, sir.
Record all information
from the Stargate.
Clear inner silo for approach.
"Clear inner silo."
Everybody outta here!
Let's go, let's go.
It's guiding itself.
Can you believe that?
The beam has locked itself
onto a point somewhere...
...in the Kaliam galaxy.
It has mass. It could be a moon
or a large asteroid.
Where are we on that map?
The blue dot.
That's right, Jackson.
It's on the other side
of the known universe.
We're losing the signal.
This is the information
the probe sent back to us.
Freeze and enhance.
You can clearly see the gate
on the other side.
Both gates must have functioned
as a doorway between our worlds.
These readings tell us
it's an atmospheric match.
Barometric pressure, temperature...
...and, most importantly, oxygen.
These markings are different.
They don't match the symbols
on our gate.
That's why we may have to abort.
This project is for naught
without a reconnaissance mission.
Once on the other side...
...we'd have to decipher
the markings on their gate...
...and, in essence, dial home...
...in order to bring the team back.
Based on this new information,
I don't see how we can do that.
Well, I could do that.
Are you sure?
Positive.
Your call.
You're on the team.
You're understand, this complicated thinks.
That's why I want you, Jack.
We've open the doorway to world, we've know nothing about.
Jackson...
Hello. Hi.
I have something for you.
No, I...
Yes.
I found it with Stargate
when I was a child.
It has brought me luck.
You can bring it back to me.
Back-up storage.
Reserve power on.
All right, we're secure.
Let's clear this area.
Surveillance and monitoring
equipment, reserve power...
...and on.
If anybody has anything to say,
now's the time to say it.
"Vector tracking set."
Molecular deconstruction
in progress.
Jackson, it's all right.
It's over. Stay with him.
Jackson, listen to me. Keep moving.
It wears off in a minute.
What a rush!
Prepare to move out.
Three teams. Let's go.
"White team, go."
Brown, Freeman, bring up the rear!
"Team two, move up."
Clear. No contact.
Freeze. Hold for sounds.
"One-two ratio stable."
Conditions are similar to inside.
I wanna take a look around.
Kawalsky. Feretti.
"Move up there."
I knew it.
"Point three, three, two."
Report.
Our quarter-mile perimeter survey
is just about complete, sir.
Wrap this up and
get everybody back inside.
I want you all back through
the Stargate within the hour.
You're coming with us,
aren't you, Colonel?
-Sir?
-Jackson!
Start working on the Stargate.
-What's that all about?
-I don't know, Feretti.
I'm gonna need more time.
There's bound to be
more structures here.
Or some other traces
of civilisation.
Not this trip. Just get back
in there and re-establish contact.
It's not so easy. This is a replica
of the Great Pyramid of Giza.
We won't find any hieroglyphic
inscriptions or carved relief.
I mean,
we really need to look around more.
Your job is to realign the Stargate.
Can you do that or not?
I can't.
You can't or you won't?
I can decipher the symbols
on the Stargate...
...but I need an order of alignment.
Those co-ordinates were
on tablets back on Earth.
There must be something
like that here and I just...
I just need to find it.
Find it?
What do you mean, find it?
You didn't say anything
about finding anything.
Well, I assumed the tablets
would be here.
You assumed?
You're a lyin' son of a bitch!
You didn't say a word
about finding anything!
Kawalsky.
Set up a camp down here.
Organise our supplies.
Sir...
You've got your orders.
This is hot.
You know, I can't believe
we're stuck here.
Don't be such a doomsayer, Feretti.
-Yeah, give it a rest.
-Yes, please.
If we're not back soon...
...they'll turn on the gate
from the other side.
Oh, no. It doesn't work that way.
If you don't turn it on from here,
we're screwed. Okay?
So I'm tellin' you guys,
we're not goin' anywhere.
Shut up.
This is a nice tent.
Oh, we each get a tent.
That's nice.
What the hell is that?
I got everything here but sun block.
Hey!
-Hi.
-Hey.
Isn't there something
you should be doing?
Like gettin' us outta here?!
Foot powder. Great (!)
Base camp is up, sir.
Where's Jackson?
It's okay. It's okay.
Shh, shh, shh...
That's a good boy.
Good boy.
It's okay.
What?
What do you want?
You want some of this?
Here you go. You like that?
I wouldn't feed that thing!
It's got a harness!
It's domesticated!
-Damn it!
-Let go of it!
Do something!
Help me!
You okay, Jackson?
Kawalsky.
You dropped these.
Brown.
Get away from me.
Easy...
All right, Jackson.
You're on.
Me?
You're the linguist.
Try to talk to 'em.
Hi.
What the hell did you say to him?
Nothing.
Hey...
Hm?
It's okay.
It's okay. See?
"Quartz primary element."
I can't make it out. It sounds
familiar. A bit like Berber.
Or maybe it's Chadic or Omotic.
Thank you.
Mmmm!
Bonni...
Bonniwae!
Bonniwae?
Bonniwae. Bonniwae.
What's that mean?
I have no idea.
He's inviting us to go with him.
How can you be so sure?
Because he's inviting us
to go with him.
We were looking
for signs of civilisation.
Obviously, we've found it.
You want me to get us back home,
this is our best shot.
Colonel, he's right.
I took some readings
on what they're mining.
This is the same material
as the Stargate.
Radio base camp.
Tell them to keep that area secured
until we get back.
Yes, sir.
The eye of Ra.
It's the Egyptian sun god.
They think he sent us here.
Yeah. Wonder what could've
given 'em that idea.
Ra.
Ra?
Where are they all going?
Come in. Come in.
Feretti, I can't hear you.
Sir, I can't make this out.
Feretti, say again.
We have to abandon base camp!
Repeat,
we have to abandon base camp!
It's useless!
It won't work in this!
Freeman, let's go! Let's go!
Everybody back inside!
Come on!
Take batteries!
We're gonna back, right now.
Wait!
Stay here!
What is it colonel?
Sand storm, coming this way!
And what about,
excellent reason to shoot everyone.
We'll stay it's over.
Sorry.
The pyramid! Back to the pyramid!
Where the hell did that come from?
Kawalsky, Brown, do you read?
Hey, Jackson. I don't think
we should eat any food here.
I don't know.
They might consider that an insult.
Well, we don't want to offend them
now, do we, Daniel?
Tastes like chicken.
It's good.
It tastes...
Tastes like chicken.
Tastes like chicken. Good!
Jackson.
You said
that was an Egyptian symbol.
Yeah. The eye of Ra.
Would you say, then, that if they
know one Egyptian symbol?
Yes.
No, no.
What's going on?
It seems like writing
is forbidden to them.
What? What?
They want me to go with them!
Should I stay?
I'll go with them.
I'll go. I'll be fine.
Okay, that's good. All right.
What is that smell?
Oh, it's...
Okay, that's good.
That's good.
My hands are pretty clean.
Thank you very, very much.
Thank you very...
Thank you. That was great.
I smell much better now...
Yes...
Oh, Christ.
I smell like a yak.
No, no, please. No more.
Please.
Please, no more.
I'm fine. I'm clean, I'm...
I'm...
I thought... you were
one of the other... cleaning...
No. No, no, no, no. You don't...
You don't have to do that. Please.
Maybe you should go.
Okay? It's okay.
No, it's okay. It's all right.
Here, let me take care of it.
No, no, no.
It's me.
I wanted to thank you. I wanted...
I'm very... I'm very happy.
Thank you.
Um...
Daniel.
No. Uh... I'm, uh...
I'm Daniel.
Sha'uri.
Uh... you, uh...
We came...
This...
...pyramid.
See, we...
...we came from the pyramid.
It's... it's okay.
Never mind.
It's okay.
Earth.
You... you know the symbol?
You know the symbol?
You've seen... the symbol?
Show me.
You show me.
Kawalsky, this is base.
Do you copy?
You're wasting the battery.
You won't get anything in this
storm. Wait till it passes.
Yeah, right.
If it passes.
What the hell is goin' on?
All right, spread out.
Behind the columns -move!
It's okay. It's just a lighter.
See?
Here.
Yeah, it's pretty fabulous.
Yeah, you're right.
It's pretty stupid.
No, you... keep it.
It's yours.
No!
It's dangerous!
What is this place?
Cypian.
Rem-e-n-jef.
Bah-ka-naf Sema.
Tah-pah-rief.
I'll be damned!
Tah-pah-rief?
What?
Tah-pah-rief.
Tah-pah...
Neh-jed?
Neh-dah.
Neh-dah. Neh-dah.
Tiu.
Tiu. Tiu.
Ah...
Netjer?
Netjer-u?
Bah? Netjer-u?
Natay.
Naturu.
Natay. Naturu.
Nafi.
No signal at all?
Nothing.
More interference?
No.
They're simply not there.
I haven't been able
to locate Jackson, sir.
I'm looking for Jackson.
Jackson.
The guy who wears this jacket.
He's, uh, he's got, like,
long hair that comes down...
No...
No, no, no. It...
He wears glasses...
...so he can see.
I guess the word "dweeb"
doesn't mean anything to you guys.
I'm on planet X looking for a dweeb
who wears green fatigues.
He wears this jacket.
He's got long hair.
It comes over his eyes,
he wears glasses, and...
...sneezes.
Chicken.
Chicken. Chicken man. You got it.
You want this?
I thought
you couldn't speak their language.
Hi... Scared me.
It's an ancient Egyptian dialect.
Unlike the rest of their culture,
it's evolved independently.
But once you know the vowels...
Just answer the question.
Well, I mean, I just
had to learn how to pronounce it.
It hasn't been a living,
spoken language...
...in more than 1,000 years.
Look at this. It says
a traveller from distant stars...
...escaped from a dying world...
...looking for a way
to extend his own life.
His body decaying and weak,
he couldn't prevent his own demise.
Apparently, his whole species
was becoming extinct.
So he travelled...
...or searched the galaxies...
...looking for a way to cheat death.
And, uh...
...look here.
He came to a world rich with life...
...where he encountered
a primitive race.
Humans.
A species which, with all
his powers and knowledge...
...he could maintain indefinitely.
He realised within a human body
he had a chance for a new life.
Now, he apparently found
a young boy.
It says as the frightened villagers
ran, night became day.
Curious and without fear,
he walked towards the light.
Ra took him
and possessed his body...
...like some kind of a parasite
looking for a host.
And, inhabiting this human form,
he appointed himself ruler.
He used the Stargate to bring
people to this planet...
...as workers for the mines.
Just like the one we saw.
This mineral is the building
block of all his technology.
With this
he can sustain eternal life.
Now...
...something happened on Earth.
A rebellion or uprising,
and the Stargate was buried there.
Fearful of a rebellion here,
Ra outlawed reading and writing.
He didn't want people
to remember the truth.
Jackson, I think
you'd better look at this.
That's it.
That's what we're looking for.
They must've hidden it here...
...in hopes that one day
the gate on Earth could be reopened.
I knew they'd have it
written down someplace.
Wait a minute.
Where's the seventh symbol?
It must have broken.
It's got to be here somewhere.
I got it here.
It's worn off.
I can't make it work
without the seventh symbol.
All right, that's it.
Kawalsky. Brown.
Come on, Jackson!
What the hell is that?
Here.
You might need this.
Look out!
Where are we going?
Why are we going to the Stargate?
I can't make it work.
Stay here and shoot anything
that comes down that ramp.
What are you doing?
Just cover me.
What is that?
-What are you looking for?
-It's gone.
Put it down, Jackson.
You have come here to destroy me.
What is that?
It's a bomb, isn't it?
That's what you were looking for.
What the hell were you thinking?
What did you come here for?
Wait! Don't!
Wait!
No! No!
Colonel! It's me!
You all right?
Where's Jackson?
Sha'uri, what happened here?
Ra punished us.
Why?
What happened to Daniel?
Son, we should not have helped
the strangers.
I was dead?
Your bodies, so easy to repair.
You have advanced much...
...harnessed the power of the atom.
What are you going to do?
You should not
have reopened the gate.
Soon, I will send your weapon
back to your world...
...with a shipment of our mineral...
...which will increase
your weapon's destructive power...
...a hundredfold!
Why would you do that?
I created your civilisation.
Now I will destroy it!
But before my workers
question my authority...
...you will prove
that I am their one god...
...by killing your companions.
If I refuse?
Then I will destroy you...
...and all who have seen you.
There can only be one Ra!
Sha'uri...
...Ra has called an assembly...
...an execution.
Skaara, Nabeh,
I want you all to listen.
We can't let this happen.
I want you to know
what Daniel told me...
...about where our people
came from...
...and why we can no longer
live as slaves.
Come on!
Freeman!
Over there! Come on!
Kawalsky!
Jacson!
To our victory!
We recovered your weapons.
Here, Colonel.
So what do you think?
They're not exactly
Special Forces...
...but they sure were
eager to join up!
Take these guns away
before they hurt themselves.
Sir?
You heard me. Send 'em all home.
There's no place
for these kids to go.
Anyway, we could sure
use their help.
For what?!
Huh?
To do what?!
Why don't you
just tell 'em everything?
Why don't you tell 'em
about the bomb?
What's he talkin' about?
My orders were simple.
Track down signs
of any possible danger.
If I found any,
blow up the Stargate.
Well, I found some.
Well, your bomb is his now.
And tomorrow
he's gonna send it back to Earth.
With a shipment of that mineral
they mine here.
And when it goes off...
...it'll be 100 times
more destructive...
...than that bomb alone
is capable of.
I'll intercept that bomb
before he can send it through.
Why wasn't I told of this?
There was no reason to tell you.
You weren't supposed to be here.
You were all gonna
go back with Daniel.
I was gonna stay behind
and blow up the Stargate...
...and that's what I'm gonna do.
It's the gate on Earth
that poses the threat.
That's the one
we have to shut down.
You're absolutely right.
But since you don't know
how to get us back...
...we don't have that option, do we?
Where are they?
Answer!
We looked everywhere.
Some kids are helping them.
You would have accepted that
no matter what happened...
...you would not be going home?
Don't you have people
who care about you?
Do you have a family?
I had a family.
No-one should have to outlive
their own child.
I don't wanna die.
Your men don't wanna die.
And these people here
don't wanna die.
It's a shame
you're in such a hurry to.
How could you let them escape?
I will not accept failure!
Why are you laughing?
Husbands don't do this work.
Husband?
Married?
Don't be angry.
I didn't tell them.
Tell them what?
That you did not want me.
What are you drawing?
The day of our victory.
Connect the moons.
That's it.
The point of origin.
What're you doing?
I've found it!
What're you talkin' about?
The seventh symbol.
We're goin' home.
Let's go.
You'll bring disaster
on all of us, son.
Father, we will not live as slaves.
Kasuf!
Take a look at your gods.
Take a good look.
The caravan is approaching.
Send the bomb down to the Stargate.
What's happening up there?
How you doin'?
Damn!
Come on, Feretti!
Come on!
Get that door!
Hey, you okay? You all right?
Spread out!
Let's go!
We're dead!
-Quit talkin' like that!
-Well, what are we gonna do!
Cover me.
Cover you?!
Kawalsky!
Feretti,
help me push this thing over!
Send the bomb to Earth now!
I will send it myself!
-What are you doing?
-Completing this mission.
We agreed to dismantle
the gate on the other side.
And you will.
That's your job now.
I'm gonna stay here,
make sure this goes off.
You've got seven minutes.
What are you doing?
Jackson!
Wait for me.
-You got any rounds, Feretti?
-We're all out of ammo!
Incoming!
Kawalsky, we gotta do something.
Damn!
Hey!
Stop!
I am no longer amused.
You will die together.
Give my regards to King Tut,
asshole.
-How much time do we have left?
-45 seconds.
He's leaving. Turn it off.
I'm trying to. I can't disarm it.
What?
I can't stop it.
They've got it rigged.
I've got an idea.
-I always knew you'd get us back.
-Yeah, right.
Later.
Thanks, Daniel.
You sure you wanna do this?
Yes. I'm sure.
You gonna be all right?
I'm gonna be all right.
How about you?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think so.
Tell Catherine this brought me luck.
I will.
I'll be seein' you around.
Doctor Jackson.
Subtitles edited by LeapinLar