Does that sound familiar?
The Rabbit's Foot. Where is it?
I gave it to you.
Ethan, where's the Rabbit's Foot?
Wait... What are you saying?
That wasn't it?
-What I gave you, was that...
-I'm going to count to 10.
You're going to tell me
where the Rabbit's Foot is or she dies.
Jules, it's going to be okay.
It's going to be okay.
Do you understand?
One.
You listen to me.
I got exactly what you asked for.
Did you want something else?
If there was a misunderstanding,
I will fix it.
I can get it, whatever you want.
Two.
Listen. Talk to me. We can talk,
Iike gentlemen.
-Three.
-God!
All right. All right, all right.
I know where the Rabbit's Foot is.
I can help you.
The way you helped me
on the airplane?
That way?
You put the gun down.
I'm not talking to you like this.
That's your choice. Four.
The Rabbit's Foot's in Paris.
You want to know where in Paris?
Then let her go.
-'Cause you will not...
-It's not in Paris. Five.
I can get it for you.
But you kill her, you do this,
you get nothing.
-Six.
-Are you listening to me?
The only way you're going
to get what you want is for you to...
-Do you think I'm playing?
-Son of a bitch!
Do you think I'm playing?
You don't think I'll do it?
Where is it? Where the hell is it?
-Look at me.
-Where the hell is it?
-Stay with me.
-Seven! Seven!
I am going to kill you.
I swear to God I'm going to kill you!
-Eight!
-No, please.
Please. Don't do this. Just let her go.
I promise you. I promise you.
-I can figure out how to get whatever...
-Nine.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
I want to help you.
I want to help you get
whatever you want.
But you got to do what's right.
What you know is right.
No. No.
No.
-Ten.
-Don't!
-What are you doing?
-Your brother wants another one.
Oh, God, no.
Ethan, that's what we talked about...
-I'm watching him. He's fine.
-That's how it is with Rick.
He's fine and then suddenly he's naked
and he's hugging everybody.
-I'll take full responsibility for Rick.
-You will? Full?
-Well, mostly full.
-It's a huge responsibility.
It's going well, right?
-It's going really well.
-Yeah.
Julia, your sister's here.
-Give me a hug.
-You look so beautiful.
I don't know about that. So, is this him?
-I hope so.
-Oh, come here. Oh, gosh.
All right. Mom's dying to see you.
I can't believe
you guys came all the way to Virginia.
Like we'd miss your engagement...
When Julia called and told me
that she was getting married,
I had one thought,
that it was just too bad
that Daddy wasn't here
to walk her down the aisle.
And then when Julia told me...
Thanks, Mom.
That Ethan doesn't have
his parents anymore, either,
I got really sad.
But it occurred to me
that this is about starting a new family
and how beautiful that is.
And I just want to say
I am making Julia an aunt,
so I expect the same treatment
very, very soon.
Cheers!
Department of Transportation?
I've been there over 1 0 years now.
Wow.
What do you do at the DOT?
I study traffic patterns.
You hit the brakes for a second,
just tap them on the freeway,
you can literally track
the ripple effect of that action
across a 200-mile stretch of road,
because traffic has a memory.
It's amazing. It's like a living organism.
Freshen that up for you?
What is it, vodka martini?
Yeah. Thanks.
Ladies, do you need...
-I'd marry him.
-I would, too.
Okay, so, a three-week
heli-boarding honeymoon?
-Okay, you actually get dropped...
-From a helicopter, yeah.
-It's how they met.
-Really?
-Tell her the story.
-There's no story.
It is a good story. Tell the story.
First of all,
no one was ever good enough for Julia.
Oh, here we go.
Not spontaneous enough,
adventurous enough, funny enough...
You know what? No, that's not true.
You make it sound like I've never dated.
No one we liked.
-That is true.
Then she goes and gets in a chopper
that takes off from this lake...
-What was the name of that lake?
-Lake...
Lake Wanaka. Wanaka.
Wanaka. Thank you.
-He heard that?
-How did he hear that?
And the hospital's cool
with you taking three weeks?
Yeah, I'm not the only nurse
employed there, you know.
I'm psyched that you're going
to be my brother, man.
So am l, Rick.
No, it's awesome.
I think it's going to be sick.
Me, too, man.
I just got to get the phone.
-You rock hard.
-Okay.
Hello?
-Is this Mr. Ethan Hunt?
-Yes, it is.
This is Ready-Travel Resort Services.
We'd like to offer you a chance to win
an all-expense-paid trip to Mexico.
We ran out of ice.
I'll be back in 1 0 minutes.
-Oh, no. Can't somebody else go?
-No, I got it.
I'll be right back. Hi, Betsy.
Thank you.
$1.86.
Thanks for coming.
Can't decide what size Slurpee to get.
I usually go for the 900-ouncer.
How's that party? Sorry I had to call you.
-Yeah, you should have come.
-You should have invited me.
-You know I would have.
-Thanks.
I know we joke about it, but I am always
this close to begging you
to stop training our people
and get your ass back in the field.
But that's not what you do anymore,
and so I respect that choice.
You know I do. Family's everything.
Come on, John. What's going on?
It's Agent Farris.
She was on an operation.
She's disappeared.
Been off-grid 1 1 hours.
I'm sending in Search and Rescue.
I was hoping you'd want in.
You've got good people for that.
Yeah. Yep, that we do.
Wheels up at sunrise
if you have a change of heart.
Take some pictures of the party for me.
Ethan. Three days ago,
Agent Lindsey Farris was captured
while on a surveillance operation.
This is the man she was tracking.
His name is Owen Davian.
Details are eyes-only,
but I can tell you
that Davian's a black-market trafficker.
Extremely dangerous
and a priority for us.
At 1 400 hours today,
a recon satellite ID'd
a caravan of vehicles
with plates matching those known to
have been used by Davian's operatives.
They stopped at a derelict factory
outside Berlin.
It appears they have a hostage.
We believe it's Agent Farris.
Normally we would disavow,
but Lindsey may be the key
to getting us closer to Davian,
and that's a risk we need to take.
Your mission,
should you choose to accept it,
is to find Lindsey and bring her home.
I've already assembled a team.
I have them standing by,
awaiting your word.
This message, let's call it
my excellent engagement gift to you,
will self-destruct in five seconds.
Good luck, Ethan, and thanks again.
Am I ready?
-You okay?
-Y eah.
Y eah.
You know, I'm sorry. I realized
I didn't tell you that the office called
during the party.
I have to go to Houston for a night.
METRO's having
a public transpo conference.
-It's so last-minute.
-I know.
Well, well, well.
Now, if it isn't
Mr. "Those Who Can't Do, Teach"
back in the field.
-What's up, baby?
-Hey, man.
Hey, Ethan, don't worry.
We're going to get the girl.
Or have you been away so long
you've forgotten how good we are?
Welcome back, brother.
Is our truck in place?
Weapons good to go?
-Yeah. You?
-Yeah.
You know I got your six.
Hey, man. That's your job.
Guns one, activated.
Guns two, activated.
Guns three, activated.
Guns four, activated.
Guns ready.
All four guns operational.
They've got men on
the second, third, fourth floors.
I count 14 of them.
Observer, I'm in approach position.
Roger that. Stand by.
Target match.
The prize is on the sixth floor.
Two Tangos with her.
Moving in.
So, Raider One, at some point,
we got to go over
this whole "getting married" thing.
Negative, Observer.
I don't respect you nearly enough
to have that conversation.
You may not respect me,
but for now you're stuck
with my voice in your head.
So, this girl,
what the hell do you see in her anyway?
Who, Julia? You've never met her.
Yeah, and the way things are,
I probably never will.
Lucky for her, right?
That's what you're thinking.
They've got communications gear.
Two Tangos, second floor,
northwest corridor.
Groundhog, that's you.
You need to grab that gear
on the second floor
as soon as we go hot.
Copy that. I'll need two minutes,
which means
you'll need me in one, right?
Yeah, just about.
Raider One,
make a left at the top of the stairs.
The prize should be
at the end of the hall.
Phoenix, I have eye on the prize.
Give her 1 0 cc's more.
-Call me when she wakes.
-Okay.
We need touchdown in less than three.
Do you copy?
Roger that, I copy.
Please, when do I not copy?
All I do is copy.
Stand by to go live. On my mark.
Three.
Two.
One. Execute.
Warning. Warning.
Raider One, you're clear. Move!
Lindsey. Lindsey.
Ethan?
I'm going to get you home.
Observer, I've got the prize.
Evac in three.
Roger that.
This is adrenaline.
Lindsey, you're going to feel this.
Groundhog, second floor is clear.
On the move!
Observer, we're on the move. Wrap out.
-Evac in 90 seconds.
-Roger that.
Phoenix, get to the LZ now.
Roger, Observer. On my way.
Ethan. I have to talk to you.
-Come on, come on.
-I have to talk to you right now!
Just for you. Turn off your transmitter.
Do it, Ethan!
Ethan!
-Lindsey! Moving!
-Moving!
Mag!
Ready to move.
We evac from here.
Get down!
I'm out. How many rounds you got?
Enough.
Now I'm out.
T minus five, baby.
Lindsey, hold on to me.
Luther!
Rolling!
God! My head! What is that?
-What is...
-ls she okay?
Lindsey! Let's get to the chopper.
Zhen, get rid of the truck.
Let's go!
God! What is that? You can't hear that?
-Oh! God!
-What's wrong with her?
-Let's go!
-We loaded?
Yeah. Let's do it! Move out!
Go, go, go, go, go!
-Son of a bitch.
-No!
Guys, we got company.
I'm going to try and lose them.
Hurts so much.
Turn it off. Please.
Please, Ethan.
Guys, their missiles are hot!
Incoming! Hold on.
Okay. That was lucky.
We only get one of those.
Do we have a defibrillator?
Ethan, turn it off!
Bring it on!
Ethan! What is it?
Did they put something in my head?
They injected you
with a time-release charge.
-Do you remember that?
-No. Time-release...
An explosive. They've activated it.
It's gonna detonate
unless we fry the charge,
-which is what we're gonna do.
-No, Ethan.
Zap her like that, you'll stop her heart.
Then I'll zap her again
and bring her back.
Do it!
Guys! They're firing another one!
-Ethan!
-Zhen!
Zhen, hold on. Hold on, hold on!
-I want you to set it for 150.
-150.
Lindsey, I'm gonna short out
the explosive in your head.
-You're gonna be okay.
-lt'll need 30 seconds.
Damn it.
-Twenty-five seconds!
-Come on.
We're almost there.
-They have us locked.
-Twenty seconds.
Hold on.
I got them!
-Ten seconds.
-Almost there. Almost there.
Give me the paddles.
Ethan. Thank you.
Shit.
Hey.
How did it go?
I'm sorry. Fine. I'm sorry.
I'm just tired.
I read your training brief
on Agent Farris.
The words you used were
"beyond capable."
That still stand, Mr. Hunt?
-Mr. Brassel...
-Does it stand?
Yes, sir, it does.
Because we've got a corpse downstairs
that says otherwise.
Killed by a detonator
implanted in her skull
through the nasal cavity.
Mr. Brassel, it's unacceptable to judge
Agent Farris' competence based...
It's unacceptable
that chocolate makes you fat,
but I've eaten my share.
And guess what?
Now, I approved Agent Farris'
surveillance op
based on your evaluations, Mr. Hunt,
of a woman
who allowed herself to be captured.
So you go to recover her.
You encounter a dozen men.
You don't grab any of them?
Our objective, Mr. Brassel,
was to recover Agent Farris.
Davian employs a cellular structure
at his organization.
The men there
more than likely had no information...
Who's drawing these conclusions?
Is it you?
-I am, sir. Based upon...
-I'm not on you yet.
You allowed Farris
to board your chopper without a scan.
That explosive device
could have taken you all out.
There is one reason that you are sitting
here before me today, and that is luck.
Because your operation was
poorly conceived and executed worse.
-Two laptops were recovered...
-I'm aware of that.
We've talked to Tech Services.
They doubt
if they can reconstitute the drives.
"Crispy," I believe,
is what they called them. Worthless.
Mr. Brassel,
as Operation Manager of this office,
-I have the authority...
-Excuse me.
Did you just throw a title at me,
Mr. Musgrave?
I don't care if your daddy plays golf
with the President.
This is lntelligence.
So far I haven't seen any.
You think this op was worth the risk,
Mr. Hunt.
What do you know about Owen Davian?
He was the one
who brought gas centrifuge technology
to Korea from Pakistan.
He was also the man who sold Toxin
Five to the Armahad Republic Jihad.
He is a man who provides,
provides, provides!
And he remains invisible.
He's a goddamn invisible man.
Wells, not Ellison,
in case you want to be cute again.
We can't find him.
He knows it. It's emboldened him.
I've been trying to bring Davian down
since the day that I got here.
Do you know what I've got for it?
It's never been confirmed
the Toxin Five theft was Davian.
Mr. Musgrave, please don't interrupt me
when I'm asking rhetorical questions.
Your operation has achieved one thing.
You have reminded Davian
that he is winning.
And now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to go inform Mr. and Mrs. Farris
that their baby girl was killed
in a head-on collision on l-95.
I stand here today deeply saddened
by the death of one of God's children,
Lindsey Elizabeth Farris.
It is always startling when the Lord
takes one of our young so unexpectedly.
Be aggressive. Come on. Stay focused.
Keep your knees bent. Good. Good.
Now, to fire the lock,
the extractor has to be...
That bag's not going to hit you back.
Hit harder.
Don't rely on your sights.
Keep your eyes dead on the target...
Attack me. Come on.
Don't ever release the firing pin
unless the extractor's...
Good. There you go. Good.
Identify the target. Point and shoot.
It's very simple. You point and shoot.
Stay focused.
Miss Farris, you know
how many recruits I've trained.
I'm proud to say that you are the first
that I've recommended
for active field duty.
Congratulations.
Am I ready?
Y es?
Is this Mr. Kelvin?
Y es. Who is this?
I'm calling from Norfolk Mail Service.
Lindsey Farris
rents a post office box here.
She sent you a piece of mail from Berlin
and asked us to call you
when it arrived.
It came this morning.
Thank you.
-This right here.
-Thanks.
It's a microdot.
A microdot with nothing on it.
This is unusual.
Lindsey wouldn't send me
a blank microdot.
I'm telling you, man, there's no image.
Then you're not looking
in the right place.
Where the hell am I supposed to look?
There's not much square footage
to this thing.
Why would Lindsey send me
a blank microdot?
I don't know.
Why would Lindsey send you anything?
You were her instructor,
not her handler.
Listen, man.
I don't mean to cross the line,
but was there something going on
between you two?
You and Lindsey.
Lindsey was like my little sister.
And you never
slept with your little sister, right?
Hey, brother, if I don't ask you, who will?
Maybe it's magnetic. The microdot.
Well, that's old school.
If she was in a hurry and only had
access to black-market gear, maybe.
-Could you get the tools to read it?
-I might know a guy.
-Magnetic means encrypted.
-Yeah, I know that.
Yeah. Be right there.
The thing about Lindsey is
she was brand-new.
She was sweet.
Remember when you were sweet?
-Can you remember that far back?
-Yeah, well, barely.
In Germany,
you asked me what it is I see in Julia.
What I see in Julia is life before all this.
And it's good.
Benji, what have you got?
Well, these hard drive platters
are just fried.
-Yeah.
-You know, they made a mess of them.
It's just like...
There's holes in them and stuff.
And it's got scorched
all the way through. And then...
Look, this one's got
a hole in it and stuff.
I can't believe. I can't even look at it.
-Benji. Did you recover anything?
-Yes. Yes.
Despite the aforementioned conditions
of the hard drive you brought back,
I managed to recover
portions of two dozen e-mail files.
Also made what I believe to be
a thoroughly
promotion-worthy breakthrough.
Your Mr. Davian is going
to arrive in Rome the day after tomorrow
and attend a function
at one Vatican City.
What the hell is Davian
doing at the Vatican?
It's all got to do with the "Rabbit's Foot."
Rabbit's Foot?
Yeah, well,
I'm assuming it's like a code word
for something he's about to sell
to an unspecified buyer,
for $850 million, by the way.
Or maybe it's not a code word.
Maybe it's just a really,
really expensive bunny appendage.
You have no idea what it is?
It's interesting. I used to have
this professor at Oxford, okay?
Dr. Wickham, his name was,
and he was like this massive, fat guy.
You know, huge, big guy.
We used to call him...
You know... Well, I won't tell you
what we used to call him.
He taught biomolecular kinetics
and cellular dynamics,
and he used to sort of
scare the underclassmen
with this story about how the world
would eventually be eviscerated
by technology.
You see, it was inevitable
that a compound would be created,
which he referred to as the "Anti-God."
It was like an accelerated mutator,
a sort of, you know,
Iike an unstoppable force
of destructive power
that would just lay waste to everything.
To buildings and parks
and streets and children
and ice cream parlors, you know?
So whenever I see, like,
a rogue organization,
willing to spend this amount of money
on a mystery tech,
I always assume it's the Anti-God.
End-of-the-world kind of stuff,
you know?
But, no, I don't have any idea what it is.
I was just speculating.
-Did you brief Musgrave on this?
-Who, me? No, not yet.
-Good. Don't.
-What?
-Don't tell anyone about this.
-This took me ages.
If something goes wrong
with the operation,
I want Musgrave to have deniability.
-That's great work, Benji.
-What operation?
That look in your eye
is a pain in my ass.
You know that, right?
Any available resident to Pediatrics.
Rehabilitative Care, call the pharmacy.
Rehabilitative Care, call the...
I have to go away again.
On business. Two days.
Two days?
Yeah.
Ethan, what's going on?
I keep thinking you just need time
to tell me whatever it is that it's...
But nothing in my mind makes sense.
Yeah.
What's wrong?
What are you not telling me?
I need to ask you for something.
And it's the most...
I need you to trust me.
Of course I trust you.
Am I ever going to be able
to understand what this is?
I need you to trust me.
Yes.
I trust you.
Is it...
Tell me it's real.
I mean us.
Follow me.
The vows you're about to take
are not to be taken
without careful thought and prayer.
This love is not to be diminished
by difficult circumstances
and it is only to be dissolved by death.
Do you have the rings?
Yeah.
Repeat after me.
I, Julia Anne Meade...
"l, Julia Anne Meade..."
...hereby take Ethan Matthew Hunt...
"...hereby take Ethan Matthew Hunt..."
...to be my lawfully wedded husband.
"...to be my lawfully wedded husband."
Tomorrow may be the only time
we can predict
where Owen Davian is going to be.
Charity event. Vatican City.
Our mission is to get in
and kidnap Davian.
I don't know why he's so happy.
I did remind him
that the Vatican is the Vatican.
A 109-acre sovereign state
in the middle of Rome,
surrounded by a 60-foot wall,
which is monitored 24/7,
with over 200 CCTV cameras.
That's not even
what makes it a challenge.
Getting Davian is good.
But getting his buyers is even better.
If they realize he's been grabbed,
they'll disappear.
I'm sorry, what are you saying?
No matter how we grab Davian,
his clients are gonna know
he's been taken.
No, they won't. Access point is here.
It's a one-way street
adjacent to the Vatican wall.
I'll need 30 seconds.
And we'll need a truck.
Now we've pissed off
every ltalian in Rome,
go do what you got to do.
-Don't forget the smoke.
-Yeah.
"Humpty Dumpty sat on a wall."