- Soeun!
- Yes?
- Is Sunmi hospitalized?
- Yes, just been there
Is she alright?
She broke her leg
She has to stay there for 2 weeks
Must have been some bicycle trick
How did you find out so soon?
Well... I was on the back seat
Is everything OK?
4 minutes 58 seconds!
Wait, wait a minute, a new record!
A Women's touch
beat the men's superiority!
Hey, just a moment
something's wrong...
A transistor is missing
How am I supposed to assemble
the damn thing?
Who gave me this?
Common, give it up. Accept it!
No excuses. Take it like a man!
You lose and game's over
Drinks on you
Anyway
this is all I have
Gotta run!
C'mon, wait!
Excuse me...
Soeun?
Soeun!
Oh! Donghee...ls that you?
Yes, I've returned
I see...
What's this?
Yeah, it's my hobby
You're a HAM? Surprising...
I like it
I see...OK then, see you later
By the way,
thanks for the letters you sent
while I was in the Army
You've sent so many
Bye now
I just wanted to take a look
I'm sorry
- Do you smell alcohol on my breath?
- Yes, a little...
It's all because of
that piece of junk
I also had to pay for the drinks
It's old and broken
Can't even find the parts
Take it!
When it's besides you,
you'll have many drinking days
Thank you. Donghee!
Oh! Soeun
You're really into it
Is it yours?
- What?
- That!
- Yes
- Is it yours?
- It's mine, alright?
- What?
- Yeah, sure...
- Yes, it's mine
- It's lots of fun
- Really?
- Goodbye
- Bye
You alright?
Hey, take it easy!
Might hurt yourself waving
So?
What's so great about him
talking to you?
So weird
Couldn't breathe and blood
gushing to my head
When he calls my name.
Soeun...Soeun...
My name sounds so pretty
Soeun...
I'll get another bed here.
You're sicker than me
You have no idea...
When he looks at me,
he looks at my eyes
Left and right
One at a time.
He could look elsewhere but...
..always the same
Left eye and right eye
Then where do you look?
Me? Don't remember
Anyway,
I feel like my heart might burst...
and every muscle in my body twitches
Is this love?
I know how you feel
but I don't think that's love
You've felt it before?
It felt like my heart would burst...
and every muscle
in my body twitched
You came to me when I fell and said
Sunmi, you alright?
You were looking at my eyes
one at a time
Then... Oh my God!
I must be in love with you
You!
Sungsu Bridge is now open
to the public
President Park participated
in the opening ceremony...
and discussed
the environmental effects
There'll be a lunar eclipse tonight.
Should we watch?
Sunmi's in the hospital?
Calling CQ, CQ, CQ.
This is DS1 AVO
Delta Sierra One Alpha Victor Oscar
Anyone copy?
Calling CQ, CQ, CQ.
This is DS1 AVO
Delta Sierra One Alpha Victor Oscar
Anyone copy?
Calling CQ, CQ, CQ.
This is DS1 AVO
Delta Sierra One Alpha Victor Oscar
Anyone copy?
Hello?
What did you say?
Oh, Sunmi! You scared me
No, I was just doing something
Where are you?
Right, in the hospital
What? You're crazy to come out
What's so great about the eclipse?
Tomorrow? OK, I'll stop by
Hello?
Soeun!
Yes?
- Are you busy today?
- Not really
You want to see a play?
A play?
I'm not really into plays
but a friend of mine directed it
He'd kill me if I didn't show up
So he just wants me to
show my face...
but I didn't want to go alone
- So if you like plays...
- Yes, I like them!
What is the title?
Well...it was too long to remember
Let's find out when we get there
- Anyway, 7 o'clock, OK?
- Yes
OK, then...
Oh! Donghee!
What?
I forgot. I have an engagement
Oh, yeah?
What can you do?
It's my fault anyway
Asking for a date
at the last minute doesn't work
I guess last minute things
only work with Rugby
- OK, I'm leaving then
- Yeah...
Then...
What's with the long face?
What's wrong?
Nothing...Do your parents know
you're going out?
Don't worry
I'll tell them you talked me into it
Where do you wanna go
with that broken leg?
Remember my friend Miyoon?
Her boyfriend directed a play
I promised her I would go
Play? What's the title?
Title? Let me see... I forgot
Too long to remember anyway
Our life has so many turns,
so let's leave when there's applause
You came!
- And?
- My friend, Sunmi
- How do you do?
- Hi...
Have a seat
You'd better go now.
Are you gonna be alright?
Yes. Need a little exercise.
Nice meeting you
Are you sure?
You'd have to go up the stairs?
Don't worry. Bye
Let's go
Do you go right to sleep?
Not right away. Wash my face, read...
- What about HAM radio?
- What? Yes, sometimes
- You have to teach me someday
- Sorry?
Sure, someday...
Hello?
Thanks for responding.
I'll introduce this OP
QRA is DS1 AVO
QTH is Kangnamku Chungdamdong
Attending Shilla University
My name is JEE as in Jesus
IN as in in-and-out. JEE, IN
Signal 59 receiving you
loud and clear
Turning it over to you. DS1 AVO
Hello?
Contacted! Are you a novice?
What I mean is...
Have you ever tried this before?
No...
I see...understandable...
But once you get used to it,
it's easier than chatting
I'm Jee In. How do you do?
Hi, Mr. Ahm Jeein
my name's Yoon, Soeun
Not Ahm Jeein, Jee, In.
IN is my first name
Oh, I'm sorry.
Have you been doing this a long time?
Only a few years
You'll get used to it.
It's more fun than you think
I have to learn. Would you teach me?
Of course!
I've got a book for beginners
I'll let you borrow it
I go to Shilla University.
Are you a student?
Oh! I go to the same school!
Wow! What a coincidence!
How come you didn't join the HAM club?
What? Oh, I just- -...
I see, trying it all by yourself, huh?
Interesting. I'll give you the book
at school tomorrow
Tomorrow?
- Sorry, I must be rushing you
- No, it's not that...
- I really appreciate it
- OK, then
Where should we meet?
How about the Clock Tower?
In front of the main building
- The one they are building?
- Pardon?
OK. We'll meet at 2p. m.
See you then.
I'll give the final call
Thank you
Down with dictatorship!
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
Am I standing in front of
the main building?
What are you talking about?
- Is that the main building behind me?
- Of course!
This is the Clock Tower, right?
Are you mad? Of course it is!
OK. Then, go
One more thing.
Is this Shilla University?
You were actually waiting for me,
weren't you?
You wanted to get my sympathy
by looking like that...
and become like a hero in a movie
Yeah, I was actually waiting for you
I came to this school to meet you
and the purpose of my birth is you
My family motto is Love Hyunji
I have your name tattooed
on my back. Satisfied?
But I think it's odd to wait for
a stranger for 2 hours in the rain?
I've never seen her.
So I waited for her
Frankly, I wouldn't wait for you.
Understand?
Bastard!
What?
Hello?
- Go home and get some rest
- I'm going
- Home?
- You don't have to know
- Why not?
- It's none of your business
Hey, leave me the umbrella
How come you didn't show up?
Well, I could understand
If you are not in college.
It's not a big deal to be in college
You don't have to have a complex
I could understand if you're not
very good looking
When you saw
a good looking guy like me
you didn't have the guts to face me
What are you talking about?
I was waiting for you for over
2 hours getting dust all over me
Dust?
You mean, dust in the rain?
Rain? What rain?
What are you talking about?
It's bright and sunny
Really?
Are you sure you're in Korea?
Not Japan or China?
Wait a minute!
45a. Can't you hear the sound?
It's been raining for days.
Are you saying I'm crazy?
Stop pulling my leg
and turn off the shower!
What the f...!
Calling CQ, CQ, CQ...
This is DS1 AVO
Delta Sierra One Alpha Victor Oscar
Anyone copy?
That's bullshit!
Even soldiers don't fight
if they're not fed
And you did what
with a disconnected HAM radio?
It doesn't make sense, right?
Then something's wrong
with the radio?
No, something's wrong with you!
What's up?
He's gone mad.
I think he's been struck by lightning
Then he should be back to normal
- He was a strange one
- You're right
Right,
I wish I was struck by lightning
What are you doing?
Fixing something
Why do you need both of you
to fix it?
Sir, why don't you take her?
She's bothering me
Why are you bothering him?
Go home.
It's not the place for a girl
Is this a boys' dorm or something?
Hyunji, my friend. Get lost!
Frankly, I can't even
find a hole because of you!
Isn't that a simple machine?
You just talk and listen
- I've been waiting for you
- I just got home
- I see, got home late
- Why, did you wait for me?
I don't think we have anything
to talk about
Well...I just wanna apologize...
I was rude
Guess it's raining still?
Not today
So, what grade are you in?
A junior
Oh, you're older...
I'm a sophomore
Wait!
Then should I call you older sister?
No, you don't have to do that.
I don't want a little brother like you
We should be the same age
since I went to school a year early
Came to school in 77
Oh, I see
- What year did you say?
- Yes? Why?
I thought I heard it wrong
77. Did you hear it right this time?
No, I heard it wrong again.
Just a minute, you mean...
when you say 77,
does it mean the year 1977?
We usually say 77 short for 1977
If you're joking, it's not funny
What?
What I mean is
you sound so sincere
How do you do that?
We are the same age
and go to the same school...
but I came to school in 77
Short for 1977
So, you came in 1999 and now you
attend school in the year 2000?
Last time I checked.
If you're right, you're talking to me
after the end of the world
Finished?
What year is this?
What? What the hell's wrong?
I'm going. Are you going?
What?
So... You were flirting with
someone old?
You pervert, or maybe she is
She entered school in 1977.
But she's still in school
I don't think she's neither kidding
nor crazy
Hey, that's simple
She got into school in 1977
and she's now a junior
Yeah, she had some time off,
maybe for 20 years?
Maybe she was in the Army
for a long time...
or got married and had babies
Why are you here?
Your bus doesn't stop here
It's too late for the bus.
We'll take a cab
I'll drop you off
Donghee!
Oh, Soeun
Have a seat here
What are your plans after graduation?
Such serious subject over lunch
Well...maybe office worker? Or...
A politician? A congressman?
I'm interested in politics but
you never know
Who knows? I may just play around
before the world ends?
- It won't end
- What?
You know they say
the world will end in 1999
But it won't
How do you know?
Well, isn't it a happy thought
anyhow?
I see...
Don't you like this? I'll eat it
No wonder I couldn't find you
Who'd think you'd be in the library?
What do you want?
A letter from your parents in America
What are you doing with my letter?
You never open your mailbox.
You should thank me
OK.
By the way, how do I checkout books?
I've never done it
I knew it. Wait here
Ma'am!
What's the procedure for checking
out books?
Fill out the form
and I need student I.D.
Student I.D.? No one carries that
How about a driver's license?
Don't you have class?
We have the same classes
When you don't have one,
I don't have one
Stop annoying me
Annoying? Bastard!
I'm not a humanist. I don't have
time to annoy assholes like you
Here. Read it
Damn it. Why are you telling me
to read my letter?
You read it.
I'm sure it's nothing
Do you really want me to read it?
- Oh my god!
- What?
What handwriting!
She writes like a young person.
Meticulous and pretty
Just read it. Ask me if you run into
a difficult word
So complicated. So many things
happened in October, 1979
So complicated.
The house, weather, Dad
Anyway, she wants you to write often
PS. You didn't forget mom's birthday?
What's the date today?
Today? 5th, why?
Forgot to send her present!
Hey, are you making fun of me?
Wear it when you get better
You'll get better quicker to wear it
Thanks, my friend
I should have gotten you
a short skirt
So you won't ride a bicycle
Leaving so soon?
Sorry. Let's celebrate
when you get better
You're really blinded by love,
aren't you?
- Go, fly to your love
- I'm flying
Sorry to make you wait
You didn't have to come out
so quickly
- It's OK. Let's go
- OK
Oh, Lord!
I was saying...
In Year 2000, do you think
people still talk at night?
As long as there's night,
people will still talk at night
It's late. I have to go
Are your parents strict?
No, but I have to jump over
the wall if it's too late
How can a wall come between us?
It was a line from the movie we saw
Oh, I see...
Have to go.
Gotta make it before the curfew
Your face...tiny
Calling CQ, CQ, CQ...
Yes, you're in 1979
and I'm in 2000
And one of us is being very silly
Or one of us is seriously crazy
Let me ask you one thing
Do you recall anything
on the news from yesterday?
I don't even know
why we're talking in the first place
But sure... Youngsam Kim was
expelled from the National Assembly
Student demonstrations are
everywhere
Do you have a 1979 archive
or something?
What?
No. Nothing
Does it say that the expelled person
would be a president 14 years later?
What the hell are you talking about?
Soeun, listen
In this world, there are many
unexplainable incidents
Those always...come on TV
I thought they were made up
If you keep talking nonsense,
let's stop
I know it must be nonsense to you.
So we couldn't go on
But listen carefully!
You're a junior in 1979 and...
I'm a sophomore and
my calendar says it's Year 2000
It's your news for tomorrow
Pusan will be
placed under martial law
At school, a completion ceremony for
the clock tower will be held
But it'll be postponed.
The Dean will have a heart attack
What?
Ah...you must respect the Dean
But don't worry. He'll be back
next month for the ceremony
Oh, yeah?
Don't you have any other news?
Like a mermaid found in the river
or an earthquake in Seoul
How about the death of the President?
The President will die
on the 26th of this month
But no mermaid nor an earthquake
OK, I'm not asking you to believe me.
We'll talk tomorrow
Sure. Let's stop.
It's the Curfew time already
The Curfew...
Jesus!
PUSAN UNDER MATIAL LAW
The completion ceremony for
the clock tower will be postponed...
Hello?
Hey, you responded right away.
In a hurry?
Who are you? What's going on?
It's simple. I live in 2000
I can find information
about 1979 just like that
Does that mean you believe
that I live in 1979?
I have no choice
Then it's my turn to believe
You probably have no choice
Donghee...
What's up?
Waiting for you.
Are you free this afternoon?
Gee, I've got something on
Would it finish late?
Anything wrong?
No, I just...
I don't mean to refuse
a surprise date offer
It's OK.
Going home?
No, I have to stop by the hospital
Oh, the broken leg!
She's funny
Yes, she's nice and pretty
Gotta go
- OK
- Bye
Let's go
So a guy from Year 2000
is making a pass at you?
No, I don't think he's a bad guy
See? You're already falling for him
Falling for who?
You're already falling for someone
whom you've never met
He must be a con artist.
Call the police
He's trying to get to your soft side...
by lying about Year 2000
Let's get him arrested
- Sunmi...
- Yeah
He does live in Year 2000
I understand
I know when you love someone,
you don't want to meet another person
So let him be
Why am I still in a cast?
We should set some rules
Don't know how we're communicating
but...
I could give you a fortune
beyond your imagination...
but that's morally wrong
A fortune?
Related to personal wealth
For example, I could tell you
real estate information
Or I could tell you
what stock to buy and strike it rich
I agree. Shouldn't do that
But I'm from the past
and you're in the future
So I'm more curious
Curiosity?
Naive curiosity
How's the future world?
I guess compared to 1979,
it's very convenient
Subways are everywhere
under the city
What about the Unification?
Ilsung Kim is dead
but no Unification yet
Gosh, he dies too
We can travel to Mt. Kumkang
in the north though
Wow, must be exciting!
Is it beautiful?
Worth living in the world?
As always, the world is a good place
to be in
Of course, there is pollution
and population problems
So some people reminisce about
what it used to be like
Really? Um...
I wonder what they reminisce about...
I wish I could see the year 2000
I wish I could show you
This world is full of things
you were imagining...
I mean, things you couldn't imagine
became reality
In that world,
if you really love someone
is there a way to make him love me?
I don't think
it will ever be invented
Oh, are you in love?
Oops! No!
It's OK. I'm from a different world
anyway
I don't know the definition of love
but I can guess it
He...looks at my eyes
each one at a time
He...
What am I saying?
I only say to this to my diary
I can be your diary for a while.
A talking diary
Have you someone you love?
Me?
Yes, I do
How much did you drink? I can
smell your alcohol from last night
Not last night.
This morning. Hangover chaser!
Hey, get closer!
Be quiet and keep a straight face
I can't keep a straight face
when I'm with him
Don't open your mouth. It stinks
So are you still talking to
that woman from 1979?
Why ask?
You don't even believe me
I believe you
You're communicating with someone
from 1979 every night
You're interested in her
But you can't do shit...
because she's from another time
I believe that
What the hell are you saying?
And watch your language
You start cursing
when you get jealous
Did you say jealous?
Do you think I feel jealous about
that crazy women...
and the show you're putting on?
I think...
You...
You're too happy
Nothing to worry about
So you're
looking for something different
Please, don't include me in it!
Looking for Donghee?
Not really...
- He got hurt during a demonstration
- What?
He's in the hospital behind the school.
He just checked in
I see...
Oh, Soeun!
Do I look that bad?
I don't know I had bad luck
or I'm just not coordinated
I'm the only one who fell
Got a pen?
Sign it.
So it will get better quicker
Got to go. I'll stop to see
Sunmi on the way
- Right! She's in here, too
- Downstairs
The president will be changed
this month anyway
Thank you.
I hope you're right
I inscribed my name on him
Interesting, you mean like a tattoo?
Sort of. It's weird to think
I have my name on him
I feel like I own him
An arm is swinging with my name.
He's walking, swinging me
Sorry?
It's similar to my parents' story
That's what my Mom wrote
when she met Dad
Your Mom?
Oh! My parents went to
the same university as us
Let me see...
Entered the school in 1977
Why didn't I think of that?
They're going to school with you!
Oh my god! Who are they?
I'd know them!
My Mom's Sunmi Hur, and
my Dad's name is Donghee Jee
Do you know them?
Of course. We've the same major...
Do you know them well?
Not really, just...
You say your father's name was
Donghee?
Yes, you know him?
They were a famous couple
Yes, of course...
Wow...I can't believe this!
They look very good together
Wow...how's my mother?
What's her nickname?
You...
Is this a fad?
Who is it?
What the hell?!
Visiting my friend
Something wrong?
Jesus!
Are you drunk?
What am I, an alcoholic?
No, it can't be.
It's all a lie
How can he be in 2000?
Does that make sense?
I'm gonna turn that crook over
to the police
What an accident! Hur Sunmi
- Are you sure that's true?
- I'm positive!
It can't be Hyunji.
You sure it wasn't someone else?
I thought I was dying.
That's a very famous bar
Are you sure it was Hyunji?
Did you see her?
- Not too close but...
- You're full of it
Her clothes and make up were
exactly the same
She must be in need of money
Hi!
Are we talking about Hyunji
working at the bar?
- You knew?
- You guys didn't know?
See? I told you
She works there
because she likes to drink
You are very quiet today...
It's one of those days
Have you met my parents?
They look so good together
I wish everything looked so good
How's your boy friend?
I was thinking maybe...
We're not destined to be
with each other
Not everything's destined for
each other
You say a destination before you leave,
not when you get there
Finally, I'm out!
You scared me.
Don't ever do that
Soeun, what's wrong?
Aren't you happy that I'm back?
I'm all better
I don't feel like fooling around
Want some?
Hello
Going to my parents' country house
To get something
Have you been drinking?
Stupid! Am I an alcoholic?
When do you come back?
Be careful
OK
It's a good luck charm, Soeun
How do you feel?
Can I keep this as a souvenir?
Soeun?
What brings you here?
I just wanted to see you
I heard you left school early
So I was worried
Don't worry.
Everything's fine
Wanna take a walk?
Can you grab my arm?
Can you do it?
Do you have a boyfriend?
If anybody sees us,
they'll think we're lovers
Are you here to say that?
Sort of...
If we are lovers, they'd know
even if we're not holding hands
People are in mourning for
the death of President Park...
who passed away at 7:50pm on the 26th
House Representative Choi
has taken over the Presidency...
and the Defense Minister...
Going to school?
Honey? Honey!
It's OK. There won't be a war
or anything
Everything will be fine
Soeun! Soeun!
Hi!
Everything you said came true.
Dictatorship will be over
I'm sure you didn't foresee the future
but everything you said
became reality
In!
Did you find out?
Hey, hold your horses...
She is no longer here
Passed away?
Dead? Is she sick?
She was transferred to
Chonan University 2 years ago
- What?
- She is an English professor
Was she ill?
I saw her picture and she was beautiful
She's still single
No
So she transferred voluntarily?
Yes, we didn't want to let her go
but she had personal reasons
Same year I came to school
If she were to choose my father...
and married him,
what would happen to me?
Then...
That can't happen
Because the world is one
we live in the dimension
that is parallel to time
There can't be another dimension
with the same organism
This can't be proven by science...
What the hell am I saying?
Anyway,
I don't believe in any of this
Your agony is an interesting
S/F melodrama
But I'm not really interested.
That's it. No more!
I don't believe in that machine
either with or without electricity
communicating with a woman
from the past!
What's this?
Is this an alarm also?
Yes
This is Soeun
I was searching for you
but I couldn't connect
Well...
I travelled for a few days
I'm sorry
I broke up with him
He wasn't right for me
As you told me, I wanted to find out
if he was my destination
But I didn't think it was right
So I let go of him from my heart
And I walked for a long time
Walked every corner of the school
They say people live with a scent
And they scatter the scent everywhere
When the scent is gone, they die
But some people still have the scent
after death
And some people pass on the scent
to others
Then it can spread everywhere
I know his scent
I'd recognize it with my eyes closed
Him and I. We definitely
live with the same emotion
Same sorrow, same joy
We'd keep the same scent and live forever
The feeling that I have in 1979
I'm sure you will be able to feel it
in 2000
You think it's right after
all these years?
I just want to say I'm sorry
If not, just want to see her face.
See if she's all right
I wish she'd look happy
If she looks sad or depressed,
what am I going to do?
I couldn't stand it
In!
Go!
Thanks
- Professor Yoon here?
- She's in class. Room 1
Soeun. I saw you today
You looked so beautiful and happy
You seemed to be doing well
When you pass me by...
I could feel
your scent you talked about
I don't think it's working anymore
This radio...
It's a bad thing!
Hey, hey...
What are you doing this late?
You guys again?
Nothing...
Fixing something...
Is that the way to fix it?
Trying to destroy it?
Won't be easy
Go home.
That's how time passes
No one will believe what we've been
through for the last several months. Right
He's right.
That's how time passes
There's nothing we can do to change
what is meant to be
You want to grab my arm?
Why all of a sudden?
- Do it!
- You're embarrassing me