Impossible...
Nothing is impossible...
Come on, Mouse.
Dig!
Dig...
Mouse.
- Jehan.
- Yes, sir?
Get the next 3.
2 more..
- Over there.
- Hurry up.
Take 2. I want Phillipe Gaston.
This is the cell, sir.
Wrong cell. I want Phillipe Gaston,
the one they call "The Mouse".
The Mouse? The Mouse…
The Mouse- he left our house.
No Mouse today- he ran away.
To ease the pain- he's down the drain!
- Where is he?!
- I already told you, gentle Lord!
Hang him. Search every sewer,
every drain!
Find him! Or Captain Marquet
will hang you in his place.
Impossible. Nobody could
escape through there.
It's not unlike escaping
mother's womb.
God, what a memory!
Lord, I'll never pick another pocket
as long as I live, I swear.
But here's the problem- if you won't let
me live, how can I prove my good faith to you?
If you've heard me, this ledge
will remain steady as a rock,
and that thing coming at me
won't be what I think it is.
If it is, there'll be no hard feelings,
of course... but I'll be very disappointed.
I don't believe it...
I believe it.
I'm coming.
It's Phillipe, Lord.
Phillipe.
You won't regret this, Lord.
I'm a wonderful person.
Hello! What are you
doing down there?
Get away, get away!
Come there, come there.
There's disturbing news, Your Grace.
One of the prisoners has escaped.
No one ever escapes the
dungeons of Aquila, Marquet.
The people of the city accept
that as a historical fact.
- The responsibility is mine.
- Yes.
It would be a miracle...
if he manages to get through
the sewage system.
I believe in miracles, Marquet.
It's part of my job.
At any rate, Your Grace, ‘tis only
one insignificant petty thief.
Great storms announce themselves
with a simple breeze, Captain,
and a single rebel spark can
ignite the fires of rebellion.
If he's out there, Your Grace,
I shall find him.
Yes.
Take 10 men toward Chanee,
we ride north to Gabroche.
The name of the man who
finds this Gaston...
will be brought to the personal
attention of the Bishop...
as will the body of the
man who lets him get away.
Open the gate!
I know I promised, Lord, never again.
But I also know, that you know,
what a weak-willed person I am.
Come on, Mouse, keep going.
Not much further.
About 350 miles, that's all.
A nice hot piece of cabbage, like
my dear old mother used to cook.
Wolf! Wolf.
Please, no wolf.
Extract of lamb.
Where the hell am I?
Hot lamb, with sauce on it.
Maybe some of that green stuff,
that Bertram used to put on.
Come on. Get out of here.
- Hello!
- Look up there!
He's taking daddy's shoes!
You've got it, little darlings.
Innkeeper.
- A drink of your most expensive!
- Yeah, yeah, show me your money.
Copper, my friend.
And a same for any who
joins me in a toast!
Let's hear your toast.
We drink to a special man,
my friends.
Someone who has seen the dungeons
of Aquila, and lived to tell the tale.
Then you drink to me, little man.
I've seen those dungeons.
A blacksmith, perhaps?
A carpenter? A stonecutter, even?
But a prisoner, from inside Aquila?
I didn't say I was a prisoner.
If you'd stuck to the woods, you
may have stood a chance, Gaston.
You're right.
Get him!
Move, move!
Get out of the way!
You, I said out!
I'm so terribly sorry!
Kill him.
May God have mercy on my soul!
You, out.
One of my men told me
you returned.
I wanted to cut his
throat for lying...
because I knew you
weren't that stupid.
- Captain Navarre.
- Francesco.
Captain?
Navarre!
I won't hurt you,
I'm a wonderful person.
After him!
Easy, sweet ponies, come here…
you filthy strumpets!
No, no!
No!
Must be somebody at home.
I see smoke.
Are you sure you don't want to ride on, sir?
There's still plenty of light.
Stop your chattering.
We'll spend the night here.
Pitou!
Give me the axe! The axe!
Good afternoon, sir, my lady. My comrade-in-arms
and I need lodging for the night.
- No, no place for you here.
- We'll pay for it, of course.
We are not above compassion
for those in misery.
You may sleep down
there, in a barn.
Thank you.
Sir?
Sir, are you there?
If there's nothing else
I can do, I think I'll turn in.
- You can take care of my horse.
-All right.
And sleep with one eye open.
And don't disturb me- I'm liable to take
your head off before I know it's you.
All right. Come on, old girl.
Come on.
Stubborn little lady!
What's her name?
His name is Goliath.
His name? Pretty name.
Go with him, boy, he didn't
mean to hurt your feelings.
Goliath, before we get to
know each other better...
I feel I should tell you a story about
a teeny little man named David.
One day.
"Comrade-in-arms"!
"Slave" is more like it.
See to the fire, feed the
animals, gather the wood...
Look at me, Lord!
I was better off at the
dungeons of Aquila!
My cellmate was insane,
and a murderer...
but he respected me!
He's a strange one, Navarre. Why did he
save my life? He wants something from me.
I can see it in his eyes.
Well, whatever it is,
I'm not going to do it!
I'm still a young man, you know!
I've got prospects!
I'm off to find my golden future,
Captain, so goodbye and good...
Hello?
Who do you think is out there?
You better draw your sword, Pierre.
Ah, Louis, you brought
your crossbow!
We'll all go back to
the barn now, all right?
- All right.
Show no mercy, Pierre!
Take no prisoners!
I'm going to get some help!
Captain, sir, Captain!
Sir! Sir!
Wolf!
Sir!
Don't go out there,
don't go out there!
There's a wolf, a big wolf, the biggest
wolf you've ever seen, and a dead man.
I know.
Miss, please!
Maybe I'm dreaming.
But my eyes are open, which
means, maybe I'm awake...
dreaming I'm asleep.
Or, or more likely...
maybe I'm asleep,
dreaming I'm awake...
wondering if I'm dreaming.
You are dreaming.
I've not seen what I've just seen.
I do not believe what I believe, Lord.
If these are magical or unexplainable matters,
then I beg you not to make me a part of them.
We'll stop now.
Not a great day for traveling.
Come on, girl, come on.
I mean, boy. Come on, Goliath. Come on.
Goliath, come on, it's cold
out here. Come on.
I can do with a rest myself,
after last night's goings on.
The wolf would have kill me,
it was horrible.
But he tore the farmer's
throat out, and left me alone.
And there was more.
There was a woman...
like fine porcelain,
with deep blue eyes...
almost like a bird's.
And her voice...
the dulcet tones of an angel.
She spoke? What did she say?
I asked her if I was dreaming,
and she said I was.
I'm not insane, you must believe
me when I tell you these things!
No, I believe you.
I believe in dreams.
I see.
This lady… Did she
perhaps have a name?
Not that she mentioned, why?
Well, she may wonder
into my dreams.
Wouldn't it be nice...
if I could call her by name and
pretend we've met before?
I've waited a long
time for such a lady.
Now get some sleep.
The bird will alert
us if anyone comes.
I got to be out of my mind.
Out of my mind.
Open the gates!
Have you found the
criminal, Gaston?
He's not in my custody
at this time.
Then why do you invade my
garden, unwashed, unshaved?
Do you think to find him here?
Navarre has returned.
Walk with me.
The criminal, Gaston, travels with him.
My men are combing the woods.
And the hawk?
- Your Grace?
- There must be a hawk.
A spirited hawk.
This one is not to be
harmed, understood?
You see, the day she dies, a new Captain of
the Guard will preside at your execution.
We live in difficult times, Marquet.
This famine has prevented people from
paying their proper tribute to the church.
I raise their taxes, only to be told
there's nothing left for me to tax.
Imagine! But last night, the Lord
Almighty visited me in my sleep.
He told me...
that Satan's messenger is traveling
amongst us. And his name...
is Etienne of Navarre.
Go.
To break faith with me is
to break faith with Him.
- Get me Cezar!
- Yes, Your Grace.
This sword has been in my
family for 5 generations.
It has never known
defeat, until now.
This jewel represents
my family name.
This one is our alliance with
the Holy Church in Rome.
This one… was my father's...
from the Crusades.
And this...
Sir, you don't think that I took that one...
This is mine to fill.
Each generation is called
upon to follow its own quest.
And what is your quest?
I must kill a man.
Tell me, does this walking
corpse have a name?
His Grace...
the Bishop of Aquila.
The Bishop... I see.
Well, then you have much to do.
And I've already been
enough of a burden to you.
I do hope our paths cross again one day.
I need you to guide me into the city.
Not for the life of my mother!
Even if I knew who she was..
You're the only one who has
ever escaped from there.
It was chance, pure chance, a miracle.
Once in a life time.
I fell down a hole and followed my nose.
I have waited almost 2 years
for a sign from God.
So when I heard the
warning bells of Aquila...
I knew the moment of my destiny has
come. You will be my guiding angel.
Me?
Sir, the truth is, I talk to God all the time,
and no offense, but he never mentioned you.
No?
There are strange forces
at work in your life.
Magical ones that surround you.
I don't understand them,
but they frighten me.
You have given me my life.
The truth is, I can never repay you.
I have no honor, and never will have.
I don't think that you'd kill
me for being what I am.
But, better that then to return to Aquila.
I'll gather some wood for the fire.
- Got you.
- Miss?
My lady, up here.
Oh, damn.
Do you remember me?
What are you doing up there?
What am I doing? Well, yes,
you might ask that.
The Bishop's guards.
A dozen of them,
we had a terrible fight.
- Why didn't they kill you.
- Why didn't they?..
It's a good question,
I asked them that myself.
- And?..
- And?
And what did they say?
They said that... that they prefer
to leave that honor to the Bishop.
They're coming back.
- They are, are they?
- Please, my lady?
A giant owl examined me
closely not one minute ago.
Please?
You're very kind.
Listen,..
Thank you very much, my lady. Tell the
Captain he ties a wicked knot!
He's gonna kill me.
Good morning!
Let's go find Phillipe.
Well, well.
Long way from the
sewers, little rat.
This time, the drinks are on me.
- Where is Navarre?
- Navarre? Navarre?
Oh, yes, yes, big man,
black horse.
I saw him riding
south, toward Aquila.
Then we ride north, sir.
It's not polite to assume that somebody
is a liar when you've only just met him.
Yet you knew we would.
We ride south. Toward Aquila.
I told the truth, Lord!
How can I learn any moral lessons,
when you keep confusing me like this?
Hawke!
No.
Easy, you'll be all right.
Get me a piece of cloth
from my saddlebag!
Easy, don't be afraid, it's all right.
It's all right.
Thanks.
You'll be all right.
You will be fine.
You'll live.
Take her, find help.
- Me, sir?
- You're the only one I have.
- But sir, the hawk is done for.
- Don't you say that!
Follow this road.
You'll find a ruined castle.
There's a monk named Imperious. Give
him the hawk. He will know what to do.
- Sir, I don't think you understand...
- Get on my horse.
You're the only one who can ride him.
You will do what I tell you.
Get on my horse, now!
Careful.
And know this...
if you fail, I will follow
you the length of my days.
And I will find you.
Go.
There it is, see? The castle.
We'll be there soon.
Ah! Well, well, that's
gratitude for you!
All right, let this Imperious watch you die.
I've got my own life to look after!
Please.
Hello!
Hello up there!
For pitty sake, hello!
Hello, hello!
What do you want down there?
- I was told to bring you this bird. It's been wounded.
- Oh, good shot!
- Bring her in, we'll dine together.
- We can't eat this bird.
Oh, why not... Oh, God,
is it lent again already?!
This is no ordinary hawk, Father.
It belongs to a man named Navarre.
Mother of God! Bring her in,
bring her in!
Stay.
Good bird.
Up here, boy! Hurry.
Hurry!
Hurry! Here, up here.
This way.
Now, careful. Walk on the left side.
On the left.
There.
Gently...
Gently.
Now, leave us.
- Can I help?
- Go out, boy.
Don't be frightened.
Navarre was right.
I know what to do.
We must wait a little.
Now, then, where is it?
Oh, yes, there we are.
Now, what we're gonna need?
Some tarragon, rosemary,
wood for the fire...
It's late. Time, I need time.
Now, there, that's it...
Navarre, is he?..
He's fine.
He's just fine, my lady.
There was a terrible battle.
Navarre fought like a lion.
The hawk...
The hawk was struck.
- You know that, don't you?
- Yes.
Are you flesh?
Or are you spirit?
I am sorrow.
How?
Now, get out.
Get out.
This time, stay out!
Ready?
Forgive me, Your Grace.
Cezar has arrived.
It's him, isn't it?
- The wolf, somehow, it's him.
- Drink, forget!
An hour ago you were drunk,
and you remembered.
- What do they call you, boy?
- Phillipe Gaston.
Her name is Isabeau D'Anjou.
Her father was the count D'Anjou,
an ill-tempered fellow.
He died slaying Saracens in Antioch.
She came to live, with her cousin
I think it was, in Aquila.
I shall never forget the first time
I saw her. It was like looking at...
The face of love.
Ah, you too?
Well, I suppose we were all in
love with her in different ways.
Even His Grace, the Bishop,
couldn't think of nothing else.
The Bishop loved her?!
As near as that evil
man could come to it.
His passion was a sort of madness.
He was a man possessed!
But Isabeau sensed his wickedness,
and she shrank from him.
She sent back all his letters
and left his poems unread.
Her heart was already
lost, you see...
to the Captain of the Guard.
Etienne Navarre!
The Bishop knew nothing
about their love.
But every day he saw it grow
stronger and deeper and richer.
Until...
Until?
They were betrayed.
They shared the same confessor,
a weak, foolish priest.
On one day, on a drunken confession to
his superior, he committed a mortal sin.
He revealed the lovers' secret
vows to the Bishop.
The old fool didn't realize
what he had done at first...
or the terrible revenge
the Bishop would exact.
His Grace seemed to go mad, he lost
both his sanctity and his reason.
He swore, that if he could not
have her, no man would.
So, Navarre and Isabeau
fled from Aquila.
The Bishop followed, ever more ardent,
ever more persistent than a hound.
An evil man, a powerful
man, hated and feared;
Rejected even by Rome itself.
He called upon the
powers of darkness...
for the means to
damn the lovers.
In his fury and frustration,
he struck a dreadful bargain...
with the Evil One
The dark powers of hell...
spat up a terrible curse,
and you have seen it working.
By day, Isabeau is the beautiful
bird you brought to me.
And by night, as you
have already guessed...
the voice of the wolf that we hear...
is the cry of Navarre.
Poor dumb creatures, with no memory of
the half-life of their human existence
never touching in the flesh.
Only the anguish of a split
second at sunrise and sunset...
when they can almost touch...
but not.
always together... eternally apart...
As long as the sun rises and sets,
as long as there is day and night
and for as long as they both shall live.
You have stumbled onto a
tragic story, Phillipe Gaston.
And now, whether you like it or not...
you are lost in it, with the rest of us.
Useless.
All of them.
My traps are full.
I can't kill every wolf that lives. Since the
plague there are more wolves then men.
And there is a woman.
Your Grace?
A beautiful woman...
with alabaster skin, and
the eyes of a dove.
She travels by night, only by
night. Her sun is the moon.
And her name is...
Isabeau.
Find her, and you find the wolf.
The wolf I want.
The wolf who...
loves her.
A black wolf.
Isabeau.
Don't...
You might start bleeding again.
Tell me your name.
Most people call me
Phillipe "The Mouse"
You travel with him, don't you?
Yes.
"You must save this hawk",
he said.
"For she is my life, my last
and best reason for living".
And then he said:
"One day we will know such happiness...
as 2 people dream of, but never do".
He said that?
I swear it on my life.
- Does she know?
- What?
That you are the priest
that betrayed them.
The Lord has declared
an end to it at last.
He has given me the knowledge
to undo what I have done.
After 2 years, he has brought
us back together again.
Make yourself clear, if you can.
I have found a way
to break the curse...
and a time for Navarre
to confront the Bishop...
and to begin his own true life again.
He intends to confront the Bishop, to kill
him with the sword of his ancestors.
No, he mustn't do that! He can't! If he kills
the Bishop, the curse can never be broken!
Look after Isabeau, boy!
Go, quickly!
Open up the door, in the name of
His Holiness the Bishop of Aquila!
Ah, away with you! This is a
house of God, not a brothel!
I said, open up, in the
name of the Bishop!
I've met the Bishop, you blasphemous
lout! And you look nothing like him!
- Break it in!
- Yes, sir.
Left side, left side.
Come On!
My lady.
Come with me.
- What is it?
- Don't talk, come with me.
Sorry!
I am a monk, not an architect!
Move it in here!
In here, my lady.
This way, my son, straight
to the big main doors.
And don't forget...
walk on the left side.
Careful...
Go back, back inside.
- I Got you!
- He got me...
My boot!
- Phillipe, it's me they're after!
- Don't flatter yourself.
Hold me!
I'm slipping!
No!!!
You!
- Where is the woman?
- She flew away!
- Where is she?!
- God's truth, she flew away!
It always pays to say the truth, my Lord.
Thank you. I see that now.
I thought you might have
been dead, old man.
There were times I wanted
to kill you myself.
But I'm very grateful... for this.
It is I who should be grateful
to have the chance ...
to redeem myself, and to
save you and Isabeau.
Because the Lord has told me,
how the curse may be broken.
You have betrayed us
once, I warn you.
3 days hence, the Bishop will hear
confessions from the clergy...
in the cathedral in Aquila.
All you have to do is to confront him,
both of you, as man and woman...
in the flesh...
and the curse will be confounded...
broken. And both of
you will be free!
- Impossible.
- As long as there is night and day, no.
But 3 days hence, in Aquila,
there will be a day without a night...
and a night without a day.
Go back inside, old man,
go back to your drink.
You think that I'm drunk?!
I swear to you!
God has shown me!
He has forgiven me!
He hasn't forgiven you.
He's made you mad.
Sir, sir!
It's all right, Father.
Sir...
Sir.
How's your shoulder?
- I'm in your debt.
- Me? Sir, no, no, not at all.
She wanted me to
deliver a message....
to say, that she still has
hope, faith in you..
- You're free to go.
- I know that, sir.
- Do as you like.
- Yes, sir
And you and Ladyhawke will be
going on to Aquila?
Ladyhawke?
Yes.
Well, it just so happens, I'm heading
in that general direction myself.
Really?
Then you better grab your
things, I'm leaving now.
Right.
Ladyhawke.
Imperious, I'm leaving with
the Captain, follow us.
But if the old man is right
about breaking the curse...
if you and Isabeau could face the
Bishop together as man and woman...
You will not mention this again.
Not to me, not to her!
Understood?
Abraham, will you get a move on?
It looks like a big one, Captain.
We're gonna get soaked.
Find shelter.
- The sun is going down.
- How can you tell?
After so many sunsets?
Take care of Ladyhawke.
Tell her I love her.
Are you hungry?
Do you understand me, Ladyhawke?
You're my favorite thing
for dinner, hawk.
I've eaten thousands of them.
I used to kill one every night.
Serves me right for getting
involved in this nightmare.
Nightmare? Daymare...
And then "a night without day,
a day without night..."
What's that supposed to mean?
Makes about as much sense
as the rest of it.
Sun sets.
I'll wait outside.
Hold on for a minute.
I can't vouch for the fit.
Take you time, my lady.
Miss?
My lady?
I'm coming in!
Miss?
It's me, remember?
- You?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
- How is he?
- He's alive, like you.
He's full of hope, like you.
He left you in my charge.
He said, "tell her that we speak as one, and
she will follow your instructions as my own".
Really?
No, don't swear.
Good evening, Goliath.
He's taking us back
to Aquila, isn't he?
Well, what do you instruct?
I instruct you to sit
by a warm fire...
to drink a cup of sweet wine...
and to listen to bright
music cheerfully played.
Perhaps even dance.
Shall we, my lady? Dance?
- Now?
- Practice.
It has been a long time, Phillipe.
I'll have my cup of
sweet wine now.
All right.
So, you intend to by my protector
as well, eh? I'm flattered.
Actually, the truth is,
he'll kill me if I lose it.
I had to steel your dress.
You stole my dress?
Isabeau. Isabeau!
Isabeau? Isabeau...
- Get inside!
- No!
If you lay one hand on her, you will
find it on the ground next to your head!
- Now, ride on!
- Easy, little man, you're frightening me.
Are you deaf? Ride on!
Turn around, and you're dead!
What a terrible night.
Isabeau...
Isabeau!
He'll kill me.
He'll kill me!
Show yourself, coward!
My beautiful.
Navarre...
A black wolf...
Will you get on, Abraham?
Go faster, it's going
to snow soon.
Good morning.
Oh... Good morning
You look a little pale,
I got you something to eat.
What a night...
What happened?
Ah... Oh, nothing I couldn't handle,
Captain.
It's a good little hawk, nice bird.
Go on now, go to your master.
- Go on, Ladyhawke.
- Last night...
Captain?
- Tell me about it.
- What's to tell?
Go on now, go on, go...
- We ran in a bit of trouble on the way to an inn.
- You took Isabeau to an inn?!
First we had to go to a stable.
Fly to your master, fly to the one you love.
- What did you do in a stable?
- We changed clothes.
What!?
- Not together, of course!
- Did you leave her alone?!
- No!
- So you did change together!..
No, no, no! Take her, take her.
She is the most wonderful
woman that ever lived...
and I can't say I haven't
had my fantasies
but the truth is, all she
did was talk about you.
Every moment you spend with her...
I envy you..
But you can tell me.
Tell me everything she said.
And I warn you, I will know
if the words are hers.
She was sad at first.
She talked about the day you
met, and she cursed it.
But then I saw her...
remember how happy you were together...
before the Bishop's curse.
And her eyes glowed.
No, she glowed.
She loves you more than life,
Captain. She's had to.
Did you know that hawks and
wolves mate for life?
Yeah... The Bishop didn't
even leave us that.
Not even that.
On your way to kill His Grace?
Why won't you listen to me?
In 2 days time...
you can face the Bishop in the
cathedral with Isabeau by your side...
and break the curse.
I will be in Aquila tomorrow.
And in one way or another,
there will finally be an end to it.
One day more or less,
what can it matter?
You too?
I warned you.
- Stay here then with the old man.
- No, I'm going with you.
How can you get inside
the cathedral without me?
I will get in without your help.
Thank you for trying, Phillipe,
and for standing up for the truth.
I should have known better.
Every happy moment in my
life has come from lying.
There you are, little Mouse.
Where is my knife?
- Isabeau?
- I just had it, now what have I done with it?
Isabeau, this may be
our last evening together.
- Why?
- I didn't want to tell you until I believed.
I mean, really believed.
- Really believed what, Phillipe?
- I think we can break the curse.
We have a plan.
- You and Navarre?
- No.
Must you keep punching
me in the liver?!
Imperious...
this hole isn't big enough
for the two of us.
Well, let's hope it's
big enough for the wolf.
Ah! What are you doing?!
When you kneel before the altar,
how do you get up again?
You sacrilegious young imp!
you... Push, blast yah!
Come on, again! And again!
He's coming, he's coming!
Phillipe!
My lady, my lady! We are
just covering the trap.
All right, hurry!
He's coming across the ice.
- Wait, my lady!
- Phillipe, help me!
The ice will break,
lie down, lie down!
He can't get out!
Wait!
Wait, my lady!
Oh, God, Phillipe, I can't...
I'm coming.
Hurry, we'll lose him!
He's heavy.
He's slipping.
Hold him.
Be careful!
Isabeau...
Hurry up!
Phillipe!
Push, push, push!
It's all right.
Hold on!
Hold on, boy!
We must live, Father.
As human beings.
Our lives are in your hands now.
Tell me one thing. Where is
my father's sword?
It's gone.
It fell through the ice last
night, crossing the river.
Damn you!
- That sword was the last bit of honor I possessed!
- There is no mission of honor now.
The jewel you wished to place in your sword has
become a symbol of your meaningless death!
But there is a chance for life now.
A new life with her!
- I needed that sword to kill the Bishop!
- Navarre, listen to him!
- Damn you!
- Go ahead!
Kill yourself, kill her too! You never cared
about her as much as yourself anyway!
What is that?
It happened last night,
when he saved your life!
Forgive me.
I'll show you idiots
how to cage a wolf.
Remember, the groove
inside the north wall.
Open the gate.
We have come a full circle, Lord.
I would like to think there is some
higher meaning in all of this.
It certainly would reflect well on you.
Go on here, come on...
Hold!
What have we here, Holy Father?
A surprise present, eh... my son,...
for His Grace the Bishop, from...
From the people of my parish.
A fine pelt for his wall.
And what have we here?
I've never had the pleasure
of killing a wolf before.
How strange, it's exactly
what the Bishop said.
I'm sure he will understand you
depriving him of that pleasure.
he's a very forgiving sort of man.
Very well, pass on.
Wisdom is beyond price, my son.
Be grateful that you have it.
Clear the post!
Your Grace.
And I am ready.
It should be soon now,
once the clouds break.
It's day, old man.
Like it was yesterday, like
it will be tomorrow.
Oh, no...
Damn.
- What's the matter?
- Rats!
Rats?! Here?!
Scandalous.
There's no time left.
The mass will be over soon.
I cannot wait for you now.
If Phillipe has done his job, I can
kill the Bishop now or never.
No, Etienne, this chance
will never come again!
You're right.
If the service ends peacefully...
the cathedral bells begin to toll...
and you will know I have failed.
But Isabeau...
I...
beg you take her life...
quick and painless.
I can't do that!
Yes you can! I beg you.
The cruelty would be to damn her to a half-life
like this, that is not what she wants.
I couldn't do it.
Have you ever considered that
this is what God intended all along?
As the one who was once your Captain...
and through God's grace will be
once again, I ask you to let me pass.
Captain Navarre...
I have my orders...
Come on, open! Damn it!
Open!
Come on...
Come on. Come on!
Navarre!
Oh, thank you, Lord.
A night without a day...
and a day without a night...
Dear Lord, go with him, be with him.
Imperious, wait!
Stop!
You're dead.
Imperious...
make it quick.
God, forgive me.
But kill me, Navarre...
and the curse will go on forever.
You must think of Isabeau.
Isabeau...
is dead.
Damn you.
- Damn you to hell.
- Navarre?
Look!
Look at her!
Look at me.
Now, look at us.
Look at us!
It's over. It's broken.
No man shall!..
Navarre!
Oh, my God!
Isabeau...
You've cut your hair.
I love you...
- Isabeau.
- Navarre.
You two!
Come here.
May God's blessings...
be with you both, from
this day forward.
I bless the day he brought
you back to us, father.
And you. And you...
You're the truest friend
we could ever have.
Thank you.
I fully intend to meet you at the pearly gates,
little thief. Don't you dare disappoint me!
I'll meet you there, father.
Even if I'd have to pick the lock.
Isabeau!
I love you! I love you!