CAPOTE
by NCC@
Hello?
Nancy?
exactly.
But at least
be honest about the facts.
That's what I’m saying.
Who's honest?
I'm honest.
Uh-huh.
I am honest about
what I write about.
I... I’ll let you know
if it's autobiographical,
or if it's about me,
or if it's not.
And I find
autobiographical stories
at this juncture of my life
to be quite boring.
...say I’m one thing,
but actually you're another thing.
I think being true
to who you are is important.
I'm not saying you need to
be psychoanalytical
about the whole mess.
But don't be afraid.
Yeah, I...
but don't be afraid.
I had... I had lunch
with Jimmy Baldwin
the other day.
How is he?
He's a lovely man.
And he told me
the plot of his new book.
And he said to me,
"but I just want to make sure
it's not one of those
problem novels."
And I said, "Jimmy,
"your novel's about
a negro homosexual
who's in love with a Jew.
Well, wouldn't you call that
a problem?"
And he... and he looked at
and he laughed
because he knew I was right.
I'm saying, you know,
if you're gonna write
something like that,
at least be honest
why you're writing it.
Can't we just be honest?
Well, I don't think
you actually
need to be honest.
But don't come asking
some white man from the south
whether your book
about a black man
fucking some Jew,
when they're both
of the same sex,
is an issue!
Don't ask me that!
"Oh, no,
it's not an issue, Jimmy.
Everyone's gonna be-be-be
quite pleased
with that topic."
So how about you, Truman?
Do you admit it?
Well, I’m not nearly
that controversial.
I'm not! I'm not! I am not.
I'm not nearly
that controversial.
Oh, come on.
Hi. It's Truman
for William Shawn, please.
Have you read the, uh,
the article
about the killings in Kansas
in the front section
of the New York times?
Well, I think that's what
I want to write about.
I... I want to go tonight.
I figured you'd missed it.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
I thought I was
heading to Kansas by myself.
God,
I’m glad you agreed to come.
You're the only one I know
with the qualifications
to be both a research assistant
and a personal bodyguard.
Thank you.
Now I’m nervous.
Yes?
Mr. Truman Capote
and miss Nelle Harper Lee?
That's us.
Where would you like
these, sir?
You can put that right the
between the doors.
What all did you bring?
Just a few things.
Thank you greatly, sir.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Um...
it's an honor
to have you with us, sir,
and I hope
you won't mind me saying,
but I thought
your last book was
even better than the first.
Thank you.
I mean, just when you think
they've gotten as good
as they can get.
Thank you very much.
Ma'am.
You're pathetic.
What?
You paid him to say that.
How did you know?
"Just when you think
they've gotten as
good as they can get"?
I thought that
was a good line.
Do you think
that was too much?
Yeah, a little bit.
Your keys.
Thank you.
Sign here, please.
Alvin Dewey,
Kansas bureau
of investigation.
K.B.I.
Hi. I'm looking
for Alvin Dewey.
Hi.
Mr. Dewey.
Truman Capote,
from the New Yorker.
Bergdorf's.
Sorry?
The scarf.
Oh. Nice.
Thank you.
Mr. Dewey, I wonder
when we could
arrange an interview,
some time to talk.
Uh, about what?
Well, we're not looking
for any inside information.
You know, I don't care
one way or another
if you catch
whoever did this.
I'm writing an article
on how the clutter killings
are affecting the town.
You know,
how you all are bearing up.
I care.
Excuse me?
I care a great deal
if we catch whoever did this.
Oh, I see.
As do a lot of folks
around here.
Oh, of course.
Do you have press credentials?
What's a New Yorker?
Magazine.
Magazines don't give out...
you can come to
the news conference
with the rest of them.
Sears, roebuck.
The boy was 16?
He was 15.
Uh, Nancy was 16.
And it's her friend
that found them?
Uh, Laura Kinney.
Can you spell that?
Uh, I... I assume you're ok
with the Laura part.
K-I-N-N-E-Y.
But, uh, please, leave her be.
There's talk
of a bunch of Mexicans.
A whole bunch of Mexicans.
Hello, George.
It's good to see you again.
Uh, I do have an opinion
whether this was
the work of one man
or "a whole bunch,"
as you said,
but it doesn't
matter a whole lot
whether it was Mexicans
or Methodists or Eskimos.
We're gonna find
whoever did this.
Now, 4 good people
from our community are dead.
So let's remember that.
The west Kansas farm committee
is offering a $1,000 reward
for information
leading to an arrest.
Please print that.
And thank you all for coming.
He was... he was foxy
with that old man.
Hmm.
This make you miss Alabama?
Not even a little bit.
You lie.
I don't lie.
Good morning.
Hi.
Can any of you tell me
where I’d find Laura Kinney?
Is that her? With the boy?
Yeah, with Danny burke.
Danny burke?
Laura?
Thank you.
Truman.
I'm gonna find out
where that girl lives.
Can I do that alone?
All right?
Ok.
I think I scared a friend
of yours this morning.
She came looking for you
when I was writing.
You hate my friends.
No, I wouldn't say "hate."
Just as long as they don't
knock on my door.
I saw the bodies today.
Which?
The clutters.
I... I looked
inside the coffins.
That's horrifying.
It comforts me.
Something so horrifying...
it's, uh,
it's a relief.
Normal life falls away.
But then, I was never
much for normal life.
No.
Yeah, people here
won't talk to me.
They, uh, hmm,
they want someone like you,
like, uh, like Nelle.
Me, they hate.
I can't think of
a single quality
I share with Nelle.
Weli...
maybe manliness.
Good morning, Henry.
Good morning, sir.
Let's go.
Bye.
Hi, Danny. I'm Harper Lee.
Nancy was your best friend?
Yeah, she was my best friend.
How has Danny been?
Pretty shattered.
Nothing terrible has ever
happened to him before.
Danny was the last one
at the house that night.
That's why Mr. Dewey
keeps interviewing him.
They don't think that he had
anything to do with it.
It's just to see
if he remembers
anything unusual.
People in town do seem
to wonder if he was involved.
Yeah. That's been
really hard for Danny.
Oh, it's the hardest
when someone
has a notion about you
and it's impossible
to convince them otherwise.
Ever since I was a child,
folks have thought
they had me pegged
because of the way I...
the way I am.
You know, the way I talk.
And they're always wrong.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
I wanna show you something.
Maybe this will give you,
um, a better picture
of what happened.
Oh...
what is this?
It's your diary.
"Danny here tonight
and we watched TV.
"So nice just
having him sit with us.
"Left at 11:00.
P.s. He's the only one
I really love."
And that was that.
Did Laura say "shattered"?
Uh, "pretty shattered.
Nothing terrible has ever
happened to him before."
You know I have 94% recall
of all conversations?
94%?
I've tested myself.
Hmm.
Weli...
how did that happen?
Apparently
detective Foxy's wife,
uh, has read fiction.
That's great.
We're in.
We are in.
In.
You came.
Hi.
Thank you for having us.
Thank you.
Get yourselves in here.
Alvin, get your pants on.
They're here.
Hey, little Deweys.
Hi.
Shake it with your wrist.
Use your whole arm.
More.
You think I’m kidding around,
but I’m serious.
Mama would've put in
half the bottle.
She had to buy it
by the crate.
Alvin's gonna hate this.
I have to stop.
Oh, I cannot believe
you're from New Orleans.
I miss it so much.
Well, I only lived there
for a short while,
but my mama
was born and bred.
You know something?
Alvin pretends
he doesn't know who you are,
but the minute
you came to town,
he read your books.
No!
He had one of his men pick up
breakfast at tiffany's
in Kansas city
'cause it's banned
in the library here.
And he said, "I feel
like you're spiting me."
I said... I said,
"do you think I took
this job to spite you?"
I was writing the script
as they were filming,
all that time in Italy
and I’d work like mad
all day long
and then dash down to the ba
around midnight
to hand in
the next day's scenes.
And Humphrey had just about
moved into the hotel bar...
Humphrey Bogart.
...where he and john...
john Huston.
...had, uh...
they drank every night.
And I mean drank,
you know, like
famished water buffaloes.
Weli...
I’d only just handed them
the final scene
when the bellhop told
me I had a phone call.
And it was my stepfather,
Joe Capote,
calling to say
that my mother had died.
I... I flew home to New York,
terribly distraught...
but when I got
to the apartment,
I could see
that Joe was in even
worse shape than I was.
He grabbed my hand
and he said to me,
"talk.
Talk about anything.
"You know?
"I mean,
any subject in the world.
"Don't worry whether
it'll interest me or not.
"Just talk...
so I won't break down."
He couldn't bear to be alone
with his thoughts.
It was too painful.
It's been a hard
couple of weeks for Alvin.
He and herb clutter
were good friends from church.
Oh, Marie.
Oh, come on, Alvin.
These are good people.
Why would they put a pillow
under the boy's head
just to shoot him?
Why would they tuck Nancy in?
So many of my friends
would love to meet you.
Oh, that'd be fine.
You don't have to worry,
'cause I’m not going
to write about this
till everything's over.
Well, I’m not worried.
I know what room
you're in at the hotel,
and I know where you live
in Brooklyn.
oh, god.
You're celebrating.
Uh, well,
remember Nelle's manuscript
she sent me in New York?
Yeah. Mockingbird.
Killing a mockingbird.
You said it was good.
And I was right.
She just heard Lippincott
wants to publish it.
Well, Jesus.
Jesus, well,
that's... that's terrific.
Tell her
congratulations from me.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Jealous.
Will you be home
by Christmas?
I... I wanna come home.
I wanna come home.
I do. I just...
thought if they catch
whoever did this,
who knows what?
I'll probably be here
till next Christmas.
I'm gonna let you go.
I... I, uh...
no, don't go. Um,
we'll go away
next spring to write.
Maybe Spain.
Yeah.
Ok, I’m gonna let you go.
Jack...
Jack, I promise.
Mm-hmm.
We'll go away
this spring to write.
Maybe Spain.
Ok.
All right.
My wife worked there, too.
What did she do in the house?
Cleaning.
Cooking a little bit.
Quiet, quiet. Quiet, quiet.
"Girdle up. No extra bulges.
"If you're dressed right,
when he gets home,
"the rest of the evening
should be smooth sailing.
Bon voyage, gals."
I can't believe
you got that whole page.
I only read it once.
I've tested my...
tested myself.
I have 94%...
percent recall.
Cut that out.
Cut that...
Cut...
cut that out.
Isn't that something, Alvin?
Oh, it's impressive.
Thank you.
I'm sorry. He's upset.
What's he upset about?
They know who did it.
2 men.
You know, they passed
through Kansas city last week
writing bad checks.
By the time
Alvin's boys got up there,
they were gone.
Skipped out.
Oh!
Yeah. They... they don't know
where.
No idea.
One of them had a cellmate
who gave him up
for the $1,000 reward.
Do they know
the name of the cellmate?
No. No, I don't know.
Alvin knows.
I guess this isn't
the appropriate time
to go ask him.
He's beside himself.
Hello?
Alvin, get in here.
Dad, it's the telephone.
Not now, Alvin.
God damn it.
Get over here.
Dad!
Alvin, not now.
Sit.
Dad? Dad?
You need to call
the chief of police
in Las Vegas.
Alvin, what'd you say?
He said you need to
call them immediately.
Truman Capote.
Dorothy Sanderson.
I figured you'd be
left alone this morning
by that hardworking
husband of yours,
so I have breakfast,
and I have news,
and I have literature.
My friend, Jack, mailed me
that book you wanted
and I inscribed it myself.
"To the maiden of the midwest,
the priestess of the plains,
the queen of the kitchen,
my first novel. Truman."
You're too much. Come on in.
Oh, thank you.
Go into the living room.
Have a seat.
Let me get that.
It's been ringing all morning.
Hello?
Truman, I meant in here.
That's the women's cell.
It's hardly ever used,
but they wanted them separate.
Let's sit in the living room.
They put you
in the women's cell.
Do you have any aspirin?
My legs.
Truman?
Please.
I'm sorry.
In the matter of
the state of Kansas.
Richard Eugene Hickock
and Perry Edward Smith,
this court has been informed
by counsel, Mr. Weeks,
that the defendants
wish to waive their right
to a preliminary hearing.
His mind is somewhere else.
Mr. Hickock,
is that your wish?
Yes, sir.
Why are they doing that?
Mr. Smith.
I... I ask that
the waiver be effectuated.
"Effectuated"?
So noted.
Remove the prisoners.
Was it your choice
to waive the hearing?
Do you still need some?
Give me your hand.
I could kill you
if you got too close.
Now, would you
like some water,
or...
Mrs. Sanderson
lent you my book.
He said we'd curry
favor with the judge
if we waived our rights.
Who did?
The lawyer.
Your picture's undignified.
People recall
first impressions.
Oh,
what's been your
first impression?
Hello.
Mr. Shawn.
Truman.
I'm writing a book.
It... it's too much
for a single article.
This town, the...
the killers most of all.
Uh, you will be stunned
by Perry Smith.
Why, what's happening?
Well, not much yet,
but I know.
I... I can sense him.
He... he's desperately lonely,
uh, frightened.
I have a question.
Are you ready?
Would it matter?
Uh, no.
How much more money
can you send me?
And... and how quickly
could you get Dick Avedon
out here to take
some pictures?
Who are you smiling at
right now?
I'm smilin' at you.
You know,
Dick's a very famous
fashion photographer.
World-famous.
Am I gonna be
in a fashion magazine?
So there's no worry
of having a bad picture.
Who were you closer to,
your mom or your dad?
What's that?
Who were you closer to,
your mom or your dad?
Well, both.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Have you talked to them?
Who'd you talk to first?
Perry, honey,
you look terrific, baby.
That was good.
Can you show us the tattoo
on your chest then?
Yeah.
Where did Perry
get the art set?
Members of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
Yes, sir.
Defendants, rise.
Perry Edward Smith
and Richard Eugene Hickock,
you stand accused
of 4 counts of the crime
of murder in the first degree.
Have you reached
a unanimous verdict?
We have, your honor.
What is your verdict?
Guilty on all 4 counts.
Have you unanimously
reached a sentence?
We have, your honor.
What is the sentence?
Death.
I need to see him
before we go.
Perry.
They're going to transfer you
up to lansing today.
And you'll have to make sure
to put me
on the visitors list.
Otherwise I can't see you.
I'm going to help
find you a proper lawyer.
You need a serious lawyer
for an appeal.
Now they took Dick last night.
And I need you to get him
to do the same thing
and just put me
on the visitors list.
And I thought,
"where does the family eat?"
You know?
I mean, does he,
like, reach his hand
through the bars
and have dinner with everyone
around the table?
Nelle, kudos on, um...
kill the bird, is it?
That's... that's close.
Thank you.
That's marvelous.
Who's your publisher?
Lippincott.
Yes. It's a children's book
right?
Yes.
No, no. It's...
it's about children.
Yes.
Yes, I’ve heard
a lot about it.
Good.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I didn't even know
she wrote.
He's sad and he's shy.
And he's terrified.
They shotgunned
the entire family
in the face.
And I thought, at first,
"mmm, I’m gonna be
scared of these men.
I'm gonna run,
run, run right home."
Actually, the brother
in the family...
Kenyon is his name,
they had placed a pillow
under his head,
and then shot him
point-blank in the face.
Almost as if they were
putting him to sleep
and then shot him.
This is the start of
a great love affair.
Yeah. Truman
in love with Truman.
The book I’m writing
will return him
to the realm of humanity.
It's the book I was
always meant to write.
Well, he hasn't actually
written a word of it yet,
but he says
it's the nonfiction book
of the decade,
so...
what have you been doing?
And I’ll tell you,
I was in Marilyn’s
apartment just last week,
talking about movies, art.
Finally I had to
break it to her that
of the 4 matisses
hanging on her wall,
2 were upside down.
Can I have another, please?
To answer your question,
I’m following
breakfast at tiffany's
by blazing a different path.
By inventing an entirely
new kind of writing.
The nonfiction novel.
You have a subject?
Yes.
On the night of November 14,
2 men broke into
a quiet farmhouse in Kansas
and murdered an entire family.
Now, why did they do that?
2 worlds exist
in this country.
The quiet, conservative life,
and the life of those 2 men.
The underbelly.
The criminally violent.
And those worlds converged
that bloody night.
Now, I spent the past 3 months
interviewing
everyone in Kansas
touched by that violence.
Now I spent hours
talking to the killers
and I’ll spend more.
'Cause researching this work
has changed my life.
You know,
it's altered my point of view
about almost everything.
Yeah.
And I think those who read it
will be similarly affected.
So you find them
a new lawyer.
Well, they're facing
execution in 6 weeks.
You know, they need
someone to argue
whether or not that's right.
Ok.
And I’d also like to
see them alive.
Weli...
yeah.
Yeah, I need to
hear their stories.
Well, just be careful
what you do to
get what you want.
I...
I’m finding them a lawyer.
Truman, you're
finding yourself a lawyer.
No, I’m finding them
a lawyer.
There's a difference.
The Warden will see you now.
Well, we do all right
by our boys.
Hmm.
Showers once a week.
Feed them good.
We'll be feeding Perry Smith
in the infirmary soon
if he don't eat.
Try and get the food in
through his arm.
I'm sorry,
what are you talking about?
Well,
he hasn't eaten in a month.
It ain't his right
to kill himself.
It's the right of the people.
The people of this state.
And that's who I work for,
the people.
No one told me.
Yeah, he won't eat.
Uh-huh.
When can I see him?
Well, let me see.
How about you coming 3:00,
Thursday afternoon?
No.
Um...
that's no good.
I...
I need to see them now.
Then... then whenever I want,
for as long as I want.
Well, that's just not
how we do things
around here, Mr. Capote.
Yeah, I understand
what a burden
unlimited visitation might be
on this institution
and on the people
who pay for it.
And I want to be clear
that I don't expect
the citizens
of Leavenworth county
to have to
shoulder that burden.
This is to be dispensed
as you see fit.
You know, I didn't know
where to count your boy
at first,
him being half-Indian.
But I did him a favor.
I counted him as a white man.
Uh-huh. You're a kind
and generous man.
Spread your feet.
This way.
Hey, hey.
Yeah, hello.
Hey,
thanks a lot for your help
with the lawyer.
Oh, that's fine.
Wow, you must be
really desperate for a story
to come all the way out here.
You want to go
see Perry, go ahead.
Thank you.
You want my advice,
though, Mr. Capote,
he's just trying to prove
the insanity defense.
It's ok.
It's Truman.
It's your friend.
It's ok.
This is before she had us.
Before she started drinking.
Who took care of you
as a child?
Orphanage.
Me and Linda.
And that's your sister?
You know,
we're not so different
as you might think.
Yeah, I was abandoned
repeatedly as a child.
My mama would drag me along
to some new town,
so she could take up
with another man she'd met.
Night after night,
she'd lock me
in the hotel room alone.
Mama would turn the latch
and tell the staff
not to let me out
no matter what.
And I was terrified.
And I’d scream my head off...
until finally I’d collapse
on the carpet
next to the door
and I’d fall asleep.
Then after years of this,
she just left me
with relatives in Alabama.
Who raised you up?
My aunts.
And that's where I met Nelle.
And she lived...
she lived next door.
Your mother was Indian?
Cherokee.
So drinking was not
a good thing for her.
No tolerance for it.
We're on, uh, suicide watch.
That's why they leave
the lights on at night.
I hope
we're past that now.
I do.
Be careful of Ricardo.
I think he wants you
all to himself.
All right.
But he's
naturally mendacious.
Not to be trusted.
If he had $100,
he'd steal a stick
of chewing gum.
Perry,
I want to take
your notebooks with me.
I want to read them.
If I leave here
without understanding you,
the world will see you
as a monster
always.
I don't want that.
'Cause he trusts me.
I mean,
that's why he gave it to me.
And he-he's given me
absolutely everything.
And he wants so badly
to be taken seriously
to be held in some esteem.
Do you?
Do I what?
Do you hold him
in esteem, Truman?
Well,
he's a gold mine.
And he's told me
his entire life.
His, uh,
his dead mother.
Uh, he had a brother
and a sister kill themselves.
Awful.
Did you tell him
your mama did the same thing?
See, I can't tell him
everything.
We've been
talking our heads off
for the past month.
And sometimes when I...
when I think how good
my book can be,
I can hardly breathe.
Anyway, th-this is...
this is what I wanted
to read to you.
Uh,
"if called upon
to make a speech..."
to make a speech"?
I mean, this is exactly
what I’m talking about.
A speech, just in case
he's ever recognized
for an achievement.
"I can't remember
what I was going to say
for the life of me.
"I don't think ever
before have so many people
"been so directly responsible
"for my being
so very, very glad.
"It's a wonderful moment
and a rare one.
Thank you!"
There's... there's an
exclamation point at
the end of that "thank you"
in case you didn't catch it.
Where'd you go?
I guess it
stopped being funny.
I... I never said it was.
But, wait,
listen to this.
I was 14.
One day I said to him,
"mom's dead."
I could see it.
A week later we got the news.
She finally drunk
herself...
...found her shivering...
she hit me so many times
with that flashlight,
she broke it.
That night, I...
I dreamed about
that big yellow bird.
Clawed that nun's eyes,
bright like the sun.
Lifted me to the sky.
Sometimes you see a thing
how it really is.
Well, you're nothing
if not hardworking.
Hey, you look good.
Healthy again.
You know, I’ve decided
on a title for my book.
I think you'll like it.
It's very masculine.
In cold blood.
Isn't that good?
And that refers to the crime
or the fact that
you're still talking
to the criminals?
Oh, the former,
among other things.
I see.
I wanted to ask
if you'd let me look
at your investigation notes.
That lawyer you helped find
for your friends
got them a hearing at
the Kansas supreme court...
yeah, I heard this morning.
...on the issue
of inadequate counsel.
Alvin,
I mean,
do you not want me
to look at your notes?
You are permitted to say no.
I'll tell you what.
If those boys get off,
I’m coming to Brooklyn
to hunt you down.
I have to be in court
at 9:00,
but you call Roy Church
and he'll show you
what you want to see.
Thank you.
It's as much for me
as for anyone.
I couldn't bear the thought
of losing you so soon.
We're gonna be able
to use your book
for our case.
You... you'll write
we never got to raise
an insanity plea.
You wrote how terrible
the lawyers was.
I... I haven't written
a word yet.
What have you been doing?
Research. Talking to you.
All right.
I... I had hoped...
wh-what are you calling it?
The book?
I have no idea.
Perry,
if I’m going to
write about you,
if I’m going to determine
how to write about you,
we need to talk about,
you know, why you're here.
And,
you know, the murders,
and that night
at the clutter house.
Do you worry
what I’ll think?
Is that it?
Dick says you know
Elizabeth Taylor.
I know a lot of people.
Perry, I have invitations
to be in morocco, Greece,
and I prefer to be here
with you.
Jack, be patient with me.
I'm just missing
this one piece.
Well, how long
is that gonna take?
Why don't you just
try leaving him alone
for a while?
Come to Spain.
You can always
visit him later.
I don't know.
Well, I’m off.
I'm just... I’ve got
my own writing to do.
Well, do it in Brooklyn.
Wait for me.
There's too many
people around. I've...
I’ll leave the address
on the kitchen table.
Well,
think about what I said,
and join me when you can.
I will.
Ok?
Bye.
Hi.
Truman.
We never intended
on killing that family.
Capote,
will you get that straight
in your book, please?
No premeditation.
What are you doing?
I have to fly back east.
When?
An hour.
I miss you already.
Write me every 5 minutes.
Hey, you know,
we never did intend
on killing that family.
Capote?
What?
Truman,
I’ve not been
able to tear myself
away from your book.
It's that good.
It's... it's not good,
it's astonishing.
This first half
is astonishing.
Oh, thank you.
When will you be done,
do you think?
Yes, I... I’m already
well into the third part.
But I...
I can't finish that
till I convince Perry
to describe the night
of the killings to me.
I was... I was planning
to visit this fall, see?
Then I think you need
to talk to him now.
And we all need to see
how this ends
for the final part.
I... I... I can't finish the book
till I know what happens.
If Perry and Dick
are executed, it's one thing.
And if not, weli...
Truman,
you've got your ending.
I really don't know.
The Kansas court
denied their appeal.
It came over the wire
on Friday.
I mean, you need to
talk to Perry now.
He'll be dead by September.
I mean, I’m sorry.
I know how much you've come
to care about him.
Right. Yes, right.
So I want to set up
a reading for you
in the fall, in New York,
and, uh, well,
we'll build some interest,
and we'll publish
in the fall.
Thank god.
There's nothing in the house.
Why aren't you working?
Well, I knew
you couldn't be counted on
to stock the kitchen.
What are we going to feed
our famous guest?
Oh, Jesus,
I completely forgot.
Plus, I, uh,
finished my novel yesterday.
What?
When was the last time
you wrote to him?
I don't know.
What's this?
It's a letter for Truman
I was asked to deliver.
It's from Perry.
Let's have it.
"Dear friend Truman,
where are you?
"Read this item
in a medical dictionary.
'Death by hanging
is caused by asphyxia,
'by fracture of
the cervical vertebrae,
'by laceration
of the trachea.'
"Not too comforting,
as we lost our appeal.
"Missing you.
"Alone and desirous
of your presence.
Your amigo, Perry."
Mr. Shawn told me
about the court
decision yesterday.
I was wondering why you were
in such a good mood.
That's
a terrible thing to say.
I... I write him all the time
I’ve just...
I’ve been so focused on-
- on the book lately.
So Jack thinks
I’m using Perry,
but he also thinks
I fell in love with him
when I was in Kansas.
Now, how both of those things
can be true is beyond me.
Thank you.
Well, did you?
Did you fall in love
with him?
I don't know
how to answer that.
Truman.
It's as if
Perry and I grew up
in the same house,
and one day he stood up
and went out the back door
while I went out the front.
Are you kidding me?
No.
Listen, you be nice to Jack.
Sometimes I think
he's what I like
about you best.
I'll see you
at the reading in New York.
16th.
Adios.
What was he in jail for?
Well, they said it was
for not paying his taxes,
but really,
for being an outsider.
Refusing to go along.
Lowell, you're being moved.
Why?
You're going to
final holding.
No.
Come on, Lowell.
Open the door.
Stand up.
Put your arms
behind your back.
Ok, last chance.
Well, get up.
Ah!
Turn around.
Put your arms
behind your back.
Now Dick and me,
we're next in line.
I'm so sorry I’ve been away.
It was a long time.
I know.
How's the book coming along?
Oh, very slowly.
Will you show it to me?
I've hardly written anything.
Good evening, New Yorkers,
and thank you for coming
to the first public reading,
the first offering
of any kind,
of Truman Capote's new work,
in cold blood.
Hello.
My name is Truman Capote.
For this...
for this evening's program,
I’m going to read, uh,
some passages
from the first 3 parts
of my new book.
"The village of Holcomb
"stands on
the high wheat plains
of western Kansas,
"a lonesome area
that other Kansans
call 'out there.'
"Until one morning
in mid-November, 1959,
"few Americans,
in fact, few Kansans,
had ever heard of Holcomb.
"Like the waters
of the Arkansas river,
"like the motorists
on the highway,
"exceptional happenings
never stopped there.
"Perry Smith's voice
was both gentle and prim.
"A voice that, though soft,
"manufactured
each sound exactly,
"ejected it like a smoke ring
issuing from
a parson's mouth.
"The 4 coffins,
which quite filled
the small,
flower-crowded parlor
"were to be sealed
at the funeral services,
"very understandably,
"for the effect
was disquieting.
"Nancy wore her dress
of cherry-red velvet,
"her brother
a bright plaid shirt.
"The parents
were more sedately attired,
"Mr. Clutter
in navy-blue flannel,
his wife in navy-blue crepe.
"And it was this especially
that lent the scene
an awful aura,
"the head of each
was completely encased
in cotton.
"A swollen cocoon
"twice the size of
an ordinary blown-up balloon.
"And the cotton,
"because it had been sprayed
with a glossy substance,
"twinkled like
Christmas tree snow.
"One Tuesday at dawn,
a carload of strangers,
"ignorant
of the local disaster,
"were startled
by what they saw
as they crossed the prairies
"and passed through Holcomb.
"Windows ablaze.
"Almost every window
in almost every house,
"and in
the brightly-lit rooms,
fully-clothed people,
"even entire families,
"who had sat
the whole night wide awake
watchful, listening.
"Of what
were they frightened?
It might happen again."
Thank you.
And I slipped
and I ripped a hole
from the bottom
of my scrotum...
All the way
up to the top
of the crack of my ass.
And I sat there.
And I didn't know it.
All I felt was a...
I... I didn't know it.
All I felt was a cool breeze
you know, between my...
Sorry. If I may, uh...
yes.
Your portrait of those men
was terrifying.
Terrifying.
Thank you.
Stop that man!
Come back here!
Dad!
Have any of you
met my father?
He hasn't spanked me
in years.
George didn't come backstage.
He had... he had a...
something that his wife
had to rush him off to.
But he made a point of...
yeah, well, I’m still wal...
I’m still waiting for a call.
It was beautiful.
And everybody came.
Hmm. Tennessee...
everybody came.
Tennessee loved it.
Of course he loved it.
Should we do more?
No, we... we just sit and wait
while people talk about it
and we let them do the work.
I mean,
this... this book is going
to change everything.
It's gonna change
how people see your writing.
I think it's going to Chan
how people write.
Are you gonna be finished
by October?
I think so.
You know, they're scheduled
for next month.
To hang.
Yeah.
We're gonna commit
as many issues
as it takes to publish.
Whatever it takes.
Well, I’m going to Kansas
tomorrow, and...
and I’ll get Perry to talk.
What's he got to lose?
Sorry, but...
hey, this may
sound strange to you,
but I’m going to miss him.
You'll be able to finish now.
Need to check your
papers, sir.
This is what we've been
waiting for.
A stay of execution
to make a federal appeal.
All thanks to you.
Thank you!
They're not gonna
corner me now.
Not unless the U.S.
Government says so.
Kansas has had it in
for me for 10 years.
They can't corner me now.
Mmm-mmm.
Hey, Perry, sit down
for a minute.
I... I need you to talk to me.
We've got all the time
in the world to talk.
I've been
thinking about Ricardo.
You really need
to stop sending him
those trashy books.
I won't even
mention the pornography.
Now, I realize that
Dick probably can't
grasp the literature
that you gave me.
Uh, the books you
send him only...
they only exacerbate
the problem.
They only heighten
or intensify it.
Maybe we can get him
started on a program.
Perry,
I know what
"exacerbate" means.
Ok, well, just thinking...
there... there's not
a word or a sentence
or a concept that you
can illuminate for me.
There is one singular reas
I keep coming here.
Truman.
November 14, 1959.
3 years ago. 3 years.
Hmm?
And that's... that's all
I want to hear from you.
Now I asked you not to. Ever.
This is absurd.
Do you know
what absurd means?
I'm ready.
I have a plane to catch.
I found your sister
in Tacoma.
Maybe she'll talk to me
about something useful.
Please don't go out there.
Hey, this is my work, Perry.
I'm working.
And when you want to tell
what I need to hear,
you let me know.
June's dead.
Frank shot himself.
Now Perry did what he did.
I used to love him.
He was my little doll.
He scares me now.
When was the last time
you saw him?
10 years ago.
10 years.
Could I borrow
one of these pictures?
Take the whole thing.
I don't want them anymore.
Don't be taken in
by my brother.
He's got this sensitive side
he'll show.
You believe he's gentle
and so easily hurt,
but he'd just as soon
kill you as shake your hand.
I believe that.
Hello, handsome.
What's the name of your book?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
"Truman Capote
read last night
before a packed audience
"from his nonfiction
book in cold blood.
"The true-crime novel
tells of killers
Richard Hickock
"and Perry Smith,
who brutally murdered
a Kansas family 3 years ago."
Wait, who sent that to you?
That's not
your goddamn business.
It is my business,
because it's not true.
The organizers of
the reading needed a title.
They picked one,
a sensational one, I admit,
to attract a crowd.
They picked it?
Yes.
It's not your title.
Perry,
I haven't chosen one yet.
How could I choose a title
when we still haven't
talked about that night?
How could I?
I couldn't possibly.
You pretend to be my friend.
I'm sorry.
I should have told you.
And I couldn't pretend
to be your friend
'cause the truth is,
I can't help wanting to be.
You don't have to
tell me anything...
if you don't want to.
I have something
from your sister.
She misses you.
Look at my belly.
There must be
something wrong with us,
to do what we did.
We heard there was
$10,000 in that house.
Once we tied up everybody
and searched all over,
I knew the guy
that told us about it was...
was wrong. There was...
there was no money.
Dick wouldn't believe it
so he went tearing
through the house,
banging on the walls
looking for a safe.
When he was done, he...
said he was gonna go up
to Nancy's room
and have his way with her.
I wouldn't allow it.
And I told him that.
So I sat with her.
Dick came up and got me.
We turned off the lights
and went down to the basement
where Mr. Clutter
and the boy was.
He kept saying,
"no witnesses," but I...
I figured
if I waited him out, he'd...
he'd give up
and we'd leave them
tied up there.
And we'd drive all night.
They'd never find us.
We tied Mr. Clutter's wrists
to a pipe over his head.
And he... he looked hurt,
so I cut him down.
I... I put a box out there
so he'd be more comfortable.
He asked how his wife
and daughter was
and I... I said they were fine,
and they were getting ready
for sleep, and it wouldn't
be long tili...
till morning
when they'd find him.
He was just looking at me.
Looking into my eyes.
Like he expected me
to kill him.
Like he expected me to be
the kind of person
who would kill him.
I was thinking,
"this... this nice man
is scared of me."
I was so ashamed.
I mean, I thought
he was a... a very nice...
gentle man.
And I thought so right up
till I slit his throat.
I didn't know what I did
till I heard the sound.
Added up,
how much money did
you get from the clutters
that night?
Between $40 and $50.
I mean, the truth is,
I’m desperate
to be done with it.
I've spent 4 years of
my life on this book.
They got a stay of executive
yesterday.
Another, yes.
Supreme court.
It's harrowing.
Me, all I want to do is
to write the ending
and there's no end in sight.
No, thank you.
"Dear friend Truman,
"haven't heard from you
in such a long while.
"Please help find new lawyer.
"If not,
Dick will have to write
"the supreme court brief
himself.
"Our last appeal.
"What a pair of
wretched creatures.
"Please help.
Your amigo? Perry."
Just put it with the others.
You know, at least for Nelle
you should...
you should try and pretend
you're having
a good time tonight.
I thought
I’d find you here.
Oh, Nelle.
Nelle.
Thank you.
I'll have another,
please.
How are you?
Terrible.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I mean,
it's torture the way...
what they're doing to me.
And now
it's the supreme court.
And can you believe it?
If they win this appeal,
I wili...
have a complete
nervous breakdown.
I may never recover,
and I’ll just pray
that it turns my way.
It must be difficult.
Oh, it's torture.
They're torturing me.
I see.
And how'd you like the movie,
Truman?
Yeah...
I frankly don't see
what all the fuss is about.
Hello.
Mr. Truman Capote?
Yeah.
I have a call
from Mr. Perry Smith
in the Kansas
correctional system.
Will you accept charges?
Yes.
Mr. Smith,
you're on the line.
Hello.
Hello?
Hello, Perry.
They let me make
a couple of phone calls
before I go down to holding.
Y-y-you heard
the supreme court
rejected the appeal?
No, I... I didn't.
I hadn't heard that.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Yeah. They let me make
2 phone calls.
We got a date set
for the warehouse,
Dick and me.
2 weeks and finito.
April 14.
Will you visit me?
Truman?
It's... it's him again.
It is utterly inappropriate
for me to talk to him.
Yes?
I'm sorry,
he won't be able to make it.
Hello?
Mr. Shawn, it's Nelle.
I just got this telegram.
Has he seen it?
He won't read it.
Would you put him on,
please?
Nelle, he won't talk.
Mr. Shawn,
if you have to hold him down
and put the phone on his ear,
I need to speak to him.
All right.
Um,
um,
it's Nelle.
Truman.
"Miss Nelle Harper Lee
and Truman Capote.
"Sorry that Truman
was unable to make it
here to the prison
"for a brief word
prior to necktie party.
"Whatever his reason
for not showin' up,
"I want him to know
that I cannot
condemn him for it.
"Not much time left,
"but want you both to know
that I’ve been
sincerely grateful
"for your friendship
through the years
"and everything else.
"I'm not very good
at these things.
"I have become
extremely affectionate
toward you both.
"But, harness time.
Adios, amigos.
Your friend, Perry."
Well, I didn't expect
to see you again.
You can visit
for a few minutes.
Yeah.
No.
5 minutes.
Well, well.
He returns.
I don't know
what you must think of me.
Well,
you haven't been foremost
on my mind lately,
as you can probably imagine.
You got the letter?
Yes, I did.
It's true.
I understand why you
didn't want to come.
I wouldn't be here either
if I didn't have to.
You got that right.
You know Ricardo
donated his eyes
to science?
Next week,
some blind man will be seeing
what Dick used to see.
Yeah, you could be
walking in Denver
or somewhere, Truman,
and suddenly these eyes
will be staring at you.
That would be something,
wouldn't it?
It would be. It would be.
You'll be watching?
I don't know, I’ll be...
do you want me to?
I'd like to have
a friend there.
Ok. Then I will.
It's all right.
I did everything I could.
It's ok.
I truly did.
I know.
It's time.
Mr. Capote.
Goodbye.
You're not rid of us yet.
We'll see you
in a few minutes.
I wish I had...
Mr. Capote.
Goodbye.
Nice to see you.
Perry Edward Smith.
For the crime of murder
in the first degree,
by order of the cour
t of Finney county
and the supreme court
of the sovereign state
of Kansas,
you are sentenced
to hang until you die.
"I will fear no evil:
For thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me."
You can say something
if you want.
Is there anybody
from the family here?
No, Perry.
Well, tell them...
I can't remember
what I was gonna
say for the life of me.
Our father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread.
...as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
And lead us not
into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
It was a terrible experience
and I will never get over it.
They're dead, Truman.
You're alive.
And there wasn't anything
I could have done
to save them.
Maybe not,
but, the fact is,
you didn't want to.