Credit to: Sakti Tandi [1st Indonesian-Script]
English. Subs. and. Re-Sync. by npdv-iD
You know there are more people
with genius IQ living in China
than they're people of any
kind living in United States.
That can't be possible be true.
That is.
What would account for that?
First, awful lot people living in China.
But, here's my question.
How do you distinguish yourself than
population of people who
all got 1600 under SAT's?
- I didn't know they take SAT's in China.
- They don't.
I wasn't talkin' about China anymore.
I was talkin' about me.
You got 1600?
Yes. I can sing in a Capella group,
but I can't sing.
Does that mean you
actually got nothing wrong?
I could row crew or invent a 25 dollar PC.
- Or you get into the "Final Club"?
- Or I get into the "Final Club".
You know, from a woman's perspective...
Sometimes, not singing in
a Capella group is a good thing.
This is serious.
On the other hand,
I do like guys who row crew.
Well, I can't do that.
I was kidding.
Yes, I got nothing wrong in test.
Have you ever tried?
I'm trying right now.
To row crew?
Gettin' into "Final Club". To row crew? No!
Are you like... whatever, delusional?
Maybe, sometimes you said 2 things at once,
I'm not sure which one I
suppose to be aiming at...
But you seen guys who row crew, right?
No.
Ok, well, they bigger than me.
They world class athlete.
Like a second ago you said
you like guys who row crew.
So I assumed you've met one.
I guess, I just meant like the idea of it,
you know the way a girl likes cowboys.
Ok.
Should we get something to eat?
Would you like to talk about something else?
No, it just that since the beginning of
the conversation about the "Finals Club"
I think I may have miss a birthday.
There are really more people in
China with genius IQ's than entire...
"Phoenix" is the most diverse.
The "Fry Club", Roosevelt punched the porc.
Which one?
"The Porcellian, the Porc,
it's the best of the best"
Which Roosevelt?
Theodore
Is it true they send a bus
around to pick up the girls?
Who wanna party with next phoenix chairman.
So you can see why it's
so important to get in.
Well, which is the easiest to get into?
Why would you ask me that?
I was just asking.
None of them.
That's the point.
My friend, Eduardo made $300.000
betting oil futures one summer.
And Eduardo won't comes close to get in. The ability
to make money doesn't impress anybody around here.
Must be nice.
He made $300.000 in a summer.
He likes meteorology.
You said it was oil futures.
You can read the weather, you can
predict the price of heating oil.
I think you ask me that because you think
the "Final Club" that's easiest to get into
Is the one, where I'll have the best chance...
What?
You ask me which one is the easiest to get into
Because you think that the one,
where I have the best chance.
The one that the easiest is to get into,
Would be the one where
anybody has the best chance.
You didn't ask me which
one was the best one.
You ask me which one was the easiest one.
I was honestly just asking, ok...
I was just asking to ask...
Mark, I'm not speaking in code.
Erika,
You obsesses with "Finals Clubs"
You have "Finals Clubs"- OCD
You need to see someone about it.
who'll prescribe you some sort of medication
You don't care if the side
effect may include blindness.
"Final Clubs" not "Finals Clubs"
And there's a difference between
being obsessed than being motivated.
Yes, there is.
Well, you do that, it's was cryptic,
so you do speaking code.
I didn't mean to be cryptic.
I'm just saying I need to do something substantial
in order to get the attention of the club.
Why?
Because they're exclusive and fun.
And they lead to the better life.
Teddy Roosevelt didn't get
elected for the president
because he was member from "Phoenix" Club?
He was a member of The
Porcellian, and yes he did.
Why don't you just concentrate
on being the best you, you can be.
Did you really just said that?
I was kidding.
I wanna try to be straight forward
You might wanna be a little more supportive.
If I get in I will be taking you to the events
and the gatherings and will be meeting a
lot of people you won't normally get to meet.
You would do that for me?
We're dating.
Ok, well I wanna try and be straight forward
even let you know that we're not anymore.
What you mean?
We're not dating anymore.
I'm sorry.
This is a joke?
No, it's not.
You're breaking up with me?
You gonna introduce me the people I
wouldn't normally have the chance to meet.
What the f...
- What is that supposed to mean?
- Wait, settle down.
What is it supposed to mean?
Erica, the reason we're able
to sit and drink right now,
because you used to
sleep with the door guy.
"The door guy" his name is Bobby.
I have not slept with "the door guy".
"The door guy" is a friend of mine.
And he's the perfectly good class of people.
And what part of Long Island you from?
Wimbledon?
- Wait
- I'm going back to my dormy.
- Wait, wait is this real?
- Yes.
Ok, than wait, I apologize, ok...
- I have to go study.
- Erika...
- Yes?
- I'm sorry, I meant it.
I appreciate that but
I have to go study.
Come on.
You don't have to study.
Let just talk.
- I can't
- Why?
Because it is exhausting.
Dating you is like dating a stairmaster.
All I meant is that you not likely to...
Currently, I wasn't making
a comment on you're parents.
I was saying that you go to B.U. *Boston University*
I was studying a fact.
That's all.
If it's seem rude,
than of course I've to apologize.
I have to go study.
You don't have to study.
Why you keep saying that
I don't need to study.
Because you go to B.U.
Wanna get some food?
I'm sorry you're not sufficiently
impressed with my educations.
I'm sorry, I don't have a row boat.
- So we're even.
- I think we should just be friend.
I don't want friends.
I was just being polite. I have no
intention of being friends with you...
I'm under some pressure
right now from my OS class.
If could just order some food.
I think we should...
Look, you will probably going to
be very successful computer person.
You gonna go thru life thinking
that girls don't like you,
Because you're a nerd...
I want you know, from the bottom
of my heart that won't be true.
It would be because you are an asshole.
Harvard University, Fall 2003
Kirkland House
Erika Albright's a bitch
You think that's because her family
changed their name from Albrecht?
Or do you think because
all B.U. girls are bitches?
For the record, she may look like a 34C.
But she's getting all kind of help
from our friends at "Victoria's Secret"
She's a 34B, as in
barely anything there.
False Advertising.
The truth is she has a nice face. I need
to do something to take my mind of her.
Easy enough, except I need an idea.
I'm a little intoxicated.
I'm not gonna lie.
So, what if it's not even 10pm
and it's a Tuesday night?
The Kirkland's facebook
is open on my desktop
And somebody of these people with
pretty horrendous facebook pics.
Billy Olsen's sitting here had the idea,
putting some of the picture
next to picture of farm animal,
and have people vote who's hotter.
Good call, Mr. Olsen!
Yeah, it's on.
I'm not gonna do the farm animal but I
like the idea of comparing two people together.
It gives the whole thing a very "Turing" feel since
people's rating of the picture is more implicit...
Than say, choosing a number to represent each
person's hotness like they do on hotornot. com
The first thing we're going
to need is a lot of picture
Unfortunately, Harvard doesn't
keep a public centralized facebook,
So I'm going to get all the images from
the individual houses that people are in,
Let the hacking begin!
First up is Kirkland, they keep everything open
and allow indexes in their Apache configuration,
So a little wget magic is all that's necessary
to download the entire Kirkland facebook.
Kid's stuff.
Next is Eliot. They're also open,
but with no indexes in Apache.
I can run an empty search and it returns all
of the images in the database in a single page.
Then I can save the page and Mozilla will save all
the images for me. Excellent. Moving right along.
Excellent.
Moving right along.
Excuse me, everybody...
You're in one of the oldest, one of the most
exclusive club, not just Harvard but in the world.
Now, I wanna welcome you all, The Phoenix
Club First Party of the fall semester.
Lowell has some security they require
username/password combo.
I'm gonna go ahead and says the don't have an access to main fas user database
So they have no worry detecting an intrusion.
Adams has no security but limit
the number of result to 20 of pages,
All I need to do is to break up some
script I use on Lowell and reset.
Quincy has no online facebook,
what a shame!
Nothing I can do about that.
Dunster is intense not only there's no public
directory but there's no directory at all.
You have to do searches. And if you're search
return more than 20 matches, nothing's get return.
Once you do get result, they
don't link directly to images.
They link to PHP that
redirect to something.
Weird! That's maybe difficult,
I'll come back later.
- Hei, Mark!
- What?
Great one.
Beautiful fish.
Leverett is a little better.
They still make you search.
But you can do an empty search and get
links to pages with every students pictures
I slightly obnoxious that they only
let you view one picture at a time...
There's no way I'm gonna go to 500
pages to download pics one at a time
So it's definitely necessary to break
out emacs and modify that Perl script.
Done.
Hey, what's goin' on?
Perfect timing.
Eduardo is here and he is going
to have the key ingredients
- Hey Mark,
- Eduardo...
You and Erica split up?
How did you know that?
It's on your blog.
Yeah.
Are you alright?
- I need you.
- I'm here for you.
No, I need the algorithm you
use to rank chess players.
Are you ok?
We're ranking girls.
- You mean others student.
- Yup.
You think this such a good idea?
I need the algorithm, alright.
I need the algorithm.
Each girl base rating 1400.
At any given time "Girl A" has a rating
R-a and "Girl B" has a rating R-b.
When any 2 girls are matched up,
there's an expectation of which will
win based on their current rating, right?
And all those expectations
are express this way.
Let's write it.
The one on the left.
The right.
It works.
Who should we send it first?
- Dwyer
- Neal
Who will you send it to?
Just to couple of people.
Question is: who are they gonna send it to?
Hey, guys check this out.
Right or left.
Look this hot.
She's my room mate.
This is pathetic.
Albright?
He blog about you.
You don't wanna read it.
Erika, is this yours?
Awful lot of traffic.
You think maybe we should shut
it down before get into trouble.
Hello?
Wa-wait... what?
At 4 in the morning?
Well, this very an usual amount of
traffic to the switch of Kirkland.
You're saying it's unusual
for 4 in the morning?
No, this should be unusual
for half time at the superbowl.
Alright.
I'm gonna go in.
What's goin' on?
Harvard network is about to crash.
You don't think...
I do...
Go to see if it's everybody...
I can't comin'
The network's down.
Unless, it's coincidence,
I think this is us.
It's not a coincidence.
Holy shit...
So you were called in front of the Ad Board.
That's not what happen.
You weren't called in front
of the Administrator Board?
No, back, I mean... that's,
back at the bar with Erica Albright.
She said all that?
That I said that stuff to her.
I was reading from the
transcript for the deposition.
Why we do even need to depose her?
That really for us to decide.
Miss, You think if I know she
can make me look like a jerk.
- I'll be more likely to settle.
- Mark...
Why don't we stretch our legs for
a minute, can we do that?
It's been almost 3 hours.
And frankly you did spend
awful lot of the time...
Embarrassing Mr. Zuckerberg with
the girl's testimony from the bar.
I'm not embarrassed.
She just made a lot that up.
She was under oath.
I guess there would be the first
time somebody's lies under oath.
You got 22 hundred hits within 2 hours?
- Thousands.
- What?
Twenty-two *thousands*.
WOW...
These guys are pretty fast.
Sure anybody make this a fair fight?
Jump up and swim.
I think we'd have to jump up and drowned.
Or you could row forward,
I could row backward.
We're genetically identical, science
says we'd stay in the one place.
Just row the damn boat.
- You guys here about this?
- What?
Two nights ago, a sophomore shut
the network from laptop at Kirkland.
- At 4AM.
- How?
He set up a website, where you vote
on the hotness female undergrads.
What were we doing that none
of us heard about this?
I do not know, 3 hour
technical row before breakfast
Full course load, studying.
Another 3 hours in
the tank then studying.
I'm not sure how we missed it.
How much activity was on those thing?
Twenty two thousands pages request.
This guy hack the facebook from 7 houses.
He set up the whole site in 1 night.
And he did it while he was drunk.
Twenty two thousands?
How do you know his drunk?
He was blogging simultaneously,
- You know what I think?
- I'm way ahead of you
This is our guy.
Cameron Winklevoss, W-i-n-k-I-e-v-o-s-s,
Cameron spell the usual way.
Tyler Winklevoss, Tyler spell the usual way.
And my last name the same as my brother's.
Mr. Zuckerberg, This in an
Administration board hearing.
You're being accused of intentionally
breaching security, violating copyrights,
Violating individual privacy by
creating the website www.facemash.com.
You're also charge with being in violation university
policy on distribution of digitized imaging.
Before we begin with our questioning you're allowed
to make a statement, would you like to do so?
I've, You know, I've already apologize
to the Crimson, to the ABHW...
To Fuerza Latina, and to any women in Harvard may
have been insulted as I take it that they were.
As for any charges stemming from
the breach from the security,
I believe I deserve some
recognition from this board.
I'm sorry?
Yes.
I don't understand...
Which part?
You deserve recognition?
I believe, I pointed out some
pretty gaping holes on your system...
- Excuse me, May I?
- Yes
Mr. Zuckerberg. I'm in charge of security
for all computer on the Harvard network.
And I can assure you of its sophistication.
In fact it was that level of sophistification
that led us to you in for less than 4 hours.
- Four hours?
- Yes, sir.
That would be impressive except if
you had know what you lookin' for,
You would've seen it written
on my dorm room window.
- So?
- Six month academic probation.
Well, they making an example out of you.
They have my blog.
I shouldn't have write nothing about
the farm animals. That was stupid.
But, I was kidding, for god sake.
Doesn't anybody have some sense of humour?
- But I tried to stop you.
- I know
How do you do these thing,
How you manage to get
all girls to hate us.
- Why do I let you...
- I know.
- Can't do that...
- Eduardo, I said enough.
Ok, let's look at a sample problem...
Suppose we're given a computer with a 16-bit
virtual address and a page size of 256 bytes.
The system uses one-level page
tables, which start at address 0x400.
Maybe you want to have DMA on
your 16-bit system, who knows?
The first few pages are
reserved for hardware flags, etc.
Assume page table entries
have eight status bits.
The eight status bits would then be...
Anybody?
And I see we have our first surrender.
Don't worry, Mr. Zuckerberg, brighter men
than you have tried and failed at this class.
One valid bit, 1 modify bit,
1 reference bit and 5 permission bits.
That is correct.
Does everybody see how he got there?
Mark?
Are you Mark Zuckerberg?
Yeah.
- Cameron Winklevoss.
- Hi...
Tyler Winklevoss.
Are you guys related?
- It's good.
- Funny.
We never heard that before.
So what can I do for you?
Did I insult your girlfriends?
No, we didn't,
Actually... I don't know.
We never asked.
Maybe we should do that...
Now, we have an idea we want to talk
you about.
You got a minute?
You guys look like
you spend some time at a gym.
We have to.
- Why?
- We row crew.
- Yeah, I've got a minute.
- Great.
- So you ever been inside The Porcellian?
- No
Alright we gonna stay, we can't take you
past the bike room 'cause you're not a member.
I've heard.
Wanna sandwich or something?
Ok, Mark, right?
- Mark, this is Divya Narendra, our partner.
- Hi.
We were really impressed with facemash.
And then we checked you out
and you also built CourseMatch.
I don't know CourseMatch.
You go online and you see what
courses your friend are takings...
You are really smart, man.
- Mark...
- Yeah.
We were talking about "CourseMatch"
It was kind of a no brainer.
And you invented something
in high school too, right?
An app for an MP3 player that
recognizes your taste in music.
Anybody try to buy it?
Microsoft.
How much?
I didn't sell it.
I uploaded for free.
- For free?
- Yeah.
Why?
Ok, well. We have something that we've been
working for a while. We think it's great.
It's called HarvardConnection.
You create your own page.
Interests, bio, friends, pics.
And then people could go
online, see your bio, request...
Yeah, how this different
from MySpace or Friendster?
Harvard-dot-E-D-U.
Harvard.edu is the most prestigious
e-mail address in the country.
And the whole site kinda
base on the idea with girls...
- Not to putting anything in delicate.
- Girls wanna go with guys who go to Harvard.
Divya and my brother don't have
trouble putting things in delicate.
Many different between
what we're talkin' about
and MySpace or Friendster any
others social networks inside...
Is that exclusivity...
Right?
Right.
Yeah, we'd love you
to work with this Mark.
We need a gifted programmer
and you're creative.
And we know you would
take this serious...
Womens group already declare a war...
You know, this could help
rehabilitate you image.
Wow, you would do that for me?
We'd like to work with you.
Our first programmer graduated
and went to work at Google.
Our second programmer just got
overwhelmed with school work.
We will need you to build the site,
write the code and we'll provide...
I'm in...
- What?
- I'm in.
Awesome!
That's what you said?
It was 3 or 4 years ago...
I don't know what I said.
When did you come to Eduardo?
I don't understand the question.
Do you remember
answering an affirmative?
The affirmative...
When did you come to Eduardo
with the idea for facebook?
It was called "TheFacebook" then.
It doesn't need to be that difficult.
I'm35
Did you answer affirmatively,
When Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss, Divya
Narendra ask you to build Harvard Connection,
4id I'd help.
Did you say, yes?
I sa currently in the middle
of 2 different law suits.
When did you approached Mr. Saverin
with the idea for the facebook?
I wouldn't say I approached him.
Sy?
You can answer the question.
At a party at Alpha Epsilon Pi
What's that?
The jewish fraternity.
It was Caribbean night.
It's not that guys like me are
generally attracted to Asian girls.
It's that Asian girls are
generally attracted to guys like me.
I'm developing an algorithm to define the
connection between Jewish guys and Asian girls.
I don't think it's that complicated.
They're hot, they're smart, they're
not Jewish and they can't dance.
- Hey, Mark's here.
- Mark.
I think I've come up with something.
Hang on, I've gotta tell you
something you're not going to believe.
- What?
- I got punched by the Phoenix.
- Are You kidding?
- No.
I mean it's just the
first of the 4 step process,
But they slipped the invitation
under my door tonight.
I go to the first punch party tomorrow.
You got punch by The Phoenix.
Yeah, probably, it was
just a diversity thing.
It was just a diversity thing.
I'll just ride that horse until...
What did you want to talk about?
- Mark?
- Yeah.
You said you've come up with something.
Yeah, I think I've come up
with something. Come outside.
It's 20 degrees outside.
I can't stare to that loop of Niagara falls which
has absolutely nothing to do with the Caribbean.
People came to Facemash
in a stampede, right?
Yeah.
But it wasn't because the
saw pictures of hot girls.
You can go any around on the internet
and see pictures of hot girls.
Yeah.
That was because they saw
pictures of girls that they knew.
People wanna go on the internet
and check out their friends,
So why not build the
website that offers that?
Friends, pictures, profiles,
whatever you can visit, browse around.
Maybe its someone you just met at a party.
But I'm not talkin' about a dating site.
I'm talkin' about taking the entire social
experience of college and putting it online.
I can't feel my legs
I know, I'm totally psyched about this too.
But Wardo...
Yeah...
It would be exclusive.
You would've to know the people on
the site to get pass thru on page.
Like getting punched.
That's good
Wardo, it's like a Final Clubs
except we're the president.
I told him I thought it sounded great.
It was a great idea.
There's nothing to hack.
People were gonna provide their own
pictures, their own information.
And people had the ability to invite
or not invite their friends to join.
See, in the world were the
social structure was everything.
Puff...
That was the "THING".
It was a big project.
And he was going to have to write
ten of thousands of lines of code.
So I wonder, why he was coming
to me and not to his room mate.
Dustin Moskowitz and Chris
Hughes they're programmers.
We're gonna need a little start-up cash
to rent the servers and get it online.
So that was why.
- Did he offers terms?
- Yes.
We'll split it.
70-30
Seventy for me, Thirty for you for
you, putting up a thousands dollar.
And for handling everything on the business end.
You're CFO
- And you said?
- I said "Let's do it"
- Ok, did he add anything else?
- Yes.
It probably was
a diversity thing but so what?
Why do you think he said that?
Gretchen, excuse me for interrupting,
But whose discovery it is?
- Sy, if you let me continue with my line of question...
- What do you suggesting?
They're suggesting I was jealous of
Eduardo for getting punched by Phoenix.
And began a plan to screw him out of
the company I haven't even invented yet.
- Were you?
- Gretchen...
Jealous of Eduardo?
Oh, stop typing,
we're off the record.
Maam, I know you've
done your home work.
And so you know that money
isn't a big part of my life,
But at the moment I could buy
Mt. Auburn Street,
Take the Phoenix Club and
turn it into my pingpong room.
I'll let you know how the party is,
We recognize that you're a plaintiff in one
suit involving Facebook and a witness in another.
- Yes, Sir.
- At any time In the weeks,
Prior to Mark telling you his idea,
Did he mention Tyler Winklevoss, Cameron
Winklevoss, Divya Narendra or HarvardConnection?
Yes. He said they'd asked
him to work on their site.
But that he'd looked at what they had
and decided it wasn't worth his time.
He said even his most pathetic friends knew more about
getting people interested in a website than these guys.
"These guys" meaning my clients.
Yes. He resented, Mark
resented that they,
That your clients thought that he need to
rehabilitate his image after the Facemash.
But Mark didn't want to
rehabilitate anything.
With Facemash he'd hacked
into The Harvard computers,
He dumps his nose at the Ad Board.
He got a lot of honorarity.
Facemash did exactly
what he wanted it to do.
Were you aware that while Mr.
Zuckerberg was building the Facebook,
He was also communicating
with the plaintiffs?
Not at the time I wasn't.
But...
It really didn't have much to do
with The Winkelvoss dating site.
H- How would you know?
You' weren't even there...
Were you aware that while Mr.
Zuckerberg was building TheFacebook,
He was leading the plaintiffs to believe
he was building HarvardConnection?
You're offering a conclusion
not found an evidence.
We are about to finding new evidence...
From Mark Zuckerberg to Tyler Winklevoss
November 30, 2003
I read over all the stuff you
sent me re-HarvardConnection,
and it seems like it shouldn't
take too long to implement,
so we can talk about it after I get all
the basic functionality up tomorrow night.
From Mark Zuckerberg to Cameron Winklevoss.
December 1, 2003.
"Sorry I was unreachable tonight. I just
got about three of your missed calls.
I was working on a problem
set for my sytems class"
From Mark Zuckerberg to Tyler & Cameron Winklevoss.
December 10, 2003.
"This week has been pretty busy
thus far with classes and work"
"So I think it's probably best
to postpone the meeting."
"I'm also really busy tomorrow"
Ok, anybody else feel like there
is somethin' up with this guy?
Tell him ok.
But we do have to make sure that we
meet up before we all head off for break.
- Hi Mark,
- Hi,
I need a dedicated Linux box running
Apache with a mySQL back-end.
It's gonna cost a little more money.
- How much more?
- About 200 more.
- Do we need it?
- Gotta handle the traffic.
- Do it.
- I already did.
Hey guess what...
I'm in the 2nd cut.
That's good. You should
be proud of that right there,
Don't worry if you
don't make it any further.
I'll get out of here.
From Mark Zuckerberg to Tyler and
Cameron Winklevoss and Divya Narendra.
December 15, 2003.
I have a cs problem set that
I'm just getting started with,
And It should be about 15 hours of
coding so I'll be busy tomorrow night,
I won't really be free to meet
until next Wednesday afternoon.
I have to cancel Wednesday afternoon.
I've basically been in the
lab this whole time and also...
Won't be able to do it Saturday as
I have to meet up with my parents...
As the plaque reads, this is John Harvard,
founder of Harvard University in 1638.
It's also called The Statue of Three Lies.
What are the three lies?
Mr. Dowd.
The three lies,
First...
Shit!
- Take your pants off.
- I know.
Mr. Saverin.
1) Harvard was founded in 1636 not 1638.
2) Harvard was not founded by John Harvard
and 3) That's not John Harvard.
Who is it?
F- friend of the sculptor,
Daniel... Chester.
Keep you jacket on.
39 days after Mr. Zuckerberg's
initial meeting with my clients
And he still hadn't completed
work on HarvardConnection.
But On January 11, 2004
Mr. Zuckerberg registered the domain
name theFacebook by Network Solution.
To the best of your knowledge, had he
even begun work on HarvardConnection?
Not to my knowledge.
No.
Hi Cameron, "I'm still
a little skeptical,
We have enough functionality in
the site to really draw the attention,
And gain the critical mass necessary
to get a site like this to run"
We'll speak soon?
This is the first time
he mentioned any problem?
Yes, he was
You'd sent 36 e-mails to Mr. Zuckerberg
and received 16 e-mails in return,
And this was the first time he
indicated that he was not happy.
That's correct!
He had 42 days to study our
system and get out ahead...
Do you see any of your code on Facebook?
Did I use any of your code?
You stole our whole god damn idea.
Fellas,
What a match-dot-com for Harvard guys!
Can I continue with my deposition
You know you really don't need a
forensic team to get to bottom of this
If you guys were the inventors of
Facebook you'd have invented Facebook.
I can't wait to stand over your
shoulder while you write us a check.
No shit.
Let's continue.
February 4, 2004
Mark...
There is a girl in your art
history class name Stephanie Attis.
Do you happen to know
if she has a boyfriend?
Have you ever seen her with anyone.
And if not, do you happen to know if
she's looking to go out with anyone?
Dustin...
People don't walk around with
a sign on them that says some...
We were supposed to meet at nine.
- Have you slept yet?
- I've to add something.
What?
Shit that's look good,
That's look really good.
It's clean and simple,
no disneyland...
But watch...
What'd you write?
Relationship status, Interested in,
This is what drives live in college.
Are you having sex or aren't you
It's why people take certain classes.
And sit where they sit.
And do what they do, and
it's um, centre, you know,
That what's thefacebook
is gonna be about...
People gonna log on...
Because after all the cake and watermelon,
there's a chance they're actually gonna...
- Get laid...
- Meet a girl. Yes.
- This is really good.
- And that was it.
What d'you mean?
- It's ready.
- It's ready?
That was it, and here's the masthead.
- You made a masthead.
- Yeah.
Eduardo Saverin, Co-Founder and CFO.
You have no idea how what
that's gonna mean for my father.
Sure I do...
- When's it go on live?
- Right now, take your laptop out.
Why we do need my laptop.
Because you've got e-mails
for everybody at Phoenix.
I'm not sure it's gonna be cool
with them that I spam their...
It's not spam.
I know it's not spam
If we send it to our friends it'll
just bounce around the computer lab.
I haven't gotten in yet.
These guys know people
and I need their e-mails.
- Sure
- Good.
Give me the mailing list.
jabberwock12@harvard E-D-U.
These guys.
They're literary geniuses 'cause the world's
most obvious Lewis Caroll reference is in their...
They're not so bad
I'm just saying.
Yeah, you're right.
The site's live.
You know, Let's go get
a drink and celebrate.
I'm buying.
Mark,
Mark, are you praying?
What ever happened to Cole
Porter and Irving Berlin?
It's a Valentine's theme.
They playing love songs.
Good point, 'cause Cole Porter and
Irving Berlin never wrote any love songs.
Honey, just put your laptop away...
Seventy four people
spam me the same link.
Casey...
- What is it?
- I don't know
But I'm really hoping it's cat look like a
hitler 'cause I can never get enough of that.
No, it's not.
Div?
What?
Div, w-what is wrong?
- Hey!
- Not now!
- We need 20 mins.
- Ok.
I just want to let you know that
Zuckerberg stole our website.
- Mark Zuckerberg?
- He stole our website.
It's been alive for more than 36 hours.
Mr. Hotchkiss
Ty, the lawyer's on the phone with dad.
Yes, Sir. I'm here with my brother
Tyler, our business partner, Divya.
Welcome to theFacebook. theFacebook is an online directory
that connects people through different social networks.
You must have a Harvard.edu
address to register.
That's right.
Yes, Sir.
I called earlier, I'm
looking for Mark Zuckerberg
Yes, Sir. He's quoted a couple of times.
I can read it to you.
"Everyone's been talking a lot about
a universal facebook within Harvard"
I think it's kind of silly that it would take the
University a couple of years to get around to it.
I can do it in class jobs than
they can't and I did it in a week.
- Tell him, Divya Narendra called, I appreciate it.
- That's how we talks.
As of yesterday evening, Zuckerberg set over
650 students to registered thefacebook.com
He said that he anticipated 900 students
would've join the site by this morning.
Divya was just reading that 650
students signed up on the first day
If I was I drug dealer I could give
free drugs to 650 people in one day.
This guy doesn't have 3 friends to rob...
Guys, please, come on...
Alright that's what we'll do, Mr. Hotchkiss
Then we e-mail it to you.
You won't be able to get
on the website yourself.
Because you don't have a harvard... uhm..
you know what it would be easy
for us to e-mail it to you.
I'm sure you right... He's a good guy,
And he's very bright and I'm sure he
didn't mean to... do what he did.
Alright,
thank you very much...
And Dad,
Love you too.
He good guy?
We don't know that he's not a good guy.
We know he Stole our idea
We know that he lied to our
faces for a month and half
He never lie to our face
He never saw our faces!
Fine, he lied to our e-mail accounts.
So he got himself 42-days head start
He knows what apparently you don't which
is that getting there first is everything.
I'm a competitive racer, Div,
I don't think you need to school me on the
importance of getting there first. Thank you.
Alright, that's was your father's lawyer?
Yeah, well his in-house counsel.
He's gonna look at all this if he thinks it's
appropriate he'll send a cease and desist letter.
What, do you wanna hire
an IP lawyer and sue him?
No, I wanna hire the Sopranos to beat
the shit out of him with a hammer!
- We don't have to do that.
- That's right.
We can do that ourself.
I'm six-five, 220lbs, and there's two of me.
I'm with this guy.
Whatever, I'm saying let's calm down
until we know what we're talking about.
how much more information
are you waiting for.
We met with Mark 3 times, exchanged 52 e-mails,
we can prove that he looked at the code...
what is that on the bottom of page
It's "A Mark Zuckerberg production"
On the homepage?
On every pages.
Shit. I need to let the
classiness waft over me.
Ok, look...
They wrote, "Zuckerberg said that
he hoped the privacy options...
...would help to restore his reputation
following student outrage over Facemash.com"
That's exactly what we said to him.
He's giving us "the finger" in the Crimson
While we're waiting for dad's
lawyer to look this stuff over, we can at least...
No...
We're not starting a knife fight in
the Crimson and we're not suing anybody.
Why not?
He's gonna say it's stupid.
What, who?
Me?
Say it why not?
Because we're gentlemen of Harvard.
This is Harvard. Where you don't plant
stories and you don't sue people.
You thought he was going to be the
only one who thought that was stupid?
During the time when you say you had this idea,
Did you know Tyler and Cameron
came from a family of means?
A family of means?
Did you know that his father was wealthy.
I'm not sure why you're asking me that.
It's not important that you
be sure why I'm asking you.
It's not important to you.
Sy...
Did you know that they came from money?
I had no idea whether they
came from money or not.
In one of your e-mails to Mr. Narendra you
reference Tate Winklevoss consulting firm.
If you say so.
Howard Winklevoss founded the firm and its
assets are in the hundreds of millions.
You also knew that Tyler and Cameron were members
of a Harvard Final club called the Porcellian.
They pointed that out?
Excuse us for inviting you in.
To the bike room...
So it's safe to say you were
aware that my clients had money?
Yes.
Let me tell you why I'm asking.
I'm wondering why...
If you needed a $1000 for an internet
venture you didn't ask my clients for it.
They'd demonstrated to you an
interest in this kind of thing...
I went to my friend for the money because
that he's who I wanted to be partners with...
Eduardo was presidents of the Harvard Inverstors
Association and he was also my best friend.
Your best friend is suing
you for 600 million dollars.
I didn't know that.
tell me more!
Eduardo, what happen
after the initial lunch?
Sy would you mind addressing as Mr. Saverin
Gretchen, they're best friend
Not anymore
I already went through this on the...
Nevermind, Mr. Saverin...
It's exploded, everybody
on campus was using it
"Facebook-me" was the common
expression after two weeks.
and Mark...
And Mark was biggest thing on a campus
that included 19 Nobel Laureates,
15 Pulitzer Prize Winners,
two future Olympians
and a movie star.
Who's the movie star?
Does it matter?
No.
Beautiful day. And I was up in my Radcliffe dorm.
He brought that magazine up and he saw it to me.
And he said, "Look, it's gonna happen
without us. We've got to start now."
And I said... "Okay."
Let's get basic hardware.
Now, most of you think you know the
rest of story that you may not.
The beginning of the
industry were very humble...
That kit computer on the cover of that
magazine, had an 8080 processor in it.
Unless you paid extra for 1K
memory board, you got 256bits,
So the challenges,
when I write the basic...
Wasn't just, uh... running 4Kbits
But I also have to leave room for
users to run the programs in 4Kbits
Hi... your friend,
Isn't that Mark Zuckerberg?
Yeah
- He made facebook?
- Yeah.
I mean both of us.
Yeah, we... yes.
Cool. I'm Christy Lee.
This is Alice.
V- Very nice to meet you.
Facebook-me when you get home
We can all go out and grab a drink.
Certainly, absolutely will do that.
She said "Facebook-me" and we
can all go for a drink later.
Which is stunningly great for two reasons.
One she said "Facebook-me". Right?
And the other...
- They wanna have drinks later.
- Yes
Have you ever heard so many different good
things packed into one regular-sized sentence?
Excuse me. Mark?
Yeah
I'm Stuart Singer. I'm in your O.S. lab.
Sure.
- Awesome job with theFacebook.
- Awesome Job.
Thanks.
- I'm Bob.
- How are you doin'.
You know, I could swear he
was looking at you when he said
The next Bill Gates could
be right in this room.
I doubt it
I showed up late, I don't
even know who the speaker was.
It was Bill Gates.
Shit... that's make sense.
Alright, thanks guys.
Are you moron? Are you medically stupid?
You can't recognize Bill Gates
in front of you for an hour?
Mark Zuckerberg now thinks we got into Harvard
on a dimwit scholarship. I'm gonna get a Glock...
It's time to monetize the thing.
What are their natives?
- Did you heard what I just said?
- When?
I said it's times to monetize the site
What is that mean?
It means, it's time for the website
to start generating revenue.
No, I know what the word means.
I'm asking how do you want to do it?
Advertising.
No.
We've got 4000 members.
'Cause theFacebook is cool.
And if we start selling pop-ups
for Mountain Dew it's not gonna be cool.
Well I wasn't thinking it would
be Mountain Dew but at some point,
And I'm talkin' as the business
end of the company, the site...
We don't even know what it
is yet, we don't what it is...
We don't know what it can be.
We don't know what it will be.
We know that it's cool,
That's a priceless asset
and I'm not giving it up.
- So it won't be finish?
- It won't be finish.
That's the point, the way fashion never finish
- What?
- Fashion, fashion is never finish.
You talkin' about fashion, really you?
I'm talkin' about the idea
I'm sayin' that never finish
Ok, but they manage to
make money, sellin' pants
Mark what is this?
What?
It's called the cease and desist letter.
What were their names?
- Who?
- The girls.
When did you get this?
About ten days ago.
Right after we launched the site
Hey, the girls what were their names?
They're sayin'... the Winklevoss twins
are sayin' that you stole their idea.
I find that to be mildly annoying.
They find it to be
Intelectual Property Theft.
- Look...
- Why don't you show it to me?
It was addressed to me
They're sayin' that we stole theFacebook
from Divya Narendra and the Winklevoss...
I know what it says.
Did we?
Did we what?
Don't screw around with me now.
Look at me
The letter says we could face legal action.
No, it says I could face legal action
This is from lawyer, Mark.
They must feel they have some grounds for...
The lawyer is their father's house counsel.
Do they have grounds?
The grounds are our thing is cool and
popular and HarvardConnection is lame.
Wardo, I didn't use any of their code,
I promise, I didn't use anything.
Look, a guy who builds a really nice chair doesn't
owe money to everyone who's ever built a chair.
Ok, they came to me with
an idea. I had a better one.
Why didn't you show me this letter
I didn't think it was a big deal
If there's something wrong,
if there's ever anything wrong,
You can tell me.
I'm the guy that wants to help.
This is our thing.
Now, is there anything
that you need to tell me
No.
What are we doing about this?
I went to a 3-L at Student Legal Services
and he told me to write them back.
And what did you say?
When we met in January, I
express my doubts about the site,
where it stood with graphic, how much
programming was left that I had not anticipated...
...the lack of hardware we
had to deal with the site use,
the lack of promotion that we go on
to successfully launch the website...
This was the first time you
raised any of those concern, right?
I'd raised concerns before.
Bullshit
Not to us
Gentlemen.
I'm talkin about at the meeting in
January to which this letter is referring.
Yeah.
Let me re-phrase this.
You sent my client 16 e-mails. In the
first 15, you did't raise any concerns
Is that a question?
In the 16th e-mail you raised
concerns about the site functionality.
Were you leading them on for six weeks?
No.
Why didn't you raise any
of these concern before?
It's raining.
I'm sorry?
It's just started raining.
Mr. Zuckerberg, do I have your full attention?
No.
Do you think I deserve it?
What?
Do you think I deserve your full attention?
I had to swear an oath before we began this
deposition, and I don't want to perjure myself,
So I have a legal obligation to say no.
Okay - no.
You don't think I deserve your attention.
I think if your clients want to sit on
my shoulders and call themselves tall,
They have the right to give it a try,
But there's no requirement that I enjoy
sitting here listening to people lie.
You have part of my attention -
you have the minimum amount.
The rest of my attention is back
at the offices of theFacebook,
Where my colleagues and I are doing
things that no one in this room,
Including and especially your clients, are
intellectually or creatively capable of doing.
Did I adequately answer
your condescending question?
I have 12:45, why don't we say that's lunch.
Back at 02:30.
So what were their names?
Their names are Christy and Alice.
And They wanna have drinks tonight
I don't care.
Hey man, sorry, uhmm, couple of
girls refreshing up in there.
Sweet...
We have groupies.
I'll be right back
Hey, where you goin'?
Mark...
Erica
Hey
I saw you from over there
- I don't know you came to this club a lot.
- First time.
Mine too.
Can I talk you alone for a second?
I think I'm good right here
I just... I'd love to talk you alone
Right here is fine
I don't know if you heard about
this new website I launched.
- No
- TheFacebook?
You called me a bitch on internet, Mark.
That's why, I wanna talk to you...
- On the internet...
- If you could just...
That's why I came over
Comparing women to farm animals?
I didn't end up doing that.
It didn't stop you from writing it.
As if every thought that tumbles through your head is
so clever, it would be a crime for it not to be share.
The internet's not written in pencil, Mark,
it's written in ink,
And you published that
Erica Albright was a bitch.
Right before you made some ignorant
crack about my family's name, my bra size...
And then rated women
based on their hotness.
- Erica, is there a problem?
- No, there's no problem.
You write your snide bullshit from a dark room
because that's what the angry do nowadays.
I was nice to you
don't torture me for it.
If we could just go
somewhere for a minute...
I don't want to be rude to my friends,
- Okay.
Good luck with your video game.
Dude, that's was great...
That was right thing to do,
you apologize, right?
We have to expand.
Is he mad about something?
Okay, we're expanding
to Yale and Columbia.
Dustin, I want you to share
the coding work with me.
Chris, you're gonna be in
charge of publicity and outreach.
You can start by gettin' a story in
B.U student newspaper. It's the bridge.
They hate doing stories about Harvard.
Somebody at the newspaper will
be a computer science major.
Tell 'em Mark Zuckerberg will do 10
hours of free programming for them.
Why do you want a story
in the B.U. newspaper...
Because I do.
Now, here's the arrangement.
Eduardo's CFO and owns 30% of the company.
Dustin's Vice President and Head of Programming
and his 5% of the company will come from my end.
Chris is Director of Publicity and his compensation will
depend on the amount of work he ends up doing.
- Any questions?
- Who the girls?
Sorry, uhmm...
they are Christy and Alice.
- Hi...
- Hi. Hello.
- Is there anything we can do?
- No, that's it.
Yale and Columbia, let's go.
- And Stanford...
- What?
Standford. It's time for
them to see this in Palo Alto.
- You don't want any lunch?
- No.
You're welcome to some salad.
No, thank you.
This must be hard.
Who are you?
I'm Marylin Delpy,
I introduced myself this morning.
I mean, what do you do?
I'm a second year associate at the firm.
My boss wanted me to sit in on the deposition phase.
What are you doin'?
Checking in to see how it's going in Bosnia.
Bosnia?
They don't have roads
but they have Facebook.
You must really hate the Winklevoss.
I don't hate anybody.
The Winklevii aren't suing me
for intellectual property theft.
They're suing me because for
the first time in their lives,
Things didn't work at the way
they were supposed to for them.
- He's expanding.
- What?
He's expanding to Yale, Columbia and Stanford,
it's gonna be in the Crimson tomorrow.
Really?
Yeah.
Well, it's look like that Cease and desist letter
really scared the shit out of him, huh?
I want to hire a lawyer to file for injunctive relief
and get this website taken down now!
Look...
Every minute, the site's up, Harvard
Connection become less valuable.
I want an injunction, I want damages,
punitive relief and I want him dead.
I want those things too!
Then why aren't we doing anything about it?!
Because we're gentlemen of Harvard?!
Because you're not thinking
about how it's gonna look.
How's it gonna look?
Like my brother and I are in skeleton costumes
chasing the Karate Kid around a high school gym.
Cam, he violated Massachusetts state law.
When he goes to Connecticut, New York and
California he'll have violated federal law.
And by the way, he's in violation of Harvard law.
There's no such thing as Harvard law.
Wait, Yes, there is.
Harvard student handbook.
Every freshman is issued one of this.
Somewhere in this book says...
You can't steal from another student.
This is what we needed.
You can't get a meeting
with Larry Summers.
My brother and I pay tuition at this
school, we carry a 3.9 GPA at this school,
We've won trophies for this school and
We'll be rowing in the Olympics for this school.
I want a meeting with the
goddamn president of this school.
Why Stanford?
W- Why do you think?
I'm sorry, I'm late for Bio Chem..
Okay.
You don't know my name, do you?
Is it Stanford?
I should just kick your ass.
How you go to party
and you meet somebody...
Amelia Ritter, but you prefer Amy.
You're from Orinda
Your father in commercial real estate
and your mother is 10 years sober.
What's my major?
Trombone.
Really?
I remember something about a trombone.
"Tu fais l'amour  la jolie fille et la mets de ct"
*You make love to the pretty girl and put it aside*
- French...
- Oui
Your major is French.
And yours?
Mine?
I don't have one.
You haven't declared?
I don't go to school.
- You kidding?
- No.
Where did you go to school?
William Elementary for a little while,
Seriously, you're not like 15
years old or anything are you?
No.
But you're not like 15, are you?
So what do you do?
I'm an entrepreneur.
You're unemployed.
I wouldn't say that.
What would you say?
That I'm an entrepreneur.
Well then, what was your latest preneur?
Well, I founded an internet company that
let folks download and share music for free.
Kinda like Napster?
Exactly like Napster.
What do you mean?
I founded Napster.
Sean Parker founded Napster.
Nice to meet you.
You're Sean Parker.
Ah, you see, the shoe's on the other,
uh, table which has turned.
I just slept with Sean Parker?
You just slept on Sean Parker.
You're zillionaire.
Not technically
What are you?
Broke. There's not a lot of money in free music.
Even less when you're being sued by
everyone who's ever been to the Grammys.
This is blowing my mind.
I appreciate that
I gotta hop in the shower
and get ready for class.
Biochem, even know you are in French major,
whose name is Amy.
You passed.
I'm a hard worker.
There's juice or anything else
you can find. Help yourself.
You mind if I check my e-mail?
Yeah. go ahead.
Amy...
Amy?
Yeah!
Can you come out here?
Just a second!
There's a snake in here, Amy.
What?
Where?
Ok, there isn't snake but I need to ask you something.
Are you kidding me?
I could've been killed!
How?
By running to you fast and gettin' twisted...
What do you need to ask me?
I went to check my e-mail
and there's a website open on your computer.
Yeah. After you passed out last night,
I went on theFacebook for 'lil bit.
What's that?
TheFacebook? Standford had it for,
like two weeks now.
It's really awesome except
it's freakishly addictive.
Seriously, I'm on the thing like five times a day.
You mind if I set myself an e-mail.
Yes, everything okay?
Everything's great.
I just need to find...
You,
Mark Zuckerberg.
I've never been in this building before.
This building is a hundred years
older than the country it's in.
So do be careful.
We're sitting in the chairs.
Yes. Very good.
You can go in now.
That's just their own stupidity,
I should have been there.
Darkness is the absence of light and stupidity
in that instance was the absence of me.
Catherine, I've got students in my office now.
Students. Undergrads.
I don't know, from the looks of it, they want
to sell me Brooks Brothers Franchise. Alright.
Good morning.
Good morning, Sir.
I'm Cameron Winklevoss and
this is my brother, Tyler.
And you here, because...
Either of you can answer.
I thought you were reading the letter.
I've read the letter.
Well, we came up with an idea for
a website called HarvardConnection...
That we've since changed
the name to ConnectU,
And Mark Zuckerberg stole that idea...
I'm understand. I'm asking
what you want me to do about it?
Well Sir, in The Harvard Student Handbook,
which is distributed to each freshman...
Under the heading "Standards of Conduct in the Harvard Community"
It says, The College expects
that all students to be honest...
And forthcoming in their dealings
with members in this community.
Students are required to respect
public and private ownership.
Instances of theft, misappropriation or...
- Ann...
- Yes Sir.
Punch me in the face...
Go ahead.
Or unauthorized use will
result in disciplinary action,
Including the requirement
to withdraw from the College.
You memorize that instead of doing, what?
What my brother and I come, here today,
to ask you, respectfully of course...
Sir, it's against University rules to steal
from another student, plain and simple.
You've spoken to your House-master.
Yes Sir, and the House-master made
a recommendation to the Ad Board
But the Ad Board won't hear us.
Have you tried dealing with
the other student directly?
Mr. Zuckerberg hasn't been responding to any of
our e-mails or phone calls for the last two weeks.
He doesn't answer when we
knock on his door at Kirkland.
And the closest I've come to dealing with
him face to face is when I saw him on the quad,
And I chased him through Harvard Square.
You chased him?
I- I saw him and I know he saw me
and after a minutes he disappeared.
I don't see this as the university issue.
Of course this is a university issue.
There's a code of ethics and an
honor code and he violated them both.
You entered into a code of ethics with
the university, not with each other.
I'm sorry President Summers, but
what you just said makes no sense to me at all.
I'm devastated by that.
What my brother means is if Mark
Zuckerberg breaking into our dorm room
And stole our computer, that
would be university issue.
I don't know this office
doesn't handle petty larceny.
This isn't petty larceny. This idea
potentially worth millions of dollars.
- Millions?
- Yes.
You might just be letting your
imaginations run away with you.
Sir, I actually don't think you're in
any position to make that call.
I was the U.S. Treasury Secretary,
I'm in some position to make that call
Letting our imaginations run away with us is exactly
what we were told us to do in your freshmen address.
I would suggest that you let your imaginations
run away with you on a new project.
- You would?
- Yes, everyone at Harvard is eventing something.
Harvard Undergraduates believe that
inventing a job is better than finding a job.
So I suggest again that the two of you
come up with a new, new project.
I'm sorry, but that's not the point, Sir.
Please what's the point.
You don't have to be an intellectual property expert
to understand the difference between right and wrong.
And you're saying that I don't.
Of course I'm not saying that.
I'm saying that.
- Really?
- Sir...
Ann... How do they get this appointment?
Colleagues of their father...
Let me tell you something Mr. Winklevoss,
Mr. Winklevoss, since you under subject of right and wrong.
This action, this meeting,
the two of you being here is wrong.
Is not worthy of Harvard,
Is not what Harvard saw in you...
You don't get special treatment!
We never ask for it...
Just start another project?
Like we're making a diorama for the science fair?
If you have problems with that Mr. Winklevoss
We never ask for special treatment.
The court are always at your disposal...
Is there anything else, I could do for you?
Thank you very much for your time, Sir.
Ups, broke 335 years old your door knob.
Eduardo, spring break, you and Mr.
Zuckerberg took a trip to New York.
What was the purpose of the trip?
Well, as CFO, I'd set up some
meetings with potential advertisers.
Who paid for the trip?
It was paid for out of the thousand dollar
account I'd set up a few months earlier.
At this point your thousand dollars was the
only money that had been put into the company.
Yes.
How did you feel the meetings went?
It went terribly.
Why?
Mark was asleep.
I was not asleep.
Can I re-phrase my answer?
I wish he'd been asleep.
So we're at 29 schools now
with over 75.000 members.
People who go on theFacebook tend to stay
on longer than almost any other website.
Now here's the most impressive statistic,
61% of people who try it once, will come back...
Now if you'll allow me...
Excuse me, one second...
What sound that he's making?
Is that like a tsk...
It wasn't tsk...
It was...
Like throttle sound
Almost a gag reflex
Guys, what is this?
There was one more meeting
scheduled for the New York trip.
Yes, it was a dinner.
It was set up through my
girlfriend at the time.
Would you say that Mark was
excited about this meeting?
Yes, very.
- Look, they're not gonna card us...
- They might.
I mean look around.
It'll be embarrassing.
Tell him they're not gonna card us.
They're not gonna card us.
Mark...
Are you gonna talk about ads again?
Unless you're the Ballet Theatre of Hartford,
the purpose of a business is to make a profit.
This isn't a business, yet.
That's tough for me because my job...
Nevermind.
He's 25 mins late.
He founded Napster when
he was 19, he can be late.
He's not a God.
Then what is he?
He's 25 minutes late.
I think Wardo's jealous.
I honestly wasn't jealous.
I was nervous.
Why?
I didn't know him at all but I
had done a search and asked around...
He struck me as kind of a wild card.
Why?
He crashed out of two pretty big
internet companies in spectacular fashion,
He's had a reputation with drugs.
He also founded the companies.
We don't need him.
He's here.
No, no, take your time.
And he does own a watch.
Stop it.
I'm Sean Parker.
How do you do.
You must be Eduardo and Christy
and Mark, great to meet you.
You guys don't have
anything in front of you.
Tori...
We were waiting...
Hey baby boy.
Could you bring out some things?
The lacquered pork with that ginger confit, tuna
tartar, and the lobster claws, that'll get us started.
Christy what do you like to drink?
An appletini
Great. Four of those.
From that point on it was a Sean-a-thon.
The question was what did you talk about?
He took us through his episode with Napster.
I didn't want to spend my twenty
as a professional defendant
Who knew the music industry
doesn't have a sense of humor.
We tried to sell the company to pay the
35 millions they said we owed in royalties,
But I guess to them that was a little like
selling a stolen card to pay for the stolen gas.
So we said, screw it,
we declare bankruptcy.
You made a name for yourself.
And you are dry.
- Tory...
- No, no, I'm good.
And then he went to his second business
venture which was an online rolodex.
Says he got thrown off by Chase Equity.
And I want to do it nice this time,
I put on a tie, I shine my shoes.
But nobody want to take orders from a kid.
So let me tell you what happen...
to twenty-old to -- dot.com
I'm not psychiatrist, but
I'm glad with got that on record.
You're not a psychiatrist, but what...
A psychiatrist would
say that he was paranoid.
They hire private detectives,
who follow you day and night.
You are target for hi press-escort.
I can't prove it but I
know they tap my phone.
Whatever it is that's gonna
trip you up, you're done already.
Private behaviour is
rally cover time gone by...
And then somehow and someway you've
manage to live your life like a Dalai Lama
Don't mixed it up.
Because they don't want you,
they want your idea.
And they want you to
say thank you while you,
Excuse me... wipe your
chin and walk away.
That's what happen to you?
And delusional.
Yes,
But... they'll be pay back.
In case I brought down the record company with
Napster and I left the company since then too.
Sorry, you didn't bring down
the record companies. They won.
In court.
Yeah.
You wanna buy a Tower record, Eduardo?
And he told story after story
about life in Silicon Valley,
Parties at Stanford and down in LA,
friends who'd become millionaires,
But mostly how Mark had to,
he had to come to California.
And then he cut around to TheFacebook.
So tell me about your progress.
Well, we're in 29 schools now,
we got over 75 thousands members...
Tell me about the strategy.
Ok, for instance, we wanted Baylor in Texas but
Baylor already had a social network on campus
So instead of going right after them, we made
a list of every school within a hundred miles
And put TheFacebook on those campuses first.
Pretty soon all the Baylor kids were
seeing their friends on our site.
- We were in.
- Its called a little bait for a big one.
That's smart, Mark.
Thanks that's was mine.
Easy.
Hey you know what,
settle an argument for us,
I say it's time to start
making money from TheFacebook,
But Mark doesn't want advertising.
Who's right?
Neither of you yet.
TheFacebook is cool,
- That's what it's got going for it.
- Yeah.
You don't want to ruin it with ads
- Because ads aren't cool.
- Exactly.
It's like you're throwing
the greatest party on campus.
And someone's saying,
it's gotta be over by 11:00.
That's exactly right.
You don't even know what the thing is yet.
How big it can get and how far it can go.
This is no time to take your chips down.
A million dollars isn't cool.
You know what's cool?
You?
A billion dollars.
And that shut everybody up.
And that's where you're headed.
A billion dollar-valuation.
Unless you take bad advice,
In which case you might as well come up
with a chain of very successful yogurt shop.
When you go fishing you can catch
a lot of fish or you can catch a big fish.
You ever walk into a guy's den and see a
picture of him standing next to fourteen trout?
No he's holding an 3000 pound marlin.
- Yup.
- That's a good announce.
But we all know, that marlin
won't weight 3000 pounds, right?
- I've seen a big one at close
- No, I haven't.
But I don't think the guy holdings
a marlin at size of a range rover.
That would really big fish
or a very strong guy.
You think you might be
getting away from the point?
I don't have a dog in this fight.
I'm just a fan who came to say hi.
He owned Mark after that dinner.
He picked up the check, he told Mark
they'd talk again soon and he was gone.
But not before he made his biggest
contribution to the company.
Drop the "the".
Just Facebook. It's cleaner.
Shit.
That's gotta be some kind of
land speed record for talking.
You want to end the party at eleven?
I'm trying to pay for the party.
There won't be a party unless it's cool.
What'd you think?
Yes, sure, let's drop the "the"
I meant catching the marlin instead of the 14 trouts.
Doesn't that sound good?
If you're a trout.
I'm going to enter this into the record.
Incorporation papers for Facebook,
and LLC registered in Florida,
- Why Florida?
- That's where my family lives.
And ask the respondent to stipulate that articles
of incorporation state the ownership as follows,
Sixty-five percent for Mark Zuckerberg,
30% for Eduardo Saverin and 5% for Dustin Moskowitz.
We stipulate
And that was April 13th 2004
You can mark it.
Do you have anything here?
Yes, thank you.
Mr. Saverin,
Have you ever done anything that might be
considered legitimate ground for termination?
No.
You never did anything to embarrass the
company or even seriously jeopardize it?
No.
No?
You were accused of animal cruelty.
Wait.
You weren't?
T- this not happening.
I have here an article from The Crimson...
Jesus Christ...
I can't have this, Wardo.
Come on, man this is bullshit, this is
another clubs playing a prank.
I'd gotten into the Phoenix. I'd been
accepted and as part of my initiation,
I had to, for one week, carry with me
all the times and take care of a chicken.
They identify you as one of the founders
of TheFacebook, "Junior Eduardo Saverin,"
I'm not the expert but being connected to
torturing animals is probably bad for business.
I did not torture the chicken,
I don't torture chickens, are you crazy?
No, and settle down, please.
I have here, an article from The Crimson...
This is scathing.
Nine-hundred-fifty-six.
I was having dinner in the
Kirkland Dining Hall with Mark,
And I had the chicken with me,
Because I had to have the chicken
with me at all times. This was college.
Somebody gonna have to answer for this.
Nine-hundred-sixty-nine.
Dining hall was serving chicken for dinner
and I had to feed my chicken.
So I took... Little pieces of
chicken and gave it to the chicken.
Someone must have seen me
because the next thing I knew,
I was being accused
of forced cannibalism.
I didn't know you could't do that. I dealt
with the various animal rights groups,
I dealt with the Associate Dean of
the College, this was all resolved.
Nine-hundred-eighty-eight.
Someone from the Porc or
the Fly must have reported it.
For all I know it was the Winklevoss...
Alright, let's just forget about it.
This is absurd, I'm being
accused of animal cruelty.
Better to be accused of Necrophilia.
It is better to be accused of Necrophilia.
I have to explain this to my father,
I'm gonna explain this to everybody, I'm
gonna... what is happening on that?
I have my final coming up for
"Postwar and Contemporary Art".
And I haven't been to class. I'm supposed
to write about those four paintings.
Is that a facebook page?
Yeah, I opened it under an alias. I posted
the paintings and asked people to comment.
Every once in a while, I hop on and
stir the pot to get a good debate going.
Mr. Zuckerberg was cheating on his final exam?
I'd rather not answer that, Gretchen.
Then why not?
Because I'm not suing him for cheating on his
final exam and so that's not what friends do.
Well you just told us he was cheating.
Oops.
You told your lawyers I was torturing animals?!
No, he didn't tell us about it at all.
Our litigators are capable
of finding Crimson article.
In fact when we raised the
subject with him he defended you.
Oops.
Nine-ninety-three, we are so close.
Oh yeah, that reminds me,
We're gonna need more money, Wardo.
I agree. More servers, more apps...
I'm interviewing two interns to come to Palo Alto
and we're gonna have to pay them something.
Sorry what?
I already found a house for rent on a
street two blocks from the Stanford campus.
It is perfect and it's got a pool.
When did you decide to go
to California for the summer?
You mean when did I actually decide?
Somewhere in the middle of
The Sean Parker Variety Hour?
He was right.
California's the place we've gotta be.
Is you Jed Clampett?
You guys got The Beverly Hillbillies in Brazil...
Yes, we got the show in Brazil,
it was genius.
What is your problem with Sean?
He doesn't bring anything to the table.
He doesn't have money,
Dustin's a better programmer...
He's got connections to the VCs.
We don't need VCs, we need advertisers
and I've got connections to the VCs.
- The real players and...
- Look.
As someone who's really embarrassed
the company in a bad way...
It was the Winklevosses, Mark!
Hang on.
Hit refresh.
150.004
150.000 members, Wardo.
Congratulations, dude.
Congratulations.
You don't think it was strange?
That he was followed by private detectives?
Who came up with nothing.
Enough to get him out of the company.
The drugs, the girls...
We don't know any of that's true.
You can read about it.
I can read about your torturing birds.
Since when reading something about...
Don't fish eat other fish?!
The marlins and the trout?!
What's he talkin' about?
I'm interviewing interns at 10
tomorrow night in the CS lab.
Get on board with this man, you know...
I don't really know what else to say.
What's goin' on?
They have 10 mins to get root
access to a Python web server,
Expose its SSL encryption and then
intercept all traffic over its secure port.
They're hacking.
All behind a Pix Firewall Emulator.
But here's the beauty.
You know I didn't understand
anything you just said, right?
- I do know that.
- So what's the beauty?
Every 10th line of code written,
they have to take a shot.
And hacking's supposed to be stealth,
So anytime the server detects an intrusion,
the candidate responsible has to take a shot.
I also have a program running that has a pop-up
window appear simultaneously on all five computers...
The last candidate to hit
the window has to take a shot.
Plus every three minutes
they all have to take a shot.
Three minutes.
Can I ask, what part of the interns jobs
will they need to be able to do drunk?
You're right. A more relevant test would be
seeing if they can keep a chicken alive for a week.
That was mean.
Here...
What is this.
I opened a new account
and put $18.000 in it.
Will that get you through the summer?
Welcome to Facebook.
- $18.000
- Yes.
- In addition to the $1000 you'd already put up.
A total of $19.000 now.
- Yes.
- Hang on.
I'm just checking your math on that.
Yes, I got the same thing.
May I continue?
After expressing misgivings about Mr. Zuckerberg taking
the company and moving it to California for the summer,
Why did you turn around and put
$18.000 in an account for his use?
I figured we were partners.
I wanted to be a team player.
I figured Mark, Dustin and the
new interns could work on the site.
While I was on generating
advertiser interest in New York.
But mostly I figured, how much could
possibly go wrong in three months?
Go, go, go, go, go...
Aaargh...
- I didn't die.
- I know.
- I made it.
- You did.
Ok, ready?
That was like an eight.
That was like a two.
- It was better than that.
- Yeah.
- I'm ok.
- You sure?
Yeah.
Yikes.
That's the doorbell.
I didn't know we had a door bell.
Andrew get the door.
No, he's wired in.
That's gonna cut into the security deposit.
Andrew...
Not now.
Good boy
- Sean
- Mark.
- Do you live here?
- Yeah. Do you?
We were right across the
street, we saw the chimney...
Yeah.
Is anybody hurt?
No. You live across the street.
I'm Sharon.
This is my... Sharon. She lives across the street
and I was helping her move out, we saw the chimney...
Yeah, we had a zip line to the pool.
You came to California.
Yeah.
You made the right choice.
Here you go.
Sharon.
- I'm so sorry.
- No problem
I don't know you're gonna...
- Here you go.
- No, no, wait...
This house and this team are great.
It's exactly what it should be.
I'm Sean Parker.
Oh, he's wired in.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
Where's Eduardo?
He got an internship in New York.
Eduardo didn't come out?
I was crashing there for a little bit
while I'm taking care of some things.
But she's done for the summer
so she's back at her parents place.
Homeless rockstar of Palo Alto.
Alright.
What your plan for the summer?
Mark.
I'm sorry, I was looking
at the architecture.
I asked, "what's your plan for the summer?"
I hit school by the end of the summer.
- I'm going to the rest room
- Okay.
I'll go with you.
Your date looks so familiar to me.
She looks familiar to a lot of people.
What do you mean?
A Stanford MBA named Roy Raymond
wants to buy his wife some lingerie.
But he's too embarrassed to shop
for it at a department store.
He comes up with an idea for a high end place
that doesn't make you feel like a pervert.
He gets a $40,000 bank loan, borrows
another $40,000 from his in-laws,
Opens a store, and calls it Victoria's Secret.
Makes a half million dollars his first year.
He starts a catalog, opens three more stores
And after five years he sells the company to Leslie
Wexner and the Limited for four million dollars.
Happy ending, right?
Except two years later,
the company's worth 500 million dollars.
And Roy Raymond jumps off
the Golden Gate Bridge.
Poor guy just wanted to buy
his wife a pair of thigh highs.
W- Was that a parable?
My date is a Victoria Secret model.
That's why she looks familiar to you.
Don't be impressed by all of this.
I read your blog.
Oh, oh you don't know.
Thats for webprints.
You know how I started Napster.
Girl I love in high school.
Was with the co-captain of
The Varsity Lacrosse team
And I wanted to take her from him
So I decided to come up to next big things.
I didn't know that.
Napster wasn't the faillure...
I changed the music industry
for better and for always.
They might not have been a good
business but it piss a lot of people off.
And this now what your facemash was about,
they scare of me pal,
And they're gonna be scare to you.
What the VCs wanna to say, good idea kid,
grown up so we could take it from here.
But not this time, this is our time.
This time...
You gonna hand them a business card
that says,
I'm a CEO... bitch.
That's what I want from you.
Where the hell was Eduardo?
He's in New York.
Suckin' up...
- He's got...
- An internship.
The company's here.
A billion dollar company is here.
- Do you live and breathe Facebook?
- Yes.
I know you do.
Eduardo want to be a businessman
for all I know he's gonna be a good one,
But he shouldn't be in New York.
Kissing Madison Avenue's ass.
This isn't once of a generation holy shit idea.
And the water under
the golden gate is freezing cold.
Look at me face, tell me
I don't know what I talkin' about.
Do you ever thinkin' about that girl...
What girl?
The girl from high school
with the Lacrosse team.
No.
Hundred of schools by the end of the summer?
Yup.
I tell you what, gesture of a good faith.
While you're getting into a hundred schools,
I put you on two continents.
Two continents.
If you don't get a place to crash,
I think you should definitely
come in live with us.
Let's line-up some shots.
Excuse me...
- Yes, Sir.
- You can take this away and bring back the 1942.
Absolutely, Mr. Parker.
- Mr. Winklevoss.
- Tyler.
- Tremendous race.
- Thank you.
And this is my brother, Cameron.
Excellence.
His Royal Highness, Prince Albert.
Sir, this is Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss.
Of course. Brilliant race.
I've never seen a race that close.
Yes, Sir.
Of course.
My grandfather, Jack Kelly, was one
of the premiere rowers of his day.
I've been coming to Henley for 30 years.
And I've never seen the race that close.
Have you seen a race that close?
No, your Highness.
Mile and a half races are more
commonly won by a boat length or two.
Yes, that's absolutely right.
Brutally close.
May I introduce my team mates...
I'm sorry you have to excuse us...
Until the Beijing.
So you flew out here to see that?
Wouldn't miss you brother.
How was the royalty?
I just want him to tell
me couple more times,
How close the race was just brutal,
brutally-brutally- excruciating.
Cam. The guy's the prince of a country the
size of East Hampton. Relax. Its fine...
- Boys.
- Dad
Mr. Winklevoss.
That was a tough beat.
I'm sorry You and Mom flew
all over here to see that.
Don't ever apologize to me for losing a race like that.
Don't ever apologize to anyone for losing a race like that.
Boys.
Mr. Kenwright.
Dad, this is Mr. Kenwright,
head of the host family this week.
Pleasure to meet you.
Good to meet you.
I just had a phone chat with my daughter.
She told me that she and her friends
are all talking about the race,
Which they just seen by the computer.
A new website called Facebook.
Do you have this in America?
I'm going to find your mother...
is it something wrong?
Your daughter doesn't go to school in States?
No, no. Cambridge. Majoring in French Literature,
though I wasn't aware these was such a thing.
They have Facebook at Cambridge?
And apparently Oxford and the London School of
Economics because that's where her friends are.
It's awesome.
Good race, boys.
I'm gonna go to rest room.
This is online.
I want to see it.
Stop it.
Stop it, Cam.
Knock it off.
I don't mind that we loss by
the Dutch today by less than a second.
That was a good race,
and that was a fair race.
And they'll see us again.
What I mind and what you should mind,
is showing up on Monday for
race which run on Sunday.
We tried talking to him ourselves,
we tried writing a letter,
We tried the Ad Board, and we tried
talking to the president of the University.
Now I'm asking you.
For the last time.
Let's take the considerable resources at
our disposal and sue him in a federal court.
Come on...
I need a real drink.
Screw it,
Let gut that friggin nerd.
That's what I'm talking about.
But check it out, I saw him today
Manningham, Mitchel Manningham,
my Chase Equity...
Are you guys using spike or ghost, miss?
We don't know, we're just
shooting at each other.
Use sweet kamikaze.
Like we know what that is.
I saw him getting into his Turbo Carrera,
and he saw me too,
I know he did.
Don't sweat it...
Bong hit.
Is anybody hear that banging?
You don't hear anything,
you are writing code.
Dude, somebody's at the door.
It's not a dish best serves cold.
It's best serves immediately and
I'm gonna call you back.
- What's up
- What's up?
Mark was supposed to pick me
up at the airport an hour ago,
I've been calling his cell.
He was on a 36 hour coding tear
so he took a nap for a couple of hours.
What happened here?
Not happened... happening.
The next big thing.
Wardo!
Hey man.
- Back to work.
- Ok.
How old are they, Sean?
It's not polite to ask.
Sean, how old are they?
You think you know me, right?
I've read enough.
You know how much I've read about you?
Nothing.
Wardo.
I waited an hour for you at the airport.
What time is it?
It's midnight. Or 3AM in New
York where I just came from.
You've gotta see some of
the new stuff we've got.
Hey, Dustin, show him the wall.
I'm just calling it the wall.
Forget the wall, tell him about
the meeting I've got set up.
- You know Peter Thiel?
- No.
No reason you should.
He just run a two billion dollar
hedge fund called Clarium Capital.
Why's he setting up meetings?
Thiel may want to make an angel investment.
I don't care if he's an actual angel,
why's he setting up business meetings?
You've had a long flight.
No, I've had long wait
on the Tarmac at JFK,
Then a long wait at the passenger
loading and unloading zone at SFO,
And in between there was a long flight.
I'm the business end of this company,
He's a house guest living here rent-free.
On a very generous grant from
Eduardo Saverin Foundation.
I heard about you big ticket advice,
Gerry's tuxedos, Harvard Bartending Course.
You're just one small step away from
bagging Snookies Cookies, I can feel it.
Can I talk to you alone for a minute?
Sure.
Bong hit!
How's it going? How's the internship?
How's Christy?
How's the internship?
Yeah.
Mark, Jesus, I quit the internship.
We've talked about this on the
phone, we... I quit on my first day.
I do remember you saying that.
So, how's Christy?
She's crazy.
Is that fun?
No. She's actually psychotic.
She's insanely jealous,
She's irrational and
I'm frightening of her.
Still, it's nice to have a girlfriend.
I do not want that guy representing
himself as part of this company.
You gotta move out here, Wardo,
this is where it's all happening.
- Did you hear what I just said?
- The connections, the energy...
Mark...
I'm afraid if you not come out here.
You gonna left behind.
I want, I want, I need you.
Out here, please don't tell me...
What you just say?
Its moving faster than
any of us ever imagine...
It's moving fast then Sean think...
Sean is not part of this company.
We've got over 300.000 members,
we're in 160 schools...
I'm aware of that.
Including five in Europe...
- I'm aware of that, Mark, I'm the CFO.
- We need more servers than I ever imagined...
We need more programmers.
And we need more money.
He set up the Thiel meeting.
He's set up meetings all over town.
He's set up other meetings?
Yes.
Without me knowing anything about it?!
You're in New York!
I'm in New York riding subways
14 hours a day try to find our...
And how's it going so far?!
What did you mean get left behind?
Can I help you?
I'd like to freeze this bank account and
cancel all existing checks and lines of credit.
May I see some ID please.
- Sean they will be right with you...
- No problem.
You know this is where they
filmed Towering Inferno.
That's comforting.
Guys... come at my back.
- She offer you some waters?
- Oh, yeah we're cool.
Come on in... You must be Mark.
Hi.
We took a look everything
and congratulations.
We're gonna start you off
with a $500.000 investment.
Maurice is gonna talk to you
about some corporate restructuring.
We'll file as a Corporation
in Delaware and come up...
With a stock structure
to allow for new investors in.
Now lemme ask you something.
Who's Eduardo Saverin?
Jesus chris...
When did you get back?
You scared me. I need you to knock.
When-did-you-get-back?
I got back this afternoon.
And when you gonna call me?
Chris... it was kind of a rough trip
and I was tired and...
Or answer one of my 47 texts?
Did you know I sent 47 texts?
I did and I thought that was
incredibly normal behavior.
Are you mocking me?
I brought you a present.
Why does your status say
"single" on your Facebook page?
What?
Why does your relationship status
say "single" on your Facebook page?
I was single when I set up the page.
And you just never
bothered to change it?
I...
What?!
I don't know how.
Do I look stupid to you?
No. Calm down.
You're asking me to believe
that the CFO of Facebook,
Doesn't know how to change his
relationship status on Facebook?
It's a little embarrassing so you should take it
as as sign of trust that I would tell you that.
Go to hell.
Take it easy.
You didn't change it so you could screw those
Silicon Valley slut every time you go out to see Mark.
That is not ever remotely
true and I can promise you...
That the Silicon Valley Slut don't care what
anyone's relationship status is on Facebook.
Please open your present.
Your phone does work.
It's Mark.
Okay, this is gonna be tricky.
Open your present. It's a silk scarf.
Have you ever seen me wear a scarf?
This'll be your first.
You froze our account?
I did.
You froze the account.
I had to get your attention, Mark.
Do you realize that you
jeopardized the entire company?
Do you realize that your actions could've permanently
destroyed everything I've been working on?
WE've been working on.
Without money, the site can't function.
Ok let me tell you the different between
Facebook and everybody else, we don't crash ever.
If the servers are down for even a day,
our entire reputation is irreversibly destroy.
Look...
Seriously, I think Friendster prove that!
Even a few people leaving would
reverberate through the entire user base.
The users are interconnected,
that's the whole point!
College kids are online because
their friends are online.
And if one domino goes,
the other dominoes go!
I'm not going back
to the Carribean Night at A-E-Pi.
Holy shit...!
What's wrong with you!
Did you like being nobody?!
Did you like being a joke?
Do you wanna go back to that?!
Hang on, hang on...
That was the act of a child, not a decent man.
And it truly wasn't the act of a friend.
You know how embarrassed I was
when I tried to cash a check today?
I'm not going back to that life.
Maybe you were frustrated.
- Maybe you were angry,
- I was.
But I'm willing to let bygones be
bygones because I've got a good news.
Look, I'm sorry.
I was angry and maybe it was childish.
But I had to get your attention.
Eduardo, I said I've got some good news.
What is it?
Peter Thiel just made an angel
investment of a half million dollars.
What?
half million dollars
And he's setting us up in an office.
They want to re-incorporate the company,
They want to meet you and they need
your signature on some documents.
So get your ass on the first flight
back to San Fransisco. I need my CFO.
I'm on my way.
Wardo.
Yeah.
We did it.
Wardo,
You're going back there already?
Yes.
And also I'm breaking up with you.
Four documents. These first two are
common stock purchase agreements,
Allowing you to buy stock in the
newly re-incorporated Facebook
as supposed the old share
which is now worthless.
The third is the exchange agreement,
Allowing you to exchanges
the old shares for new shares,
and then finally voter
holding agreement.
How many shares of stock will I own?
1.328.334
Jesus Christ.
That's a 34,4% ownership share.
Why they increase from the original 30%?
Because you may need to dilute it
to award shares to new investors.
I love working with business majors.
Economics.
You should know that Mark's already
taken his percentage from 60 down to 51.
Well, Mark doesn't care about
money and he needs to be protected.
Dustin Moskowitz owns 6,81%,
Sean Parker 6,47%
I can live with that.
And Peter Theil 7%
Would you like to use my pen?
Eduardo?
Can you please repeat the question?
No. It was an outrageously
leading question, the first time.
Now you want to hear it twice?
Would you re-read that please?
Go ahead.
And when you signed these documents,
Were you aware that you were
signing your own death certificate?
No.
It was insanely stupid of me not to have
my own lawyer look over all the... uh,
In all honesty I thought
they were my lawyers.
I was your only friend.
You had one friend.
My father won't even look at me.
Okay. Eduardo. Did Mr. Zuckerberg saying
anything to you after you signed the papers?
There was a lot of handshaking
and a lot of congratulations.
He'd already told me he wouldn't be coming
back to school for at least a semester.
So we were saying goodbye for a while.
And then before I left,
he said...
But you gotta come back.
Somewhere around the end
of November or early December.
Peter wanna throw us an amazing
party when we hit a million members,
It's gonna be out of control.
You gotta come back for it.
A million members.
Yeah.
The algorithm on the window at Kirkland?
Yeah, I'll be here.
- You sure about this?
- You're 20 mins late.
You're gonna walk in there and say you overslept
and you didn't have time to get dressed.
They're gonna pitch you.
Chase equity is going to pitch you.
They're gonna beg you to take their money.
You're gonna nod, you're gonna nod, you're gonna nod
and then you're gonna say, "Which one of you is Ralph"
No, not Ralph... No Manningham.
Which one of you, Mitchel Manningham?
And he'll say I am.
Then you'll say, Sean Parker says "F*ck You."
Walk out.
Okay.
In late November I got the e-mail from Mark
telling me to come out for the millionth member party.
What else did e-mail say?
It said that we had to
have a business meeting.
That Mark and Sean had playing some
kind of revenge stunt to Chase Equity.
Manningham was so impressed that he was makin'
an investment offer that was hard to turn down.
I went out to California and I
went straight to the New Offices.
I didn't know whether to dress for the party or
the business meeting so I kinda dressed for both.
But it didn't matter.
Why not?
Because I wasn't called
out there for either one...
What were you called out there for?
An ambush.
Mr. Saverin. Hi...
At first I thought he was joking,
giving me more contracts to sign.
But then I started reading.
What is this?
Well, as you know we had
some new investor that...
What is this?
Mark...
MARK...!
- He's wired in.
- Sorry
He's wired in.
- Is he?
- Yes.
How about now, you still wired in?
Call security!
You issued over 24-million
new shares of stock.
You were told that if new
investors came along...
How much your shares are diluted?
How much are his?!
What was Mr. Zuckerberg's
ownership share diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What was Mr. Moskowitz's
ownership share diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What was Sean Parker's
ownership share diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What was Peter Thiels's
ownership share diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What was your ownership
share diluted down to?
Point-zero-three-percent.
You signed the papers.
You set me up.
You blame me because you were
the business head of the company,
And you made a bad business
deal with your own company?!
It's gonna be like I'm not part of Facebook.
It won't be like you're not a part of Facebook,
You're not part of Facebook.
My name's on the masthead.
You may wanna check again.
This is because I froze the account?
You think we were gonna let you
parade around in your ridiculous suits,
Pretending you were running this company?
Sorry, my Prada is at the cleaners,
Along with my hoodie and my 'F*ck You' Flip-Flops,
you pretentious douche bag!
Security is here.
You'll be leaving now.
I'm not signing those papers.
We will get your signature.
Tell me this isn't about me
getting into the Phoenix.
You... you did it. I knew you did it.
You planted the story about the chicken.
I didn't planted the
story about the chicken.
What he talking about?
Seriously, what the hell with the chicken?
And I'll bet what you hated the most,
They said they identified me
as a co-founder of Facebook.
Which I am!
You better lawyer-up, asshole,
'Cause I'm not comin' back for 30%
I'm comin' back for everything!
Get him outta here.
It's okay. I'm going.
Hang on...
Almost forgot.
Here's your $19.000.
I wouldn't cash it though.
I drew it on the account you froze.
I like standing next to you, Sean.
It makes me look so tough.
That's it. That's our
show for tonight, people.
Look, I want to see everybody here
get geared up for a party.
We're gonna walk down to the
club like it's the Macy's Parade.
Mackey, put it up on the big
screen, we've gotta almost be there.
- You alright?
- Yeah.
You were kinda rough on him.
That's life in the NFL.
No. You didn't have to be that rough on him.
Sean...
You didn't have to be that rough on him.
He almost killed it!
I'll send flowers.
Speaking of flowers, I'm putting together
a party after party at Kappa Eta Sigma.
Ashleigh there's a sister.
Ashleigh.
The Intern.
I know who she is.
Are you guys?
Ashleigh and me... no...
A little bit.
Why?
Excuse me, Mark.
We were just talkin' about you,
You're doing a really good job.
Thanks. I appreciate that.
This came in for you.
Put on my desk.
What's the package.
Nothing.
Mackey...
Yes, Sir.
Refresh!
And you need a hugger, I know.
1 millions, who's got champagne?
The next transformative development
of picture sharing application.
A place that you view picture
and go share with your social life.
It is the true digitalization of your life.
You don't just go to a party anymore,
you go to a party with your digital camera,
And then your friends re-live the
party online. And tagging. The idea...
Would this be easier without the bra?
It's worth finding out.
Stop the music, now!
I've spent hours...
watching what people do when they log on
They check friends status update,
That's weird, why the music off...
Checked to see which of their
friends had changed their profiles,
Changed their photos and mostly...
Seriously, what happen with the music?
We lived on farms, and
then we lived in cities
and now we're going to
live on the internet.
Sean. Stop, I think
something's goin' on downstairs.
Please... Time to go home!
Party is over.
It's the cops!
Shit.
Good to see you officer...
What can I do for you.
What's goin' on?
Was the music too loud?
We were havin' celebration.
Miss, I need you to button your blouse.
I can tell them to turn the music down...
That's not mine.
Ok, we gonna need identification,
keep your hand where we can see 'em.
Anything else in your pocket,
I should know about?
No, Sir.
No.
- Don't be stupid now.
- I don't, I...
What this?
That's an Epipen.
- And this?
- That's my inhaler.
How old are you?
I'm 21
Lying only would make it worst!
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have lied.
- Hello?
- Listen, something's happen...
Shit.
It's alright, it's gonna be alright.
I've posted bond.
I wasn't doing anything.
I mean, I've got allergies...
- Interns...
- It was just a party
This gonna be news, Sean.
It's gonna be online, any second.
I know.
You know with an intern...
It's cool, I have it under control
I will get it under control.
I will call someone
and see what the next move is.
But this gonna be news now.
You don't think Eduardo was involve, do you?
- Do you think?
- No.
Or Manningham, one of them, somebody,
somebody sent the cocain there, 'cause it got in there.
You believe me, it's gonna be fine...
Right?
Go home Sean.
Mark...
We're done for the day
Yeah, I was just sittin'...
What happened to Sean?
He still owns 7% of the company.
All you had all day only was that salad,
you wanna get something to eat?
I can't.
I'm not a bad guy.
I know that.
Under emotional testimony,
I assume 85% of it is exaggeration.
- And the other 15?
- Purgery
Creations myth needs a devil.
What happens now?
Sy and the others are having
a steak on University Avenue.
Then they'll come back up to the office...
And start working on a settlement
agreement to present to you.
They're gonna settle?
Oh yeah... and you're gonna
have to pay a little extra.
Why?
So that these guy sign an
non-disclosure agreement.
They say one unflattering word about you
in public, you own their wife and kids.
I invented Facebook
I'm talking about what a jury.
I specialize in voir dire...
Jury selection.
What a jury sees when
they look at the defendant.
Clothes, hair, speaking style, likability...
Like-ability?
I've been licensed to practice
law for all of 20 months.
And I can get the jury to believe...
That you planted the story
about Eduardo and the chicken.
Watch, what else?
Why weren't you at Sean's
sorority party that night?
You think I'm the one
that called the police?
Doesn't matter, I ask the question,
now everybody's think about it
You've lost your jury
in the first 10 mins.
- Farm animals?
- Yeah.
I was drunk, and angry and stupid.
- And blogging...
- and blogging.
Pay them, on the scheme of things.
It's a speeding ticket.
That what Sy will tell you tomorrow.
Do you think anybody would mind if I
stay and use the computer for a minute...
I can't imagine that would be a problem.
Thanks.
I appreciate your help today.
You're not an asshole Mark...
You're just trying so hard to be...
Cameroon and Tyler Winklevoss received a settlement of
65 million dollars and signed a non-disclosure agreement.
They rowed for the U.S. Olympic Team
in Beijing and placed sixth.
Eduardo Saverin received an unknown settlement. His name
has been restored to the Facebook masthead as a Co-Founder.
Facebook has 500 million members in 207 countries.
It's currently valued at 25 billion dollars.
Mark Zuckerberg is the youngest
billionaire in the world.
# Wasior
# Mentawai
# Merapi
Floods - Tsunami - Earth Quake & Vulcano
#Pray FOR INDONESIA
Support and Contribute
ACT for Humankind
how to help:
www.pmi.or.id
Indonesian Red Cross
## Baby, your a rich man ##
"Baby, You're A Rich Man by The BEATLES"
Sub. made & uploaded
by npdv-iD
npdv.indoheroes [at] gmail.com