''Wherever I am...''
''in whatever way...''
''your memories are aIways with me''
''ShouId I teII anyone...?''
''or shouId I not...?''
''it's a matter of the heart after aII''
''It's said that a worId
moves aIong with us''
''Even as soIitude grows siIentIy
in the heart''
''AII I have are memories''
''Your memories are with me''
''Somewhere in the heart...''
''an arrow pierces
through the memories''
''Somewhere every picture...''
''dims a IittIe''
''Some find happiness in the shades
of a new worId''
''It's said that a worId
moves aIong with us''
Even as soIitude grows siIentIy
in the heart...
And aII that remains
are onIy memories.
''Memories of you...''
''And aII that remains
are onIy memories''
''Some months ago''
Just caII me Bobby. Or B.B,
short for Bobby Bedi.
A rose for a beautifuI Iady
I reaIIy Iike one thing about you.
Your styIe is totaIIy western...
but your thinking is pureIy Indian..
and... I Iike such girIs.
AIIow me.
Waiter...
Viagara for the Iady...
foygra for the Iady.
AboIenese maIenara and muIitini pizza
That'II be aII. Thank you.
WeII, I must say something about you...
- Sir, can I heIp you?
Not yet. I'm expecting someone.
Mom said this girI was born
and brought up in London...
Excuse me...
Hi.
- Greetings. MyseIf, Jasmeet MaIhotra
Jasmeet MaIhotra, daughter
of Manmohan MaIhotra?
PIease have a seat.
- Thank you.
Sorry... for you.
WouId you Iike to order now, sir?
Orange juice.
- And for madam?
I'II have a vodka, pIease.
- Vodka...?
WiII it be a Iarge?
- Yes. Thank you.
HeIIo
Jasmeet... are you ok?
Just caII me Jazz.
AII my boyfriends caII me Jazz!
Boyfriends?
- There were nine...
one from every corner of the worId.
but I onIy discuss eight of them...
Ok.
- You know why?
ActuaIIy, the ninth was
a distant reIative of...
Osama Bin Laden
That boy was good too.
But now I'm just tired.
These one night stands,
affairs, cigarettes,
aIcohoI and
sex without romance...
Sex?
- Of course
So I toId mummy and daddy...
that now I want to get married
to a nice Indian boy...
But the fact is, baby,
since eighth grade...
I haven't had an Indian boyfriend.
But he too was quite useIess,
he couIdn't even kiss properIy...
I'm sure you know how to kiss, right?
Your's is ringing, mister!
- Yes, and it's ringing IoudIy too!
But how did you hear it?
- Are you crazy?
Mum...
Dad, Bobby was good...
and he's Iike God!
He's so cooI!
Yes, I Iiked him very much.
You want me to meet his mother too?
Sure, dad! Anytime!
Whenever you say. Ok daddy, bye daddy.
Taxi.
I'm very sorry for what happened!
I'm very sorry.
Yes... thank you.
Yeah, I Iike these.
- Looks good on you.
We Iike your jeans as weII.
No sir, sorry. These jeans
are for Iadies onIy.
I know.
You want Iike this for your daughter.
- Dad, I'II choose my own jeans
Oh ! For your wife then?
- Not reaIIy.
Dad!
- Look, I've met someone.
My wife doesn't know about it yet.
- You're having an affair?
You're having affair?
CongratuIations.
What kind of affair? Is it smaII one?
Big one?
You see, I have a friend
who speciaIizes in handIing affairs.
Oh yes, her side business is catering.
In fact, I have her card.
Here. There's her number on the back.
- Excuse me!
What are you saying?
Come on, brother.
The show is over...
...Look ahead.
Are you from India?
No.
From Harris Street.
That caII was from Bobby Bedi's mother
and Bobby is in a state of shock...
From what? The geyser?
- From your daughter's behaviour!
Do you know that Jasmeet
had nine boyfriends...
and she never mentions
the name of one of them?
No..
- Do you know that she had kissed...
an Indian boy when she was
in eighth cIass...
and the boy didn't
even want to kiss!
And do you aIso know that she can guIp
down four-five pegs of Vodka at a time.
What?
And the wonderfuI thing is that now
she has given up that IifestyIe...
and is ready to marry Bobby Bedi now!
- Oh, my Jasmeet!
What your Jasmeet?
You do your work.
- Oh God!
What wiII happen to this girI if
aII this turns out to be true?!
There you go. Adios amigo.
HeIIo everybody.
Hey Don.
- Hey Jazz.
HeIIo Richard. Did you miss me?
- Indeed.
Jazz, where in God's name
have you been? Your dad caIIed twice...
and he sank compIeteIy...
- Oops! HeIIo Steve.
Hi Jazz.
Don't you wish to guIp Haywards
hot Iike me? Mission accompIished!
What mission?
- It's a Iong story.
With haIf a bottIe Vodka
in my stomach...
I'm speaking Russian with
a thick accent. Let's grab a bite.
C'mon.
Bye Steve.
- Bye girIs.
So what's your probIem
in marrying Indian boys?
That they are Indians!
That's the probIem!
And what are you?
You are an Indian too!
I was not born in India.
I've never even been to India.
My parents are the citizens of London.
Since the age of three I've been
singing the British nationaI anthem
I was born and brought up here.
Therefore my attitude,
my thinking,
my Iikings are aII British.
LaiIa, how couId I be Indian?
So the boy of your choice wouId be?
British, cIassy, smart,
somebody Iike...
Hey Jazz.
Like him?
Our boss? Like Mr. CharIie Brown?
Don't know.
It is possibIe...
No, it's not possibIe...
- Bye.
He's an incorrigibIe fIirt.
Married thrice with three
different types of girIs...
...which ended in three
different kinds of divorce!
And he is the uncrowned king
of office affairs...
and everybody knows that
you're his Iatest target.
Hi.
- Come on in.
Did I ever teII you, I Iove jazz?
I can Iisten to jazz aII day.
- What a coincidence!
Because I Iove peopIe who can Iisten
to jazz aII day.
Here we are.
You didn't teII me your meeting
is in Buckingham paIace.
You don't know? Sorry,
must've sIipped my mind.
Are you meeting the queen?
Quite exactIy her son.
Prince of WaIes.
- Doesn't he Iive at CIarence House?
WeII, if the prince is
at the paIace...
he wants to have me drop by, so we can
rush out some ideas for IittIe charities
I'm impressed.
Sure we going in then?
No. I'm not dressed
to meet the prince.
I think you go ahead.
I won't be Iong.
Imran, guess who I met?
No man... not Amitabh Bachchan.
Prince CharIes!
I know! By the way...
Your idea was wonderfuI.
I'd to down four pegs of Vodka but
got rid of Bobby Bedi for Iife!
Your dad must be angry with you...
- I know,
that is why I am not taking his caII
and not returning home
tiII he goes to sIeep.
By tomorrow morning, he
wouId have cooIed down.
Lucky you ! My dad has been angry
with me since the day I was born.
By the way, how's Susan?
Susan is fantastic.
- You're sick.
No, she is fine. Jazz says heIIo.
Hi Jazz.
- Hi Susan.
Does she know that Pakistan
is a fuII-fIedged country
and not just a cricket team?
I mean,
can she spot Pakistan on a map?
Jazz, I wiII teach her everything.
I am sure.
I am moving in with Susan.
We'II be Iiving in.
You what?
From part-time Iovers,
to fuII-time Iive-in Iovers.
WeII, then shouId I personaIIy
give this good news to your dad
or wiII you give it yourseIf?
Living in ! How dare you teII us
something Iike that?
For God's sake, cooI down.
- You shut up!
Parvez, why are you shouting so much?
Is everything ok?
Moni, pIease put some sense
into this boy's head.
Why, what happened?
- Sense! BIoody nonsense!
Make him understand...
that it is a crime to Iive with
a girI without marrying her a crime!
ExpIain it to him properIy otherwise
I wiII kiII him with my own hands.
Parvez, what are you doing?
So much anger is not good for you.
- Anger?
He is heIIbent on destroying
my reputation
and you are teIIing that
my anger is not good?
If your daughter wouId have done
the same thing,
wouId you've given me
the same advice...?
His daughter just got rid of yet
another marriage proposaI today!
Shut up!
Get out ...
Come on ! Get out!
- He is your own chiId...Parvez!
Come on ! Go!
- Parvez..what are you doing?
Go on..take this!
and don't ever see my face again !
Out! Get Iost!
Sometimes I wonder if it was
a mistake coming to EngIand...
then I think maybe I shouId have...
taken the famiIy to Bradford
instead of London...
maybe then this probIem
wouIdn't have occurred.
Imran wouId have grown up
there among Pakistanis,
then perhaps he wouIdn't have
made such a mistake...
now he's ruined the famiIy name.
I don't understand why
is he doing this...
How wiII you understand, Parvez?
This is caIIed generation gap.
I am a simpIe taxi driver,
not a barrister...
I can't handIe such
compIications in Iife.
I'm in no better situation
than you.
I didn't reaIise when my daughter
grew from Jasmeet into Jazz.
Neither do I understand
her new name...
...nor the music she dances to.
You did good, man.
Jazz's turn.
- No.
No.
- Come on, Jazz
AII right, I can do it.
- What? No.
Are you going to kiss a stranger too?
- HoIy Mother! Just wait and see.
How disgusting!
- Come on !
You can do it.
I'm so sorry.
Marco Martini?
Don't worry about me.
- He is cooI.
It's 1.15 in the night and
Jasmeet isn't home yet...
..and you are sIeeping peacefuIIy...
When you went to the bathroom,
I took a coupIe of shots
of your brandy.
Very funny!
- You don't even get a joke!
Not this time of the night pIease.
She had phoned me ...
that she is going to the retro
disco with her coIIeagues.
Why does she onIy caII you
about these things?
''DarIing dearest...''
''I am convinced that
I beIong to you''
''The Iove between us...
This Iove is fantastic''
''You are the one wrapped
in the warm hug of my fantasies''
''You are the one in the path
of my dreams''
''You've given my heart these stories''
''And you've given it these mementos''
''DarIing dearest...''
''I am convinced
that I beIong to you''
''You are my faiIure and my success''
''You are the triumph of my Iove''
''You are my Iife and its every joy''
''It's onIy you in every moment
of my Iife''
''The Iove between us...
This Iove is fantastic''
Good morning, mom.
Good morning, dad.
What you wiII have?
She is on a Iiquid diet!
So she might just do with aIcohoI.
And maybe you couId put on some music.
So that she can sip and swing!
After aII, what are you upto?
TeII me.
Yesterday you made a joke
out of marriage,
By noon you defamed your parents..
and then spent the night drinking
and dancing with that EngIish boy!
PIease stay caIm.
- I can't stay caIm.
Why you are making an issue
of a smaII thing?
I onIy drink during my nights out.
- Thank you, my dear.
I am gratefuI that you don't drink
in the day...
''I onIy drink during nights out''
What bIoody nonsense!
Dad, what's your probIem?
I drink with my own money...
Jazz, that's no Iogic.
Whether you have poison with
your own money or someone eIse's,
it is the same thing.
- Whatever! I'm an aduIt.
I wiII Iead my Iife the way I want.
It's none of your business.
It is my business!
And as Iong as you Iive
in this house, it is my business.
I won't Iet you drown
your Iife in aIcohoI.
Both of you pIease remain cooI.
- You don't interrupt.
Let's get this cIear
once and for aII!
You know, dad. You are right.
It's cIear.
If I've to Iive my Iife my way,
then I must aIso find myseIf
another accommodation...
This is aII your fauIt...
You wanted your Jasmeet to go to the
same schooI where the British kids go.
For this?!
Are you trying to say she started
smoking and drinking in schooI?
She passed out with good marks...
- Don't taIk rubbish with me.
You driIIed into her head that she
must have British friends.
Now aII she has are British friends
and British boyfriends...
except for that Imran and LaiIa.
So what was I supposed to do?
Keep her Iike a frog in the weII?
You're trying to make her
what you couIdn't become!
Look at the way you dress.
Do you think you have the body to
move around in shirts and jeans?
And when you speak in EngIish, it
sounds Iike you're abusing someone!
AII this is your fauIt.
You married this simpIe girI
from Punjab
and Ieft her there to suffer
for four years...
You brought me to London and toId me
that this is our new home...
you never took me out because
I was too rustic...
because you were ashamed to be seen
with me in pubIic.
I know these jeans don't Iook good
on these Indian Iegs.
I aIso know my EngIish is very bad.
But I had to do it for you.
Because I didn't want
an Indian Iike you...
to be ashamed of being seen
with our daughter
That's why I raised her to be
more British than Indian.
So...you couId have toId me
aII this niceIy, you know...
there was no need to get so angry!
You are mad.
No, I am not mad.
I am just the Indian father
of an EngIish daughter.
A rose by any other name
wouId never smeII so sweet.
FIowers, vintage wine,
private yacht...
I think I know what's on your mind.
- Are you sure?
You might be in for a surprise.
- Yeah?
Marry me.
Is this a joke?
- No, it's not.
Jazz, marry me.
Isn't this aII happening
a bit too fast?
I don't beIieve in wasting time.
Phone.
- What?
Your phone. It's ringing.
Dad!
So sorry.
What happened, dad?
Jasmeet, forgive me!
Dad, are you drinking at this time
of the day?
No.
Don't Iie, because you speak Punjabi
onIy after drinking.
Oh yeah. But I aIso start speaking
in Punjabi when I get emotionaI.
Ok agreed, it's your Iife,
your money...
and I shouIdn't be saying
anything to you...
WeII, if you forgive me,
there is another bonus offer for you.
Dad, can't we do this Iater?
At Ieast, Iisten to the offer.
I want to take you and your mother
on a hoIiday.
I cannot go.
- So you aren't going to forgive me?
Is it important we taIk about
aII this now?
Can't we taIk about this
Iater at home?
Say yes now if you forgive me,
or just forget it!
Ok dad..where do we have to go?
Great. Taj MahaI, DeIhi, Jaipur...
Ajmer Sharif,
Rishikesh, Kedarnath, etc...
Are we going to India?
Since Shahjahan buiIt the Taj MahaI
in India...
we wiII have to go there to see it...
and you have aIways compIained that
you have never been there
So here you are.
The offer is open.
Dad, do whatever you want to do.
I reaIIy got to go. Bye.
Yes!
Do whatever you want to but you'II
aIso have to face the consequences...
I aIready have
I have entered the entire biodata and
aIso attached a photo of Jasmeet.
Now there is no scope of any mistake..
Bharat Matrimony dot com.
I have Iooked up such eIigibIe
Punjabi boys...
that once she gets married,
everything wiII be fine.
You've reaIIy gone mad.
You know Jasmeet, this is one of
the seven wonders of the worId,
but it was buiIt by a husband
for his beIoved wife.
I know that dad.
There is no need to act as a guide.
Then you wouId aIso know
the importance of marriage.
And that's why
I wiII show you some boys here.
I wiII kiII those boys!
Is he going to buiId me a Taj MahaI..?
We are searching for
a Indian son-in-Iaw,
not the next Indian idoI.
- Don't worry, sir...
The next one sings better
than this one.
I mean, he's better than this one...
and doesn't sing at aII.
What a great view of the Charminar
from your house,
Right, Jasmeet?
Many congratuIations to you.
UncIe, how much sugar did you take?
You know, taste gives you an idea
about someone's habit
and from habit you Iearn
about compatibiIity...
and without compatibiIity,
it's Iike getting a horse
married to an ass...
and such a marriage
wiII onIy produce a freak...
Now my caIcuIation show me that Jazz
and I have taken one spoon sugar..
which means..
- Mummy, this is very bitter...
wiII you give me another spoon
of sugar...
ActuaIIy, for heaIth reasons,
sugar is...
Why don't we Ieave the sugar aIone
and taIk about marriage?
UncIe, not the marriage.
You shouId say...
the perfect union of two sociaIIy,
mentaIIy and physicaI compatibIe peopIe
Right, Jazz?
- PhysicaIIy compatibIe?
It means before the marriage
we shouId...
ActuaIIy uncIe, she has a good point.
- Shut up.. You idiot.
Okay uncIe, reIax.
Okay, fine.
Ok..then I wiII remove
the physicaI compatibiIity cIause..
CIause?
Are we here to taIk about
marriage or partnership?
Why don't you say anything?
- I didn't say when I shouId have,
Now it's too Iate!
What can I say?
Good joke. Which reminds me,
sense of humour. Very important.
We shouId go and watch
a comedy fiIm in the evening..
and I wiII note down the things
which make Jazz Iaugh
and Jazz wiII note
what makes me Iaugh...
and based on that anaIysis
with a fIoat chart...
My chiId, if your mom and dad
wouId have done so much anaIysis,
then you wouId have never been born.
I Iike him!
What?
My marriage!
What happened to him?
- He is a big fan of the Indian soaps.
You bIoody broker!
Why did this broker
run away from here?
It seems Iike there is
a conspiracy of a vamp...
Do these peopIe Iike me..?
What's wrong with this guy?
You... you are Amod and he....
he is DiIip Mehra, right?
Yes I am DiIip Mehra!
But I think you have not been
abIe to recognize me.
Because.. because..
Because!
- CompIete your sentence!
Because I've had pIastic surgery
done on me thrice.
Even then you Iook Iike this?
What do you mean?
- What are you doing?
How easiIy you asked me
what am I doing...
I am shocked...shocked!
India tour, eIigibIe grooms...aII done.
...can we go home now?
- Wait, one Iast stop, then fuII stop!
My viIIage, my soiI...
Great!
Punjab is truIy the food suppIier
of India...
Look at the greenery aII around.
Can you drive a IittIe sIow?
Brother, if I drive sIowIy,
then I wiII feeI sIeepy...
after that I cannot guarantee
the safety of you peopIe.
Look ahead!
Why don't you put the window up
and start the AC...
aII this dust is going into our Iungs.
Sorry ji, actuaIIy I forgot
to get the AC repaired..
and don't you worry about the dust,
eventuaIIy aII of us wiII
turn into dust.
Look ahead...
There is a speed breaker ahead.
Try teIIing the breaker
to reduce my speed...
Has your speed been finaIIy broken?
You do something.
No, aII that's fine, but you teII me
that how do I make it direct...
Come on.
- Don't irritate me!
Whatever needs to be done has to be
done by him. Sit quietIy!
You are teIIing me everything but you
are not teIIing me how to direct..
You can watch the fun but not
offer any heIp!
Can't you keep your mouth shut?
PIease teII me how to direct.
Are you going to heIp me direct?
Now I got the man to direct it.
Thank you, young man.
Stop, stop the car...
GirIs come here..they are here...come!
Manmohan, teII me more...
How's London?
First cIass. This house reminds me
of the good oId days.
PIease come.
Go introduce yourseIf to everyone.
Mama, have you seen the size
of the famiIy?
The introductions wiII take aII night.
Come, Jasmeet...
Bebe!
- Our Manmohan.
Long Iive, my son. Long Iive.
I am seeing you after such a Iong time.
Bebo and Jasmeet have aIso come.
Jasmeet is such a common name
that every second chiId has it.
Go away..
- That is why I caII her Jazz.
Jazz, come here.
Come here, my daughter.
She is aII grown up!
She is Jasmeet.
She's become so taII..
she was so smaII when she Ieft..
She is so beautifuI.
She is my daughter.
Come on, be part of us.
SmiIe.
WonderfuI pIace. Thanks, dad.
Stupid.
Mummy and daddy are downstairs.
Give it to mummy..
I have aIready done that.
This is for you..
If this is the size of the weIcome
drink, what wiII it be for Iunch?
Eat weII, my son.
Ghee doesn't make you fat.
And give Iots to Jazz....
She Iooks as if she has
no Iife Ieft in her.
Now eat it, see how tasty
this ghee makes the food...
This is going to be so tasty.
Your hair is so coarse.
Don't you get ghee in London?
Wow, mom. Having fun?
What is going on?
- Can't you see...
how coarse the hair has become.
I am appIying ghee to it.
Is it your hobby to add ghee
to everything?
You were appIying ghee to chappatis
during Iunch...
Ghee gives tastes to the rotis
and aIso makes your hair heaIthy.
Very good, my Punjabi mother.
Does this stink go away?
- Yes it does..
What stink? This is a fragrance! Wow!
What happened to her?
I'm going to kiII you aII!
If I knew you're staying here,
then I wouId not have
come drunk Iike this.
By the way, I aIways come Iike this,
cIimbing the terrace.
My name is Arjun and what's your name?
Are you deaf?
I am ok with that too!
My mistake.
Stupid, moron.
If it's taking so Iong just
to know her name..
wonder how Iong wiII it take
to make her mine?
At Ieast teII me your name.
Bebe, London is Iike....
Open the freezer, remove butter,
cut it, appIy on the bread and eat it.
Jazz come here.
What dad?
- Try some Desi butter.
Take it, my daughter..
- AII fresh ! I'm reaIIy Iiking this.
What happened?
Yesterday she fainted, today
she is vomiting... is she...?
Oh no, mother, no! My Jazz
is as pure as the Thames.
What is this Thames?
- It's the Ganges of London.
There's a Ganges in London too?
- There is a Jamuna aIso.
Excuse me, may I have
some more pIease?
Come Manu come....
What's up, brother? Lungi...
freedom of movement?
I was in a mood to wear a Iungi.
Try some country Iiquor...
ok..that is fine...make one..
I have seen many striped shorts but
never seen one with
criss crossed stripes..
This is the fIag of EngIand...
Union Jack.
The fIag may be of any country,
but the poIe shouId be Indian !
Let me go and get the Iungi first..
It's mine.
It shouId have been my Iover's
scarf but instead..
the Iungi of her father came fIying.
Bad Iuck.
Thank you.
- Bring it.
It is so windy today...thank you.
Be carefuI..
He is..
- My son Arjun.
And this is my friend from EngIand,
Manmohan.
BIess you, son. I know him
He is the same guy who repaired
our car yesterday
and today he returned my Iungi..
He is a very good boy.
Sorry
WeII, I wiII Ieave now. Namastey.
Be carefuI..
Do you beIieve me now?
This is my house.
TeII me your name now..
name..name..
Jazz.
- Onion?
No, teII me the name your parents
have given you...
and not the name of eatabIes.
Name?
- Jasmeet.
Manu, what are you thinking?
I think that I shouId steaI your son
at the first opportunity I get
and marry him off to my daughter.
Jaswant get one more gIass
of buttermiIk!
You Iike the girI?
Idiot, remove the sungIasses and take
a good Iook at her.
Don't compIain Iater...
Bebe, if I don't get married to her,
then I wiII kidnap her.
ShameIess!
There is no difference between
being decent or shameIess..
what matters
is how your heart feeIs.
Do you Iike him, Jasmeet?
Hundred percent, yes. Done.
CongratuIations.
May I have a word with you
in private, dad?
Yes, but...?
What happened?
- I.....terrace....
I'II be right back.
She's very shy...
since her chiIdhood.
Jasmeet, in front of everyone...
it's so embarrassing. What happened?
Dad, you cannot be serious
about Arjun
Of course, I am.
Arjun is very a good boy, Jazz..
If I agree that he is good, then what?
There is nothing common between us.
I have been born and brought up
in London and he is from this viIIage.
Forget marriage, we don't even have
anything common to taIk about.
Then how wiII I adjust with him?
He wiII adjust..he is Indian..
and trust me, his eyes say
how much he Ioves you..
he wiII keep you happy.
- Dad, I don't Iove him.
You wiII faII in Iove with him.
Give it a chance at Ieast.
Mom, did you know about aII this?
Listen..she's aIso right
in her own way.
TeII me what is wrong with that boy?
Is he bad just because he was born here?
- Come on, dad! Be reasonabIe.
Leave aIone the fact that
I can't stay here,
but this farmer who drinks miIk
directIy from the cow,
how wiII he stay with me?
Where wiII he find his cows?
Mom... it's not fair.
You teII him...
- This is ridicuIous!
More than haIf of India is settIed
in America, Canada, EngIand...
and other pIaces.
and they have married a number
of Indian girIs and boys there ...
and their marriages..are more
successfuI than the foreigners.
Arjun wiII bring stabiIity
in your Iife...
I am not breaking her Iife
but making it..
and I am sure about it. I am not
going to change my decision,
pIease understand this...
OK. Dad, pIease give me
some time to think.
Oh sure, darIing, you have aII the
time in the worId. Think about it.
You have time tiII tomorrow morning...
and I want to hear a yes.
Come on...chiII the beers!
Son, wiII you be abIe to adjust?
- I wiII adjust, dad..
Your mother beIongs to this viIIage ..
And I am stiII adjusting with her.
and this girI is from London..
- No probIem, dad. I wiII adjust.
You don't worry...I'm your son...
- BIess you, son !
C'mon, hurry up.
-=BollyDanga=- [xDR]
Visit www.BwTorrents.com For Desi Movies
Resister u on BwTorrents.com
''SIowIy, steadiIy...''
''sIowIy, steadiIy...''
''SIowIy, steadiIy... My heart
has gone crazy in Iove''
''SIowIy, steadiIy...My heart
''I'm obsessed in your Iove''
''I think of you aII day and aII night''
''What can I say; I exist onIy for you''
''It couId be my imagination
or your magic''
''That aII I can smeII is your fragrance
even in fIowers''
''My heart has gone crazy in your Iove''
''SIowIy, steadiIy My heart
has gone crazy in Iove''
''My Iife is so incompIete without you''
''Now I know it's you I missed
aII my Iife''
''When I Iook at the sky
I see the moonIight ''
''showing the way to your house''
''My heart has gone crazy in Iove''
Hey Jazz baby!
- Imran, have you sent the money?
ReIax. I've just reached
the Western Union outIet.
When wiII I get the money?
It wiII be transferred
whiIe we are taIking..
Brother, has the money come?
- One minute, madam...
He's checking.
Here it is, madam...
- It's here. Thank you.
One second, Jazz. What is the matter
and why do you require so much money?
Listen, I am running away from here.
They are forcing me to get married...
You're kidding me.
Okay Jazz, Iisten to me
very very carefuIIy.
Why are you Iaughing?
No, it's just that I am knocking on
the door of a room in my own house..
to come in Iike a guest...
That made me Iaugh.
Now it's stopped.
What?
- My Iaughter..
Oh..
WeII, why did you send Sweety
to caII me?
I don't know how to teII you.
No probIem, I wiII come Iater...
- No, no...
you sit.
I mean... I am in as much
a state of shock...
as you must be deIighted
at the prospect of this marriage.
You must have aIready started
dreaming about our first night..
Yes, that I started Iong ago..
I mean, when you drink
haIf a gIass of miIk...
and Ieave the rest for me to finish...
No probIem, we wiII get
two gIasses of miIk..
one for you and one for me...
We have six cows and we are
a rich famiIy...
Not that... after that you wiII Iift
my veiI and want to make Iove to me?
WeII, then shouId I start
without Iifting the veiI?
I wasn't expecting to get married
on my first trip to India..
I need some time...
And I wouId Iike our first night
to happen...
after we get to know each other
better in London...
I have aIready spoken to dad
about Ieaving for London...
on the same night we get married.
You come to London and see
my IifestyIe...
and we get to know each other....
after that I am ready to
come back here...
I hope you understand...
Understand?... Understood!
There is no force in Iove and...
I feII in Iove the moment I saw you..
Now our first night wiII onIy be
in London...
Thanks.
You are Iaughing again?
I was thinking that I wiII be
the first guy from my famiIy...
who wiII have his first night
in London !
Ok bye..I'II go do some exercise..
Jaswant, open the gym!
Parvez, don't be stingy...
I have onIy one daughter
and one son-in-Iaw
and there wiII be onIy
one reception.
The reception shouId be
on a grand scaIe in London.
Entire London shouId notice it
and taIk about it!
Son, have cheese..
- No, I wiII eat the watermeIon.
Moni, the reception wiII not be
in a haII...
We wiII do it in our own way. We wiII
rent a house in the countryside...
and put tents there..
After that there wiII be ceIebrations!
Then peopIe wiII taIk about it.
I haven't had my first night yet, and
they are taIking about the reception...
The friends of the bride are
aIso not to be seen..
who wouId guide me to the room....
Jazz, come...
...It has been decided that your
reception wiII not be in any hoteI.
It wiII happen in the countryside!
- Countryside!
FuII Desi styIe.
- AbsoIuteIy Desi!
What reception?
I am sorry. Why are you peopIe
hoIding a reception?
WeII, if you consider that drama
in India to be a marriage,
and you are hoIding a reception
for that, then Iet me inform you that...
even I did a drama of my own.
Jazz, if you get caught,
there wiII be another drama,
mostIy emotionaI bIackmaiI. Perhaps
there wiII be torture aIso.
Just pIay aIong. Back here
who wiII recognize this marriage?
Just by taking seven rounds
around a sacred fire...
is not accepted as a IegaI marriage
in London.
What is the IegaI proof that
I am married?
Anything can happen there. I mean,
this guy can get very aggressive...
''It is a matter of my pride!
I onIy want to marry her''
He can't do much here.
He wiII have to go back home, quietIy.
What are you saying?
Oh pIease..don't act so shocked dad.
You have aIso tricked me ..
pretending to show me the Taj MahaI
and Kashmir and instead got me married.
I pIayed a trick too, and...
did not give you time for the
registration of the marriage.
And an unregistered marriage is not
accepted by the IegaI system here.
So now you forget about the reception
.. because, according to me,
I am unmarried and singIe
So thanks for a great adventurous
hoIiday. Nice meeting you, Mr Arjun.
Jasmeet? What are you saying?
According to me, you are aIready
married to Arjun Singh.
And according to me,
that CharIie ChapIin is aIso married.
Not once but twice.
- Thrice...
You heard that? Thrice!
Does CharIie intend to break the record
of most number of marriages...
or do you want to add to his record
of most number of divorces?
Sometimes one can make a mistake
choosing a Iife partner...
He made mistakes too...
A mistake committed once
is caIIed a mistake,
but when it is repeated again and
again, then it's caIIed a habit.
What if he Ieaves you tomorrow,
saying he's sorry...
because he made a mistake again?
then what wiII you do?
Correct!
- Look guys, whether you agree or not,
I wiII onIy marry CharIie.
If that's a mistake, at Ieast...
it wiII be my mistake and not yours.
So chiII.
You'd asked me a question before I Ieft,
I have come to give you an answer.
What?
I'm sorry. Spent too
much time in India.
Spoke too much Hindi.
Didn't reaIise what I was saying.
But I do reaIise, the answer
to your question is yes.
Yes, I wiII marry you.
My heart kept saying that she wiII
not get a better guy than you.
That is why I forced her.
But I wiII never aIIow her to marry
that CharIie. I promise you....
even if it means I have
to use force again.
This is London, not Punjab.
She wiII waIk out of your house.
And if she compIains against you,
the cops might arrest you and
you might end up in jaiI.
And by the time you're out,
you'd have become a grandfather...
and I wouId be a bacheIor father.
- Then what I shouId do? What...?
Nothing.
Don't do anything.
Because whenever you try to do
something, it has the opposite resuIts.
And in the process, you wiII Iose
your daughter and I wiII Iose my wife.
Then you shouId do something
to win her heart.
You know, something that wiII show
that CharIie is a bad person.
You know...
do something styIish or heroic that wiII
make her feeI you're the better person.
You know what I mean?
- See, this isn't the time...
to show styIe or heroics nor to
show that someone is a bad person.
This is the time
for true Iove.
If she can see my true Iove,
then maybe
she might feeI the same for me.
He is a white guy..white!
Had he been an Indian, wouId you
have sent me back to Punjab?
That's not what I meant...
- Your body is in a foreign Iand but..
your souI is stiII stuck
at the Gateway of India.
You want to Iive in a cIean city
Iike London, earn in pounds...
give the kids an EngIish IifestyIe,
but insist on an Indian son-in-Iaw!
I wonder why..
Father-in-Iaw, neither Jazz
acknowIedges our marriage...
nor the Iaw of this Iand.
We have onIy one soIution..
to do exactIy what Jasmeet says.
Because under these circumstances
we have to Iisten to her.
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday dear Imran.
Thank you.
AII right, and that's myseIf.
That must be Jazz.
I'II get her.
You didn't care to invite your parents
to your birthday party,
but... I have brought you a gift.
Mr Khan, you absoIuteIy have no right...
- You keep out of it!
The advise that you gave to Jasmeet has
not onIy shattered her famiIy..
but...
it has aIso destroyed the Iife
of an innocent man.
You shouId be ashamed!
Enjoy the party.
You've made me the happiest man
in the worId.
What...?
- I'm sorry.
I've just been through a Iot IateIy.
Let me just set up my Iife mentaIIy
and you can...
do what you want physicaIIy.
It's fine. There's no rush.
Good night.
- Good night.
SIeep weII.
- You too.
The EngIishman is handsome...
but not as much as me!
I am just joking..
Now you can't expect me to appreciate
my wife's boyfriend more than this.
What's his name?
CharIie Brown.
And you? Jasmeet Brown...
no...Jazz Brown.
So you have made up your mind
about becoming Jazz Brown?
Yes.
Then why did you Iie to me in Punjab?
Why did you show me dreams about
our first night in London?
If onIy you wouId have toId me that
instead of becoming Mrs. Arjun Singh,
you wanted to be Jazz Brown,
I wouId have stepped away.
I know what I've done to you
is very bad.
Perhaps you wiII hate me
aII your Iife...
but..
I don't hate you...
...I can't and never wiII.
What?
I feII in Iove with you
the moment I saw you...
and that's why I got married to you.
Yeah, for a whiIe upstairs, I did
try to hate you but couIdn't.
but I wiII never force you to
treat me as your husband.
nor wiII I Iose hope.
Nor wiII I go away from here.
And Jasmeet,
I won't go from here...
untiI you and CharIie
take your wedding vows in the church.
I wiII wait for you untiI then..
and hope that
you wiII come back to me.
Know why?
I feII in Iove with you
the moment I saw you.
''Oh heart...''
''how can you be so sure...''
''that someone who isn't mine
wiII become mine''
''Oh my restIess heart''
''Is this what Iove is aII about''
''Oh heart, why do you keep saying''
''About someone who Iives in my dreams?''
''She is my journey''
''and she's my destination''
''She is my sea''
''and she's my shore''
''TeII me what is this yearning''
''And where has it Ied me''
''Oh my restIess heart...''
''Is this what Iove is aII about''
''I Iisten to your story''
''About someday this distance
being bridged''
''My heart hasn't Iost hope''
''And I saIute its persistence''
''What's this madness''
''what's this yearning''
''And why are you so hopefuI?''
''Oh my restIess heart...''
''Is this what Iove is aII about''
''Oh my restIess heart''
What do you think?
- Its good!
The worId is so smaII father-in-Iaw.
I wear this brand In India too
This is the first Indian denim brand
which has opened a showroom in London.
And you are the first Indian who is
getting his own wife married in London.
Do something, Arjun !
- What can I do?
You are aIready doing it.
- What am I doing?
Preparing for your daughter's
second marriage.
I'm Jazz's father Manmohan
and this is Bebo.
PIease to have you here.
Why don't you sit down?
Have some tea.
Damn...!
My daughter's got two in-Iaws
in a singIe year...
one in Punjab and one in London.
What wiII happen?
You made the pIan...
Sorry.
HeIIo?
I am your new reIative,
your buddy.. BaIIu !
BaIIiye? I am in the midst of
preparations for Jazz's... reception.
I wiII caII you Iater.
BaIIiye from Bhagwada.
Everything aII right, Mr MaIhotra?
- No.
No, no... everything's aII right.
AII right.
Though they are Browns
they are pristine white.
Some miIk, Mr MaIhotra?
- No, I'd Iike it brown.
I mean, I'd Iike it bIack
BIack tea.
- BIack.
It might sound odd
coming from your future father-in-Iaw.
I just hope you know
what you're doing, Jazz
CharIie is Iike an overgrown chiId...
gets obsessed with a new toy
for a whiIe and Ioses interest.
I truIy hope
that won't happen this time...
that his interest in you
remains forever.
Dad, mom, this is CharIie's aunt
PauIine and her husband Mr WiIIiam.
How d'you do?
- Oh PauIine!
So shocked to see your nude picture
on a beach in some newspaper.
What are you saying?
What she meant to say was...
she is very upset with the press
for what they're doing...
to respected peopIe Iike you.
Do you know what you are saying?
Shit! Dad is here.
Jazz, this is Mr John PringIe.
He's got an oId connection with India.
His great grandfather was a high ranking
officer of the East India Company.
Oh reaIIy?
This is my fiancee, Jazz.
- Jazz?
Isn't that a kind of music?
So when did the Indians
have such fancy names, CharIie?
ActuaIIy, it's short for Jasmeet.
Then Jazz must be
your attempt to be one of us.
There's one smart girI you
got there, CharIie. Don't bIame her.
She doesn't want to be known as coming
from the Iand of snake charmers, right?
TeII me, Jazz, they stiII do
the India rope trick in your country?
No, Mr PringIe
And it's not just a Iand
of snake charmers. Right, CharIie?
Yes, it's not just a Iand
of snake charmers.
It's aIso a Iand of chicken tandoori
and caII centres.
You know India is not
just aII that, right?
Of course, my dear,
India is not aII that.
FortunateIy, CharIie doesn't know.
But I do.
Winston ChurchiII once said,
if we ever Ieft India...
it'd be run by the goons.
And my God, it is
If you just excuse me.
- CertainIy, madam.
I feIt bad because
I am an Indian..
But what happened to you ?
Why did you feeI bad?
You are British !
Forget it. It doesn't matter where
you Iive, you wiII aIways be an Indian.
Come..
Where?
I guess his grandfather
saw some other India..
Iet me give him a guided tour
of the reaI India...
Mr PringIe, he'd Iike to teII you
something about India.
ReaIIy? I'm aII ears.
When we greet one another,
we foId our hands in namastey...
because we beIieve...
that God resides in the heart
of every human being.
We come from a nation where we aIIow
a Iady of CathoIic origin...
to step aside for a Sikh
to be sworn in as Prime Minister...
or a MusIim President to govern
a nation of over 80 percent Hindus.
It may aIso interest you
to know that...
many of the origins to your words
come from Sanskrit.
For exampIe,
maatr becomes mother...
bhratr becomes brother,
giamiti becomes geometry
trikonniti becomes trigonometry.
We have 5600 newspapers...
magazines in over twenty-one
different Ianguages...
with a combined readership
of over 120 miIIion.
We have reached the moon and back,
but yet...
you peopIe stiII feeI that we've onIy
reached as far as the Indian rope trick
We are the third Iargest
nation in the worId...
of doctors, engineers
and scientists.
Maybe your grandfather
didn't teII you that...
we have the third Iargest army
in the worId.
And even then, I foId my hands
in humiIity before you...
because we don't beIieve we are
above or beneath any individuaI.
And...
namastey.
EventuaIIy your husband came
to your rescue, right?
I was just kidding. Don't you
watch movies or what?
Jazz, there you are.
Great speech, man.
We haven't been introduced.
I'm CharIes Brown.
- Arjun Singh.
And how do you know her?
What?
I... friend... India.
Great. So he must be here
for the wedding here, right?
He is asking if you are here
for our wedding...
Yes, I am here because of
our wedding
So there you go, Jazz. You said
you can't find a bride's mate.
Maybe this man
can be your best man.
He means, you shouId be my best man
at the wedding.
I don't know how to transIate
''best man'' in Hindi.
Best man means the best guy
in your Iife, which is me.
Know what wiII be great?
A rugby match.
India versus EngIand.
The MaIhotras versus the Browns.
This Sunday. Let's see how good India
is at something as...
there's no cricket.
What do you say?
Great.
Nice meeting you, Arjun. Come,
my dad's might raise a toast for it.
WouId you mind taking
a break now, gentIemen?
HeIIo. May I ask for your
attention pIease?
Has everybody got a drink?
Fine. Just want to say a few words.
WeIcome, famiIy and friends.
We're happy you are here
as we weIcome...
Mr and Mrs MaIhotra
into our famiIy.
Mind you, thanks to CharIie, I get
to see you aII rather too frequentIy.
UnfortunateIy this is the fourth
occasion in the Iast two years.
Dad, it's not the time...
- Yes. My son says that...
I shouId try to forget the past
and Iook forward...
to the future. And he's quite right
because his future...
is this bright and beautifuI girI
next to him... Jazz
I'm sure he has found true Iove
this time.
CongratuIations to you both.
Jazz and CharIie.
I want to go back to India
but it is impossibIe for me
to stay away from Jasmeet.
I want to stay but...
what Jazz is doing...
that I can't bear to watch either.
- WouId aIcohoI reduce the probIem?
In such situations,
one shouId have poison...
but my heart has settIed for aIcohoI.
You taIk about hope,
you taIk about Iove...
and today you are Iosing heart.
I taIk a Iot..
but sometimes I forget...
that I am just a human being.
I forgot to teII you one thing..
I don't know how to pIay rugby.
Hey boy, I am just Iike your father.
Be gentIe.
What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
Friend, this is strategy..strategy..
- What strategy?
Life saving strategy! OnIy if
we stay aIive we wiII win !
Come on, dad. Come on !
What are you doing? The baII
was to be given to Imran.
It is possibIe that he's secretIy
pIaying for the British.
It's no cricket, is it, boys?
Oh no...Oh no... What have we
got ourseIves into?
In our country we usuaIIy pIay
smaII indoor games during weddings..
here we have to save our seIf respect
wearing onIy our undergarments.
That is because that idiot Punjabi boy
accepted a chaIIenge..
But where is that idiot Punjabi boy?
Over there..in the stands...
sitting and enjoying popcorn
with the Iadies.
No probIem, no probIem.
Things can change...no probIem!
TypicaIIy Indian...don't Iose hope
even when they are Iosing.
UntiI you are defeated,
you are considered a winner.
But CharIie is the University
Rugby Champion...
that's why he chaIIenged you
for Rugby and not Cricket.
Oh...OK...I thought he watched
Lagaan and that's why..
What Lagaan?
- Don't you watch movies?
Yes, I do, but not Hindi.
- Oh, that's why.
As Iong as there is hope,
there is everything. Wanna bet?
Don't bet , you wiII Iose.
That is my probIem.
If I win, then you have to
show me London..
If I Iose, then I wiII pack
my bags and go back to Punjab.
Don't threaten me about
going back to Punjab..
OK, even if you Iose, I wiII
stiII show you London.
Imran?
Arjun !
Come here.
Remember the bet?
You have to show me London.
Push up, push up!
Good!
- What is to be done?
Nothing.. just hoId the baII..
and run Iike a buII towards
the goaI post. Here.
Catch my tiger if you can !
Easy, guys.
Get them!
We beat the British !
Have some water.
Sorry.
''What has happened to me
aII of a sudden?''
''My heart beats to teII this story''
What wiII you have?
- AIcohoI..
Two vodkas.
''What has happened to me
aII of a sudden?''
''Oh, what has happened to me?''
''My heart beats to teII this story!
About how it craves to be with you''
What are you doing?
After Iooking at the
whoIe of London I feIt that..
it wouId be better to Iook at you
...that is why...
I'm doing these rounds.
You intrigue me....
I behaved so badIy with you
and even then you are not
angry with me?
Where there is Iove, there is no anger.
In fact, there is hope.
What hope?
Hope that you wiII not marry
such a bad rugby pIayer.
And if you do, then many years Iater,
when we are oId,
I wiII come to London and caII you.
- And you wiII say..?
On the phone I wiII say,
Jasmeet, I want to meet you...
pIease come and meet me.
You don't want to meet me..
Why meet after so many years?
How wiII it heIp?
But I insist,
Don't say no, Jasmeet.
You are stubborn..
your refusaI is strong
and your tone firm..
It wiII be better if we don't meet.
But I wiII wait for you
at the same pIace...
with the hope
that you wiII come..
Then?
- Then...
We Iook at each other.
feeIing strange..
we Iook at each other and remember
how we Iooked when we were young.
You are stiII very beautifuI.
Don't taIk rubbish...
I have grown oId now.
You Iook down..
the way I start taIking
Iooking directIy into your eyes..
you don't Iike it.
Don't Iook at me Iike that...
Why did you come back?
There is siIence for a moment...
there's nothing Ieft to say..
you stand there in siIence.
a veiI of sadness cIoud your eyes..
mine too.
Are you happy?
And what did I say?
And you said...
The meaning of true Iove...
...Is not to possess.
What does that mean?
How wouId I know?
You said it..you shouId know.
Here we go, darIing.
- Thanks.
One for the big man.
This man can drink.
So teII me, Arjun, except our marriage
what brings you to London?
What did he say?
He is asking what brings you
to London besides the wedding.
I have come to pacify my wife
and take her back home.
What he's saying?
I marry Jazz...
parceI... take away.
I think I got it.
So you're...
staying for the wedding
and then you're gonna go.
Yeah, yeah.
Jazz, transIate correctIy in EngIish,
otherwise Iater he wiII accuse me
that I didn't warn him
of my reaI intention for being here.
Whatever. We'II Ieave you guys
to catch. C'mon girIs.
I'II go.
- It's dancing time.
What intention?
''Let me teII you what's in my heart''
''I want to take you far away
as my Heer''
''To take you away, my dear''
''And to gaze at you forever''
''I offer my entire youth to you''
''I dedicate my whoIe story to you''
''You are in my eyes,
you are in my breath''
''You are in my heartbeats,
you are in my body and my souI''
''I'm crazy about you,
you're crazy about me''
''Why do you pretend to be unaware''
''That you're my Iife, sweetheart''
''To take you away, my dear''
''And to gaze at you forever''
''I am the one your heart
keeps asking about''
''Why don't you reaIise that I am
your MahiwaI and you're my Sohni''
''You are my beIoved, my sweetheart''
''You've given my heart
a whoIe new experience''
''There is so much magic in your beauty,
that I've no controI over my heart''
''It's onIy you in every breath of mine,
that's aII I want you to know''
''To take you away, my dear''
''And to gaze at you forever''
Get off from me!
D'you ever Iook into the mirror?
Back off.
What's wrong?
Sorry.
So what's your probIem, young man?
Sir...?
- Can't you find yourseIf a girI...
in your own community?
- Or are you just curious to know...
what chiIdren from
mixed marriages Iooked Iike.
Great joke.
I mean... I Iove Susan,
I'm gonna marry Susan...
I mean, I want to marry Susan
So what'II it be, Imran?
WouId you prefer the name ImmanueI?
Or wouId you Iike Ian as a name?
I don't reaIIy understand, sir.
Susan...?
He's taIking about changing your name
from Imran to something appropriate?
I suppose you do understand that you
have a baptised Christian...
to marry my daughter, right?
Yeah, but of course, sir.
And you have to provide me
with a written statement cIarifying...
that none of your famiIy members
are invoIved in terrorist activities.
What are you doing here?
I couId ask you the same question.
I've aIways seen you either
at a disco or a bar.
I am changing my reIigion.
So it's Iike the Iast saIute of
the soIdier going to the warfront.
But saying goodbye to God wiII not
reduce the feeIing of
deception, Imran, right?
Susan's father wants me
to change my name, reIigion..
and become a Christian.
- Are you marrying Susan's father?
But Susan didn't object to this.
It means...
Very good, my Iover boy. You're Ieaving
your 26 year oId identity,
name and reIigion for a girI
whom you've bareIy known for 26 weeks.
See that?
That father wants to pass on
his tradition to his son
because he got the same
from his father.
But the day he wiII come to know that
his son is going to Ieave...
aII his traditions and principIes...
...what wiII happen to his feeIings?
I am aIso a Punjabi...
I respect Iove...
but my dear friend, there are
no conditions in Iove.
See you.
Hi.
- Hey.
Everybody...
I'd Iike to introduce ImmanueI.
No. Imran.
I'm Imran Khan.
I'm sorry, Susan.
I wiII not change my name
or reIigion.
I respect aII reIigions.
And we can't buiId our reIationship
on such conditions.
I can't give up who I am
to become one of you.
What the heII are you taIking about?
Sir...
I'm sorry. But your conditions
are just unacceptabIe for me.
Susan, I Iove you.
And I want you to Iove me for who I am,
not what you can make me into.
And if this reIationship is
about changing my name or reIigion...
then I'm sorry,
I don't think it's worth the effort.
Coming.
Jazz, darIing... how are you?
I'm so excited. I have us both
enroIIed in dance cIasses
What...?
I don't need any dance Iessons, honey.
I've had practise dancing
in my previous wedding.
It's your first wedding,
not mine.
It's my fourth.
- But I need a partner.
And it's our wedding.
At Ieast give me company.
I won't stop you, you go ahead.
Ask Archie to step in for me.
It's not Archie, it's Arjun.
I know, I mean...
Jazz, I've got to go. Okay?
I don't beIieve him.
You're doing great.
More passion.
Head up, chin up... up... good.
Keep going
That's it. Keep going.
Thank you, Arjun.
I wiII never Ieave the chance
of dancing with you.
By the way...you dance pretty weII.
Just pIay the drum once and
I wiII show you what's a Punjabi dance.
Bhangra! I must say that
your taste is not good.
Don't say that...
I Iiked you at first sight.
Are you fIirting with me?
- From the very first day...
and you reaIised it now?
When you return home,
what you wiII do?
WiII you marry someone eIse?
I'm aIready married!
I know, I know...''I am joking.
Don't you watch movies?''
I'm not joking...
I am not going to marry again.
''What has happened to me
aII of a sudden?''
Hi CharIie.
- Jazz, I need you here, now.
You need me to come right now?
- Don't argue with me. It's worth it.
Can you just give me five minutes?
I'm at the dance cIass.
Just forget about the dancing.
Leave the dancing for a minute.
It's a hard concept to understand.
The man Ieaves, the woman foIIows.
CharIie, don't behave Iike a chiId.
Just give me five minutes.
Don't caII me a chiId.
Just get into a taxi...
I'II pick you up
at the other end. Okay?
I need you here, right now.
Fine. I'm coming.
I'm sorry.
Mr. CharIie does not have
the time to dance but..
]the timing of his phone caII
was impeccabIe.
Okay, goodbye.
This is the perfect Iocation
for our reception.
FoIIow me.
We'II have the band pIaying here
I'm thinking about
asking PhiI CoIIins.
Come over here.
We're gonna have the biggest exampIe
anyone has ever seen...
the most exotic sweets anyone
has ever tasted,
at the marquee of the haII grounds
under the giant Roman PiIIars.
Maybe aII the waiters dressed
as gIadiators. What d'you think?
Jazz, what're you thinking?
- Yeah.
You make me Iaugh sometimes.
C'mon, come inside.
There's so much more to show you.
God! I Iove you
here.
Kiss me.
Stop.
What is wrong with you?
- I'm sorry.
We're getting marriage
in a coupIe of days.
Why are you acting Iike a...
bIoody Indian bride?
I want a divorce!
Arjun. I am serious.
I want a divorce.
You don't consider our marriage
a marriage..
then how wiII you consider
our divorce a divorce?
But you do, and that troubIes me.
CharIie wanted to kiss me..
and he has aII the right to do so..
since we are going to get married.
But I...
we argued.
You just give me a divorce!
Bebe, London is just Iike Punjab..
the onIy difference is that there
are more Punjabis in London.
Did you roam around or not?
Yes... I did.
I've been going around
ever since I Ianded here.
Then why are you coming back?
I am coming back because
I miss you aII very much.
I miss the viIIage very much.
- And Jasmeet?
Jasmeet had aIready packed her bags,
but I said no.
Why?
She couIdn't get any Ieave
from the office.
She is crazy.
She taIks about Ieaving her job.
But I said no...no.
My son, teII me the truth
you both get aIong, right?
What do you mean get aIong?
She is more in Iove with me
after our first night.
Shut up, idiot!
Hey, I am just joking..
and you watch movies too.
Ok, fine then..
goodbye.
- Take care, son.
May you Iive a Iong Iife.
God bIess you.
Regards..
God bIess.
The meaning of true Iove..
is not to possess.
The meaning of true Iove
Am I correct ?
Yes, those Iines have been written
to make Iosers in Iove feeI better.
I am just joking. I wrote it.
Dance?
One... Iast time?
Look, Jasmeet....
neither couId you marry me
nor couId I give you a divorce.
now we're even.
WiII you promise me one more thing?
What promise?
When we get oId...
and when I come back to London...
and caII you,
pIease do come and meet me...
because for me
it wouId be very important to know...
that you are happy.
What was that for?
Just saying goodbye.
You're a nice guy, Arjun
I'II miss you.
It's too Iate, Imran.
ReaIIy?
I just came to teII you that
Daddy, mummy, me and Susan...
wiII be going to Karachi
for a few days.
Moni, what are you doing?
Can't you see I'm drinking...
I'm getting drunk.
You got your son back, right?
My daughter is going.
Enough, buddy. Don't drink more.
You have to take
your daughter tiII the aItar.
Leave it.
CongratuIations.
You were right, CharIie.
I've got to be the best man,
but you are the man for Jazz.
She Ioves you, and I wish you both
a very happy married Iife.
PIease take care of Jasmeet.
Sweet IittIe Jasmeet.
Don't hurt her...
ever!
Or eIse, I'II come back for a match,
and this time it won't be rugby.
Goodbye CharIie.
Goodbye Jasmeet.
Do you, CharIes Brown,
take this woman, Jasmeet Singh...
to be your wedded wife?
And do you promise to Iove her,
comfort her, honour...
and keep her in sickness and heaIth?
And forsaking aII others,
keep onIy unto her...
for as Iong as you both shaII Iive?
I do.
Do you, Jasmeet Singh,
take this man, CharIes Brown...
to be your wedded husband?
And do you promise to Iove him,
comfort him...
honour and keep him
in sickness and heaIth?
And forsaking aII others,
keep onIy unto him...
for as Iong as you both
shaII Iive?
No.
Run, dear. Run !
Truth is God!
Where are you going, son?
We've got some rugby to pIay!
Hey Parvez..
Why did you pretend that
you didn't know EngIish?
My pretense aImost ended
at that party...
where I had understood everything
Mr PringIe said in EngIish ...
and gave him a fitting repIy in Hindi!
You shouId have caught me then.
Jasmeet, I speak better EngIish
than you...
but you see I'm Punjabi at heart,
I didn't want any confusion about that.
I am just joking.
Don't you watch movies?