ReSlaN MoHaMeD
Help me on my new www.Blurayz.org
Becca?
Oh... Hey Peg.
It looks so nice back here.
Well, I’m just, you know, trying to
get things back into shape.
Listen, I don’t know if you and
Howie are free tonigh
having a few people over for
dinner.
Oh, that’s very sweet of you.
I know it’s really short notice.
Actually, we have plans.
Oh. Oh, well.
But, uh, another time though. I
haven’t talked to Pete in ages.
Well you haven’t missed much. He’s
still the same S.O.B. he always was.
Oh God. I’m so sorry.
It’s okay.
I am so sorry.
No, it’s fine.
These stupid feet.
Well, have a great dinner, Peg.
We’ll do it next time.
Absolutely.
Say hi to Howie for me.
I sure will.
Goodbye
Mmmm. Smells good in there.
If Peg asks, we went out tonight.
Where’d we go?
We saw the Stoppard play.
Really?
Did we enjoy it?
Very much.
She asked us to dinner again.
She's just being nice.
You're more than welcome to go over
there.
And abandon your risotto?
Careful, Howie. The pan’s hot.
Hey...
I’m gonna hop in the shower.
Uh-huh. About twenty minutes.
Hello?
What time is it?
What’s going on?
You have nothing to say?
Thank you?
You were in a bar-fight
it wasn't a bar-fight
You were in a bar. Fighting.
It wasn’t a fight. Some drunk girlwas screaming
in my face, so I hit her and that was the end of it.
Well who was she?
I don’t know.
People don’t scream at you for no
reason.
Sure they do, you should get out
more.
God Izzy, it’s so... Jerry Springer.
What’s that supposed to mean? You
think I’m trashy?
You can’t keep doing this. You’re
not a kid anymore.
I didn’t know there was a cutoff
date.
Well there is. For acting like ajackass,
there’s a cutoff date...
I wanna stop worrying about you.
Hey, don't worry about me. She was
the one on the floor.
Can I stay with you tonight?
Danny, look at me when you come
back.
He’s getting used to it.
- Do you want any cake?
- Yeah!
Oh, do we have cake today?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, we do.
Oh, my gosh. And you really want
some?
Well, if it isn’t Ma Barker.
I’m sure that would be very funny
if I knew who that was.
Rick and I are gonna play squash.
I have my cell if you need me.
Squash. You go play squash, Howie.
You don’t even know what squash is.
I don’t care what squash is
Hello?
Yeah! Yeah.
I thought she was gonna kill me!
Yeah, I know. I think Auggie must
have told her.
Hey, I gotta go.
Mmm. Thank you Becca.
Oo, I like the way it cracks.
Of course you do.
So you did know that woman.
Oh my god! Why are you listening
to my phone conversations?
Are you sleeping with that girl’s
boyfriend.
It’s been over between them.
They’re just living together because of the rent.
Then why did she accost you?
Because she's a lunatic!
And Auggie told her I was pregnant
You are not.
You’re gonna love him. He’s a
really great guy. He’s a musician!
That's terrific.
He works, Becca. He gets work as a
musician.
How long have you known?
A few weeks.
Did you tell Mom?
Oh, come on. You told Mom before
me?
I had to.
Why didn’t you tell me?
Why do you think?
- I’m sorry, Becca. I know the timing really sucks.
- Hey, what can ya do?
I’m just glad you finally told me.
Debbie’s been driving me crazy with
these kitchen renovations.
The
counter-top negotiations alone...
I told you not to marry an agent
She still hasn't called, you know.
No, I know.
I don’t mean to be a pest about it,
but...
I just know Becca would
love to hear from her.
I know. I tell her, Howie. I do.
But she’s still...
I don’t know
freaked out, I guess.
It’s been eight months.
I know. I'll talk to her.
Thank you.
Hey, how are the kids?
They’re good. Emily's doing
ballet. Robby is in tee-ball.
Wow. Tee-ball.
Have you guys talked at all about
having another?
No.
It's a little soon.
Just be open-minded.
I’m here, aren’t I?
How’s it going?
Good.
Yeah, good. Hanging in there.
You sure?
Yeah. Yeah, um, we just...
found out that Becca’s sister is pregnant. So.
Howie.
What?
That can be hard, I remember when
my cousin got pregnant-
Yeah, it's not really a big deal
Okay. If you wanna talk about it though,
you know the group’s right here.
Yeah, I don't think so. "Hey
everybody, fresh meat."
Becca, be nice.
Doesn’t she remind of you of Lydia?
There was this woman in the group a
couple years ago
It was four. Four years ago.
Well it doesn’t really matter whenshe was here,
my point is that she reminds me of Lydia.
She reallywasn’t into the
support group model at first.
How long have you been in Group?
It’ll be eight years in June.
Oh, I didn’t... I didn’t realize
it was that long.
Yeah, we’re the veterans. You know
for us,
it’s a good way to touch base.
Everyone’s on a different schedule...
Of course.
She, uh, she visits me sometimes.In dreams.
And she tells me it’s okay. And she’s with God.
And we have good days. Then youthink that if you have
enough gooddays it might actually get better. But then...
It was her anniversary last week.
A year last Tuesday.
And it just starts all over again.
We just have to remind each other
that it was just part of God’s plan.
And we can’t know why. Only God can know why.
God had to take her. He needed
another angel.
He needed another angel.
Why didn’t he just make one?
Another angel. I mean, he’s God
after all.
Why didn’t he just make
another angel?
Just putting it out there...
I’d like to go.
I think we’re gonna go.
Is that alright?
Excuse us.
They’re talking, it’s their time,
and you have to respect that.
Come on.
I mean, you sit there for weeks and
you don’t say a word.
I’m sorry. I can’t stand the god-
freaks. You know that.
But they're not all like that.
Kevin and Gabby aren't.
No. Kevin and Gabby are
professional wallowers.
I mean come on? Eight years,
Howie.
Eight.
If that’s what you want to become, then...
Look, if you wanna take a break-
No, not a break, I'm done.
I know the Izzy stuff got under
your skin
Please don't do that. One semester of Psychology
fifteen years ago and suddenly you can analyze
Well Jesus, Becca
I just don't like the group. I
gave it a try, and it's not for me.
Okay. It’s not for you.
Thank you.
Do you mind if we not eat here?
Nothing’s really jumping out at me.
Taz! Stop! Come here and eat!
Come on!
Sorry. He’s not really dangerous.
Hey, eat.
Just kinda dumb
No, I know. He’s my dog.
Oh, you’re Becca! Of course!
I should’ve recognized you. I’m Auggie.
- Oh. Hi, Auggie.
- Hi
Oh my god, why didn't you tell me you were
coming over? I would've picked up the house.
That’s Auggie.
Yeah, we met. Is Izzy here?
Oh yeah, she's here.
She got fired from the Applebee's.
I was planning to bring it all down to Goodwill,
but now I'm glad I didn't.
Look at all these shirts,
and the sweaters.
I don't know, Bec.
They're in babyclothes for so long
before he could even fit into that
stuff.
It comes up very quickly. You'll see.
You’re gonna be happy I saved them.
Is he living here?
He has to. His girlfriend kicked
him out.
Ex-girlfriend.
She knew what I meant.
Did you see this one?
Cute.look at thay
But what if it's a girl?
I don't know, Then I'll give them to someone
else. You're gonna thank me.
A couple years worth of clothes here.
Think of the money you'll save.
It's not about the money.
Well it should be. You need to
start thinking about that.
Especially if the dad's a musician.
It costs a lot to raise a child.
It'd be weird, Becca. If it's a boy.
To see him running around in Danny's clothes.
I would feel weird about it.
Yeah, I’m sorry. Of course it'd be
weird.
It was a nice offer.
You’re gonna get a lot of clothes anyway Christmas,
Birthdays. You won’t have to worry about that.
It's probably a girl anyway. I'm a
little psychic about these things.
Remember I said Sheila was having a
girl? And Karen?
I think there's
a girl in there.
I hope there is. I mean i want a girl
i want as it's healthy obviously, but I
hope it's a girl.
Me too.
You want some coffee cake, honey?
I got some coffee cake in here.
I'm gonna take off. I promised
Howie that I'd pick up some dinner.
Mmm looks good though.
Here. Eat some cake.
When did Rick ever beat me in
squash?
Did he mention Debbie at all?
You can call her, you know. Get the
reports directly.
I don’t wanna call her. She should
call me.
I would have been there for her if god forbid
anything had ever happened to Robby or Em.
I wouldn’t have vanished the way
she did.
I wouldn’t.
Howie?
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Howie.
Turn around. Come on, you need to
relax.
You're shoulders are all knotted
up.
Yeah, well...
Forget about Debbie, and whatever
else is bothering you.
Ohhh, I see what this is. Dimmingthe lights
You’re trying to seduce me. Plyingme with liquor
It worked in college.
That’s enough.
That's enough.
Where are you going?
I'm feeling kinda antsy tonight.
I’m sorry. It was a weird day...
Right.
What, now you’re gonna pout?
Well it's been eight months.
But who's keeping track?
I am. I'm keeping track.
I'm just not ready yet, Howie. I'm
sorry if you think that's abnormal
I don't.
I don't think that's normal at all but...
Then what's the problem?
We need to at least head in that direction,
which might feel strange at first, but...
But you wanna have sex
Well don't say it like that.
You’re trying to rope me into
having sex!
I am not. I wasn't roping you into
sex-
Al Green isn't roping?
No.
Al Green?
I thought it was nice. That's all.
I was trying to make things nice.
Well you can't.you just can't, I'm sorry.
Things aren't "nice" anymore
And, will you hold him for a second?
Just hold him, just hold him like that.
Dad, quit it!
Quit it.
Yeah, pull him past you. All right,
now.
Cause Taz wants to go on the tire
Okay, you ready? I’m gonna let you go.
Ready?
Yes.
Here goes. There! Whoa! Keepyour feet up.
Danny, look at me on the way back.
Keep your feet up, Danny.
Hey.
If you're not gonna go to Group, I
think you should see someone.
Any plans for the day?
You're looking at 'em.
Well, I’ll see you tonight.
Yup.
Hi, I'm here to see Scott Bader in
the Events Department.
I don't have a Bader listed.
Oh. Well that’s weird
Kate Finn. What about Kate?
I have a Robert Finn in Dec. Arts?
If you have an appointment, I can
just call up there. Who are you?
Um... I’m just... I didn’t have an
appointment actually.
I'm just an
old friend. I used to work here.
Becca?
Gary?
Heeey. What are you doing here?
Um... I had some errands in the city,
and thought I'd pop in and say hello.
But apparently nobody
works here anymore.
Oh yeah, Scott went over to
Christie's back in March. The traitor.
Well nice to see you’re still doing
the coffee runs at least.
Oh, no, I don’t usually-- Um, I’m
in Scott’s old job.
Hey, how's the family?
You know what, Gary? I know how
busy it gets up there,
so I’m gonna
let you get back to it.
Yeah, that hasn't changed.
It was great to see you though
Yeah, you too.
Well there are fines you know.
No, I know
The book’s quite overdue. We've
sent out several notices.
Yeah, that's why I'm here.
Seven dollars.
Can I help you?
Uh, yes, actually. Would it be
possible for me to check this out?
Certainly
"I will become a fish in a trout
stream and I will swim away from you.” Look he’s
He's in the water.
Yes, he is, "If you become a fish
in the trout stream, said his mother
I will become a fisherman
and I will fish for you."
Oh! Sorry.
Hey.
I just scored Yankee tickets offa
Rowan. Tonight. You interested?
I can’t. I have Group.
You can't skip one night?
They'rebehind home plate.
Another time.
If there is one.
Going stag tonight?
Uh, yeah.
Becca's gonna... take a little
break. From the group.
I’m gonna get a coffee.
Wanna sit?
Yeah.
Hello?
Hey Mom, it's me
What's wrong?
Nothing. I was just... thinking about making
Izzy's birthday cake. Would that be alright?
Oh Honey, you don't need to do all
that.
I was just gonna grab her one of
those Carvel things. She likes those.
I don't mind. It'll give me
something to do.
Okay then
No group tonight?
Howie's there. It's too much God
talk for me, so...
What.
Nothing. It’s just... some people
find that comforting.
Yeah, well, it pisses me off.
You know, Becca, when your brother
died, I found the church very helpful.
I know you did, but that's you, not
me. And Danny isn’t Arthur.
I know, brought you to
church every Sunday-
Let’s not start this again, okaymom?
I was just calling about the cake..
You’re not right about everything,
you know. What if there is a God?
Then I’d say he's a sadistic prick.
Alright, Becca. That’s enough.
"Worship me and I'll treat you like
shit."
No wonder you like him, he
sounds just like Dad.
I'm sorry.
You're gonna do the cake then?
Yeah.
Right, I'll see you tomorrow.
Who has a birthday party at a
bowling alley anyway?
Izzy thinksshe's still fourteen.
If you’re not up to this we don’t
have to go..
No, it’s just a party. I’ll be
fine.
I really wish you’d take that out
of here, Howie.
You’re hardly in this car, what’s
the difference?
It’s just weird.
What if we give it another try?
- Another baby?
- What
Well we’re not getting any younger.
Is that what the sex thing was
about the other night?
No-
You trying to get me pregnant?
Becca, no, of course not. I know
it's scary, but maybe it might..
Help us get us back on track.
On track?
What, we can’t talk about it?
I think we should sell the house.
I've been thinking about it, and
since we're on the topic...
what you mean How were we on the topic?
I’ve talked to a realtor and she thinks we can
pull together an open house pretty quickly
why would you talked to a
realtor without telling me?
I’m telling you now.
You want to get us back on track, I
think it'd help if we moved.
We love that house.
He's everywhere, Howie. The puzzles,
the fingerprints on the door jambs
I like seeing his fingerprints
That’s because you don’t have to
sit and stare at them all day.
You get to go to work.
You get to escape!
I don’t want to move!
And I don’t want another baby!
Jesus!
What are you doing?
What do you think I’m doing? I’m
checking the cake. It’s fine.
Are you kidding? The Kennedys?
With the assassinations... the lobotomy...?!
Yeah, but that’s not a curse
though. That's just bad luck.
The plane crashes?
Too much money, that's their curse.
If those Kennedys lived like normal people
most of them would still be alive.
I think it’s sad.
All those goodlooking people
falling out of the sky like that.
It’s a friggin’ waste.
Didn't I say no wine?
She brought it herself
Isn’t this nice? Sitting aroundtalking politics?
I never do this. It’s a nice change.
Let’s do gifts.
Yes! Pass em!
Okay. It’s heavy.
It’s so pretty. I hate to rip it open.
It's a bathroom set.
It's more of a practical gift
Is this your way of telling me you
don't like my Three Stooges shower curtain?
I didn't know what to get you.
Seriously, this is great.
Say thank you.
Thank you, Becca. Thank you,
Howie.
Don't thank me, Becca picked it
out
Okay, now me.
I know it’s a little early but-
Oh, my God! So sweet. Thank you,
Mommy.
I thought we weren't doing baby
stuff. For the birthday.
I thought we'd wait for the shower
No honey, it's not baby stuff, it's
mommy stuff.
This is perfect, Bec. I needed a
bathroom set.
Yeah, but you need baby stuff more.
We can take it back
That's right, we should. I'll getyou a basket
of Mustela lotions. They prevent stretch marks...
Becca, let go. You can get me the
lotions another time.
You can get me the
Thank you.
Here.
Oh, I just remembered what I was
gonna say about Aristotle Onassis!
It was about the son who died in
the plane crash!
- You ready to go?
- Yeah
You should’ve stopped me from going
off on that Kennedy stuff,
because my point was about
Onassis and how he put up a reward
to anyone who could prove that
someone had sabotaged his son’s plane.
He was so desperate to blame somebody.
Did you read this?
He needed a reason for losing his
son.
Mom, why are you telling this
story?
I'm just talking. I can't talk?
You never just talk.
Thank you guys for coming to my
party. Becca the cake was so good.
You forget what I went through when
your brother died.
You think I don't know anything,
but I do Becca!
Like who to blame?
You guys, this is my party.
Let em’ go. That’s not on you.
I'm not talking about blame, I'm
talking about comfort.
Ohhh, comfort. Well then.
Where are you getting it?
Comfort? I'm not.
Well I think you should.
Okay. I'll get right on that then.
See what I can dig up on eBay.
I'm just trying to help you, Becca. I wish someone
had given me a little advice when Arthur died.
You know what I wish? I wish you would stop comparing
Danny to Arthur! Danny was a four-year-old
boy who chased his dog into the
street!
Arthur was a thirty-yearold
heroin addict who OD’d!
Frankly I resent how you keep
lumping them together!
He was still my son.
We’re gonna go. Izzy,
I hope you enjoy the bathroom set.
I'm gonna.
When Arthur died, I was just as upset as she was,
but I never took it out on other people.
What about Mrs. Bailey?
Nobody's talking about Mrs. Bailey!
Hey, did you call that guy about
the roof?
I couldn’t find the number.
It’s in my phone. It’s on the
mantle.
What’s his name?
It’s not under his name.
Then how am I supposed to call him if I--?
It’s under Roof Guy.
Roof Guy.
Well what was I supposed to put itunder.
I don’t know how to use this thing.
It doesn’t--
Okay, now scroll down.
Now what?
Scroll down with your finger.
You do it.
Roof guy.
Thank you.
Are you waiting for me?
Oh. Um, hi. Yeah, I... I'm sorry,
I thought you took the bus.
I do
Right. But not...?
Not today, no. Today I skipped
school.
...you shouldn't be playing hooky,
young man.
Why are you waiting for me?
I thought we could talk?
About what?
Is this okay?
Yeah. It’s fine.
It's not too weird?
Um, no. I mean...
No, I know. It’s weird for me too.
Don’t you like school?
I like it alright.
Okay. I just thought, you seem to
not be going so
I’ve been accepted to college
already, so...
Oh. So it’s not a big deal then.
No, it is a big deal, but... only if
my mother finds out.
She said she’d confiscate my phone
if I did it again.
Not that I use the phone anyway.
Where are you headed?
Connecticut College.
That's a good school. And not too
far. I bet you parent pleased to you
It's just my mom, but yeah, she's
pretty happy about it.
She keeps saying she's gonna apply
to the grad program
so she can keep
an eye on me while I'm up there.
She's just joking though.
She's not really looking forward to
it, since I'm the only one at home now,
but I told her I'd come back
on the weekends if I could.
That'll be nice.
So, I'm sorry.
Oh, I know, you don't have to...
I know that doesn't help, but...
No it does. It really does.
And I know I should’ve tried to get
in touch
No, it’s fine.
I just really wish I had driven
down a different block that day
I know
You know what? I should maybe go
It’s alright.
My mom’s gonna start to wonder
where I’m at
That's okay. You really don’t have to
Could we do this again sometime?
Sure.
Jesus Christ!
Hey, Gabby
I can’t believe you just saw me do
that.
I didn’t mean to sneak up on you.
I thought something was wrong.
But
obviously everything... smells fine.
You can smell it huh?
God, everyone in there is gonna
know. I swear I never do this.
Where’s Kevin?
He’s not coming to group. And I
blame your wife by the way.
I think she put the idea in his head.
Well, he didn’t seem to really like
group all that much.
He’s gotten me all upset. I mean,
look at me.
I am Smoking pot in a
parking lot.
It’s like I’m in highschool.
I’m ridiculous.
Do you have any more?
Yeah! Come on in, partner!
Well if today is rage day,
most of you know that I am a little more
comfortable with rage.
Talking about rage.
I deal with rage every single day.
And I listen to these guys at work,
and they go on and on about
paving their driveways
or whatever, just the most stupid
nonsense. They don’t know.
They haven’t had their
lives ripped apart yet.
They’re not in the club.
Exactly. Meanwhile, I’m sitting there like,
“Hey guys, my daughter died of leukemia--!”
I’m sorry, I need some water
You’re one of those bad kids my
mother warned me about.
Yes, I am corrupting you.
Don’t worry, I won’t tell Becca.
I’d appreciate that.
- Good night.
Becca
What'd you do here?
What?
Goddamn it, what did you do to my
phone?
Jesus, Howie. I thought something
had hap
This morning. When you used it.
What did you do to my phone?
Nothing. I just got the number for
the roof guy.
For christsake!
What, you told me to call him.
You deleted Danny's video.
No, no I didn't. No. I just...
you were right there. I just got the number.
Yeah, and you kept pressing the
screen.
Because I couldn't figure out how
to use your phone.
I checked already. It's gone.
We have a hundred videos of him,
Howie.
That's not the point, Becca.
Then you should've put it on your
computer.
Right, it's my fault.
I didn't say that.
I said it's gone!
Jesus, Howie! I didn't do it on
purpose!
Are you sure?
What does that mean?
You think I deliberately deleted
his video?
I don't know
You don't know?
It’s like you’re trying to get rid of him.
I'm sorry, but that's how it feels.
Every day, it's
something new.
Really.
Yeah. It’s like you're trying to get rid
of any evidence he was ever here.
You took his paintings off
the fridge.
Yes, to save them. They are in a
box downstairs.
His clothes?
We don’t need all that stuff.
Your wanting to sell the house.
Your sending Taz to your mother's.
There was a lot going on, Howie.
The dog got under foot.
Right. And he was a reminder.
Yes, he was a reminder,
and I wanted one less reminder around here.
And since you never wanted the dog.
Oh, for godssake
Well if I hadn't bought the dog
danny whould still alive
And if I hadn't run in to get the
phone or if I had latched the gate
I left the gate unlatched!
Well I didn’t check it! I’m not playing this
game again Howie. It was no one’s fault.
Not even the dog's.
Dogs chasesquirrels, boys chase dogs.
I know that
He loved that dog! And you got rid
of it!
Just like I got rid of the video.
It's not just the video! I'm not
talking about the video, Becca!
It's about Taz, and the paintings, and
the clothes, and it's everything!
The is no pictures in all that around
You have to stop erasing him! You
have to stop it!
Do you really think I don't
see him every second of every day?
The video was an accident, Howie.
And believe me,
I’ll beat myself up
about it forever, I'm sure.
Just like everything else that I could've prevented.
That's not what I want, Becca.
No? Because it feels like it is.
It feels like maybe I don't feel badly enough for you.
Maybe i am not feelling enough
What do you want from me?
I m just got to change
Because I can't do this... like this.
It's too hard. It's too hard.
And I want that dog back. Your
mother's making him fat.
I miss the dog. I'm sorry, but Imiss him.
I want him back.
You really made these?
I did
They're good. Still warm.
I'm glad you like them
So I've been reading that book.
The parallel universe book?
Yeah? Did you like it?
Yeah, it’s interesting. I don’t
know if I buy it.
The whole
alternate reality thing
I don’t
know
But it’s interesting.
Did
you have to do it for a school
No. It's research.
Oh. Research.
It's a comic book.
Impressive.
- You did all this?
- Yeah.
Wow. It’s amazing
What's it
about?
A scientist, I guess. And his son.
The father discovers this network of holes
that leads to other galaxies and, um
Parallel universes.
Yeah
Yeah, but the scientist dies. So
the son has to go
into this rabbit hole
to try and find him.
But it’s not
him, because he's dead,
so it’s like another version of him.
- I know it's kinda stupid, but...
- No.
No? Okay.
Not at all. I would love to read
it.
Yeah it’s um...
it’s not done
yet
But when it is done, I will
let you read it.
- Okay.
I don't want you to feel
uncomfortable.
- I...
- I might've been going too fast....
That day.
I'm not sure, but I might’ve been.
So... that's something I've been wanting to tell you.
It's a thirty zone. And I might've
been going thirty-one.
Or thirty-two.
I would usually look down, to check, and if I
was a little over, then I'd slow down obviously.
But...
I don't remember checking on your
block,
so it's possible I was going
too fast.
And ..
The dog ran out
really fast
so I swerved
I didn’t know
I thought you should know
I might've been going a little over the limit.
I can't be positive.
- It’s okay.
- Okay.
Well.
I know, okay?
Thank you.
I don't wanna go in there.
Yes, yes!
Sorry. I was...
Take care.
Oh, come on!
I’m sorry, you suck...
I’d be doing better but your pot
messed up my depth perception.
All right.
I’m gonna support that one. I’m
totally gonna support that one.
Thanks.
Hey you know what. I have a
confession to make.
Remember when I
said Kevin left Group?
Yes.
What I meant to say..
Is that heleft me. He left me.
I left myself.
Yes...
I came home and was gone.
Wow. No note or...
Oh there was a note.
Well, not a
note so much as a manifesto.
On all the ways that we were destroying each other.
Jesus. I'm sorry.
Well... this is generally how it
goes, right?
It changes you.
It
literally changes people.
You know, Part of
me thinks it was inevitable.
I love my wife.
Of course you do
I love her very much.
Okay.
So I think you're right. We should
maybe...
look into selling the house.
It's probably for the best.
Okay.
Don't do that
Quick and clean, like a band-aid.
Or we'll never get through this
Here.
Hey, kid.
Welcome to light up apple
I don't know how to turn it off.
Only people without children give
gifts like this.
Come on!
Goodbye.
I hope you'll visiting us soon.
- Have you heard from Debbie yet?
- No.
That's too bad.
But it can be
worse the other way,
you know. I
remember when Arthur died...
You can say his name.
- Can I?
- Yes.
Do not know your rules.
I don't wanna get scolded again.
You can talk about Arthur.
I justdon't like the comparisons.
Okay.
So how is it worse?
- You remember Maureen Bailey?
- Yes.
Well...
I couldn't get rid of her after
your brother passed away.
- She was always at the house
- Yeah, I remember that.
Yeah well, I never had a moment to
myself.
So finally in the middle
of coffee one afternoon, I said,
"Maureen, why are you always here?"
What'd she say?
She said, "I wanna be there, Nat, I
wanna share in your grief."
And so
I said "Well it's not working.
You plant your fat ass in that chair
every frickin' day"
- You did not say that!
- I did!
- Mom!
- I said that.
- You said "fat ass"?
- "You suck up all my coffee.
And I don't see you leaving with any
of this grief you're allegedly sharing with me.
In fact the only thing you do take outta
here are my cinnamon buns."
So I never saw her again obviously.
Oh my God, I can not believe it.
I feel guilty now.
- You do not.
- I do.
You’re right, I don’t.
I don’t
miss her at all.
Okay, we will be alright.
That takes care of Taz.
Ah, the ol' apple pie trick, eh?
What?
For the Open House.
Warm baked
goods makes it feel homier.
No, just making a pie.
I thought you were doing it for the
Open House.
So...
- now you’re not gonna stay?
- Oh, no. No.
You shouldn't either
- You shouldn’t
- Come on,...
I'm not gonna bother
anyone.
So we have the garbage cans in the
back, the sign out front.
I mowed
the lawn.
I thought we’d set the
sign-in sheet here
and they could
move into the living room.
That's fine.
My wife's gonna go hide out, but
I'll stick around
if that's okay
with you.
Sure. However you want to do it.
- Okay. Perfect.
- All right...
- Bye, baby.
- Bye.
I think that’s everything.
- I know...
- Southwestern exposures.
Sun all day..
- Why don’t we take a look upstairs?
- That’s a great idea. I’ll show you.
- Okay.
- Follow me.
Come on, baby.
It is the largest part in the neighborhood.
We can start in the master bedroom
if you want to see
Wait. What’s in here?
Oh,
This is... This is...
This could be a good room for the
little guy, obviously
How about that, buddy? You like
this room?
- Oo, careful with that.
- That's not yours, honey.
- Thanks.
How old's your son?
This is your son's room, I assume?
Uh, yeah. I mean... it was,
It was his room.
But... he died.
He died...
Yeah, a car. Right out front
Oh my god.
- I’m so sorry..
- Thank you.
This must be so difficult for you.
It is,...
It's pretty weird.
It is strange that yet...
I still
forget he's not here sometimes.
Maybe he's just hiding under the bed and
he's gonna pop out. That’s what he used to do
But...
I still feel him here.
- Would you like to see the master bedroom?
- Yes.
Yes.
Yeah, I’ll be there.
- Who was that?
- Becca.
She wants to “hang out.”
This was a good idea.
I know. I feel like a big ole
balloon
You're starting to show so early.
Yes, I know. I feel like a balloon.
I swear, once this kid is
born I’m going right to the gym.
While Mom watches the baby
What does that mean?
“While Mom watches the baby.”
While you're at the gym, Mom can
watch the baby.
She loves that.
No, Auggie can watch the baby. He
works nights, so he'll be home.
Okay. Auggie, then.
I resent the feeling I get from you
that I don't deserve the baby.
I'm not mature enough
or smart inough to take care of him.
I mean, my god, if Mom
could do it, how hard could it be?
- This alright?
- Yeah, it’s fine.
I’ve just gotta pick up a few
things and then we can do lunch.
Okay. Well
i want strawberry
Mommy, vPlease can
I have some Fruit Roll-Ups?
- No, Sammy, you know the answer
- Please?
- Can I have some, please?
- Sammy, no.
- I want the Fruit Roll-ups.
- Not happening.
- Please, I’ll be good.
- Stop it...
- Please?
- No.
- I promise.
- No, I’m not gonna get ‘em.
You know what? It's only threebucks,
why don't you just get him the roll-ups?
Not that it's any of your business,
but we don't allow candy in our house
- and my son knows that
- Come on, it’s just fruit
Why don’t
you give him a treat?
Are you a mom?
Yeah, I didn’t think so.
Excuse me....
Go to the car, Becca.
I said go to the car.
It's okay.
She just lost her son eight months
ago and she’s...
I don’t care.
Everything is okay.
Hey, hey.
Hey.
Fun day out?
How'd it go here?
Not so good
We need to clean out
that room.
Okay
Maybe make it into a guest room or
something.
Don't get any ideas.
Jesus...
Hello
The door was wide
open so...
And I knocked, but...
Taz! Shut up!
I saw the sign outside..
So I thought it’d be okay to-
- You looking to buy a house?
- Howie...
No.
No, I just came to give you this.
I said I'd let you read it when it was done, so...
What... what is this?
Thank you.
We... bumped into each other, in the
library
and i. .. And i. ..
And we decided to meet.
You decided to meet?
Yes.
A couple times.
- Well...
- I'm sorry. I didn't realize...
It is...
Did you meet here?
No, we met in the park
You met in the park a couple times.
Yes.
So my wife...
agrees to meet you in a
public place, and you..
And you... Apologize?
- I guess.
- You guess
Well...
Okay, you apologize, and then what?
Alright, Howie, that's enough
- And then what?
- It is enough.
- Look at me.
- Howie, that's enough.
- What is that?
- It's a comic book.
It is a comic book?
A comic book?
Did she tell you to bring it here?
- No, she didn't.
Because this is our house.
And just because there's a sign
out front doesn't mean you can pop in.
Howie, all right.
No it’s not alright
You don't just
walk into someone's home like that.
You should show a little fucking
respect.
All right i go
You're an asshole.
Wait!
Jason, wait a minute. I m Sorry.
I am an asshole!
Taz, stop it.
Taz!
Taz.
Taz, stop it.
Oh, buddy..
Why didn’t you tell me?
For the same reason you don’t tell
me why you come home reeking of pot.
Does it ever go away?
No.
I don't think it does. Not for me it
hasn't. And that's goin'on eleven years.
It changes though.
How?
I don't know.
I don't know. The weight of it, I guess.
At some point it becomes
bearable
It turns into something
you can crawl out from under
and carry around
like a brick in your pocket.
And you even forget it
for while. But then you reach
in for whatever reason and i. ..
"Oh right.
Which can
be awful
But not all the time
Sometimes it's kinda.
Not that you like it exactly, but it's what
you have instead of your son
So you carry it around
And it doesn't go away
which is..
What is it?
Fine... actually.
- Hello?
- Hi.
Hey, it's Howie.
Howie Corbett. From Group?
Hi, Howie.
Here we go buddy
- Hey.
- Hi.
- You're going to group?
- Yeah. You didn't want to come, did you?
No.
I'm Jason. Please leave a message.
Did you find the house okay?
Howie?
Sorry.
Becca?
Becca!
God.
Sorry.
What time is it?
Almost six.
And you're just getting home?
So how was it?
It was okay.
- Well you look nice.
- Thank you.
Was that your girlfriend?
Just a friend.
She's pretty.
Yes.
Well, I liked this so much. It’s
beautiful.
- It's wonderful.
- Thanks. Thanks.
It reminded me of Orpheus and
Eurydice.
- Do you know that myth?
- No.
Eurydice dies, and Orpheus misses
her so much
that he travels to Hades to retrieve her,
but in the end it doesn't work out.
I should read it
So, is the scientist your dad?
The scientist the boy is looking
for...
No.
Is it based on him?
No. My dad was an English teacher
Oh. Okay. I was curious about that
It's just a story.
- No, I know. I was just...
- Reading into it?
Do you think they're real?
Parallel universes?
I think it’s basic science.
You know, If space is infinite,
then everything is possible.
So somewhere out there,
i m what?... making pancakes?
- Or at a water park?
- Sure. Yes.
- Yes?
- Yes. Both, Wherever.
I think... you know, Laws of
probability.
There are tons of
you's out there, and tons of me's
Yes...
So this is just the sad version of us.
Yes, I guess
But there are other versions
where everything goes our way.
Assuming you believe in science.
I like that thought.
It's nice.
Somewhere out there I'm having a
good time.
I thought maybe you had left.
No. I didn't leave.
So I was thinking we should invite
Rick and Debbie over for a cookout.
She's never gonna call. She thinks
I hate her. So...
just
let her off the hook
cookout?
It'll be good to see the kids.
We should get something for Emily
though. It's her birthday.
She turned four last week
Right. Okay
Danny's is coming up
I know.
That's gonna be a tough one.
Yes.
So the kid... Jason.
Did you tell
him we didn't blame him?
- We don’t blame him.
- I know, but...
let him know that?
I guess so
That's good
- you Can talk with him if you want.
- I do not want to.
Okay.
It's so quiet.
That's because I slipped Taz a
couple Ambien.
You're funny
You think I'm joking.
So what are we gonna do?
About what?
I don't know.
Pick something
Well...
We could go to Village Toys
pick up Candy Land for Emily
probably something
she'd like
candy, yes...
Then what?
Then we wrap it
And then we have the cookout...
And they'll come over..
And we'll have a couple
other people so...
it's
not too awkward for anyone.
Then...
And to make them feel comfortable
we'll ask a bunch of questions
about what the kids have been up to
and we'll pretend that we're
really interested.
Then...
And then we'll wait for someone to
bring up Danny
while the kids are playing.
And maybe that'll go on
for a little while.
And after that...
they'll go home.
And then what?
I don't know.
Something though.
ReSlaN MoHaMeD
Help me on my new www.Blurayz.org