It might not be any
of my business, but, uh...
JC's crew's headed this way
to bump you, and they all got shanks.
I know.
- Go, get out.
- Be good, homie.
- Out of my road, nigga.
- Yeah.
See this motherfucker right here?
This motherfucker think he special.
- want to be left alone and shit.
- Fucking yeah.
Don't want to be mobbed out
with the rest of us niggas,
like we ain't shit.
You understand what I am saying?
Shit don't work like that
around here, homeboy.
Yeah, you going with the pack,
you the pack bitch.
Feel me?
He kind of tight, too.
That shit don't mean nothing
round here though, player.
I have seen a whole lot of
built motherfuckers...
get their ass bent over
up in here every day.
You understand
what I am telling you?
I am talking to you, partner.
You got to the count of five.
- This motherfucker talking to me?
- One.
You hear this motherfucker?
Two.
- You hear this motherfucker?
- Three.
You just signed your own
death certificate, player.
Goddamn.
Shit.
I need you to deliver a message.
I want you to tell every
motherfucker behind these walls...
that if they get the notion
to fuck with me...
don't.
Man, you know it's hotter
than a motherfucker out here.
Then tell your mother to stick her fat
ass out the window and give us some shade.
Fuck you, nigga.
- Shit, here she comes.
- Hey.
Hi.
Are you tweaking? You all right?
You all holding?
- Yeah, what you think?
- Yeah, baby. You got some Swiss?
- Count this shit.
- Let me count that. Let me count that.
- Make sure she does.
- Good?
All crinkled up and shit.
Yeah, give it to her.
Hey.
You all get off my block before I
call the police on your asses again.
Fuck you, you old
Fred Sanford-looking ass.
Yeah, yo.
Take your ass back to TV Land,
you Nick-at-Nite-looking
motherfucker. Peace, homie.
Checkmate.
See, I told you I am always
thinking three moves ahead.
Thanks, baby.
You know, this thinking
generates heat.
Thank Jesus for the shade.
You looking for a room, mister?
Yeah.
Yeah, come on.
Hey, Tamara, there's a fellow
here looking for a room.
Jared, it's time
for dinner, baby.
Can I help you?
Sign says "Room for rent".
It may need a little airing out.
This is just fine.
You know, since I keep kids,
I have rules.
No gangsters, no guns,
no loud music...
and no women in or out.
So this may not be the type
of place that you're looking for.
This seems like just the kind of
place I am looking for.
So what's your name?
Call me Bone.
Well, Mr. Bone...
Ante up.
I am not taking a chance
on you, am I, Mr. Bone?
No.
Bone.
Come on, big fella.
Yeah, baby.
Yeah, bust his fucking ass.
Dicks on the wall.
And the winner, coming straight from
the New York City penal system,
the homicidal homosexual,
the savage faggot,
the queer that inspires fear,
the butt-battling bandit,
Mommie Dearest.
Dicks on the walls, baby.
Here we go. You up next.
Hey, this is serious.
This ain't no joke.
I am ready.
Let's get this show
on the road.
Yo. What up?
We got three to one.
Ladies and gentlemen,
niggas and bitches,
next up we got the man from
the Lone Star State,
the raging redneck,
half man, half steer,
a shotgun
and a bottle of beer, bitch.
This motherfucker, this motherfucker
right here's so raw,
he eats steaks directly
off live bulls' asses.
I am talking about the killer
from Dallas' grassy knoll.
Giddy-up, you all, for the Cowboy.
Nigga better be on tonight,
because he's going up against
the baddest of the bad.
Oh, yeah. I know you all know what
I am talking about, right? Right?
I am talking about
the unholy combination...
- from the Zulu nation.
- We got three to one.
Yeah, three to one.
You got 10 G on Hammer?
All right.
We're in the pipe, baby.
Five by five.
The Hammerman.
Okay, cuz, here we go.
I know he's a big motherfucker.
That is a big motherfucker,
but you are faster, man.
You're way faster.
All you got to do is stick and move,
stick and move, bob and weave,
like I told you.
Are you ready?
Get him. Kill him.
I ain't scared of him.
Dumbass motherfucker.
Knuckle up.
Hammer, it's over.
It's over. Hammer, enough.
It's over.
And the winner, once again,
the Hammerman.
What can I say?
You have still got one of the
hardest hitters in the streets.
Tell me about it.
Well, ain't you going to count it?
I trust you, Pinball.
Do I have a reason not to?
No.
Good.
Fuck.
Don't.
What the fuck you want?
What you want? My rims?
No, I don't want your rims.
Well, then, what the fuck?
I want to fight with Hammerman.
Oh, yeah, and I want to fuck Beyonce.
Looks like you need a new fighter.
So, you a fighter.
Yeah, you know what?
I could sling fifty cents of nickels
outside this car and hit ten fighters,
ain't one that can fuck
with Hammerman.
What the fuck's
so special about you?
Set me up a fight
and I will show you.
Well, first of all, it's going to cost
at least 20 large to set up a fight.
Second, Hammer don't fuck
with no scrubs.
You ain't got no name,
you ain't got nothing.
Who the fuck you think you are?
And third, you think
I am going to put up my own money...
for a fighter
I ain't never seen fight?
Shit, you must be smoking
that new kind of crack.
260 dollars.
Get me a fight with anyone.
- What's in it for me?
- 20%.
Use your own money,
you get 40.
Yeah.
James, Franklin here.
I'd like you to pay our old
friend Darryl a visit tonight.
Okay.
- I will handle it.
- By the way, nice suit
You out of here, James?
Yeah, a few things to take
care of, you know how it is.
You're looking kind of hard there,
ain't you, family?
Hard not to.
Yeah.
Angela.
James, you ain't met my
new fighter yet, huh? This is...
What the fuck
they call you, anyway?
- Bone.
- Bone. Bone.
I call him Bone because that's
what he breaking when he hits.
In your ass,
little Asian Liberace.
Teddy.
Boys, let's break it up.
Let me give you
a piece of advice.
You'd just as soon
glue mouse ears to your balls
and dangle them
in front of an angry alley cat
than fuck with that girl.
What?
Don't you ever do that again.
- What?
- Don't pretend like you don't know.
What?
Say "what" one more time.
Say "what" one more time
like you don't know.
What the fuck do you mean?
James, where we going?
Darryl's.
You all want to go to Darryl's?
I hear Shelly's cooking.
Take her home.
Let's roll, let's roll.
Come on, Angela, let's go.
Man, I got 260.
I got 260. Give me 10 to 1.
- No, baby, no, baby. 5 to 1.
- Come on.
- 5 to 1.
- Huh? You killing me, D.
That's the best odds
you're going to get for a scrub.
All right then. Let's do this.
5 to 1, and that suit.
Hey, yo, gather round.
Gather round, everybody.
We got one more match up tonight.
Gather round because
there's a new kid in town.
You all didn't know,
he was sent to serve somebody.
Yo, Big L, you ready?
Big L, whoop his ass.
Yeah, baby, break a bone, baby.
Break a bone.
All right, then.
Knuckle up.
Yo, Deke, give me
that motherfucking money...
We going to make some money.
You and me, baby.
You and me, partner. No doubt.
I am fucking getting this shit
all together.
We're going to start outside
of town, right?
A few little fights, here and there.
You just going to whoop some ass.
We're going to stack
our Swiss up just enough...
that these greedy motherfuckers
around here don't know what's up.
Then we go straight for James.
Man, fuck that motherfucker,
we're going straight for James...
because James is the real money
around here.
Boy, you got to treat
that psycho-ass nigga just right.
because that motherfucker will kill
your ass just as much as talk to you.
But we got to fuck with him
just right.
Take it out of here just enough
so we get the odds that we want.
Then we drop that motherfucker down.
But, fuck, you know he got Hammerman.
But Hammerman ain't never put down.
That's when your ass comes in.
You got to whoop that motherfucker's ass.
Yeah.
What can you tell me
about the girl?
Fuck that.
Hell no, no. No.
Get that shit out your head
right now, man. Fuck that.
You need to sit right there and have
a long, introspective conversation...
- with your dick there, homes.
- Tell me about the girl.
She's James's girl. That's all
the fuck you need to know.
Fuck me.
Angela Soto. All right,
that's her name.
James turned her real bad...
She was married, matter of fact,
to a man, a choirboy...
I forget his name.
Word on the street is,
James set him up, triple homicide,
sent his black ass to jail.
James just swooped in,
snatched the girl for himself
But the fucked up thing is,
I heard she was pregnant.
This motherfucker took her
to a clinic and got that baby...
After that,
she got hooked on the horse and
that's the end of that sordid tale.
Don't you ever tell me to tell
you that story again because...
that's the type of shit
that make a brother...
lose all hope
in humanity and shit.
You know what I am saying?
Yeah.
So this guy,
first time up, first hole,
first game, he swears,
par five, shoots an eagle.
An eagle, first try.
- Couldn't believe it.
- Wait. That reminds me, Darryl,
you get that thing off to Franklin?
Franklin, dude,
don't even worry about that guy.
We could have some music.
- Yes.
- Good idea.
- Well, I will get it, baby.
- Okay, okay.
Yeah, I am usually shooting
like a 79, 80.
This guy, 72, first game.
A little white-boy music
to aid digestion?
What's wrong, you don't think that
brothers are down with Wang Chung?
Take your baby by the hand...
See, he knows it.
Make her do a high handstand...
Take your baby by the heels...
- Come on, sing with me.
- See?
- Do the next thing that you feel...
Sing with me.
You don't know it, right?
- We were so in phase...
- In our dance hall days...
- We were cool on craze...
- When I, you, and everyone we knew
- Could believe, do...
- and share in what was true...
Darryl,
don't take this personal.
What?
- Get over here.
- Oh, my God.
Shut the fuck up.
Shut up, shut up.
God.
What good are you anymore?
You ain't nothing but a junkie.
What is the music on that thing?
It's a new joint, man.
By what's-his-name, you know,
the cat does the song, Homegirl.
Yeah, well turn it off. You know
I don't like profanity in my home.
My bad. It's off.
What is that thing anyway?
That, man, is the PKL 370.
Better known as the Pickle.
And check it. If I call you up,
all you got to do is press star 40,
and it automatically activates a GPS
that can find you anywhere by satellite.
It's tight, huh?
You know if you ever use
that thing on me, I will kill you.
I am messing with you, man.
Check this out.
One kick.
Folded up Big Lamont
like a paper bag.
Where's he from?
Only cat that knows is Pinball.
Okay.
Here's my boy.
You're my babies.
Get back, get back,
get back, get back.
Get back.
- What's wrong with you?
- They eat dogs in China.
Get in here. Come on, man.
Yeah.
Them motherfuckers...
Sorry?
Just saying, they're looking
at me like Chinese takeout.
It's because you don't know
how to treat them.
Just like everything else, you just
got to show them who their master is.
You ready?
For what?
Just tell me if you're ready.
Yeah, I am ready, man, I am ready.
What? What?
- Kill.
- James, stop messing around, James.
Stop messing around, man.
Get them motherfucking dogs
away from me, man.
Stop.
What did I tell you
about cursing?
Remember, profanity is a brutal vice.
He that uses it is no gentleman.
I got to warn you,
I am always thinking 3 moves ahead.
- He's looking fresh today.
- Yeah, yeah, with his church shoes on.
Yeah, I mean,
he likes this bike, right?
- I know you feeling it.
- See this?
- You see the bling?
- Bling, bling, bling.
You want that, right? You want that.
A fiend for that.
Jared. Get your little behind
up here right now.
Hey. You two good-for-nothings,
take that... Get off this block.
Man, fuck you,
you gray-haired,
Grandpa Moses-looking motherfucker.
You Metamucil-drinking-ass
motherfucker.
You don't want me
to come down there, do you?
All right.
It's all in the tone
of your voice.
That's how you get things done
around here.
Hey, yo, Bone.
Time to go, partner.
That's checkmate.
What? Checkmate?
I play four moves ahead.
Here.
Damn.
I am not sure I approve
of the company you keep, Mr. Bone.
Me, neither.
Hey.
You know Car Wash
is not just a movie.
This may seem like some old underground
fight club shit, low-key and all.
These motherfuckers
can scrap, though.
You see that chick?
I used to hit that.
Pretty hot for a fighter, huh?
Not anymore.
Shit.
And the winner is,
the vindictive Veretta Vendetta.
Don't get on her bad side, homies.
That's fucking right.
Tatt, what up?
- What's up, man?
- Chilling.
So, check this out.
I got this new fighter,
I will bet you 5 thousand,
what you think?
- Who?
- That man right there, Bone.
I am talking about your
best fighter right now. 5 G's.
- My best fighter?
- Your best fighter.
- All right, man.
- All right?
- Yeah.
- 5 G's?
All right.
Okay, we got the next fight.
Over here we got this guy, Bone.
He seems to think he can come here
and take all our money.
But tonight, he's got to put it all up
against the man with the golden grill.
Yeah. Now we already seen what
he does to a dude that he likes.
And I don't think he likes
this guy Bone very much, does he?
Okay. You guys ready?
Fight.
Holy shit.
What technique. What technique.
You ever see some shit like that?
I never seen no shit like that.
My man Bone will wreck shop
on your punk-ass fighters, man.
Two at a time, bitches.
Two at a time.
- Pay me, Tattoo. Pay me.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
What'd you say, two at a time?
Is that what you said, two?
Hey, everybody heard that?
Two at a time, okay?
- That's the bet. Two at a time.
- No, no, no, no, what bet? What bet?
Hey, hey, calm down, homie.
That's what you just said,
two at a time, right?
Hey, Carlos, Manuel.
Hold on. No, no, wait.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You said two at a time.
- What, you scared? You going to forfeit?
- Fuck that, man. Fuck you.
Fuck you, homie.
Fuck you.
Your man as good as he says he is?
Let's do it.
- This is bullshit.
- Double or nothing.
No, no, no. Bone, Bone,
he owes us money right the fuck now.
Double or nothing.
Get this motherfucker, man.
What the fuck?
That's double.
- want to double up again?
- Hey, hey, hey.
David, Jesus, Lorenzo,
get this motherfucker, man.
What the fuck was that?
One, two, three. Uno, dos, tres,
homes, just like that. What?
First bet was 5 thousand.
Double or nothing
on the second made it 10.
No fucking way, homie.
- Double that made it 20.
- Hey.
- You want to triple?
Hell no, motherfucker.
Hell no.
Hey, you said this motherfucker
was a beginner.
You said
he just got started, homie.
You said this motherfucker
was a beginner, homie.
- No. No, you took the bet.
- I ain't having it, man.
You took the action.
Time to pay up.
You want your money, homie?
You want your money?
Give me the fucking money, man.
You want your money? You see it?
It's right here, baby.
Come and get it.
What, motherfucker?
Pussies.
These pussy motherfuckers, man.
- Right here.
- What the...
Right here. What?
Right there.
What now? You all weren't expecting
no superhero shit like that, huh?
Call me.
Goddamn.
You just took out the whole village.
The whole fucking village.
You know where that's been, right?
Goddamn, you are one
crazy son of a bitch.
I never met no crazy motherfucker
like you, you know what I am saying?
This motherfucker won't...
Oh, shit.
Pussy motherfuckers,
where you going?
Motherfuckers.
Ante up.
Break his hand.
Come on, break them off, man.
Break them off.
Get the money.
Man,
my whole life motherfuckers
played me for a mark.
Act like I am some kind of punk.
Inside, I always felt
like a baller...
even though my pockets were flat.
And now it's all coming true.
And it's all because of you, B.
So what I am trying to say is,
I love you, B.
I don't mean that in a homosexual,
I am-trying-to-get-with-you kind of way.
I mean that in like...
Like a motherfucker who, now,
he-got-a-ride-to-match-his-rims
kind of way.
You know what I am saying?
That's love.
Damn. That was
way mellow and shit.
What happened to you?
I had an accident.
What did you do,
trip and fall on someone's fist?
Come here.
Sit down.
Are you always up this early?
Yes. To make breakfast
for the children.
You take good care of those kids.
Yeah, well, I do what I have to do to
stop them from being killers, thugs, hos,
street fighters.
You have any family, Mr. Bone?
Long time ago.
What happened?
So, how long you been
taking care of the kids?
Well...
Angel I have had for 3 years,
Regina, about a year and a half,
and Jared, about a year.
Why does Jared
always stand at the window?
He's waiting for his folks
to come back.
As far as I know,
his father's in jail.
But he does have a mother
out there somewhere.
Thank you.
You know I saw you doing
tai chi out there.
I watch the old people
do it in the park, you know?
It just always looks so beautiful,
so relaxing.
Come here.
Let me show you something.
Okay.
This is tai chi.
This is called Push Hands.
Step with your right foot.
Put your hand here.
Now, this hand goes on my elbow.
Now, this is called Push Hands.
When I push, you yield,
roll back and push me.
Just like that.
And push with your hand.
And roll back.
There you go.
Checkmate.
Five moves ahead, young'un.
Shit.
Why you running?
You know you're going to twist an ankle.
I didn't do it, James.
I swear I didn't do it.
Do what? Why are you running?
because I know he told you what you
think I did, but I didn't do it, James.
I swear. I put that
on my babies, James, please.
Then why don't you stop running
and tell me your side?
because ain't nobody got no
other side with you, James.
You think I am that one-sided?
I am that one-sided?
Monique, I am hurt. I am hurt.
Will you stop
climbing that fence?
You are giving me
a complex over here.
You know what?
Man, James.
- She's messed up.
- Now I feel bad.
Come on, let's go.
Shit.
kind of motherfucking name is Bone?
He's about to get boned
by the Hammer.
Know what I am saying?
- You ready for this?
- Yeah.
Hold steady.
Just knock this motherfucker out.
Afterwards, we will get those little
schoolgirls, you know what I am saying?
You ready for this, Hammer?
You ready?
- Yeah.
- Let's do this.
Let do this.
I don't smell no Hammer.
I smell pussy. Are you a pussy?
No. No. You're the Hammerman.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah.
What's up, James?
How you doing, fam?
Got your money?
Well, there it is, just waiting
for you to give it a little company.
You need to count it?
Bring him up.
Step to the rear,
because the Hammer is here. Yeah.
You know that thing you
always say every time I fight?
What? You mean,
"They call him Bone because
that's what he break when he hits"?
- Yeah.
- Don't say that.
All right motherfuckers
and motherfuckettes,
it's time for the main event.
Now, without further ado,
let me bring to you,
coming straight
from Skull Island.
You all might know him
from his numerous appearances...
atop the Empire State Building,
swatting down airplanes and shit,
the primate from another climate,
the Hammerman.
Hold up, hold up,
hold up, hold up.
But now,
coming from this corner,
he's new on the scene,
but he's stacking much green.
The one-technique
knockout artist...
who's breaking down pros
like they just got started.
The brother man
with death in each hand,
the man they call Bone,
because...
Because that's what
his parents named him.
Bone.
And now, you hedonistic savages,
knuckle up.
Come on, baby.
Shit.
Tastes like
a Timberland boot, bitch.
The man Bone.
The winner is my man Bone.
Yo, Hammy, he just took
your juiced-up ass to college.
Bone, bitches.
Yeah, yeah, no, get the money, right.
Get the money.
That's the deal.
Get the money, bitches.
That motherfucker Bones
is the truth.
What can I say, James?
Homeboy just got lucky.
Yeah, well, like they say,
every dog has its day.
This is yours, I guess.
Watch his leg.
My leg, man.
- It's just my leg.
- Put no weight on it.
Take it.
Mr. Bone, that was one
hell of a show.
I never seen anything like that
before in my life.
You know, you cost me
a lot of money.
I hear you got a lot.
Not really.
You know, why don't you and Pinball
come by my place, celebrate?
That way we can talk.
I am sorry, James,
We got some plans.
We will be there.
Good.
You know,
invincibility lies in defense.
Possibility of victory
in the attack.
You ain't got no qualm
with the Asiatic.
Welcome, welcome, welcome.
Glad you two could make it.
Well, I didn't think you'd want to see us
after we won that money from you tonight.
Well, I guess it had to happen
sooner or later.
Didn't know
you had a secret weapon.
Poor, old Hammer's at the hospital
straightening out his knee.
Hey, baby, come meet my man, Bone.
He just whooped the Hammerman.
Words can't describe
how little I give a damn.
Come, come, walk with me. Talk.
Where'd you learn how to fight?
Here and there.
I got something to show you.
I have always admired fighters
and the fight game.
A warrior's life,
that's the life for me.
There's honor and virtue.
A warrior's life must be pure
in body and in spirit.
That's why I don't drink,
I don't smoke, I don't use profanity.
Genghis Khan once said,
the greatest pleasure...
is to vanquish your enemies
and chase them before you,
to rob them of their wealth
and to have those dear to them...
bathed in tears.
I am the punishment of God.
And if you had not
committed great sins,
God would not have sent
a punishment like me upon you.
Genghis Khan.
You see?
I am not like the rest
of those thugs you see out there
smoking blunts and playing
video games and neither are you.
I could see that right off.
Do you train with weapons?
Catch.
Hey, hey, hey.
Now, I guess you're thinking,
what does this street hustler
know about honor and nobility?
Well, the truth of the matter is,
not very much.
But I am learning.
I have a path, I have a vision,
I have a plan
that I would very much like you
to be a part of.
How so?
International underground
street fighting is by far...
the biggest moneymaking
fight game, period.
It is the pastime
for a group of fat cats...
who like to call themselves
The Consortium.
This is the game
that I am trying to get into.
You got an in?
You ever hear of a man
called Franklin McVeigh?
No.
Franklin McVeigh is an
international arms dealer. Large.
If there's a war in this world, that fool
is probably providing the party favors.
But he wasn't always this big.
He was a small-time thug from London,
selling pop guns to
the little black and brown kids...
on the streets of America.
Needless to say,
that is where I met him.
Anyway,
Franklin McVeigh runs the international
fight game for The Consortium.
And he manages
the best fighter in the world.
They call him Pretty Boy Price
Now, don't let his looks
fool you...
He has already killed
four men in the ring...
Pound for pound, he's considered
the best fighter in the world.
It costs five million dollars,
to get in the ring with him.
Now, ordinarily, you would have
to work your way up the ranks...
to get a fight with Price.
But McVeigh owes me.
I want to do to Franklin McVeigh
what you and Pinball did to me.
You beat Price,
you can retire a very rich man.
I will think about it.
What is there to think about?
Like I said,
I will think about it.
Okay, my friend. You do that.
But you should know
I don't like people
that say no to me.
Maybe you should get used to it.
This what you're looking for?
No.
I need you to do something
for me first.
Come with me.
What now?
Do you see that man
that you keep looking at?
I want you...
Fuck you and the mule
you rode in on.
Hey. What'd I tell you
about that language?
Fuck you.
Come here.
Do you know
what I can do to you?
Look at me.
No, really, look at me.
Now, you know
what I am capable of, right?
And you know...
that I will do it, too.
So why don't you
go over there...
and do what I told you to do?
Come with me.
"Take care of my wife
and my kid".
That's what he told me.
That's the last thing he said
before he died.
Who?
Who do you think?
Danny.
You knew Danny?
How?
In prison.
He was my friend.
Well, sorry to do this
to you, but...
Checkmate.
Man.
Hey, check this out, man.
It's a beautiful picture, man.
That's my family.
My wife and my son.
Never got a chance to meet him,
but I am going to see him soon.
You know, you remind me
of my brother.
Really? You have a brother?
Had a brother.
A twin.
What happened to him?
Somebody killed him.
Thought he was me.
Some chess.
Come here.
All inmates to their cells, now.
- Go.
- Lock it down, lock it down.
Back in your cells.
Come here.
Tell me something.
Is this the woman
that Danny cried over...
and begged me to look after
as he was dying?
Danny.
Did you forget you had a son?
Don't you judge me.
Don't you fucking judge me.
The whole reason I am in this shit
is because of Danny and my son.
I knew James set him up
to get to me.
I also knew
that if he couldn't have me,
he would have killed Danny
and my son.
I always hoped he'd get
tired of me and let me go.
I could find my son.
But that's all just a pipe dream.
I don't know where my son is.
I don't even know if he's alive.
Your son is alive
and I know where he is.
So let's get you cleaned up
and go get your son.
So that's what
this whole thing is about, huh?
You're my white knight here
to save me from the tower?
Well, I don't know
about white knight.
Okay, just play along, smile,
act like we just had a good time.
That's good.
So?
So I think
I am going to like this organization.
You don't look any worse for wear.
Why should I?
It feels good
to make love to a real man.
Hey, listen.
If you're tired of her,
why don't you let me take her
off your hands for a while?
Well, I might consider
to do that.
Depends upon what
you're willing to do for me.
What you think?
Get your stuff together.
You're going with Bone
for a while.
And don't forget your medicine.
So we will talk about this
later, right?
All right?
Where are you taking me?
Someplace where you can
get yourself back together.
Okay.
So, what's up?
See all that?
All that is mine.
Every block,
every sidewalk, every alley.
It's all so...
dark and unsophisticated.
It is not where
I want to be anymore.
- It's anonymous, right?
- Absolutely, sir.
We're good.
What about my son?
I want to see my son.
Not till you're straight.
This way, miss.
Bone.
Thank you.
Good to see you, James.
You should visit more often.
I hear you have become quite the golfer.
Yes.
But unfortunately,
I just lost my golfing partner.
You, my friend, should learn
the fine art of subtlety.
So what do I owe the pleasure
of this visit?
Five million dollars.
What's this for?
I want a fight
with your pretty boy.
So we're looking to sit
at the grownups' table, are we?
I have a fighter.
This guy's the real deal.
You're not talking
about Hammerman, are you?
He's not even in Price's league.
No, this is a new guy.
Best I have ever seen.
And I have seen Price.
Well, it's not as simple
as that, James.
The Consortium is owned
by a private organization.
All newcomers have to be
agreed upon by committee.
Come on, Franklin.
After all I have done for you... you
couldn't do me this one little thing?
You're asking me to vouch for you.
Well, the funny thing
about vouching for someone, James,
is that when that someone
shows themselves
to be less than what was promised,
every decision you take from
that point on is second-guessed.
And that, in my line of work,
is suicide.
Besides, why does a cool,
mellow fellow like yourself
want to hang around with a
bunch of stuffy, old white guys?
Same reason you want to hang around
those stuffy, old white guys.
Power.
Connections.
But let's keep it real.
I am just a cool, mellow fellow,
just shucking and jiving,
crip-walking, basketball-playing,
singing and dancing
and taking out your garbage.
That's what I am to you.
You're right.
You are African-American.
And myself and my friends,
for the most part,
don't care for the company
of African-Americans.
Quite frankly,
we're entertained by you.
We're thrilled by your high-flying
acrobatics on the basketball court,
that wonderful sense
of rhythm you have,
your animal athleticism.
But apart from that,
we have no use for you.
Understand?
I mean, let's face it, James.
Do you set a place at your
dinner table for your pit bulls?
Now, is this keeping it
real enough for you?
I have another theory on this subject
matter and it goes something like this.
I imagine several
hundred years ago,
a group of very powerful men,
not unlike yourself,
were out
conquering the known world.
So they get to Africa,
feeling pretty good
about themselves,
definitely feeling superior to the
savages they see running in the jungle.
That is, until one of the brothers
drops his loincloth.
And then these powerful men
all of a sudden...
come face to face, so to speak,
with one of life's
great inequities.
Let's whip them out and I will settle
that myth right here and now.
Let's go.
Okay, my friend.
I will stick my neck out
and vouch for you.
But if you let me down
in front of my people,
life will become very lonely
for you out there on those streets.
Am I clear?
Clear as water.
I am hosting a retreat for Consortium
members over the next three days.
Have your man ready in two.
He will be ready.
Wait.
I know this man.
You know him?
His name is Roberto.
He liked to help kids.
You hear about Roberto?
Yeah. I saw him.
They put the dogs
on that poor, sweet old man.
Put the dogs on him.
Chewed him up
like a piece of meat.
I just don't...
I don't understand
this place anymore.
I don't.
I am just saddened.
It will get better.
Mr. Bone,
someone's here to see you.
Come on, baby, let's go.
Cute kid.
Always wanted one of my own.
I got to call you
pimp of the year, player.
I give you my best girl
two days ago.
I turn around, find you
putting it to the nanny.
What're you doing here?
It's on, brother.
It is on.
What is on?
The fight
between you and Price.
You put the money up
for the fight?
Five million dollars.
But I never said I would fight.
Excuse me?
I told you I'd think about it.
I thought about it.
Decided not to fight.
Man, are you out of your
fucking mind?
Five million dollars.
- Get it back.
- Get it back. Get it back.
Do you know...
how much shit
you are getting me in?
You're smarter than that.
You are in that fight.
Yes, motherfucker.
You are in that fight...
or somebody's going to be dead.
You're right.
Somebody might be.
No.
Ease the fuck back there,
motherfucker.
Look. Listen.
I want you to take this money,
take the kids and check into a hotel.
Stay there till you hear from me.
It's too dangerous for you now.
I will.
But when I come back,
I want you gone.
Rustle up the crew now.
I want every motherfucker
with a gun...
locked, loaded and ready
to regulate in 15 minutes.
Get Bone, get Pinball,
that bitch,
the nanny,
all of them motherfuckers.
You smell like
watermelon bubblegum.
Where that motherfucker, Bone?
Well, the last time I saw him,
I believe
he was at your mother's house...
with a box of condoms
and a bucket of chicken.
He got jokes.
You done did it now.
Don't you know I am from Pittsburgh?
We don't play that shit.
No.
I said, where that nigga, Bone?
Where that nigga...
- ... Bone?
- Hold on, slick.
Where that nigga, Bone?
I said, where that nigga, Bone?
Man, B, you're really good with
that gun as you are with your fists.
You going to tell me what the hell's
going on around here?
You want to talk about it here
or down at the police station?
Yeah, let's talk about that later.
But help me get this
side of beef off of me.
James.
Homegirl says
she got the 411 on Angela.
Yeah, I seen that girl you all was
talking about at the Intersection.
- What intersection?
- No, man the Intersection,
back where the judge sent me
to get clean, she in there.
That girl, she in there.
Seven.
Angela.
Angela, come on, get up.
What's up, bitches?
The fuck you going to do?
Don't move. because I'd love to
bust a cap in one of your asses.
Get their cell phones.
- You got that bitch yet?
- Yeah, I have got her...
- Bone?
- Now I am coming for you...
Fuck.
Okay, motherfucker.
- What's up?
- You want to play games?
Time to play
follow the motherfucking leader.
Shit. He wants us to follow him.
And I think I know where.
Yeah, Franklin. James.
That fight,
it has to happen tonight.
Good evening, sir.
This way, if you will.
Mr. Bone,
it's good of you to join us.
Like I said, family,
you are going to fight.
And you are going to win me back
my money.
And if I don't fight?
Then you will die.
And I will go back to town
and I will kill the nanny
and the three little brats
and your little rat, Pinball.
And this will hurt.
But I will gut and filet Angela
like a sea bass.
Just like you killed Roberto.
That stupid old man opened
his mouth one time too many.
And you killed my friend Danny in prison,
set him up for a murder he didn't commit.
You knew Danny?
So that's what this is about.
Danny and Angela.
He was a stupid-ass boy.
He didn't deserve Angela.
Well, I guess right about now
you will be getting the picture...
about how the fuck we roll.
James, you talk too much.
Yes, you do.
I want to report a possible homicide,
4215 Westgate Terrace.
Yeah, I am about to send you
a video. All right.
So, you're ready to fight,
Mr. Bone?
And if I don't?
Then I will beat you
where you stand.
Need I say more?
Do you want to change?
For what?
Not bad.
Winner by forfeit, Price.
You motherfucker.
- James.
- Fuck you, too.
O'Hara.
- I will see you later.
- Nobody move.
L.A.P.D.
L.A.P.D..
Everybody, stay where you are.
If I go down, you go down, too.
We will see.
Hey, Bone, when I get out,
you got family on the outside.
Believe that, big homie.
Believe that.
want to go see your mommy?
Go, baby.
Never going to leave you again.
Never again.
I know I said you had to leave,
but you can stay if you like.
No, you were...
You were right. I am trouble.
You knew that boy was here
the whole time, didn't you?
And who his mother was...
long before you ever came
and knocked on my door.
I have got some money
in this envelope for you.
Nobody's looking for it.
I'd like Angela to stay here with
Jared after she gets cleaned up.
- That's if it's all right with you.
- It's all right.
You did all of this just
to keep a jailhouse promise?
I like to keep my promises.
I got to go.
Thank you.
Give you a lift?
No.
I think I will walk.
Life in the city
keep going, don't it?
Oh, yeah.
Sure you don't want to stick around?
I could set some fights up.
We could make some real money, man.
Nope. Got some business
to take care of.
Sit on my shank, motherfucker.