For 74 years, the might
of Soviet socialism was so great
it split the world
along Eastern and Western lines.
Then, in 1991,
it collapsed completely.
One by one, the various countries
which had supported the Soviet Union
began splitting away,
declaring their independence.
The parliament
of the Eastern Slav Republic
followed suit, declaring
the country a sovereign state,
independent from Soviet rule.
Capitalism advanced rapidly.
The conglomerates gained influence
in political circles,
and as a result,
the oligarchs came into power.
In the Eastern Slav Republic,
the divide between rich and poor
became so great
it ignited the fuse of a new rebellion.
The push for independence
exploded into the streets.
Armed freedom fighters pitted
themselves against their government,
now controlled by the oligarchs.
The military prospered
during this time,
becoming ever stronger
and better equipped.
Under the guidance
of Ivan Judanovich,
an Ataman
from the Council of Elders,
the freedom fighters
moved their base
to a hidden location.
A more suitable place to launch
their guerrilla war
against the government.
After several years of brutal fighting,
it was Svetlana Belikova,
Eastern Slav's first female president,
who offered a ceasefire
to the freedom fighters.
But the break from hostilities
was short-lived.
In November of 2010,
the government discovered
that the rebels' land
contained valuable resources.
The military continued
their attacks,
claiming they were
fighting terrorism.
Losing one base after another
to the military's onslaught,
the freedom fighters
escalated their efforts
and became more and more
radical in their tactics.
It was then that strange rumors
began spreading like wildfire
among the people
that monsters had joined the battle.
In February of 2011,
the rumors made it to
the old city of Holifgrad,
just a few kilometers
from the Presidential Palace,
an important strategic location
for the government.
Listen to the words of the elders.
We have finally gained
the power that we need.
Power that will lead us to victory.
Gather, people.
Gather and fight.
Fight for independence!
Retreat! We're getting slaughtered!
Another rebel!
Do not resist arrest.
- Retreat!
- Drop your weapons.
Surrender immediately.
- Government pigs!
I repeat, do not resist arrest.
Surrender immediately.
Moving into position.
COPY-
I've got a clear view
of you from the sky.
Great.
Maybe you can help me find
a clear route to the CIA drop-off.
Looks like they're doing some
serious renovations down here.
Listen to me carefully, Leon.
Your mission has been aborted.
The U. S. is going to pull out
of the country.
What? I just got here.
After taking me off furlough
and sending me to this
godforsaken place?
What the hell?
Washington and the government there
have decided to go their separate ways.
Everyone has to leave,
not just embassy staff
All American citizens have been
ordered to evacuate the country.
I don't give a damn
about the politics.
We've got confirmation that B.O.W.s
are being used in this war.
If we don't stop them now,
the same shit will
happen everywhere.
Do you really wanna see that?
This is a war
and things are different.
No one can do anything without backup
from the American government.
Not even you.
Well then, I guess
my only option is to
lose my American
citizenship for a while.
Leon!
She can tell them I got lost
and missed my flight.
Better hurry up and get this done.
I need some breakfast.
Scarecrow.
I'm the Tin Man.
Can you talk?
What's the connection between the
anti-government forces and the B.O.W.s?
I guess scarecrows
aren't known
for rousing
conversation.
Hang in there.
I'll get you out of here.
Bee--
What?
Say that again.
Bee
keeper.
Beekeeper?
The honeybee I saw outside.
Great. Now I got a
cowardly lion to deal with.
It's the army.
Is anyone here?
Check the room down there.
Hey-- Unh!
Don't say a word.
How about that one?
Shh.
Huh?
This one's clear.
Clear.
- This one's clear.
- We're moving on.
Pull out.
They're gone.
We better stay here
a while longer.
They may come back.
Do you think our hostage
will be of any use?
Do you know who we are?
Are you Dorothy?
You people in the CIA
call us terrorists.
But we prefer to call ourselves
pro-independence fighters.
What is the CIA
doing here?
Did you put the
government up to this?
Are there any more
of you?
I'm not a CIA agent.
I'm just an American who was
screwed out of his vacation,
dumped on a plane
and brought here.
Without breakfast.
They came for you
while you were on vacation?
Hey, Buddy.
He's got to be high up
in the CIA for them to do that.
You watch too many movies.
Then what are you?
Is it common for people in America
to be packing one of these
while on vacation?
Sure. We've been doing it since
the country was founded.
Wow, America's the bomb, yo!
Eh.
Whatever.
But even if you're not CIA,
there is no doubt you
must be pretty special
for America to send you here.
You were able to take on
that thing, after all.
If you don't stop messing around
with that thing,
you're gonna get us all killed.
There is no doubt about the fact
that you are our enemy.
An anti-terrorist
sweep is now in operation.
Civilians should avoid
going outside
as much as possible.
If you see any suspicious
people or behavior,
report it to the authorities
immediately.
Hm.
Status.
Some escaped underground.
But it's only a matter of time
before they are rounded up.
Tell me in more detail.
When, exactly?
Well...
Um...
You see--
How many times are you going
to make the same mistake?
We should have become a member
of the United Nations five years ago.
And by now
be a respected member
of the international community
in our role as an EU nation.
But before that could happen,
another group came crawling
out of the sewers,
screaming their declarations
of separatism.
And the main cause of this
is because you allowed
the terrorists to do as they please.
If we don't act soon,
we will lose our chance
for true independence forever.
And we cannot
allow that to happen
at any cost.
Madam President.
Your visitor has arrived.
Show her in.
Welcome to Eastern Slav,
my dear.
I am President Svetlana Belikova.
Gentlemen, allow me to
introduce you to our guest.
This young lady
is a special investigator
for the United Nations'
Bio-terrorism Security Alliance.
Good day, Madam President.
Gentlemen.
I have been sent here by the BSAA.
My name is Ada Wong.
Hey, you.
My name is not,
"Hey, you."
I'm JD.
Although that's not
my real name.
The old man's
not looking too good.
He always looks like that.
Let's hope you're right.
Anyways, what are you
really doing in this country?
Hey, a different question
for a change.
Ugh. What I mean is,
being in America
is a lot more fun than
being here, right?
I wouldn't know.
The hamburgers, man.
The fried chicken.
Food in your country's
fantastic.
I could eat it every day.
Thanks for the valuable insight.
And the Hollywood movies.
I love those things.
I have 50 DVDs.
None of them are pirated.
I thought you guys hated America.
Sure, we hate it.
But things made in America?
Now, that's different.
Whatever you do,
don't push that button.
I'm not falling for that.
No way I'll allow them
to trace the call.
How are things
out there?
Looks like they have the old pan
of the city surrounded.
We'd better wait and see
how things pan out.
Bio Organic Weapons.
Also known as
B.O.W.s.
Most developed countries
and the United Nations
are against the use and
manufacture of B.O.W.s.
However, they are, unfortunately,
still traded on the
world's black markets.
From a quick glance at this report,
I'd say that using these weapons
in a real conflict
would be extremely
impractical, no?
There's no way to differentiate
between friend and foe.
It is true that total control
of most of the B.O.W.s
has been nearly impossible
up until now.
But a new technology
that changes that fact
has recently been developed.
Tell me more.
Recent technological advancements
can establish
a master/slave relationship
between a human and the B.O.W.s.
So? What do they do,
crack whips at it?
Like they do with wild animals?
Not exactly.
Organisms, designed to determine
whether a host is to be
a controller or a controlee
take up residence
within the host's body
and creates the perfect
master/slave relationship
between a human
and the B.O.W.
Similar to the relationship
a queen bee shares
with her worker bees.
Yo, bro. Can I speak
to you for a moment?
What about?
It's about Ataman.
It could be dangerous
to move him now.
And your American friend has
also taken quite an interest in him.
You don't--
You don't have to worry
about me.
We can't stay here forever.
Who's in there?
Open the door.
- Anyone there?
- Open the door.
Open up!
- Stop resisting
and come out.
- Step back.
Three, two,
One!
Don't move. Hands in the air.
Don't move.
Stay still.
Don't shoot.
Drop your guns!
Let's go. Take them away.
Keep away
from him!
He's turned!
Downstairs.
Someone is in the basement.
Shoot. Shoot!
Quick, run!
Are you all right?
Ataman.
We have to hurry.
They'll be here soon.
You...
go on ahead.
Damn, just when things
were going well.
We can win this war,
can't we?
JD.
It's-- It's time
for me to go.
But I'll be rooting for you
from heaven.
Ugh. Get up, you idiot. You think that
vest you're wearing is a girl's blouse?
We have to get Ataman
away from here.
Huh?
Wow. I should have guessed.
Made in America.
Wait.
Where's the American?
Dead, probably.
Give me a hand.
Leave me here.
If we go on like this,
we'll all be killed
before we can launch an attack
on the capital.
Go.
Create a new future.
This way. I heard gunshots.
They're here.
I'm going to go
and check on Marco.
You head to the church
and join the others.
Okay.
Shh.
Hm?
Do you really think
I'm gonna fall for that?
Aah!
Kill you.
Do I look like I need a pruning?
Don't kill him!
That's one request I can't grant.
Ugh!
Mr. Chenkov.
I told you
not to kill him.
He was my teacher.
It was him or me.
And don't forget,
he wasn't your teacher anymore.
Ugh!
Shoot.
Shoot, JD!
Why the hell carry that gun around
if you're not gonna use it?
Don't worry.
I'll use it next time.
If you ever decide to shoot those things,
shoot them in the head, got it?
Wait.
This way.
Two grown men
should be able to open it.
So, what is this place?
Old partisans used to
hole up here
back in the day.
They sure knew how
to keep the enemy out.
This thing ain't gonna budge.
Stand back.
That way.
This way.
Quick.
Oh, I knew I should have
stayed off the
junk food.
Hurry LIP
Get away!
Get him.
Stay away from me!
No.
- No. No!
- Get him.
Aah!
Please, somebody help me!
Help me!
What's happening?
Stay away! No!
Get away!
Help!
What happened to everybody?
Anywhere we can hide?
Yeah.
What did you do
to everybody?
The Plaga you were
hiding got loose.
I don't know what
you're talking about!
Your precious townsfolk are
being controlled by a parasite.
It attaches itself to the central
nervous system via the spinal cord.
The people of the town are--?
They'll never be normal again.
There must be something we can do.
Rip out the spinal cord,
but the best you could hope for
is paralysis or death.
You are lying!
If you really believe that,
then why did you kill the old man?
But that was--
Because you knew he would
never be human again.
What he says is true.
I have some more
questions for you.
Maybe this time
we can get to the truth.
What are we going to do?
I have to go and get it.
Go and get it?
Why?
We need somebody
to take over for Ataman.
You've seen what's
happening outside.
Do you want that to happen to you?
What we do today will carry
the country into tomorrow.
But even so...
I'll meet up with the others
tomorrow to plan
an attack on the
Presidential Palace.
Get ready for that.
I'll be back soon.
I want a word with him.
He's gone to get it.
The Plaga?
I don't know its name.
All I know is that it was
given to us by the elders.
You inject that stuff into your body
to control the Lickers, right?
Some compassionate elders
you got there.
What other options do we have?
Do you realize
that the whole world ignores us?
That we are in danger
of extermination?
Save your breath.
We're not gonna see
eye to eye on this.
Help us.
I don't want to see him
change into a monster.
Irina would not be happy
about this.
Irina?
We knew her
since we were kids.
Buddy's fiancée.
She was a school teacher
and, believe it or not,
so was Buddy.
Bastards thought
their school
was a pro-independence
hideout and attacked it.
Irina and the kids died in the attack.
That's the reason why
he's fighting this war.
He had never even held
a gun up until then.
I'm going to pretend you escaped.
In return, you must get
ahold of it before he does.
So now you trust me?
I don't know who or what you are,
but I do know that
you saved my life.
You must stop Sasha.
You'll find him
in the central marketplace.
Everyone, evacuate immediately.
The operation begins at 2000 hours.
Looking for someone?
Ada.
It's been a long time, Leon.
What are you doing here?
I was about to ask you
the same thing.
Did you release
the Plaga?
Don't make me laugh.
I'm not interested
in defective products.
I'm just here to lend them
a hand.
Them?
Although it seems as if
my help wasn't needed.
What are you doing here?
If they attack the capital,
it'll make my job a lot easier.
That's all.
By the way,
when are we going to, um, carry on
from where we left off that night?
Heh. Any time but now.
You're angry with me, aren't you?
Suits you.
Quick word of warning.
This town will be purged soon!
Women.
General?
Yes.
You may start the attack
when you are ready.
Thank you.
Bring Ada Wong to me.
She should see this.
Great. I get to play Santa Claus.
Are you all right?
Yeah, just let my guard
down for a moment.
They got us pretty good.
Where's Buddy?
He already left by the time I got there.
Damn!
We have to leave now.
The military's gonna
burn the whole area
and everything in it.
What?
We're out of time
What's wrong?
Nothing.
There's just something
I have to do.
Won't you be needing that?
Hm.
Ah, you my man. Heh, heh.
Buddy.
Cool. You're still human.
JD.
You. What have you done?
No. He's not our enemy. He's--
I'm fine. Just go.
I don't want to cause
any more trouble.
It's time to say goodbye.
JD!
Wait.
You know, I didn't really care
about independence.
All I wanted was to have fun
with you and my friends.
And...
I was looking forward
to showing you America.
Trust me,
I've seen this
happen every time.
When you're dealing with B.O.W.s,
there's no difference
between friend or enemy.
It takes everything from you:
The cause you're fighting for,
the respect you have for others.
We have to keep this from
ever happening again.
Give me the Plaga.
As far as I am concerned,
there is no difference between
this and using B.O.W.s.
If you want to keep this
from happening again,
put down your gun.
Well, then.
That is my answer...
and your answer.
The eradication of the B.O.W.s
is moving ahead according to plan.
You mustn't allow even one of them
to escape the city.
We are prepared for all
eventualities, madam.
And one more thing,
regarding Ada Wong.
Did you find anything out?
There is no one working for the BSAA
by the name of Ada Wong.
Are you serious?
Yes, madam.
Hm.
Of course.
Central gate.
Report your status.
Central gate reporting.
All is calm.
- Roger.
Keep your eyes peeled.
Three trucks are approaching.
Heads up, everyone.
Halt.
Halt!
Where did you go last night?
You were not in the hotel.
I went to meet an old friend.
And this old friend...
is he a spy?
Hm.
Who are you working for?
The Russians?
The Americans?
I'll leave that
to your imagination.
Considering that you will never be
leaving this country again,
I would say it is in your best interests
to stay on my good side.
Very funny.
So it's true what they said
about you being a former instructor.
Hm.
Former? I still am an instructor.
Yes?
The terrorists broke through the
central gate.
As I said, we have decided
to delay your departure.
Permanently.
Now, that's impressive.
I keep saying
these things make bad pets.
We are under attack by terrorists.
We need reinforcements, now!
We can't defend
the palace much longer. Aah!
Sony, but I don't have time to stay
and chat right now.
Amateurs.
They didn't even
give me a pat-down.
I didn't expect to get into
this place so easily.
Pretty impressive for
an old nuclear shelter.
Heh. So you missed me, huh?
Yeah. In your dreams.
You seeing
what I'm seeing?
Uh-huh.
It's like a beehive.
Have you looked inside
one of these?
It's the Plaga.
Hmm.
Big surprise.
Workers have been
cultivated in the past.
But this...
This is the first time that
the dominant members
of the species have been cultured.
What are you doing?
I'm working.
Don't worry about it.
Oh, I'm worried.
Enough!
So this is what you're here for.
Well?
Are you satisfied?
Yes, thank you very much.
Who is he?
I don't know.
He's an American agent.
Well, now that we got that
out of the way...
An American?
You'd better watch out.
That old broad's got a bite
worse than her bark.
Say what?
Over there! Over there! Shoot!
Ceasefire! Ceasefire! Unh!
Ceasefire!
Don't move.
Do you have any idea
who you are pointing
your gun at?
Hmm. Yeah, let me see.
You're the beekeeper.
The beekeeper?
The person who
released the Plaga.
Just as I thought,
you haven't a clue.
I am the president
of this country.
So that's what Ada meant.
He is an enemy of the state.
Kill him!
Creatures broke through
the cargo entrance!
They're heading your way!
Aah!
Open fire!
Cease fire. Cease fire.
Help me!
SOLDIER 1 I
Aah!
Fall back! Aah!
Did you use it?
Get him.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't stop him.
You bastard! Aah!
Help!
Unh!
What will you gain
by killing me?
Have you thought
this through?
Who will lead the country
once you gain independence?
You?
I have no intention
of taking advice
from a pretender to the throne.
Heh.
In case you're interested,
all of the elders,
with the exception of Ataman,
have already come over to my side.
They all said they would be happy
to renege on independence
once I promised to share
the oil profits with them.
That's not possible.
Yes, that's what I thought.
But I'm afraid it's true.
Shut up! Unh!
While we have been wasting time here,
things have been happening in the world.
We don't have time
to fight amongst ourselves
in this tiny little country.
Shut up!
Oh, great. It just keeps getting better.
We have to go.
Svetlana!
A biohazard
release has been detected.
Evacuate. Evacuate.
The incineration of the facility
will begin shortly.
Run!
Why is it doing that?
You owe me one.
Why are you helping me?
Don't get all sentimental
on me.
I'm not doing this for you.
There's nobody else left to tell the
world what really happened, that's why.
The hatch!
This will take us up.
Damn it.
Hurry.
Come on.
Let's get going.
This is an announcement
from the government
of the Eastern Slav Republic.
We are under attack
by terrorists.
Biochemical weapons
may have been used.
You are ordered
to evacuate the city immediately.
Please keep a distance
of five kilometers from the capital.
Excuse me.
Yes, what is it?
Forces have been
evacuated from the city
to escape the B.O.W.s
released by the terrorists.
However,
it appears the two in the
shelter have managed to escape.
Why are you wasting
my time telling me this?
Just let the you-know-what
get rid of them.
I'll see to it immediately.
Help me!
Nice work, pal.
Get out of there!
You really
shouldn't have done that.
You really want to fight this out, huh?
Sony for butting in.
You can run, but you can't hide.
Ah, come on. Don't be shy.
NOW!
This might hurt a little.
I didn't expect to be saved
by B.O.W.s.
Wanna go grab a few beers?
Are you buying?
You'll have to go without me.
Can't they find anybody
else to play with?
Why don't you go without me?
I like the company.
We'd better move a little faster.
Today the capital
was subjected to a powerful attack
launched by terrorists.
They struck with fearsome weapons
of mass destruction
known as B. O.W.s,
which have been banned
internationally.
We as a country desire nothing more
than to live in peace.
Together with the elders of the
anti-government movement,
who, might I add,
graciously listened to our pleas,
have managed to avert
the most serious crisis
in the history of our nation.
I believe this is undeniable proof
that as a country,
as a people,
we are suitable for full acceptance
into the international community.
As leader...
Something wrong?
I don't need this.
I'll improvise.
What about the elders?
It's over. All of them.
A little while ago.
I suppose I should mention that
during the press conference,
that the terrorists
executed the elders
as traitors.
Yes, madam.
Is there anything else?
I've already contacted
the BSAA and Interpol
with regard to the damage
we sustained because of Ada Wong.
An international warrant for
her arrest will be issued soon.
A few of the terrorists
managed to escape the city,
but you don't have to
worry about them.
What about the other two?
It's just a matter of time.
Finally, there is no one
left to stop us.
That's right,
Madam President.
Very well, let's start the
press conference immediately.
Yes, of course,
Madam President.
At last,
a new tomorrow begins.
They were keeping an eye
on me the whole time.
On air in five, four, three...
Good evening. I am President--
Madam President.
We're under attack
by the Americans and Russians.
What? It can't be.
Stay down,
you dogs.
Stay still.
Move. Keep them away.
Move! Move!
- Hands in the air!
- Help me.
So...
The Americans and Russians
had us in the palms of their hands
from the beginning.
That's what it looks like.
Did you know about this?
No.
If I did, I'd still be enjoying
my vacation.
He?!
I've lost everything.
My mentor,
my friends.
I have nothing left to fight for.
Kill me.
Please.
I don't want to change
into one of those monsters.
Well...
I guess there is no other choice.
I'd feel the same way if I was you.
But the option of taking our own
lives no longer belongs to us.
Once we start using these, we owe it
to the people who died alongside us.
We have to continue living.
Even if it means living the rest of our
lives without the use of our limbs.
That is my answer
and your answer...
Buddy.
It's been three days
since the end of the civil war
that tore through
the Eastern Slav Republic.
The fierce battles
were halted thanks to the intervention
of American and Russian troops.
Today marks the first day
in which the world's media
has access to the city.
A temporary government
headed by the U. S. and Russia
will be set up in the Eastern
Slav Republic to maintain peace.
Svetlana Belikova has resigned
from her presidency
and companies that supported her
and the former government
will be thrown out of the country
and dismantled.
Top brass knew about it right
from the beginning, didn't they?
The report from
Scarecrow tipped them off
that Svetlana was in
possession of B.O.W.s.
That's why they pulled out
in a panic
and ran like hell to join forces
with the Russians.
To protect themselves, right?
You're mistaken.
The president had nothing
to do with this.
Not even we knew what was going on.
You have to believe me.
Leon.
I'm not going anywhere
Don't--
In the end, nothing's really changed.
Everything went according to plan.
The facility has been destroyed
and I salvaged
the cultivated Plaga.
But I haven't decided
whether or not
I should send it to you.
Really?
Thank you. That's very kind.
Although, I sort of liked the idea
of adding an international
arrest warrant to my profile.
What are you doing?
- You're going to get in trouble.
- Did you do yours?
- Morning.
- Hi.
Good morning.
- Morning.
Oh, come on, let's
go, we're gonna be late.
Morning.