Look up!
Bogeys overhead! Pull up!
I'm hit! I've lost control.
Ejecting!
Look out! That's the Teacher!
He's on my tail!
Help!
I'm gonna kill him.
Hey.
Who are you?
I'm Sasakura, a mechanic here.
Hello, I'm Kannami Yuichi.
Never seen a female mechanic before?
No, I've seen one before.
Good.
That's the bird you'll be flying.
I can't fly this one?
The company's going to retrieve that one.
Aren't they the same?
I don't want to switch if possible.
You'll find out when you fly it.
Besides, it's an order from the boss here.
Who flew that bird before me?
Why?
Taking it over will require some work.
Then ask the boss.
Come in.
I'm Kannami Yuichi, stationed here as of today.
I'm Kusanagi Suito.
You're early.
I was expecting you this evening.
The sun was too bright.
Is that Camus?
Use room 204.
You'll be rooming with Tokino.
You'll fly with him tomorrow afternoon.
Um...
Sorry.
Excuse me.
I'm Kannami, stationed here as of today.
I'm Yudagawa.
And that's Shinoda Uroyuki.
How many pilots are stationed here?
Normally, there are three of us.
Including you and him?
Four of us including you, starting today.
Only four?
Yes, four.
Add the beautiful Kusanagi, and there are five who can fly.
She can fly as well?
Did he stay out all night again?
Who are you?
I'm Kannami, stationed here as of today.
Ah, so that's you.
I'm Tokino, your roommate.
I know.
I saw the room too.
And about us flying together tomorrow?
That too.
Then, nice meeting you.
You don't mean this is your first time, do you?
The mission? Or this bird?
Bird.
I've been flying Mark Bs since I was born.
Yes.
You tested me?
Now nobody thinks you're a chicken.
I can't see anything unusual.
Let's get home.
Roger.
Look out! Three birds!
Same height, ten o'clock!
Are you all right?
No damage.
How many did you kill?
Two.
Bravissimo!
Welcome back.
Thanks.
Hey!
Damage on our side?
Zero.
What about the Lautern Corps' test line?
It remains quiet. No movement seen.
All right, well done.
Excuse me.
Um... may I ask a question?
It's about the person who flew that bird before me.
His name was Kurita Jinro.
He was stationed here seven months ago.
He sortied sixty-three times.
He was pretty good.
Where did he go?
I can't answer that.
The reason he transferred?
Not that either.
Did he die?
Even if he did, it doesn't change your situation in any way.
To be present or not:
a person is always in one of those two states.
Normally, we contact the former pilot when we take over a bird, correct?
Of course, that's only possible if the original pilot is still alive.
That bird is still new.
I decided that there was no need for a briefing.
Any complaints?
No, I couldn't ask for a better plane.
Anything else?
Are you one of the Kildren?
You're also a smoker.
I don't trust superior officers who don't smoke.
For what reason?
Just a gut feeling, based on experience.
Experience...
That will be all.
Please excuse me.
How did you kill two birds in such a short time?
Flattery?
I don't flatter.
My opponents just happened to be beginners.
Being modest?
Yeah.
Where were you before this?
I don't remember.
Wanna go out tonight?
Where to?
I thought I'd show you around.
You could say it's my job.
What's this place?
They have great meat pies.
Aren't you hungry?
...appears to be an engagement.
Three of Lautern's twin-engine fighter aircraft, Rainbows, downed.
And it is reported that two pilots were killed and another was severely wounded.
On the evening of October fifth,
the situation on the Northern front in Europe has apparently turned more favorable for the...
The fight here has been rather one-sided recently,
so Lautern might mount a stiffer resistance.
Isn't she talking about your mission?
Congratulations.
I'll have a beer.
He'll have a meat pie and...
Coffee.
This is the place you wanted to show me?
This is only the first point.
We've got to follow a certain order.
I thought I'd tell you about your predecessor.
Mama was giving me the evil eye.
"Mama"?
You know how she looks after our birds?
So we call her Mama.
Here comes the second point.
Hi, Naofumi!
Hi!
This is Kannami Yuichi, a new guy at the base.
Hi, I'm Kusumi. Nice to meet you.
I'm Fuko.
Hi.
Did you like it?
Like what?
The meat pie.
It was delicious.
And it tasted somewhat familiar.
Come on, it'll be all right.
You were here a long time ago as well, right?
Don't know...
Bye, Yuichi.
Later.
How is Suito?
Is that scary girl still doing all right?
Let's go.
Have fun, bye!
That's a good smell.
Since you're here,
that must mean Jinro is dead.
I don't know.
I don't even know who Jinro is.
Do you want something to drink?
Coffee, if you have any.
What was this Jinro person like?
He was kind.
He had a gentle smile and a naïve face like you.
But he seemed to be hung up about something.
Watching him made me anxious.
I once asked him,
"Where do you always leave your heart?"
What did he say?
He didn't answer.
But I guessed maybe in the sky.
And I thought that was true.
How long have you been around here?
You have a funny way of talking to me.
It's funny.
You and I are the only ones here.
And listen to that.
You sound like a kid.
I am a kid.
So, do you like flying?
Yeah, I do.
Good.
Will you come again?
Yeah.
You'd better.
Welcome back.
Did you like it?
It felt just right to me.
I'm completely comfortable with it.
Of course you are.
My work is always perfect.
Jinro flew this before me, right?
How did he die?
Seeing that the bird's still here, he wasn't shot down, was he?
You should go to your room and get some rest.
What's up?
Looks like an oil leak.
What happened?
An oil leak, it seems.
Where's Tokino?
He should be back soon.
Identify the cause and submit a report.
Who are you?
I haven't seen you around here before.
I'm Kannami.
I'm a pilot here.
Kannami what?
Yuichi.
My name is Kusanagi Mizuki.
I'm Kusanagi Suito's younger sister.
Nice to meet you, Yuichi.
Yeah, nice to meet you.
What's nice about it?
You said it first.
I meant that it'd be nice to be friends and be able to talk.
Me too, for the most part.
Do you want something to drink?
Yes.
What brought you here?
School's closed today.
So I came here to play.
Suito said I shouldn't come, but I came anyway.
I'm exploring the place alone, so I don't get in her way.
Let's do something fun.
Like what?
Well...
What do you usually do?
Nothing much.
Nothing I can show you.
Any games or something?
Nope.
Even though you're a kid?
Right.
Are you a Kildren, Yuichi?
I am.
You can't grow up to be an adult, right?
Right.
Why can't you?
It's not that we can't. We just don't.
Do you want to become an adult?
I don't know.
See?
Wow!
Don't look! It'll damage your eyes!
Meanie!
Excuse me, can we borrow welding goggles?
Can we watch the sparks?
Niki!
Coming!
Thank you.
Wow, I can't see anything.
Boo!
It's dangerous, so don't come close.
Got it?
Okay!
Good job.
That took you a while.
Yeah.
Because I was finished, I did some recon.
That's not her sister.
What do you mean?
That's her daughter.
I'm back.
I'll hear your report later.
All right.
Thanks.
It's fine.
Watching her makes me hate myself sometimes.
Why is that?
She'll reach my age soon.
Then what?
I want to ask you a favor.
We're expecting tourists.
Can you take care of them?
Will I be able to?
I'm taking her home.
Okay.
Let's go home.
I hear some tourists are coming to visit?
They came here once before.
I guess they're related to our sponsor or something.
They're a group of people who support our company.
What do you think about that?
What do you mean?
The whole idea of taking a tour of the place.
Nothing much.
I'm sure you'll want to kill them.
That woman's already shot someone.
Which woman?
The one on the second floor.
Kusanagi did?
Yeah.
Why?
She always carries a gun.
Have you heard about Kurita Jinro?
What about him?
That woman shot him.
Why?
Here they are.
This is our hangar.
Does anyone want me to take your picture?
Hello, how are you?
Great, thank you.
My whole family's a big fan of yours.
We're always cheering for your team.
Thank you very much.
Is that your plane?
Yes, it is.
What is it like?
What's what like?
I mean, how does it feel to fly?
Well, I don't know what to say.
What about when you shoot down an enemy plane?
I feel like a winner.
Don't you put a kill mark on your plane?
Some do, but I don't.
It's just like a game.
I know war is always horrible.
You're fighting for a peaceful world.
We really appreciate what you're doing for us.
It's my job.
It's going to crash.
Was the pilot from our company?
The bird's one of our models.
Perhaps it's from a neighboring war zone.
God... help... him.
Poor boy...
Enough is enough!
There's nothing pitiful...
Nothing pitiful at all!
Don't insult him with false sympathy!
Calm down.
It is disclosed that identification of the downed aircraft
is one of Rostock's Sanka-B fighters from the 502 Squadron,
stationed at neighboring district 202,
but other details are not available yet.
Public affairs officials of the company declined to answer further questions concerning this...
Wanna call her?
Call who?
Well, you know...
Oh, no.
I'm heading back after finishing this.
This is Kannami.
Where are you?
At the drive-in.
Sorry, I'm busy. I'm hanging up.
There are three Fortunes heading your way.
Two Fortunes.
No, three of them.
Did you see them?
Yes.
How long before they reach us?
Probably less than five minutes.
That gives us enough time to take a breather.
But you won't make it back.
What about my bird?
I'll fly it.
Thanks.
Heading back?
Yes, although I won't have a plane to fly.
Be careful.
About what?
Yuichi!
Are you guys all right?
We saw big planes flying.
We've already been hit.
What about Naofumi?
I don't know.
Why don't you hop in?
I can't leave this here.
It's not mine.
Then we'll go on ahead.
Sure.
Did all our birds take off okay?
Your bird gave me the most trouble.
It's flying without a spinner.
We didn't even have time to fuel up,
so it might be running low on fuel by now.
Is Kusanagi flying it?
Yes.
That's Naofumi!
Naofumi!
We'd better send those girls back.
Kusanagi will scold you if she sees them.
Scold who?
They said you gave them permission.
Yuichi!
He seems to be doing fine, so we're heading out!
Bye bye, Yuichi!
That's not necessary.
Tokino's late.
I know he's all right.
He was circling just a minute ago.
He must've stopped somewhere.
It's me.
Patch me through to Field Operations.
Hey, you got a smoke?
This is Kusanagi.
Please let me speak to the Director.
Just put the Director on the phone!
Yes, miraculously.
The damage is negligible.
But it's only because the enemy failed.
Why did the message come in late?
That's not enough of a reason. I'm coming over.
Yudagawa!
Can you watch my desk until I return?
An emergency call might come in.
Sure, if I can eat and drink there.
Certainly.
Kannami, come with me.
Aren't we going too fast?
Sorry. I'm in that kind of mood.
There's Tokino.
I knew he'd be around here.
The road in front of the drive-in is perfect for an emergency landing,
so he can get a cup of coffee.
Thank you for this warm welcome.
Long time no see.
So, you won't let me inside?
Strange.
It's not like you suffered damage from a typhoon.
He's my subordinate.
I thought I might be too exhausted after this.
Then he can drive me back.
So, you must be...
The Director is not here at the moment.
I can tell whether or not he's really out once I see his room.
The fact that you came here is proof enough of how severe the situation really is.
I'm sure they'll realize how you feel.
Don't get me wrong.
I just want to see the face of the man who tried to kill me.
How childish...
This is why I hate children.
Oh, sorry.
Actually, you're right.
But do you think it's necessary for those children to grow up,
since they might die as soon as tomorrow?
Turn right at the next corner.
I want to make a stop.
Any calls?
Okay.
You can go and rest.
Thanks.
What is this place?
It's a guest room of sorts.
Employees have the right to use this place, and we need to use it once in a while.
Although nobody comes back here twice.
So, has everyone been here?
With you?
It's rare for me to come here with just one other person.
Why?
Are you hungry?
There's only frozen food, but I'll fix something.
How can you eat that stuff?
Why?
It's pretty disgusting.
But it's made from edible ingredients, right?
Are you going back?
You can stay here tonight.
Did Jinro spend a night here as well?
Yes.
Why?
Yudagawa said something strange.
That you killed Jinro.
Do you...
want me to kill you too?
Five minutes to bingo fuel.
Let's go home.
Turn right to 160.
Maintain this height.
Look out! Bogeys!
Two o'clock behind. Two bombers.
They got escorts.
Twins?
One is a prop forward. Maybe J-Zwei.
Are you sure?
Wanna bet?
I'll check it out.
You head home.
By yourself?
No way! Come back, Westy!
Westy, come in. Where are you?
Confirmed. It's a J-Zwei.
A black panther on the nose.
It's Teacher!
Teacher?!
Pull back, Cairn!
Westy, are you all right?
Where are you?
Come in!
Answer me!
Yudagawa said it was Teacher?
Yes.
That's all.
It happened over the sea.
The plane sank in no time.
Did you see it?
Skily wasn't used to flying around here.
Perhaps he wanted to see for himself whether the bird you saw really was Teacher.
Who's this Teacher?
Once you see him in the sky, you don't come back alive.
He's the ace pilot of Lautern Corps.
Maybe he's been reassigned here because we've been beating them too easily.
It's entirely possible.
Teacher...
I've heard a rumor that he's not like us.
He's an adult.
Even though he's a fighter pilot?
Yeah.
An adult male.
An adult male...
Any word?
None.
I told her that we should head back.
The weather was getting bad, and we were starting to run low on fuel as well.
She agreed with me.
Then why?
She broke formation when she saw an enemy bird.
Since then, she hasn't come back yet...
You shouldn't have any beer.
We may have to fly search-and-rescue.
It was Teacher!
You saw the black panther markings?
If we were close enough to see that, I'd have stayed behind too!
Why is she so adamant about Teacher?
Ask her when she returns.
If she manages to, that is.
Out of my way!
Call a doctor! And an ambulance!
Bring blankets!
I guess she crashed near our place.
Thank you.
I've seen her in that state once before.
Her heart apparently intact, yet crushed inside.
She visited our place once before.
To see my client.
She chased me out, and then stayed in there for hours.
She's not stable.
What are you looking at?!
Stay outside!
Yes!
Got a smoke?
I'm sorry to cause trouble.
Tell that to everyone too.
She's only lost consciousness.
I didn't see any damage to her bones or internal organs,
so it's best to let her sleep until the doctor gets here.
I heard a large-scale operation is coming up.
We'll probably move the base as well.
Move?
I'm sure it's a temporary measure.
She probably wanted to settle the matter before leaving this area.
Sasakura, you've been with Kusanagi for a long time, haven't you?
And?
That girl named Mizuki...
Could the father of Kusanagi's daughter be...
I'll stay with her until the doctor gets here.
You should go and rest.
No matter where we go, the guys are always the same.
It's rare to see someone who makes me think,
"I've never met anyone like this."
Aren't twin pilots rare?
I've seen a few before.
And it's rare for one to return from a mission without the other.
What are you guys doing?
Those are for kids.
I'm a kid too.
Is the man named Kannami still at the party?
I don't think so.
Then he went to his room?
Are you Kannami?
Yeah.
Why didn't you say so in the first place?
You didn't ask me.
What a bummer.
You're nothing like I imagined.
I'm Tokino.
Am I different from what you imagined?
I'm Mitsuya. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you!
I can't wait for tomorrow.
What's up with that woman?
She was pretty good.
Who was?
That woman from last night.
Oh.
She's the ace here.
Female aces are a pain.
I think male aces are a pain as well.
I don't care about men.
You're our ace.
I heard Kusanagi was quite something too.
Oh man, God help me.
Oh well, you're free to do your thing.
What?
I mean, do whatever you want!
You'll be participating in an operation of unprecedented proportions.
The target is Lautern Corps' largest stronghold, located in the central theater of operations.
First, eight fighters, flown by you, will take off from this base.
Units from other bases will gradually join these fighters,
and by the end, the force will total eighty fighters.
In addition, there will be thirty medium bombers and twenty heavy bombers at higher altitudes.
This will be Team B.
Team A, comprised of forty fighters and fifty ground-support craft,
will attack the two forward bases before your arrival.
Any questions?
May I ask something, although it's not related to the battle?
Go ahead.
Will the party tonight be canceled?
Another party?
The local children come here every other month for a party,
and it's being held tonight.
Sorry. I didn't know that.
We are not canceling it.
This operation is top secret.
We can't announce a cancellation now.
Kusanagi, anything to add?
The battle will most likely take place over the sea.
The enemy will definitely react
after their front bases are attacked.
They can't use anti-aircraft weapons if their own birds are in the area.
They'll resist, even if it's futile.
It'll be an unusually lengthy operation for a fighter plane squadron.
Because of their short range,
the Sankas will have to refuel in mid-air.
Don't drop the extra tanks until the last minute.
That's all.
Report to the runway in twenty minutes.
Rostock, contracted war-bird company for the European Confederation,
began long-range raids against the strategically vital facilities of its opponent, Lautern.
It is expected that more large-scale engagements will ensue.
The strength of the attacking force is,
according to the statement by Rostock,
three squadrons of heavy bombers from the Strategic Bombardment Wing,
escorted by fighters from eight squadrons and four tactical squadrons.
Fighter control, flight sixty zero zero to waypoint one.
Estimated time of contact correction: ten zero zero minus zero five.
Repeat. Ten zero zero minus zero five.
Fighter squadrons Able, Baker, Charlie, stay on your altitude.
Whale, fly and evacuate.
Warning! Enemies in sight!
Altitude eighty zero zero.
Fighters contact, engage at will.
All weapons ready.
Let's dance!
Control to everyone.
Evacuate battle area.
Repeat. Evacuate battle area.
Cairn, where are you?
Altitude thirty zero zero. Turning left to join.
Confirmed.
Joining aft left. Turn, turn.
Where's Sturdy?
Not sure.
Sturdy, come in. This is Cairn.
I get no answer.
Mission complete.
RTB, everyone.
Repeat. Return to base, everyone.
Rostock's big offensive that had started at ten o'clock this morning
met with an unexpectedly fierce and effective interception from Lautern
and fell into a total confusion,
inflicting heavy casualties to both sides.
The engagement has seemed to be halted as a recommendation was hastily issued from the European Confederation.
We will report the precise figures of losses and casualties of both conflicting companies
as soon as the Conflict Control Committee will—
Master!
Where are you?
Master?
They lost a lot too.
Did you see them go down?
Which side?
Skily came up from below Kishinuma's bird,
and just when he had almost caught up with Kishinuma,
he made a sudden half-roll,
climbed like this, then went into a stall turn,
let Kumatake's bird fly by as it was trying to catch up,
made a snappy turn, went after him from above and behind...
He was shot down at point-blank range.
A similar maneuver probably took out Shinoda's Sanka.
The enemy was a bird with black panther markings.
Let's go out on the town after this.
Are there any clubs here?
Let's get off at the next stop.
They close early.
It's not that late yet.
I guess it's a small town.
What does that look like?
What a coincidence.
Bowling?
I thought they might at least serve beer.
Close!
Let's go for a spare!
What's she up to?
Tokino.
Hey, he plays pretty cool. Come join us!
Come here, come!
Maybe he'll come...
Your turn, Kannami.
Where do we go next?
Where are you taking us?
Later!
Bye!
You play great.
I want to line those types of girls up, and then mow 'em down with a ball.
Do you want to continue?
Let's ask the staff to recommend a better place and drink some more.
I can't drink any more.
I'll drink.
Why were you so reckless the other day?
Is it because you saw the black panther markings?
He used to be with our company.
Oh?
You said that tactfully.
He was my superior.
As a pilot, he's special.
He's a normal adult.
A grown man.
Why did he join the other company?
He quit this company after some trouble.
Will shooting down Teacher change something?
Like our fate, our limits, or something.
Maybe.
But nobody can shoot him down.
Why?
Who do you think we're fighting?
I don't know.
I've never even thought about that.
Even though we're killing each other?
It's our job.
It's the same, no matter what business we're in.
Whoever shoves the competition hardest and earns the most profit wins.
Compared to normal companies, what we're doing is an inefficient and old-fashioned game.
Yes.
Because it's a game, we can kill and be killed legally.
That's an interesting notion.
Interesting?
No matter the era, war has never been completely eradicated,
because the reality of it has always been important to humans.
The reality of someone fighting somewhere, even now,
is a necessity in the human social system.
And that need can never be fulfilled by lies.
It's not enough to read what wars are like in textbook stories.
The reality of people dying, the reports of that news on the TV:
we can't maintain peace without seeing those tragedies.
We would cease to understand the meaning of peace.
Just as we don't feel alive unless we kill each other in the sky.
And as long as our war is just a game that must never end,
rules are a necessity.
For example, the existence of an enemy we can never defeat.
And that's Teacher?
Haven't you had too much?
What are you looking at?
Get lost! Get lost!
Go away!
Do you want me to kill you?
Or would you kill me?
Otherwise, we'll be like this forever.
Only two have returned.
We'll have a hybrid squadron including Someakas starting today?
Their engines are kinda flaky.
I assigned Rokuta, Haga, and Niki, who have experience with twin engines, to that duty.
Hey, you there!
What?
Who's that kid?
That's Kusanagi's daughter.
Daughter?
Who on earth is the father?
There are lots of rumors about her.
Who are you?
I'm a pilot stationed here.
I'm Kannami.
I'm Aihara.
How many pilots are here?
Seven, including you and the boss, I think.
I see.
Yes?
Well...
I just remembered someone who used to fold his newspaper like that.
I see.
Sasakura...
How long have you been with Kusanagi?
Well, eight years, I think.
Then you know about the days when she was an ace.
Yes.
Is it okay for her to end up like that?
What do you mean "like that"?
She's a wreck.
To me, she appears to be doing her work normally.
She had a child.
And?
A child had a child!
Don't you see?
No, I don't.
Everyone pretends like they don't see it.
They pretend not to know about it.
Even the company must know about her child.
Kusanagi is...
She was an excellent ace,
so she survived and lived a little longer than everyone else.
She saw and thought much more than everyone else,
and learned to interfere with her fate and the fate of others.
To kill her own loved one? Was that a part of her interference too?
Don't you see?
No, I don't!
Let's go out, Kannami.
To Kusumi's?
Yeah.
Say hi to Fuko.
Who is it?
Who is what?
Who's going out with Mr. Kannami tonight?
If it's Kusanagi, don't go.
And don't tell me it's Mitsuya.
Don't go, for your own sake.
What's so dangerous about them?
It's obvious. If you sleep with Kusanagi,
she'll shoot you in the head, and it'll be bye-bye.
And Mitsuya?
She's like an inescapable vortex.
Any other advice?
I won't kneel down and beg you,
but this is my best advice as a friend.
Be careful tonight.
Thanks.
Come in.
Do you have a minute?
I only have coffee.
If you want some, there's some left in the pot on the table.
I'm relieved.
I thought you'd gone out.
Tokino did.
Went to play with grown-up women?
Yes.
Why did you stay?
I had a hunch.
That I'd visit you?
I'm not that conceited.
Just a hunch that I should stay in my room tonight.
And I'm usually right.
How long has it been since you were assigned here?
Well, maybe since the end of the summer.
What about before that?
How many hours on your flight log?
How many years since you became a fighter pilot?
You came to talk about stuff like that?
I trust you the most of all the people on this base,
so I want to ask how you deal with your emotions.
Like how you deal with the memories of the past and present when everything repeats itself.
I'm just guessing, but we become very forgetful,
and are protected by the vagueness of our memories, as if we're in a dream.
We can't differentiate what happened yesterday, last month, or last year.
They all feel the same.
Am I right?
That's about right for me.
It's been like that ever since I was young.
People have told me that I always look spaced out and that they can't tell if I'm awake or asleep.
And you can't tell yourself?
Did you know that "Kildren" used to be the name of a product our company made?
You were born suddenly in the process of developing a DNA manipulation drug,
and the name that was intended for that new drug became the word to describe your kind.
You're saying you're different?
You Kildren don't age.
You live forever.
Nobody knew that at first.
They didn't believe it even after they found out.
But then rumors started spreading...
that there were people who wouldn't die unless they were killed in battle.
I can't tell!
Am I a Kildren?
I don't know where I heard or read what I just told you. Is it really true?
Everything feels fragmented.
I'm not confident that I've been through any particular experience.
I have no tangible feelings whatsoever.
Wouldn't it be too much if I were the only one who's not a Kildren?
How long have I been flying?
How long have I been killing people?
How and when did I become like this?
I wonder that every night.
I can't remember.
I try and try,
but I can't remember anything from my childhood except for a specific scene.
Apparently you liked to play with kids.
I met a volunteer worker at the last base,
and I was just providing a place and giving her my help.
I like watching children.
I wish that I'd had a childhood too.
Because maybe I was born just as I am now.
When I think that maybe I've never grown up,
I feel like I'm walking on air.
Don't you feel the same?
Don't you get anxious?
Perhaps the reason Kusanagi shot this Jinro guy was that she wanted to end things for him.
But he didn't die.
He didn't?
Because he turned into you.
You regenerated as another person.
They gave you a new memory and thus created you.
You are the reincarnation of Jinro.
Because they'd lose his know-how as a pilot if they didn't.
Because they'd lose his quality as a weapon.
Why don't people realize that?
They're just pretending that they don't.
They'll pretend that they don't know until you realize it.
That's an interesting notion.
How was the coffee?
It was good.
Thanks.
Likewise.
That was an interesting story.
Thanks.
What's your reason?
You'd better put away the gun.
Or would you give it to me?
This is my gun!
Then let me borrow it.
Why?!
I'll shoot Kusanagi instead of you.
Good idea.
Leave the room, Mitsuya.
Die if you want to!
May I smoke?
Go ahead.
This is your room.
Did you kill Kurita Jinro?
Yeah.
He asked you to kill him?
Did you love him?
Yeah.
Kannami,
shoot me with that gun.
Should I kill you?
Yes.
It's your turn to kill me.
Please.
You must live until you can change something.
Even on the path we walk everyday, we can step on different spots.
Just because it's the same path doesn't mean it always has the same scenery.
Isn't that good enough?
Or is that not enough...
because that's all there is?
Warning! Enemy in sight.
Two o'clock, same height.
It's... J-Zwei!
Everyone, retreat.
Cairn! What are you doing?!
Get back!
I'm gonna cover you.
Quit it!
This is my battle.
Just because it's the same path doesn't mean it always has the same scenery.
Isn't that... good enough?
I'll kill my father.
Come in.
I'm Hiiragi Isamu, stationed here as of today.
I'm Kusanagi Suito.
I've been expecting you.