One can prevent mildew
by spraying with copper sulfate.
There are two
classic solutions used...
in Bordeaux and Burgundy...
French provinces
well-known for their wines.
Three treatments are necessary--
the first one when the sprouts
reach twelve centimeters...
the second one just before
or after the blooming...
and the third one a month later.
This spraying with sulfate
is purely preventative...
and should never be neglected.
I'll conclude with the means
of preventing mildew.
Like each year...
airdropped leaflets
will be at your disposal.
Those leaflets will remind
the peasants of the mildew...
deadly disease for the vine
that appeared...
along with this new
ideological disease...
that ravages men.
But the chief of police
will develop this point.
Any similarity to actual
persons or events is deliberate.
As the Under Secretary
of Agriculture said...
three treatments are necessary.
An ideological illness
is like mildew...
and requires
preventative measures.
Like mildew,
it is due to septic germs...
and various parasitic agents.
So the treatment of men
with appropriate solutions...
is indispensable.
The first stage occurs
in the schools, where...
if you'll pardon the metaphor...
the sprouts
are still very young.
The second treatment occurs
when they begin to bloom...
as college students
or young workers.
The draft is
the best time to spray...
and save the sacred tree
of national liberty...
from the disease
of ideological mildew.
Airdropped leaflets
are telling our peasants...
of a new kind
of ideological mildew...
beginning to ravage our land.
This new variety is
spreading insidiously.
It's a sly enemy...
pushing us away from God
and the Crown.
It's against this enemy
that our action is aimed.
Don't take notes!
It's all in our pamphlet.
With the outbreak
of isms like...
socialism, anarchism,
imperialism, or communism...
sunspots start to multiply...
on the face
of the golden orb.
God refuses to
enlighten the Reds!
Scientists forecast
an increase in sunspots...
due to the arrival
of beatniks and pacifists...
from certain countries such as
Italy, France, and Scandinavia!
As head of law and order
here in the North...
I wish to tell you
who are high civil servants...
we must preserve...
the healthy elements
of our society...
and heal those that are ill.
Tonight, the enemy's holding
a meeting in our city.
But we are not an ism !
We are a democracy!
We won't forbid the meeting.
Nor will we forbid...
the opposition
from demonstrating!
With these healthy antibodies,
we must fight all diseases...
of the vine
as well as society.
That's all I have to say.
Bear it in mind
during the days to come!
Having lunch?
Rapidly.
I'll take you to your plane.
Thank you.
It's my pleasure.
Tell my wife
I'll pick her up this evening.
An excursion
for the Bolshoi ballerinas.
From Moscow?
The Bolshoi ballet is here
for four days.
They open tonight.
Stay over.
You can sit in my box.
I must return to the capital.
Ah, the capital. The palace.
The palace thinks well of you.
What if one of them
chose freedom here?
Like that famous dancer--
No. None of that.
For freedom, they pick
London or the U.S...
where the money's stable.
We have
enough hotheads in town.
Enough problems.
Stop! Take that down!
No permits needed
for a meeting indoors!
I don't want any trouble!
Get a permit to use the hall!
Do as I say!
Bring me your permit
or meet elsewhere!
Take it down!
How can we find
another hall now...
and tell 3,000 or 4,000
people about it?
It's a rally!
You signed the receipt.
Now it's unsigned!
Here's your check.
I'll pay you compensation.
You got threats.
I don't know what you mean.
You don't cancel a rental
unless you're pressured.
You lawyers are--
Bozini, you're an honest man.
Who's behind all this? Why?
I don't want you
in my hall, that's why!
If you don't like it,
lump it.
There must be a reason.
My father died today, OK?
I'd gladly let you see it...
but the city inspector came by.
-When?
-Yesterday.
The seats must be specially set.
We can set them this afternoon.
No. Fastened to the floor.
It will take a week at least.
Since when?
We cancel or meet in the street.
And without a permit.
That would mean
instigators and cops.
We won't find a hall.
They'll all refuse.
I say, we have to cancel it.
He'd never agree.
We cancel it and go
quietly off to bed...
or better yet,
to the Bolshoi opening.
And we take him there, too?
And send his audience there?
You got a hall?
The Bolshoi.
A plot on the doctor's life.
Says who?
My wife.
Who told you?
None of my business?
What will we tell the police?
Don't hang up.
She won't say.
The guy didn't know
the doctor's due today.
This is George Pirou.
You must tell us who--
Certainly not!
I trust him.
He didn't know
about tonight's meeting.
He overheard a discussion.
He won't tell you. Me neither.
He's had enough trouble.
He has a family.
Now they know.
Now you know.
So do something.
It's for you.
I know, darling.
See you later.
What do we do?
Call the Red Cross.
Attorney General.
It's all quite vague.
An anonymous witness...
an overheard conversation.
Maybe it's a hoax
or a chronic liar...
like those who phone
there's a bomb on a plane.
Who'd want to kill
your president?
Marie, open the door.
Shall we go?
I'll call the head of security.
He'll provide protection...
unofficially.
We've no basis for any action.
Yes, I'm interested
in the Paris Commune.
I'm late.
You'll come
to the theater tonight?
As for the hall,
I can do nothing.
The colonel.
Property rights can't be
infringed upon...
even though some
may want to change that.
-Yes, Papa?
-Niki, see to our guest.
In two seconds.
He's a fine magistrate.
He's out?
Give me his duty officer.
You know about tonight?
Not the Bolshoi.
Yes. The doctor's life
has been threatened.
No, but he's due to arrive--
shortly.
He'll arrive shortly.
No...on the phone.
Like you say.
Tell the colonel I phoned.
''All quite vague.
No basis for any action.''
The doctor will be mad
when he hears...
we asked those puppets for help.
-Puppets?
-Of the U.S.A.
What can't they have
to do with it?
Always blame the U.S.A.,
even if you're wrong.
Cut it out.
You're not always funny.
There they are.
The police?
They've tailed me
for three days.
Everything's set?
No. We lost our hall,
and no one knows it.
They want to sabotage
the meeting.
Who can fix it?
Only the head of security.
We'll see him after lunch.
Let's go now.
Then to the hotel.
Your life's been threatened.
A guy overheard
some talk about it.
We'll ask the cops--
for nothing.
Just for a hall, that's all.
This hall does not meet
safety regulations.
It was in use two weeks ago.
Here's the report.
It has no emergency exit.
It never did.
With a normal show,
there's no danger.
Your rally might excite people.
It is in no way dangerous.
I've no reason to hinder
your meeting.
My decision is based
on reports.
I'm neutral in this affair.
Then why are we being tailed?
For your safety.
The Minister of Interior
ordered us...
to protect your committee
members from extremists.
Whom you are using.
Other halls meet
the safety requirements...
like the Employees' Union Hall
opposite your hotel.
You simply cross the square.
I'm neutral in this affair.
All right, Colonel.
There on the first floor.
Not room for over 200 people.
We'll look stupid.
In a city of 500,000,
only 200 would hear you.
The rest will be outside.
Ask the colonel to let us hang
loudspeakers from the trees.
Permit or not,
people will be here.
We'll go now and try
to alert people.
Print posters with the rally's
change of address.
Manuel, come discuss my speech.
George, you, too.
I'll hold on.
Hello, darling. How are you?
Fine. Yes.
Problems with the hall,
as usual.
Why should there be any fights?
Why any fights?
Yes. Tomorrow.
George sends a kiss.
Till tomorrow, darling.
The kids?
Fine, but I don't
see them enough.
Helen?
We don't always see
eye to eye...
but it's not serious.
They say a hungry bear
won't dance.
The bears are going
to read that.
Your pen.
Go!
Hold your meetings in Russia!
We'd rather stay here!
Do as you're told!
Hey, you.
What's the idea?
Never mind.
Better than the Bolshoi?
I only came to please you.
Your dancers are old hat.
Except when one chooses freedom.
And the Warsaw Pact?
We're against the bomb,
Russian or American!
Disarmament!
Long live the bomb!
You could sell them
to the ''Daily Worker.''
They are blas.
So are they.
No more NATO bases!
Calm down! No fighting!
No provocation!
You just ease them away.
You don't push.
Leave them alone.
Calm down!
Don't provoke them !
Mr. Lawyer!
Start now!
There's no more room up there!
Squeeze them in!
Get the speakers.
Ready?
I'll get them.
Go on in.
Let them in.
So that's it.
What?
The new opposition.
Women go for him.
Communist?
Never. He's antiforeign.
Next election, he'll win.
Good-looking.
Ex-Olympic champ, doc,
college professor...
and honest politician.
Perfection.
He's at the Bolshoi.
He must cancel it.
We back down.
To avoid provoking the crowd.
The students
could maintain order.
A free-for-all!
You and your nonviolence.
We must respect the law.
The law of the jungle.
They stuck us in that hall.
It's a trap.
Set by whom?
The C.I.A. We want the
foreign bases to be dismantled.
You think too much.
There are some
stubborn extremists.
The threats?
It's not the first time.
We've all taken risks.
They're all at the Bolshoi.
Keep trying.
The police must face
their responsibility.
We're going to our rally.
Rotten politicians!
We'll put you in your graves!
We'll kill you all!
Stay outside.
-And you?
-I'm a mason.
OK, let's go.
They hit me.
Why?
Why do our ideas provoke
such violence?
Why don't they like peace?
Why don't they attack
other organizations?
The answer is simple.
The others are nationalists
used by the government...
and don't upset our
Judas allies who betray us.
General, they're getting
out of hand.
I'll have the loudspeakers
cut off.
It would excite the others.
Don't do that.
Where's the chief of police?
I was told he's here.
Really? He must be over there.
We lack hospitals and doctors...
but half the budget goes
for military expenditures.
He's the one!
A cannon is fired...
and a teacher's monthly salary
goes up in smoke!
That's why they can't bear us
or our meetings...
and use hired thugs
to jeer and attack us.
Around the world, too many
soldiers are ready to fire...
on anything moving
toward progress.
He's our guy?
You sure?
I think.
An Olympic champ?
Stop!
Finish him off.
Shit! It's not him !
I told you it wasn't!
They said it was!
Take off!
I'll go around
to avoid the cops.
Tomatoes out of season.
They cost a fortune.
Fix your muffler.
I can't even make
the monthly payments.
Shit! The cops!
But our fight is theirs, too.
We live in a weak
and corrupt society...
where it's every man
for himself.
It's blocked off
here, too. Hide.
Even imagination is suspect...
yet it's needed
to solve world problems.
The stockpile of A-bombs
is equal...
to one ton of dynamite
per person on Earth.
Horny again?
Yeah.
They want to prevent us
from reaching the obvious...
political conclusions
based on these simple truths...
but we will speak out.
We serve the people,
and the people need the truth.
Send them back to the Bolshoi.
The truth is the start
of powerful, united action.
Get those hoodlums out of here.
Down with the police state!
No more foreign bases!
Inspector!
Chief!
What are you waiting for?
Watch out!
Throw him off!
It's my cousin. He fell off.
By his feet.
I saw you hit him.
What?
What is going on?
I hit the brake,
and my cousin fell off.
He's bleeding and needs care.
Your papers.
Just a moment.
Here they are.
He's bleeding. He needs care.
He hit him with a club!
See? It's nothing.
This is nothing?
He tried to kill him.
Dummy! My truck?
It'll be OK.
Call in for a patrol car.
Sure. Call the station.
Stay there.
Look.
I'm going.
Pretend to try to stop me.
I can't explain,
but I got to go. Just play dead.
One move and I'll slug you.
What time is it?
I got a date I can't miss.
The regime can't change that.
All the Russians want
is to live like Americans.
Quick, sir. It's serious.
Come with me.
The Attorney General.
We'll talk later.
And the ballet?
I had to miss it.
Why wasn't I told?
During the performance? How?
-What is it?
-A stupid traffic accident.
The culprit?
We'll have him soon.
The victim?
The hospital will tell us.
I'll go there in your car.
Certainly!
Have the papers heard about it?
I doubt it.
I must call the ministry.
Editorial room.
What on Earth's wrong?
There was a demonstration.
We taught the bastards a lesson.
They hold a meeting?
Well, we can demonstrate, too.
It's like a biological reaction.
Society's healthy elements,
the antibodies.
We beat the hell out of them.
What do you want from me?
Write that I was there
and beat them up.
What for?
So my pals will know.
OK. If you want.
Get fixed up at the hospital...
so they'll know
both sides were hurt.
Go now, and I'll put
your name in the lead.
We warned you, but you said
it was a hoax or a crackpot.
Please.
This attempted killing
is your responsibility.
The police have proof
it was an accident.
Go easy. We need their help.
Such unfounded accusations.
They're blind or worse--
accomplices.
They have no proof.
Assassination?
I was there taking pictures.
You got the truck?
No. I missed it.
The cops chased us away.
Such cynicism. They'll
use the incident politically.
Surely!
They know how to make martyrs.
Death-lovers!
Let's hope he doesn't die.
That would suit them.
The brain is damaged in two
or three spots. We're operating.
His heart is fighting hard,
but it's too soon to say.
But you must!
He can't hear you.
You realize
the political aspect?
But the other victim
is out of danger.
Other victim?
Senator Pirou.
He was found in the street.
It's serious,
but he's all right.
Two senators hurt.
Such incompetent police.
I must phone the minister
in private.
His wife knows?
I don't eavesdrop.
I'm sure.
When is she coming?
Tomorrow, first plane.
Tomorrow is today.
It's for my paper.
What did she say?
Nothing. I heard her breathing.
Then she said, ''Will he live?''
The director couldn't answer.
And she said,
''So they finally did it.''
Were you there?
I'm a reporter.
I'm afraid the police bungled
it. I wanted no one hurt.
Two senators hurt,
one critically!
We have the culprit.
Where? I want to see him.
He's in the canteen.
The canteen!
The cells are in poor condition.
No electricity,
so we use them for storage.
The minister says
this is serious...
and a political catastrophe.
If the papers knew
he's in a canteen!
The minister wants
to be kept fully informed.
No handcuffs.
-His son?
-No, a street peddler.
-Was he alone?
-No. Two of them.
We have the end man's address.
It seems he slept through
the accident.
He gave himself up?
He was arrested
for drunken driving.
You'll get a report.
Breathe.
No alcohol.
It's the stew.
Mutton stew kills all smells.
What have you been doing?
I made the stew.
He made it?
And you hid this from me?
I didn't know.
I found out later.
You weren't told? Since when?
Since about 10:30 p.m.
That's harboring a criminal.
You knew about it, Colonel?
I knew, but I hadn't the time
to tell the general.
Then you arrived.
The general said
we didn't have the culprit...
and I couldn't contradict him.
Fine.
I'll take his statement myself.
Get the second culprit.
Eat.
They're at the presses.
Now what? You wear glasses now?
It's a disguise. Take my name
off the list. The guy's dying.
What's that to you?
Nothing. It was an accident--
two drunks in a pickup truck.
If my name's in the paper,
I'll be questioned.
I'll remove it.
Are you free now?
No. I can't. I'm busy.
You'll have to go.
That way.
No one is to move.
What do they want?
To start trouble. We refuse.
But how do you explain
it's always ours who are killed?
He's alive.
Clinically, he's dead.
Why dream?
Clinically dead.
The brain's destroyed,
but the heart's still beating.
It won't quit.
One word
and they'll tear up the town.
Why hold them back? I wonder
if we've any will to fight.
He had. That's why
they killed him, not us.
Come on.
It's all I could find.
The papers--
The cops put the blame on us.
Coffee?
''The broadcasting of the speech
was a provocation.
''The antinational tone...
''of the attack on foreign policy
aroused the crowd at once.
''Hence, the violence.
''The police handled
the situation efficiently...
''yet thirteen policemen were
injured in the course of duty.''
So said the general
to the press.
We must answer that!
Yes, and stress the pacifist
nature of our rally.
We had permission.
So the cops could do
a better job on us.
But we have no proof.
Nothing valid.
We can only deplore
the police's passiveness.
Later, we'll underline
all the contradictions.
Why not call the Red Cross
or the Rights of Man Commission?
You're making a crybaby defense.
We must attack
and expose those responsible.
Take up arms in the streets.
-Why not?
-Anything goes.
-We can consider--
-Nothing at all!
-It must be legal.
-We've been legal for years.
-This is no time to change.
-It's our only way.
Or the affair could backfire.
Aren't you ashamed?
He's dying in there.
We've no case against them.
And the threats on his life?
He ignored them, too.
But that was yesterday.
Will your guy talk now?
Statement to the press?
I doubt it. He was scared then
of reprisals...
and now, even more.
Try! Can you find him?
Not before noon.
We'll have to be careful.
We're being watched.
It's them.
But they're protecting us.
We're as safe as the doctor.
What was your reaction
to the news?
The U.S. President
sent you a telegram?
Saying what?
Happily wed?
Was he threatened?
You'll let the Reds
exploit this?
Was it an attempted
assassination?
Why did you send
for a British surgeon?
Do you want a divorce?
Was it an accident?
They're operating
for the third time.
Here's the hospital director.
Your husband had an accident.
I knew your husband.
We were at school together.
I wanted to go
to his peace marathon...
but it was forbidden.
It's serious, but he'll make it.
Professor Dodd from London
is here.
He's one of London's
best surgeons.
Want to tell them the truth?
They'll live the truth later.
The fall broke
the dome of the skull...
and no doubt the brain
has been affected.
The shock was very violent...
causing an explosion inside
the skull like an earthquake.
I can't evaluate
the aftereffects...
of the concussion
even if the operation succeeds.
The third operation
has just begun.
His heart is
the only positive factor.
We've massaged
and used adrenaline...
and its resistance is amazing.
It's beating regularly.
Come in.
General Missou.
A stupid accident.
I'm deeply sorry.
Head of the police.
We have the culprit, a drunk.
-Attorney General.
-My sympathies.
The inquest judge.
Well, certain areas of the brain
have been affected...
but the lesions
can't be defined.
But the surgeons are optimistic.
We must await the end
of the third operation.
You husband's heart
is exceptional.
If it holds, he'll live.
We have every hope.
The capital is on the phone.
The ministry!
They'll try to use his wife.
They'll use
the people's emotions.
The files.
Their committee secretary.
I want resumes on each--
details of their private lives
and jobs, too.
For this evening.
The injured senator.
The other lawyer.
And his? Have it?
It just came.
Any love affairs?
I don't know, but there must be.
Break his halo.
Does he get along with his wife?
-Watching her?
-Like the others, General.
-Two of our men.
-I don't want to know that.
They met this morning, picked up
his wife, then separated.
Some took his wife to
the clinic. As for this one...
He took a statement
to the press. You have a copy.
They saw
some university student.
-Students!
-Call our students.
That one's a mad dog.
He wants to make the most of it.
-A Jew?
-Only half.
They think they're superior even
to other Jews.
The Attorney General.
Stay on him day and night.
We were expecting you.
The second culprit?
We have him.
He turned himself in.
Come into my office.
Please sit down.
He's boss now, officially.
So you're to give him
your initial findings...
and then follow
his instructions.
My deputy will keep me posted.
The colonel's men have checked.
Can I see the second culprit?
Whenever you want to.
It seems he was asleep
on the truck, dead drunk...
so he's innocent
if it all checks out.
Their whereabouts earlier?
The driver's statement
and photo.
They'd been drinking
at the Chinaman's bar.
We have Chinese tradesmen
in town?
The owner
was in the Korean War...
and now he's called
''the Chinaman.''
He backs them up.
I'll read his statement.
''I, Bertrand,
alias the Chinaman, et cetera...
''bar owner, et cetera...
''do state that
on May 22 of this year...
''Yago and Vago
came into my bar at 7 p.m...
''and stayed until 10 p.m.
''They were drinking Pernod.''
It's not allowed, madam.
Three witnesses, a docker.
''I saw Yago and Vago
drinking Pernod all evening.
''They left at 10 p.m., drunk.
''The Chinaman said,
'not in the kamikaze!'''
Kamikaze?
The pickup truck.
It's Japanese-made.
You'd think
we were in the Far East.
I think it's clear.
Though we lack some details
on the culprits...
it's obviously an accident.
I agree.
Besides, the minister phoned...
and wants this settled
very quickly...
to cut short
political speculation abroad.
I think the prosecutor
must take a statement...
about the accident today and say
the culprits are caught...
and accused of drunken driving
and assault and battery.
And willful flight.
Naturally.
And the man who took him
to the clinic?
It's for you.
He just died.
That doesn't change
the statement.
Instead of ''assault and
battery,'' say ''manslaughter.''
Go away, Shoula.
I'll wait for you.
Who are you?
An admirer of your husband--
a reporter.
No photos.
Only a few questions.
The public has a right to know.
Was it an accident or not?
Yesterday, his life
was threatened.
Did you know?
You expected it?
You said,
''So they finally did it.''
What did I say?
To the hospital director,
you said...
''So they finally did it?''
Who are they?
Go away.
The culprits have been arrested.
You thought of them?
Go away.
They know already?
Yes, and it's only beginning.
Unmask the killers!
The police are accomplices!
Wait. I don't understand.
The fall didn't kill him?
Not at all.
The skull fracture was due
to a blow struck on the head.
That's our conclusion.
The fall caused minor bruises.
You're sure?
A blow?
You mean by the truck?
The truck hit his body.
It wasn't serious.
The death blow hit his skull...
and was made by an instrument
such as a club...
an iron bar or a gun butt.
But no one's mentioned a weapon.
Continue, doctor.
The skull fracture
can only be due to a weapon...
that struck from above.
It is the sole condition...
that causes symmetrical lesions
on the brain...
touching the subjacent area...
and the area opposite the wound.
An autopsy showed the lesions...
the right cerebral hemorrhage...
and the fracture
of the left temple.
In the case of a shock
due to a fall...
on a hard surface
like the street...
such lesions couldn't exist.
Why didn't you tell us sooner?
-Sooner?
-Yes. Yesterday.
Mr. Deputy, he was still alive.
We needed an autopsy.
Time for other tests
would have shown the same facts.
Another hypothesis is...
if the truck dragged him...
his skull could have
hit the curb.
It's a fact that he was hit
in the middle of the street.
Then a fall couldn't cause
such lesions.
A phone?
Next-door.
Yago was driving.
The second man was drunk and
couldn't have been so precise.
A demonstrator.
Their story's odd.
Know them well?
Very well.
Political?
Maybe.
Communists?
Not if they work here.
The opposition?
One never knows.
The general, please.
I wanted to see you
to clarify a few points.
It all seems clear enough to me.
A new fact has come up.
It's stuffy in here.
You saw the accident?
How did it happen?
In what respect?
When the truck arrived,
what happened?
The colonel and I were there...
when he walked out,
waving to the crowd.
They didn't applaud him, either.
He didn't see the truck
zigzagging toward him...
and he was hit.
The colonel's men
ran after the truck.
Two men drew their guns...
but due to the crowd,
they didn't fire.
The truck zigzagged
and finally got away.
The police cleared the square...
and helped put the victim
into a Volkswagen...
to go to the hospital.
No trace of
the Volkswagen driver?
Not yet, but he must be
a friend of theirs.
He helped them at once.
When the victim was run over...
could his head
have hit the curb?
No. It occurred in the square.
You're sure?
Positive.
But what's this new fact?
The autopsy says
he was killed by a club.
A club?
Why did the doctors
do an autopsy?
It's the legal procedure.
Yesterday, it was all settled.
Now you'll foul us up.
A new witness.
He claims he has proof
the senator was assassinated.
He'll be here today at 2 p.m.
There you are. An assassination.
Soon they'll say it was a plot.
I saw him. He was drunk.
He nearly fell
in front of the truck.
What happened? You saw it?
Yes. He slipped and fell.
Anybody here?
I'm the Chief of Police.
I was on my way to testify,
and as I walked along...
You fell and hit your head.
You suffer from epilepsy?
Someone hit me.
I was on my way to testify
that I have proof...
the senator was assassinated.
It was no accident.
Yago told me so himself.
I was going to testify...
but someone hit me on the head
from a truck...
with a club...
to keep me quiet.
They tried to kill me.
I don't know who told you
to say this or why.
I don't want to know.
We can forget all this.
Let's say you were influenced.
You're almost one of the family.
Your cousin's a policeman...
brother-in-law
has a government job.
Forget all this.
General, they're coming.
If you need anything,
come and see me.
I'll drop by again.
I'm a bachelor
and live with my ma.
Profession?
I have a varnish shop.
You know Yago?
Sure.
He makes deliveries for me.
The other two, I don't know.
The killing...
The accident!
Was the day I phoned Yago
about a delivery.
Varnished coffins, and I
can't even pay off my kamikaze.
Come back this afternoon.
I'll be busy.
Tonight, then.
I'm busy, too.
I'm gonna make
a real big mistake.
It'll be a murder.
Next day, I learned
he'd killed the senator.
Yago told you all that?
You belong to the party?
I never belonged to any party.
I like soccer.
What is this?
The general says I'm epileptic.
What general?
The Chief of Police.
He was here?
Just before you came.
But I'm no epileptic...
and never belonged to any party.
Go on about Yago.
That's all. He left.
He's the lucky one.
What about the delivery?
I tried to set him straight,
but he does as he pleases.
Who told you to call
the inquest judge?
No one.
I see Yago's picture
in the papers...
on the front page,
like a minister.
Jealous?
You made up this tale.
No. Someone advised him.
Even Ma was against it.
She said to keep quiet.
Come and eat.
He killed him.
Who?
A senator.
In the government?
No, a leftist.
He did right.
What's it to you?
His picture, too.
Eat and let them
kill each other.
Not hungry.
Later, my sister came.
So you want to be a big shot?
Just doing my duty.
Your duty is
to see to your family.
I always have.
You have an idiot
who sees to you.
Don't call my husband an idiot.
You think they'll
give you a medal.
I came anyway...
or I would have
if they hadn't slugged me.
You didn't fall?
I'd have to be an acrobat
to land on my head.
You can sign a statement later
if you still want to.
Of course. I'm not crazy.
First witness
for the prosecution?
They lost no time.
Tomorrow, you'll have ten,
maybe fifteen.
They'll say Yago
did this or that...anything.
Vague, worthless statements
that will create unrest.
They sent him and beat him up
to turn a witness into a martyr.
They left him hospitalized...
yet able to talk.
You admit I was beaten
and didn't fall?
You realize what perjury means?
It's not perjury.
I wanted to help,
but if I'd known...
Told you so.
Why did you get involved?
Weren't you all right at home?
Eat.
Suppose you say you slipped
on an orange peel.
I didn't slip.
Why are you so pigheaded?
Listen to me for once.
The first and last time.
Like always.
Really the last time.
Say you slipped,
and we have no problems.
You won't go to prison.
I'll send others to prison.
I got them.
Yago and his picture.
Who sent you--
the cops or your daughter?
Yes, it's me.
You want to ruin my home?
Mama, leave.
Leave us alone.
-Don't argue.
-Go outside!
You hate me because
I've succeeded in life.
You and your husband hate me.
Never mind him !
You've caused him
enough trouble!
You want to ruin my life.
When Papa died, I hoped
you'd take his place.
I needed protection.
You neglected me
and never took me anywhere.
You preferred soccer
and slobs like Yago.
See what it's got you?
Prison, maybe...for perjury...
and my husband
will lose his job.
Come here. Listen.
You hear a guy's
gonna be killed...
you don't believe it.
Then you hear he's dead.
Would you tell the cops?
That's all I did...to help them.
Help who?
To help the cops
find the murderer.
You're helping the others.
What do you want?
Your mother sent me.
I'm a reporter.
I'll tell you
what truly happened...
because you print
just everything.
He wasn't hit.
Either he slipped
or felt dizzy and fell...
or else leftists hit him
to create trouble.
So say the police.
They say he's crazy
but can't prove it.
Can you?
No, I can't.
Then why try?
I never said that.
He's stubborn as a mule.
He never changes his mind.
If he doesn't,
the inquest will continue.
What if he is crazy
and had epilepsy as a baby?
Tell him you and your husband
are right-wingers...
and how you got your jobs.
Yes. I do belong.
The cop!
She woke him.
Sleeping?
Pictures?
For the press?
That's no good.
But that way people will see
you were slugged...
to keep you from saying
something important, see?
They'll beat me again?
They won't dare.
You're famous now.
But the press
must talk about you.
Tell me who saw you here--
your sister, your mother,
the judge.
The general, he can't stand me.
I wanted to help
and got a cold shoulder.
They asked if I was a commie.
Are you?
No. I only like soccer.
We'll be on the front page
for a week.
Sorry.
Who was it?
I know him.
And you're a cardiac case?
No. I...
It's an old fracture.
Name and profession?
Any convictions?
Yes. Four.
Four?
Yes, four.
Carrying arms illegally...
public outrage...
theft...
and rape.
Rape?
Not really.
I was a counselor
at a boy scout camp.
Why were you in the hospital?
The head of security
put him there.
My client has a weak heart.
The police doctor certified it.
I know, but why
the plaster cast...
and a cane like a club?
It's because of an old fracture.
I was broke when it happened.
I needed x-rays
and ten days in bed.
Two days of no work,
and I starve.
It was a rich man's fracture.
The rich get a cold,
a week in bed.
For the poor, a fracture means
work or the grave.
So I had it seen to
while I was in the hospital.
Where were you that night?
At the Chinaman's
with Yago till 10:00.
You see Yago often?
We're friends and cousins.
Was he drunk?
Yago drinks a lot.
The Chinaman told him
not to take the kamikaze.
I got in back and fell asleep.
The shock and the yells woke me.
I thought we were in a ditch,
but we were still going.
Then a guy leaped
onto the kamikaze...
as lithe and fierce as a tiger.
He grabbed me and threw me off
in the street.
He leaped like...
-A tiger.
-Before that.
Lithe and fierce.
Yago used the same words.
Yet he didn't see him.
A simple coincidence.
They haven't met
since the accident.
The police can swear to it.
Continue.
I was in the street
and almost got run over.
Then?
I went home.
Next day,
when I read the papers...
I went to the cops who put me
in the hospital.
There he got lost in the halls
and met that reporter...
by accident.
That agrees
with the other testimony.
Yet one phrase makes me wonder.
It could change
my investigation.
You're a communist.
You and Yago, too.
Something you said
makes me think so.
''The rich get a cold,
a week in bed.
''For the poor, a fracture means
work or the grave.''
You gave yourself away.
I hate the communists!
Words! I want proof!
Only a communist
would say such a thing.
I belong to
an anticommunist group.
-And Yago?
-Yago, too!
Which one?
CROC!
Christian Royalist Organization
against Communism.
You created a storm.
Vago was jailed for collusion,
and that means premeditation.
The judge believed you...
and found out Vago and Yago
belong to a secret society.
Secret?
Yes. The CROC.
Anybody knows that.
The cops use them
to keep order at parades.
You've nothing to fear now.
But in a year,
I'll be forgotten.
No one can touch you.
Know anyone who'd show me
CROC members?
I'd pay.
Sure. It's them.
So help me.
Know anyone?
Yes...
but don't say I told you.
It's Dumas.
He was born in Russia.
CROC has a hold on him...
because of trouble
with his brother.
He'd like to get to Germany...
so if you can get him
a passport...
I can get one
through my newspaper.
-Pictures?
-Here.
I've kept my promise.
Now it's your turn.
Don't like it?
Sure.
The questions?
Does CROC meet regularly?
Where?
At a guy's place
on the edge of town.
Are there many of you?
Sometimes.
What goes on?
The boss talks.
Religion and the monarchy...
are the two pillars
of our eternal land...
and Western Christian
civilization.
If you don't listen,
you get no work.
What else?
In Russia, a worker can't strike
or believe in God...
or have his own house
and garden.
He's crushed
by a totalitarian regime.
You agree?
I even read it in the papers.
The individual
belongs to the State.
Yago went to the meetings?
Always.
They'd talk about capitalists.
No more capitalists
or workers...
or Left or Right.
A unified people
is what we need.
We need a clean sweep...
starting with
the intellectual scum.
The bookstore next-door.
He'd talk about
political youth groups.
What did he say?
Unite the youth...
And give them a common ideal.
Abroad, some say,
''Make love, not war.''
We say, ''Make war on corruption
and on liberalism...
''and on indiscriminate liberty.''
I say, ''OK,''
but I don't give a damn.
And Yago?
He agrees because he wants
to pay off his kamikaze.
Now he'll be able to easy.
He killed the senator?
You said no accusations.
No. I'm paying.
Never.
But you can point them out to me
for some photos.
That's what you wanted?
The three on the pickup.
The butcher's involved.
The fat guy owns the bar
where we meet.
The barber.
The mechanic...
and the two in black.
In khaki.
Him?
An ex-boxer who lived
in the U.S. awhile.
In the yard, the boss...
an officer
during the German occupation.
The fig seller, a loudmouth...
always up in front
for the rough stuff.
Some figs, please.
Pictures, eh?
He sells his blood
and gets a good price
in case of emergencies.
He got rich selling
one of his eyes to an American.
He doesn't
attend meetings anymore.
His sight is bad,
so he sells blood.
Not him?
Them?
Him?
No?
It looks like him.
He hit me twice...
even in the ambulance.
Write that in the margin.
Publish it in your paper.
Sign the caption.
Publish it.
Yes, but not in your paper.
In a big daily paper...
for more readers and money.
Money.
In my paper tomorrow.
I'll give the inquest judge
my photos.
Don't you want to be efficient?
In a local leftist paper,
no one will see it.
In mine, it's sensational news.
You recognized me?
You dishonored me.
You made me out
to be a gangster.
I wasn't at that demonstration.
I have nothing to do
with politics.
Let him be.
Leave.
I'm the judge.
Explain.
I'm on the front page.
Mr. Pirou says I hit him
at the demonstration.
I wasn't there.
I have witnesses.
Politics are a lot of crap.
I was at the market
with my figs.
Your picture's in what paper?
I forget.
It arrives from the capital
at 10:00.
I can't read very well.
The news vendor showed it to me
and read it to me.
At the market,
they think I'm a hoodlum.
I wanted an explanation...
man to man.
From the capital?
Still recognize me?
I said, what paper?
The papers that arrive
from the capital at 10:00.
This morning, they didn't.
The mail plane was fogged in.
Who told you to say all this?
Yes.
I hit him.
But I had to.
Somebody forced me to.
Who? His name?
I can't tell you.
He's too big...
too important.
I can't.
He told me about it.
Barone, your picture's
in one of the capital's papers.
Mine?
One that arrives at 10:00!
So at 10:45...
you go see Pirou
at the hospital.
Raise hell.
Say you're innocent.
Scream and shout.
Reporters will be there.
Now tell me again.
I rush to the hospital--
Get out of here!
To see Pirou.
But tell me his name.
I can't. He's too big.
All right. Follow me, please.
I'm innocent.
I only wanted to testify.
It's all left-wing politics.
This important man...
he helped you?
Yes, in my work
and for my birds.
They wake the neighbors.
I was gonna have to move.
But my birds are pretty.
You should see them, Judge.
He helped me in my work, too--
the market permit and all that.
The day of the accident,
you saw him?
Yes. Jimmy said,
''The boss is downstairs.''
He was in the car.
Get in!
You know it's tonight?
Impossible.
I got some figs due in.
They got to be uncrated.
To sell them, you need a stand?
I got one.
And you need a permit?
But for how much longer?
Six months.
And who renews permits?
He does?
Yes.
Then he dropped us off.
Do a good job tonight.
I'm counting on you.
You'll get a permanent permit...
and maybe a new house
for your birds.
I said, ''Colonel,
I'll do my best.''
The police colonel?
Yes.
Let's start at the beginning.
Can you come in, Deputy?
Prolonging the inquest...
gives the opposition fuel
for subversive action.
You've sided with them?
It's not a prolongation.
It's a totally new case.
Some points are awkward,
but the case is clear.
On the contrary, we began with
an accident and two drunks.
Some ice, dear.
Their testimony
coincides in detail.
Confirmed by the Chinaman.
Next day, the autopsy says death
was due to a blow by a club.
A second autopsy will say no...
and a confirmation will disprove
the initial autopsy.
I'd had no time to examine
this new theory...
when a witness said
it was an assassination.
Based on a vague discussion.
On his way to see me,
the witness was clubbed...
and he's still in the hospital.
What do you mean?
I'm only stating facts.
Then comes the reporter.
He's not a militant,
and that's important.
I learned Yago and Vago
belong to CROC--
the Christian Royalist.
I know.
Along with the assailant
of the second senator...
and most of those
at the demonstration.
It seems the police know
and use them as auxiliaries...
to maintain order
for state visits.
That's yet to be proven.
Like the fact that
the police colonel...
drove this man
to the demonstration.
Really! He wouldn't be
involved with such a person!
Not openly. No one
will believe it.
My conclusion is this:
As a case of drunken driving,
it's simple...
but impossible.
If we accept the premeditated
act of a group...
aided or simply abetted
by the police...
it all becomes clear,
fits together.
This is serious.
I must phone the minister.
I favor the accident theory...
premeditated, if you wish,
by two drunken fanatics.
Yes, you don't smoke.
You must settle this quickly.
The country, the whole world,
is watching and waiting.
Our country's honor is at stake.
Don't bother with these fools.
Your future lies before you.
This case can either make
or break your career.
Trust in my experience.
My group is authorized
by the state.
We are honest citizens,
healthy elements of society...
antibodies in the fight
against infection.
We want to protect Western
Christian civilization...
but it is a moral struggle.
No members of my group
were at the demonstration.
Where were you that night?
I was at the Dockers' Union.
Alibi confirmed.
I was playing cards
with my dentist.
Confirmed.
I'm a baker. I slept
till midnight at my shop.
Alibi confirmed.
I was at the Chinaman's.
Confirmed.
At the Chinaman's.
I played cards with my dentist.
Confirmed.
That's not you?
It does look like me.
Indicted for perjury...
along with those who
confirmed his alibi.
Plus obstructing justice.
Take him away.
Witness 27 has died
of a heart attack.
He owned the CROC meeting hall.
Earlier you stated Yago
hit you with a club...
like a police billy club.
Do you maintain that?
Yes, Judge.
The Attorney General
says he phoned you...
that the senator's life
had been threatened.
Your superiors never
got his message.
Yes. I forgot to tell them.
That's a serious error.
I'll answer to my superiors,
not to you, Judge.
That morning, you were
warned of death threats...
against the senator.
Who told you about them?
A colleague's wife.
She can't tell us the name.
She'll have to.
The man says I can tell you.
He's waiting in the hall.
Bring him in.
His name's Coste.
-The day--
-Of the incident.
He came to my office
to tell me of a conversation.
But he'll tell it to you better.
Don't mention me in the papers,
not my name.
Why? Isn't your story true?
Yes, but I want no trouble.
If you do, come see me.
Wait in the hall, please.
Name and profession?
Ilya Coste, delivery man.
On the day of
the assassination--
Day of the incident.
An assassination's
not yet proven.
The day of the incident
was rainy.
I work myself to death...
and the bank gets half
of what I earn.
Someone for you!
Again.
Which one?
That one.
Go on.
I heard Yago say...
-If it rains?
-So?
-We'll skid.
-It won't.
It won't rain,
but I got payments due.
We'll cover you.
All the payments?
The varnisher phoned!
He wants you this afternoon
to deliver some coffins!
It's a good sign.
See you tonight.
Then he came over.
I'll buy you a drink.
As he sat down, I saw the club.
What's that for?
Tonight. A delivery job
that'll take care of a lot.
What kind?
A delivery into hell.
A senator from the capital.
A dirty job.
No one knows.
If they do, it'll be you.
Later, the same man came back.
He's different in civvies.
You knew him?
I'd asked for a truck permit.
Every six months,
I went to him about it.
He was always in uniform.
But why pick Yago?
He's the best driver in town.
You should see him
with his kamikaze.
He has a political record.
He was in the Communist
underground in the war...
then deported to the islands.
His testimony.
Is suspect, of course.
I wouldn't use it.
Never mind.
They want to eliminate
all troublesome witnesses.
They just tried to get me.
-What?
-Attempted murder, just now.
The plot continues
and will continue!
I don't need your advice.
This involves the top brass.
The police are their toys.
And cops haven't the capacity...
to commit such a murder
without being protected.
The guilty ones
are in the government...
or at the palace...
where the general
is head of the guards.
And the palace takes orders
from abroad.
One more word and...
I'll charge you with
defamation of the state.
This isn't a rally.
What happened?
They tried to kill me.
They knew I had
important info for you.
So a car tried to run me down
on my way here.
Any witnesses?
Here are three honest,
God-fearing housewives...
who'll testify, plus...
a park guard, a war vet
with medals.
What's this information?
The police own the Volkswagen.
That took him away
to the hospital?
But no cops were allowed
in the car to finish him off...
so the driver took
the longest route.
I know. I was there.
But the car belongs
to one of your friends.
He must be a friend.
He helped them at once.
Who told you such a tale?
The car disappeared.
No trace of it at the hospital.
The page was torn
out of the registry.
Don't you find that odd?
I think you did it
to add grist to your mill.
Is this the car?
Yes.
Find the owner of this car.
If you wish to wash.
Thanks. I'm all right.
Tell me what you know.
But I warn you, you risk
indictment for perjury.
Go ahead.
The car was waiting there,
hidden by the police.
And when the truck came?
It pulled up.
Inspector!
Chief!
He wanted the general
to clear the square.
Come on.
What are you waiting for?
I saw the truck arrive.
Watch out!
The man in back was standing up?
Did he hit him?
I don't know.
It happened too fast.
-And then?
-He fell to his knees.
His knees?
His head hit the pavement?
No. He was on his knees,
surrounded by the demonstrators.
The police did nothing.
Which demonstrators?
Impossible to say.
We pulled him free.
Then he collapsed.
A Volkswagen arrived;
from where, I don't know.
Finally the cops intervened
and tried to get into the car.
Come on!
Get to the hospital!
Get going!
Faster! Honk your horn!
Is it broken?
Turn right!
This way avoids traffic.
He did it to waste time.
Then he hit another car.
Keep going!
I need a damage report!
A man's hurt.
It's a matter of life and death.
OK. Go on.
He did it on purpose.
And the cops would have
killed him in the car.
On purpose?
I did my best. They were upset.
I can understand that.
No one noticed me
at the hospital.
I'd rented the car
for an afternoon date...
and was on my way home.
Roadblocks were up.
I must not have
noticed the police.
At the hospital, I washed
the seats of the blood.
You said,
''I'm a part-time chauffeur.''
But you're a serviceman.
I'm doing my military service.
What branch?
As a policeman.
You're a police chauffeur.
What section?
One close to the general.
How close?
Personal.
Since when?
One year.
The general's driver
for one year.
You were all at the scene
of the murder by accident.
Shall I write ''murder''?
You said ''murder.''
Do you know who has arrived?
The National Attorney General.
Leave us alone.
The National Attorney General
has come to talk to you...
in secret.
Yes, he's here.
I'll bring my files at once.
So it's you. Sit down.
You're ready to indict
the chief of police?
It's inevitable.
My friend, only Divine Will
is inevitable.
Proof is overwhelming, sir.
Proof? Hearsay!
So-called proof
by so-called pacifists...
who want to create a hero.
That's certain, sir,
but police complicity...
with the demonstrators
is certain.
Those two men circled in red
are plainclothes men.
They admit being
in the demonstration.
We also know the police chief
met Yago that day...
plus other demonstrators.
The general said he didn't
know the driver of the VW...
but he's the general's
personal chauffeur.
I won't mention
the police's passiveness.
Then comes the intimidation
of witnesses.
Vago is hospitalized with
a police medical certificate.
He's found near the room
of a major witness, with a club.
Then there's Yago's club
during the demonstration.
Several witnesses saw it.
It disappeared
when he was arrested...
but the agent admitted
rewriting his report.
You shouldn't mention
the club in your report.
But it's done, sir.
I'm the police chief general.
At ease.
Don't worry.
You did your duty.
You've been a policeman
how long?
Six years.
Just rewrite your report.
The Attorney General.
And then you arrived, sir.
He couldn't lie.
On the contrary.
His confession
will cost him a lot.
There is a case
for indictment...
but not enough for a jury
to condemn the police.
The jury will do its duty.
I've done mine.
You'll discredit the police
and the court...
who will be blamed
for absolving them.
As if it's not enough
our country's been invaded by...
long-haired atheists
and addicts.
Now you want to cast doubt
on our armed forces...
the sole healthy elements
in our country.
We dream of a renewal...
of a land with no parties,
Left nor Right...
obedient to God.
You want to ruin it.
I have a proposal for you.
I understand your scruples.
They honor you.
My idea should suit you
and the government...
and the palace.
We'll divide the case in three.
First the trial
of the two criminals.
Let justice be done.
Second, the police authorities.
Their negligence is evident...
but can't be tried
by a circuit court.
It's strictly
an administrative matter.
Third, an action against
the rally organizers.
They and their loudspeakers
are responsible...
for the ensuing violence.
An old rule of thumb
is to always look...
for those who benefit
from a crime.
The minister of justice
thought you were a leftist.
I formally denied it.
Here's a list
of helpful witnesses.
It seems no one wanted
to kill the senator...
just intimidate him.
I trust I've convinced you...
to save the honor of the forces
of law and order.
But you're the sole master
of your conscience, after God.
I won't be disgraced.
Indict me
and I'll commit suicide.
Dishonor is unbearable.
My blood will be on your hands.
Name and profession?
You must answer.
Sign your statement.
You are indicted
for premeditated murder.
The law allows 24 hours...
to superior officers
before their imprisonment.
To avoid the reporters,
use that door.
You're indicted
for premeditated murder.
It's unbearable!
You've no right!
I've been thrown to the hounds.
Name and profession.
You're indicted
for premeditated murder.
Sit down.
For me, there's no choice.
Either I'm cleared
or I'll commit suicide.
Name and profession.
It's routine, General.
What did you do that day?
I was to attend
the Bolshoi Ballet.
Not out of love for the dance.
I'm not one of those perverts.
But it was a chance
to spot some Reds.
The day of the assassination...
you were told his life
was threatened.
No one told me about it!
I'm sure it was only a tactic...
to justify any incident.
My men couldn't
stop the truck...
but a man leaped
on the rear platform...
lithe and fierce as a tiger.
I knew no one
in that organization.
I've had no contacts
with this CROC.
You're seen here at a banquet
you gave for them...
to thank them for keeping order
during a state visit.
Is he a Red?
Why is he after me?
His father was police chief.
The photo's phony.
It's not proof.
You're indicted
for premeditated murder.
Are you a martyr like Dreyfus?
Dreyfus was guilty!
Helen!
Helen, they're all indicted,
even the general.
The judge didn't back down.
Helen, it's as if
he were still alive.
It's a real revolution.
The government will fall...
and extremists
will be wiped out.
Election will be a landslide.
The deputy was not at the trial.
He died of a heart attack,
according to the coroner.
Several other witnesses
died before the trial.
A car accident...
a gas explosion...
a suicide, a drowning...
a work accident,
a second car accident...
and a heart attack
while driving.
''Foul play is doubted,''
says the new chief of police.
Vago was sentenced...
to 8 years in a farm prison...
where one year equals two years.
Yago got 1 1 years of the same.
Ten months
for disturbing the peace.
One year with a possibility
of paying it off.
The four indicted officers...
only received
administrative reprimands.
Yet the government
had to resign...
after the leftists seemed
certain to win the elections.
Prior to the elections...
the army seized power
and dismissed the judge.
Senator George Pirou
died in a police car...
of a clot in the brain...
said police officers.
Deported to the islands.
During questioning,
fell from the seventh floor...
trying to escape,
said the police.
Three years for revealing
official documents.
Also, the military regime
banned...
long hair, miniskirts...
Sophocles, Tolstoy, Euripides...
Russian-style toasts...
strikes...
Aristophanes, Ionesco...
Sartre, Albee, Pinter...
freedom of the press,
sociology...
Beckett, Dostoevsky...
modern music, pop music...
new math, and the letter ''z''...
which means ''he is alive''
in ancient Greek.