I just missed your heart.
You are dead right now.
I've killed you.
Use your hands.
Drag the deer back yourself
What's wrong?
Are you hurt?
You were half asleep.
You must always be ready.
Even when you're sleeping.
Think on your feet.
- Adapt...
- Or die.
I'll do better next time.
German.
Italian
I'll do better next time.
Spanish
Español
Did you really want
me to snap your neck?
How much did you pull off the deer?
In 120 parts.
200 pounds in total.
I think so.
That explains it.
What?
How you beat me.
You've getting stronger.
I'm glad you didnt snap my neck.
The great blue whale is the
largest animal to have ever existed.
Its heart weighs 1300 pounds.
And the male has 7 gallons of...
testicles.
The blue whale's music can be
heard for over five hundred miles..
A blue whale's tongue weighs
overs two and a half tons. 41.
What does music feel like?
Music
- a combination of sounds
with a view to beauty of form
and expression of emotion.
I want to hear it for myself.
We've all we need right here.
It's not enough.
I'm ready.
Papa, I'm ready.
Grimm's Fairy Tales
One, two, three, four, five, six
I live in Leipzig German city
Population: 0.7 million peoples
Tell me again 54.
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Straza,
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
We live at number 7, Vicenza Platz.
I go to school at The
Klaus College Gymnasium.
And my best friends are Rudy
Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Straza,
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
I like literature and sport.
In particular, tennis and athletics.
We live at number 7, Vicenza Platz. I go
to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
And my best friends are Rudy
Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
I also have a dog called Trudy.
I'm ready.
I'm ready now.
Did you see it? Did you hear it?
It's like thunder! It was so beautiful!
What is it?
It tells Marissa Wiegler where we are
If you think you're ready,
and you want to leave here,
all you have to do is flip that switch.
But once it's done
there's no going back.
She won't stop until you're dead,
or she is. You understand?
I won't be there to hold your hand.
So be sure
Be sure it's what you really want.
It's here. There's no rush. 80mm
Laika, a mongrel dog
from the street of Moscow,
was the first animal to orbit the Earth.
She was launched into outer space
on the third of November, 1957.
Scientists believe humans
would be unable to survive
the conditions of outer space.
So flights by animals were used
as experiments precursory
to human missions.
A rocket was not designed
to be retrievable,
and laika has always
been, intended to die
But she didn't, did she?
They couldn't bring the
rocket back, remember?
I remember.
But sometimes I wish you
would read it differently.
When a star collapses,
the supernova explosion
is ten billion times
brighter than the other stars
Will you hunt with me?
If you want.
Well, it's up to you.
Me? Yes
I'll stay.
Yes, good.
Marissa Wiegler...
...come and find me.
You were lucky to have caught that deer.
There was nothing out there today.
The smell's good.
When will it be ready?
Soon.
We've picked up an unencrypted
signal. One of ours.
When?
- 0630, 2 Eastern Standard.
Triangulated about 60 miles
below the Arctic Circle.
Near kazuma. We think it is Erik Heller.
- Erik Heller?
- You're his handler, right?
Sure, the name sounds familiar.
Fuck Erik.
Why now?
How does it look?
Good...
Almost good.
Erik Heller, recruited in 1991.
Formal FSK operative He
became integral to our
Counter Intelligence Ops in Eastern
Europe and Central Asia.
His file ends in '94.
There was no sign of
life until April 18, 1996,
when his fingerprints were
found on a 22 calibre ruger,
found beside body of one, Johanna Zadek.
Johanna Zadek, born in 1970, German
She was spotted and
developed by Heller in 1994.
- Never recruited.
- Why was she being developed?
That's not in the file.
Let's keep on the past.
Heller is a rogue asset. I
propose we go and pull him out.
We got bigger problems, Marissa.
Let Interpol pick him up. He's
no longer our responsibility.
Interpol nabs him, that
exposes him to BND, FSB, France.
Do you really want
every intelligence agency
in Europe scratching at this threat?
- Lewis?
- I'm Sorry,
but we need to keep this
contained, gentlemen.
Keep it small. I've
worked with this man.
He knows things I don't
think you wanna know.
I appreciate your candor.
- What do you need Lewis? -
One man, one-day operation.
- Tell me again.
- Marissa Wiegler.
- Then?
- Postcard.
- What?
- The address where we meet.
- Wilhelm Grimm House,
Stefan Straza, 21610559,
Berlin, Germany.
- Then what else?
- Adapt or die.
- Think on your feet...
- ... Even when I'm sleeping.
Papa.
Remember what I taught
you and you will be fine.
I'll see you there.
Macalahan, do you read me?
Macalahan.
Go, go, go.
Erik Heller escaped.
How did that happen?
Unclear. We think he got
away in the snow storm or
And 'something bigger
than that I can manage.
- One man, one day of operations. Just find him, Lewis.
- Look there were many variables.
Find him and bring him to me.
There was a kid. Things
got out of our control!
Wiegler
Wiegler, are you there?
Where is she now?
Hello, Hanna.
Hello
My name is Dr. Burton.
Would you like to talk to me?
I was told by my father
to gain the upper hand.
That's very interesting.
What else did your father tell you?
Where am I?
You are in holding.
I've never been in a room like this.
Must all be very strange for you.
How long have you been
in the forest? 180mm.
Hanna?
- Are those cameras?
- Uhuh.
They're taking our pictures right now,
to keep a record.
How does that make you feel?
Camera obscura...
It's Latin, for dark chamber.
It was first described
by the Arabic scientist
Ibn al-Haytham in the year 1021.
Plug the cctv through to Langley.
Hey, you should have a visual
on the psych evaluation there
Can I get you something?
What do you like?
Music, magazines
Just ask, anything.
I want to speak to Marissa Wiegler.
- Tell her I'll be there tonight.
- I can handle this.
Just do what you're told.
John, take a look at
this kid's blood sample
- Is that right?
- Is it?
- Can be right.
- Got a sample of her hair.
Must be contaminated. Run it again.
My name is Marissa Wiegler.
You wanted to speak with me?
You can wait outside.
Where am I?
You are in a safe place, sweetie.
Where did you meet my father?
Erik.
You mean Erik?
Yes
I met him by a news kiosk at
Alexander Platz. East Berlin.
I met him at a news kiosk,
- Alexanderplatz...
- Say it was raining.
...in the rain.
He'd just arrived from Prague.
You know where your father is?
Did he tell you where he was going?
We're are worried about him.
It's okay.
Agent, keep your distance.
Do you want me to give her something?
I think that might be necessary.
Abort.
Open up.
I repeat agent, abort!
Oh, my...
Wiegler!
I want everyone here now
Do not let it escape from the gallery.
- Do you think she got out?
- She can't get out.
Detail every unit available
Mama
She will never be yours.
Hey, hello.
Don't you speak English?
It's not your fault if you can't.
Emma Ackery couldn't speak
English until she was eight,
because she was like, a refugee
or something from Sri Lanka.
But now she's a pop
star, in America too.
So don't worry if you
can't speak English yet.
Who's she?
I found her, She can't speak
English. She's from Sri Lanka.
I'm from Germany.
Oh
I live in Leipzig, Population:
0.7 million peoples.
We live at No. 7 Vicenza Platz.
I like literature and sport, in
particular tennis and athletics.
I go to school at The
Klaus College Gymnasium.
And my best friends are Rudy
Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
They sound fun.
I also have a dog called Trudy.
We had a dog called Vincent,
But he went mad and died.
Sophie, come on.
See ya.
I'm Sophie and that
is my brother, Miles.
I am... Hanna.
Do you need a lift somewhere?
No. I prefer to walk.
Suit yourself
Sophie, come on, We
are all waiting for you
Tacticle says she's in the desert,
south east of vessel we're in.
Focus all operations on Heller.
Are you saying the girl's
not of interest to us?
Yes, of course she's of interest, Lewis.
But not an immediate threat to the
security of the United States of America.
Erik Heller is the immediate
threat. Focus on Heller.
Where is your family?
- Are you Arabic?
- I am Moroccan.
Morocco Capital city: Rabat.
Marrakech, Salé.
Religion: Islam. Language: Arabic.
I like Arabic very much.
It's like Japanese, it's big.
You speak Arabic?
Yes, of course.
Where is your family?
I need a room for the night.
Can you help? I have no money.
It's the best we've got.
Thank you.
Do you have one of these in every room?
All the rooms are the same.
It's electricity.
Of course, all mod cons.
I know a little about electricity.
They say Edison invented it
- Or was it Franklin?
- Some American I'm sure.
This is an electrical kettle.
It's for the English.
They like to make their own tea.
What is it?
It's the best we can do.
Where do you come from?
The forest.
It's the German girl.
It's Kraut in a big Djellaba.
Like quail or lesbo.
I think I'd quite like to be lesbian.
But not one of those fat ones,
one who's like, a supermodel.
But who don't hold hands, and I
think I'd probably marry a man.
What?
No kiss?
She's a bit old for you, isn't she?
She has male and female genetalias.
And you love her just the way she is.
I like to give people what they want.
Vera
Make my friend something sweet
I'll save it for when I need it.
What do you want, Marissa?
Erik Heller's still alive.
Of course.
And the girl.
Ah.
Why are you here precisely?
I need you.
You need me? Little old
me! I'm very flattered.
I need your talents, darling.
I need you to do things
my agency will not let me do.
Stop!
Again.
Start again.
The devil is in the details, isn't it?
- It's the girl or Erik?
- She is in Morocco.
It's all in the envelope.
Let me worry about Erik.
Shall I kill her?
Just find her.
Marissa.
Did she turn out as you hoped?
Better.
Once more.
Again.
...and gave me lots of advices.
About how to spend these
money do these taxes.
You see even though she is beautiful,
she is actually brilliant with money.
Get off.
Like for one of the
anniversary, he said his 15 grand
For a Hermes kelly bag or a boob job.
Now she said she knew that the boob implant
will have to be replaced every 10 years.
But that the Hermes kelly bag
never depreciates in value.
- That's enough for the boob job
- I mean that's not just common sense
And that's why I really love her.
Mum is against plastic surgery.
- I am. - Mum doesn't
even wear make-up.
I don't. I think it's dishonest.
This is my face, Take it or leave it.
If you study History
of Art, Anthropology...
Rachel got a first at Cambridge.
...you learn that red
lipstick mimic arousal
and suggests the geography
of the labia minora.
- Puke!
- Where as I have a lot of natural red pigments
in my lips and so I
really don't need it.
- Vomitory
- Sophie!
- It's embarrassing.
- Just grow up! All right?
- Grow up?
- Yeah
Oh, because yesterday mum was saying
how I shouldn't act beyond my years.
No, it does leave her with
mixed messages, darling.
Because we're trying to communicate
to her how to enjoy childhood.
I just want her to stop
saying vomitory, all right?
Oi, It's not funny.
So, Hanna. Hanna?
I'm quite impressed about you
traveling around on your own.
My father encourages
me to be independent.
You see, that's wonderful.
- I was back packing at your age.
- And where is he, your father?
I spent a heavenly summer, just
island hopping around Greece,
Island hopping around Greece!
What? No. It's valuable.
Our experience makes us who
we are. Isn't that right, kids?
So Hanna, is your mum
and dad still together?
My mother is dead.
Nice one, dad!
I'm sorry to hear that. I lost my
mum when I was very young, so...
It's all right. It
happened a long time ago.
Hanna,
what did your mum die of?
Three bullets.
Omg, That's appalling!
Combination of sounds
with a view to beauty of form
and expression of emotion..
MEDICAL REPORT
"Abnormal. "
What happen if it rains?
Well, you going to get wet. Aren't you?
Because someone broke the sunroof.
- Your mother and I are...
- Your mother and I...
Your mother and I are
responsible adults...
My fungus nail infections' back.
Who are you?
What do you want from the girl?
I am her uncle. 400mm
We are very concerned about her.
I don't know what you're looking for.
She came, she was nice, she left.
Bingo!
Voila!
The van has checked out?
Today
North or south?
The ferry. They caugh
the ferry to Spain.
Can you lend me your pen?
- I've contacted Interpol.
- On who's authority?
Walt. We can't keep this
to ourselves anymore.
- Were you not listening?
- He killed two policemen.
He's reframed the situation.
It is out of our control.
Then we must regain control, Mr. Lewis.
I am the first and the last person
Erik Heller will see. Are we clear?
Are we clear?
- Mr. Lewis?
- Yes, Madam.
THE WITCH IS DEAD.
Oh, my God! What are you doing here?
The sun roof, was it you?
Would it be very bad if it was?
You mean you were in
the van, the whole time?
My dad would have a heart
attack if he found out.
- Will you have to tell him?
- Hanna, you are so mental!
Of course I'm not going to tell him.
I think it's brilliant. Have
you got anywhere to stay?
- No.
- Yes, you do.
- You're staying with me.
- I am?
Yeah, obviously. I'm sneaking
you in, on one condition.
What?
These boys. Spanish. Gorgeous.
No, don't look. Don't go all
pruny about it, like footballers.
Haven't got their eyebrows
waxed, or anything!
- Good.
- Anyway, we're going out tonight and you have to come.
- All right..
- God, you're not hard to convince! Perv.
Who?
Have you got anything to wear?
You can't wear those, you
look like some mad German.
Are you scared?
Of what?
Are we going to kiss now?
Would you like to?
Kissing requires a total
of 34 facial muscles
and 112 postural muscles.
The most important muscle involved
is the orbicularis oris muscle,
because it is used to pucker the lips
Hanna, you mentalist!
Please tell your friend
I wanted just a kiss.
Hanna!
- Should I let him go?
- As opposed to what?
Yes, you should let him go!
I'm going to go now.
Okay.
It was nice.
Sophie, is that you?
It is the sandman.
Go to sleep.
Oh, my God You acted like
a bandit. It's embarrassing.
- Like what?
- Oh I can't believe you.
Hello, Mama.
I know you're disappointed in me.
I know it. I am very sorry, Mama.
But.. But maybe I've found
a way to make it better.
I'm in a programme now.
A programme to make babies stronger.
It's an American
programme, very scien...
How did you get into
my house, Mrs. Wiegler?
I'm looking for Erik.
He said you were dead.
So you've seen him?
He sent word.
Where is Hanna?
Did you ever have children of your own?
I made certain choices.
Then you will never understand
what it is like to lose your child.
To not know what happened.
The years of waiting.
Of watching from the window. 480mm
And waiting..
Waiting..
Have you seen her?
Hanna!
Can you tell me what she looks like?
Like her mother.
- Hanna?
- Yes
Where do you really come from?
Leipzig. I live in Leipzig.
If we're going to be friends, you're
going to have to be honest with me.
Those are the rules.
- Are we friends?
- Yes
I like you.
I'd like to have a friend.
I mean, you're a freak and
everything, but I like you.
I like you too. I really do.
But
There are things I can't tell you.
- Do you understand?
- Yes
Actually, no I don't.
There are peoples that want to harm me.
- Bad peoples.
- I see.
- And they won't stop.
- Right.
So, for your own safety.
Can we still be friends?
I don't know.
I mean I don't really
know who you are, do I?
That's just it.
Neither do I.
- What is it?
- It's something about me.
I know what DNA means, but I
don't understand the rest of it.
- Are you sick?
- I don't feel sick.
- What's wrong with you?
- Nothing's wrong with me.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to Berlin.
I have to meet meet my father
at the House of Wilhelm Grimm.
From Grimms fairy tales?
That's right.
If you say so.
Did I say the wrong thing again?
Keep this.
To remember me.
It's a friendship bracelet.
Thank you.
Where's Hanna?
Wow, you look rough! Do want some tea?
I had some. Who's Hanna?
The girl we ate dinner with in Morocco.
She's here, or was. She
came out with me last night.
How did she get here?
Is she with her father?
No, she came on her own.
What?
Look, other people have
their own style of parenting.
He's promoting independence.
She's like an orphan!
Call me conservative.
- Are you really conservative, darling?
- No I'm not.
I said we'll give her a lift to
Lyon. We are going to Lyon, aren't we?
- I found breakfast.
That's gross!
We've got him! We have Heller.
Do you read me? Bring him to
Wiegler. She will id an interview
- Is that what she said?
- Confirmed with her two minutes ago.
Marissa, damn it!
I feel so grounded in the countryside.
The city stifles me,
emotionally, creatively, spiritually.
Places like this bring us closer to God.
God?
Well, not any modernistic sense.
Buddha, Krishna, the God within.
Whatever you believe in.
What do you believe in, Hanna?
Nothing.
Everything alright?
I think so.
I'm not sure if it's true
that the baby can hear me,
but at night I feel her.
I hope she hears me.
Was it like this for you, mama?
I think I know what she looks like.
I can see her when I close my eyes.
I can hear her inside me.
Do you think is that silly?
Oh, I think it's a girl.
I hope so.
Erik...
What?
Oh for Christ's sake, Lewis.
Hello, Marissa.
I heard you were dead.
Did your little girl tell you that?
- What are you listening to?
- Self help.
Are you in need of help?
It's good to hear you.
I didn't imagine we'd
have the chance to talk.
You don't have her, do
you? You're not that good.
Oh, Erik! You're such a flirt.
- Tech's on the way.
- You were a good agent, Erik.
Sad to see you go dumb.
What did I miss?
I couldn't do it anymore.
The things we did.
I... I'm sorry with Johanna.
With all of them. With Hanna.
So, why come back now?
Tech guys.
I asked you a question, Erik?
Erik, are you still there?
Move. Get up.
Shit... shit... shit...
Hanna, I think we're lost.
- I have to pull over.
- No, don't.
Can't see the map.
Have we stopped? I need to pee.
Don't want you going
too far right now, love.
I think you should stay
where you are, Sophie.
Hanna, what's going on?
Keep calm.
- Are we are in Lyon?
- No we're not.
Whatever you do, don't follow me!
Promise not to follow me.
I promise.
Thank you for being my friend.
Hanna!
Come on, come on!
Silence! Shut up
Hanna.
Definitely odd. Disconnected.
You know, I like to think that
I have a rapport with kids.
You know, I get with them.
You know, sir, it's days like
this that I really hate my job.
- Yeah, I'm sure you do..
- This is very, very difficult.
But sometimes children
are bad people too.
- Stop crying.
- I'm not telling you anything!
- Do you know this boy?
- No!
He knows you. Your friend
is in a lot of danger.
I don't know anything!
She said she lived in Leipzig.
She went to The Klaus College Gymnazium.
Her friends were Rudy and Gunter
She likes tennis and she
has a dog named Trudy.
- She lied to you.
- Absolutely.
It is not lost, but we must act very
carefully. But she needed taken care of.
I've got something to show you.
- A little help from mom.
- This is Hanna's mother.
Biological mother.
15 years ago, she was shot
to death by Hanna's father
on a camping trip.
Don't you wanna see what's inside?
- Say "Please. "
- Please.
You like her, don't you?
It's okay. I won't tell anyone.
She's very pretty.
- Where is she?
- You tell me.
- Is she in lots of trouble?
- The worst kind, sweetheart.
Some very bad men are looking for her,
and I need to find her.
I wanna protect her.
Do you want her to get hurt?
No.
She's going to Berlin.
To Wilhelm Grimm's house.
To meet her dad.
Hanna. Hanna... Hanna come, come.
This way.
Been waiting for you a long time.
What did Erik told you about me?
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Straza,
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
That's it.
He didn't tell you of my magic.
Klaus, 09/05. Be there Tuesday. Erik.
- What day is it?
- It's today, my dear.
Come, come. 650mm
Sit.
Oh, you're hungry.
- Waffles.
- May I have one?
An egg? Of course.
You can eat whatever you want, my dear.
My shoe!
Oh, I've almost forgotten.
A present.
For me?
You will need a fresh photograph.
But everything's in order, yes?
Why do I need a piece of
paper to tell me my name?
Not you, not you my dear.
But everyone else we
need paper and computers,
so we don't have to ask people
their names to look them in the face.
You have a good face.
You look just like your father.
And you walk like him too, uh uh uh.
- I don't walk like that.
- Yes, you do! You do, my dear! Uh uh.
Did you know my mother too?
But, of course.
She was a singer. A wonderful singer.
Do you sing?
Papa.. Erik, didn't teach me.
Oh, you poor child.
He has truely limited you
from all the wonderful
things the world has to offer.
No magic.
No music.
I'll teach you.
Is that him?
Upstairs with you, my dear Quickly.
Good day.
We're closed, boys and girl.
Where is Erik?
He doesn't know much
or he is a very good liar.
He knew Johanna.
- Yes, of course.
- Bits and pieces about the programme.
- What does he know about the girl?
- He thinks Erik's the father.
- Everybody thinks Erik's the father.
- That's precious!
Yes? This is Marissa Wiegler.
Walt, I didn't recog...
Lewis is dead.
Do you think it's important to tell us?
Why didn't you call us yet?
One man, One-day operation.
Yes. Yes. Yes! We all want, Lewis.
He was shooting through the door, Walt.
No, I'm not standing down...
No, I'm interest..
Well, yes.
No, listen, Walt.
Heizinger.
So off to grandmother's house, we go.
Have you seen her?
Hanna!
SOUGHT
Sit down.
Are you my father?
Sit down, Hanna.
- Are you my father?
- Please, sit.
Are you?
Hanna, of course I'm your father.
- I raised you.
- But Marissa said...
- Hanna!
- Don't lie to me!
I'm your father. I've been
with you your whole life.
Treated you like my own flesh and blood.
But I was not your flesh and your blood.
- I am abnormal?
- No!
Where was I born?
Tell me the truth.
You were born in a research facility.
In rural Poland, Galinki.
What was the research?
They took fertilized embryo's
and made small changes
to them to improve them.
To reduce the capacity
for fear, for pity,
to increase muscle strength,
heightened senses. Anything
to make a better soldier.
The perfect soldier.
I've recruited your mother
in an abortion clinic.
I've recruited twenty
women the same way.
- There were other children?
- Yes
When you were two,
Marissa Wiegler, she
closed the whole programme
and all of this research,
it was disposed of.
Do you understand?
I love you, Hanna.
You have to know that.
Because I'm a freak?
No.
Because you are my child.
Where are you going?
Stop this.
Let me go!
Hanna! Hanna, please!
I tried to prepare for what
that would be your life.
You didn't prepare me for this.
Run!
Take it.
That's all you got?
Run, pig!
Why now, Erik?
Kids grow up.
Mr. Grimm!
Mr. Grimm.
Hanna
I'm here, Hanna.
Oh, don't worry sweetheart.
Don't! Don't move any closer!
Hanna, I can help you.
Please!
I don't want to hurt anyone anymore..
I just wanna talk.
It's over now, Marissa.
Let me go.
Hanna!
Don't walk away from me, young lady!
I just missed your heart