I'm on my way!
I'm sorry.
I'll fix it up for you.
Hold on. Wait here one sec.
- Enjoy your coffee.
- Thanks.
Hey.
Why? I just had a look.
After two years,
you're sick of me, huh?
No way.
You even gave away your dog
after you got sick of it.
A dog and a person are different.
What's this?
- Who is it?
- Interested in her, too?
She looks like a lunatic.
How could she laugh like this?
She looks scary.
What would you like?
- What's with your attitude?
- Pardon?
Can't you be nicer to customers?
- I'm sorry.
- I'll have coffee.
Why? Feel bad that I got mad at
a girl you're interested in?
Hello?
Yes?
- I'll call you if there's a problem.
- Okay.
Did you see that?
My license plate got bent.
- Why'd you take her card?
- Just in case there's a problem later.
- But why'd you give her yours?
- Just because.
Just because?
And why'd you open the door for her?
Didn't they have hands?
Do you work here?
- Are you jealous?
- Give me her card.
What are you doing?
You said your car was okay!
Why do you need her card?
- Aren't you being too much?
- What? What's too much?
Those girls talk to you smiling,
and you take it like an idiot.
And why'd you park for them?
Are you their friend?
Aren't you the one who's too much?
You should've said the insurance
will cover it and hurry back.
But why'd you give in so easily?
You're overreacting.
It was nothing.
What?
It was nothing?
Seh-hee!
You should've just apologized.
But why'd you give him your card?
Who are you to yell at me?
Who are you to give your card
to my boyfriend?
Did you expecthe'd call
a slut like you?
Hey.
I'm sorry.
Sorry about what?
They're sluts anyway.
You crazy bitch!
Crazy bitch?
Yeah, I'm crazy!
So what?
- Screw you!
- Sit down, Hee-sun.
I'm very sorry.
Stop. This is embarrassing.
Embarrassing?
You're ashamed of me?
She must love you very much.
I envy you.
I'm sorry.
Look at me.
I'm crazy, aren't I?
I wanna poke out girls' eyes
when they just look at you.
Sorry for always having
the same boring face.
Seh-hee.
I'm sorry, I've been tired lately.
You're tired of seeing
my same body everyday.
Don't talk like that.
It's not because of that.
Do you remember that girl
who hit your car?
No.
Liar.
Be honest.
What?
She'd look pretty if naked.
With big tits.
What are you doing?
Are you thinking of her tits?
It's okay.
Think about her.
This hand is hers.
You know, you're getting weirder.
Think of me as her.
It's okay.
Did you imagine sleeping with her?
What are you talking about?
Tell me the truth.
Did you think of her?
You told me to think of her.
Hey, that hurt.
I bit you harder before.
- But it hurts now?
- It really hurt, why'd you do that?
I'm sorry for having
the same boring face everyday.
Stop it! I told you
stop talking like that!
Why are you acting so weird?
Let me see.
Look at me!
Stop being so paranoid!
You said to think of her!
What do you expect me to do?
What the hell is this?
You want me to imagine
another girl while having sex.
What the hell is this?
Is this your idea of love?
The number you are calling
is not in service,
Excuse me.
What happened to room 1005?
No one's there.
Seh-hee? In 1005?
She suddenly moved out yesterday.
Do you know where she moved to?
I don't know.
Okay.
Hi, Yoon-a.
Oh, hi, Ji-woo.
What brings you here?
Do you happen to know
where Seh-hee moved to?
What?
She moved?
To where?
I'll have coffee, please.
And I'm sorry about the other day.
The number you are calling
is not in service,
I don't know if I can make you.
I don't want to be prettier.
Just different. A new face.
Are you tired of your face?
Please do it.
Are you still sure you want it?
This person and this person
are the same.
Do you believe it?
You can never get back
your real face.
Have anyone as your model?
The eyelids need to be
a bit deeper.
Just the tip of the nose
needs to be raised.
And smaller lips.
It won't be difficult.
One moment.
I'll make your jaw and chin
look softer.
Your face will be smaller.
It takes six months
to fully recover.
It will be painful.
Can you take it?
I'll have to
if I want to look new.
Look ahead please.
I'll take your picture now.
Now look this way please.
I'll give you one last chance
to think about it.
Hello?
Hey, Tae-suk.
Now?
Why are you waiting for her
after she disappears like that?
Forget about her.
But how could she do that?
You two went out for two years.
Two years are enough.
- I can't even last six months.
- Enjoy!
Aren't you sick of the same body?
Yeah, when it hits two years,
you start checking out other girls.
But it's not
because there's no love.
It's because there's
no more thrills and turn-ons.
- You got a nose job and a face lift, huh?
- No.
Come on, you got your eyes,
nose and jaw done.
- I said I didn't.
- You did.
Let me see your boobs.
- What are you doing?
- Hey, hey, hey.
It's none of your business.
~ If time never stops running
~ Can I forget you like a dream?
Hey, why are you touching
my partner, you crazy asshole?
~ I miss you tonight
~ My love, my love
You always act like an ass
in these places.
- Hey, I liked her more.
- You should've told me.
Then I'll change seats!
~ Are you coming tonight?
If you touch her one more time,
I'll kill you.
But I can touch you, right?
Some drink?
You're too damn noisy!
Stop singing!
- His song is terrible.
- What is that song?
I don't know.
What the hell? Fuck.
You bitch, watch your mouth.
Honey.
What the fuck are you staring at?
Apologize.
Why'd you fucking hit my partner?
Fuck off, asshole.
- That's enough.
- You understand me, right?
Cheers.
Honey. Have you read Marquez's
'Memories of My Melancholy Whores'?
Mar, who?
Who fucking cares.
Who wants to screw these girls?
- Don't ask dumb questions.
- Bingo!
Not me. Leave me out.
Hey, we came here for you.
You can't bail, idiot!
I wanna talk with you.
You do? Let's go.
Don't get any wild ideas.
We're just gonna talk.
What? Talk physically?
I love Seh-hee.
You crazy bastard.
All we're gonna do is talk, okay?
I forgot to ask your age.
How old are you?
Honey, wake up.
You just gonna sleep?
Wake up.
Come on, honey.
Hey, is this your idea of talking?
Yeah, raise your arms.
I can't.
- Why not?
- I broke up with my girlfriend.
- You can.
- I can't do this out of respect.
But we're all human, right?
What's going on?
Who did it?
What was that noise?
Damn it.
What the hell are you doing,
you drunk!
You wanna go to the police?
You're supposed to just screw,
not break the window!
- Hello?
- Ji-woo, It's me, Yon-hee,
Hi, Yon-hee.
It's been a long time.
How have you been?
I'm going to hold an exhibition,
Congratulations.
Can you come visit?
Okay, I'll try to make it.
Ji-woo! You made it.
Congratulations.
The artwork is very nice.
It's definitely you, Yon-hee.
Where did you take
all those pictures?
I wish I can go there one day.
You wanna go together sometime?
Did you and Chul-soo break up?
He just disappeared one day.
Why don't you find him?
Why look for someone
who got sick of me and left?
You're seeing someone, right?
She disappeared one day as well.
Really?
She must be with Chul-soo now.
Then that means we can be together.
Let's mind nothing.
- Are you sure?
- You liked me, didn't you?
But you couldn't tell me
because of Chul-soo.
Dummy.
I'm rather worn,
but you can have me now.
You're still beautiful.
- Shall we go?
- After I go to the lady's room.
- You wanna come to my place?
- No.
Then, a motel?
I'll see you next time.
What are you talking about?
You asked to be with me.
I think this is wrong.
Are you playing with me?
You called me to make
a fool out of me?
What do you want from me?
Just that you weren't like this
before you went to the lady's room.
Why'd you work me up like that?
Worked up for what?
Damn it, I shouldn't have come.
Bye.
I think this is the last time.
Hey, Yon-hee.
Be with me just tonight, okay?
You've changed a lot,
and have no self-pride now.
Okay, okay.
I'll take you home by my car.
Let's talk some more.
What are you doing?
- Keep your promise.
- What promise?
Don't do this.
I'm so lonely.
We're all human.
I'm sorry.
You should realize how happy you are.
Just do well on your part.
Where are you heading?
Hop in. I'll take you there.
Can I take some pictures of you?
This is that famous
well-being 'feet bath'.
Your knees are very pretty.
Specially this lady here.
She's exactly my style!
Hyo-nim?
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Hi.
Eun-hae?
That's me. Hello.
Hi.
Hyun-jung?
Everyone satisfied?
For the one-on-one in 10 minutes.
Applause.
How do you like this place?
Not bad, huh?
I'm so happy.
It's the first time ever
for me to have the one I wanted.
I picked you the moment I saw you.
Oh, I see.
What do you think about me?
I'm not too sure yet.
You seem like a nice person.
That's just a mannered thing
to say to an unattractive girl.
No. I'm serious.
You liked the long-haired girl?
Eun-hae.
Long hair? Who was that?
I don't remember.
- What's your hobby?
- Well, taking pictures.
Take a picture of me one day.
Sure, great.
Shall we go shooting?
With real bullets.
You looked awesome
when you were shooting.
Shooting is great
for relieving stress.
I had a great time today.
If we turn around once...
and make eye contact
then we should meet again.
Now, one, two, three.
Hey.
Where are you?
Still with her?
I just got back home.
Damn it, my girl kept
talking about you.
I got annoyed, then gave her
your number and left.
She'll probably call you.
Why'd you give her my number
without asking me?
You weird bastard.
Hello?
Do you realize how late it is?
You sure you gave her my number?
- She hasn't called.
- You crazy bastard.
I'm sleepy as hell.
Hello? Hey!
Welcome!
Here's your coffee.
Enjoy.
I love you,
Do you need more coffee?
Yes.
- Welcome!
- It's hot!
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
I'm sorry.
You should've been careful.
- Oh, hello.
- Hello.
- Going to the island?
- Yes.
Do you want to try this?
- Throw it, not eat it.
- Yeah.
Like this.
Up.
They're seagulls, right?
Of course.
Think they're eagles?
- I...
- Throw it up.
- How far are you headed?
- To the Sculpture Park.
Really? Hop in.
I'm headed there, too.
- How about this one?
- It's nice.
Yes, isn't it?
Looks like a fireball.
This is fun,
too, isn't it?
Yes.
- Climb up like this.
- I'm okay.
Come on, climb up.
Have you gone inside
that shell before?
- Have you?
- Yes.
What did you do in there?
- Let's take a picture together.
- Okay.
Excuse me!
Could you take a picture of us?
Here you go.
To the left a bit.
A bit lower.
Get ready.
One, two, three.
Looks great, doesn't it?
Do you have a girlfriend?
She left me six months ago
without saying a word.
- Without saying anything?
- Yeah.
Are you waiting for her?
Sometimes yes, and sometimes no.
Since time's passed,
I don't know anymore.
Feels like the right fit for my hand.
- I had a great time today.
- Me, too.
- Bye.
Bye.
Welcome.
What's that?
A letter?
Something seems to be...
But I'm not sure.
It looks like 'I love you'
written over and over again.
Is that what you're hoping for?
What would you like to order?
- Coffee, please.
- Okay.
I'm sorry.
I forgot it was a letter.
It's 'I love you' written
over and over again, right?
I haven't even asked you
your name yet.
- See-hee.
- Seh-hee?
- See...
- What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
I forgot it was a letter.
What can I do?
- How could you laugh now?
- I'm sorry. Are you upset?
- I'll get rid...
- No!
Aren't you being too much?
I said sorry.
Hey. This is a letter
from my girlfriend...
who disappeared without a trace
six months ago.
So how could you write on it?
If you can't forget her so much.
Then why'd you kiss me in the car?
Tell me.
Why did you kiss me?
I'm sorry about the other day.
See-hee, go tidy up over there.
What a weird girl.
She's the one who popped up here.
I'm very sorry about what happened.
No, I'm the one who's sorry.
Could you tell me See-hee's number?
I'm really lost.
I don't know what to do.
Please call me.
I'll be awake.
Please call me for sure.
See-hee, I beg you to call me,
I can't do anything,
I miss you,
Come on in.
I'll prepare dinner first.
- Watch a DVD if you're bored.
- Okay.
Looks very delicious.
Wait a bit more.
- How is it?
- It's delicious.
That's great.
For a guy's place,
how come it's so clean?
Then is your place messy?
Yes.
I don't have much time to clean up.
Then I'll go and clean it for you.
Can you really?
Yes.
It's delicious.
I have to go.
Thanks for dinner.
Stay the night.
Next time.
Please stay, Seh-hee.
Seh-hee?
See-hee.
Good night.
See-hee!
I'll go and clean your place later.
Excuse me.
Have any old pictures of yourself?
I wanna see you as a kid.
I don't have any.
- Not even one?
- Yes, not even one.
That's strange.
Show it to me.
I bet it's an old photo.
No.
- Show it to me.
- No.
Can't you show it to me?
I wanna see it.
How was it?
It was new to me.
It's the first time
I've felt like this.
Thanks.
Thanks for what?
Just everything.
For all the time that's passed.
Do you love me?
I don't know yet.
I just feel very happy.
Why do you keep smiling?
Because I'm happy.
You're kind and a great guy.
Thanks.
But...
Tell me.
Did you love Seh-hee very much?
Yes.
Even now?
Why?
If Seh-hee comes back for you?
She won't come back.
What if she does?
That's what I want to.
Do I look happy?
But I'm sad strangely.
My heart is gonna boom up.
What the hell?
Did you just hit me?
Yes.
Why?
I love you.
Sorry, sleep again.
Don't hit me.
I'm gonna be angry.
To Dearest Ji-woo,
I tried to forget you but I couldn't,
I want to return to you,
Meet at the cafe on the 20th at two,
Seh-hee
Tell me.
What is it about?
Don't make me so curious.
Seh-hee is coming back.
So?
I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
Are you gonna meet her?
I was very lonely after she left me.
So you're meeting me
because you're lonely?
No, that's not true.
Do you still love her?
I think so.
I can't give you up, either.
- I'm sorry.
- No.
I'll meet her and stop her.
- You can't!
- You can't, either!
Who do you think I am?
Think I'm some slut
who comforts you with sex?
Watch your mouth!
- Tell me! What am I to you?
- Get out!
Forget when you sweated on me
like some crazy horse?
Am I a whore?
Stop it!
This is embarrassing.
Embarrassing?
You're embarrassed of me?
Hey! Hey!
Damn it.
What are you embarrassed of?
Who made me like this?
- Is this who you are?
- Yeah!
This is me!
Kill me first before you go to her!
I really mistook you.
You...
You son of a bitch!
You filthy son of a bitch!
Go! Go!
The number you are calling
is not in service,
- So what do you want?
- We're not right for each other.
I thought you were
crazy about me, fuck.
Why do you always curse?
- I hate that.
- I'm sorry, shit.
How have you been?
I missed you so much.
What is this?
It was you on that island?
I wanted to see you somehow.
How could you do that?
What kind of crazy act is this?
I was scared of time.
- Time that makes everything change.
- So what the hell is this?
Were you happy playing with me?
Then what the hell am I?
What am I?
I believed if I'd changed my face
you'd love me longer.
But you couldn't forget...
your girl of the past.
And I couldn't stand
being so jealous.
That doesn't make sense.
Both of them are you!
No.
I'm not your woman of the past.
I'm a new woman.
You're crazy!
Who are you?
Damn it.
Think this place is
some theatrical stage?
What's with the mask?
And stop being so damn loud.
Haven't you heard of manners?
Think this place is your home?
What the hell is this?
Why'd you fix your face?
Are you crazy?
I was too nervous.
I thought you'd get sick of me
and find a new woman.
Think I'm some meathead
who chases after women's bodies?
I love you.
You're scary.
You're really scary.
Don't be like this.
Just take off my mask
and see my new face.
No.
You're crazy!
You got a problem?
Let's take it outside.
Fucking bastard.
Min-soo.
Get up, asshole!
Min-soo, stop it.
Let's just leave.
Welcome...
Hello, Seh-hee.
Hello.
Your face looks natural now.
Is there anything uncomfortable?
No.
I was just passing by.
Do you wanna go back
to your real self?
Doctor!
Do you wanna try it?
- How do you feel?
- I feel great.
Do you know her?
Doctor, can you have
a drink with me?
You know now, right?
About how much I love Seh-hee.
But I really can't understand her.
How could she do that?
Because I might dislike her...
how could she change the face
her parents gave her?
She must love you a lot.
But still, I can't understand her.
Doctor, you know how beautiful
Seh-hee was.
And natural.
You saw her real face.
I know of course.
That's why at first...
I showed her a dreadful surgery
on tape and tried to stop her.
You should have tried harder.
I'm sorry.
You think saying sorry
will fix everything now?
Is that your conscience?
Are you taking it out on me?
Why are you blaming me?
Think I did that for money?
What I mean is that...
how could you chop up
a person's face so easily?
Chop up?
Watch your mouth!
Whoever made her think
like that is to blame.
What, you bastard?
How could you tear up
a person's face?
Think a hospitalis
a butcher shop?
Was my Seh-hee a guinea pig?
Who the hell
do you think you are?
Want some surgery done
with my fist?
Hit me! Go ahead!
Son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch!
I'm a doctor!
I didn't buy my way
into this profession!
Watch your mouth, you bastard!
I can fix your face up so bad
no one can even recognize you.
Wanna see what chopping really is?
Crazy bastard.
Doctor, Doctor.
Please, wait, Doctor.
Please tell me what I can do.
What can I do?
Please tell me.
Ji-woo!
I thought I should let you know.
About a month has passed
after his surgery.
He's still probably recovering.
Ji-woo loves you very much.
He will show up before you
in five months with a different face.
Wait for him.
You've been taking
pictures of water.
Aren't you scared of me?
No, I'm not.
Wanna see an old picture of me?
No.
But I want to show you.
Then, can you show me?
I'm sorry.
I swear I had it before.
That's too bad.
I was a really handsome guy.
I hope you're happy.
If you want to see my new face,
come back here in five months.
Welcome.
May I sit here?
Aren't you curious about me?
- I am.
- About what?
About who you are.
Try to guess who I am.
Can I hold your hand?
My hand is warm, isn't it?
Your hand is too big.
Wait a sec.
Wait.
Who are you?
I must've gotten the wrong place.
I'm sorry.
Mind if I have a cup of coffee?
Come inside.
You took that picture at
the Sculpture Park, didn't you?
Yes, have you been there?
I took a picture of that sculpture
with my girlfriend before.
What's wrong?
I was thinking of old memories.
How does my hand feel?
Warm.
Feels like you're holding my hand?
Or your hand's being held by mine?
Being held by yours.
Do you think our palms
are touching or not?
Not touching.
Why?
You're testing something,
aren't you?
No, just because.
You look better in person.
Welcome.
May I sit here?
When was the last time you cried?
This morning.
Because of a man?
When was the last time you laughed?
It's been a long time.
Laugh for me.
Make a sound.
Louder.
How does my hand feel?
Feels like the right fit for my hand.
It's time to kiss now, right?
What was that?
Who's there?
There's too many weirdos around.
Wanna come to my place?
Come in.
Wash up first.
- Where are you going?
- Let me go!
Let me go!
I haven't finished washing up.
You can't go yet.
Let me go!
Didn't you come to my place
for a reason?
Why'd you change
your mind suddenly?
You're not the man I'm looking for.
Damn it.
What's going on today?
I've been waiting for a couple of days.
I thought you wouldn't come.
How are you?
Fine.
How about my new face?
I like it.
I'd like to show you
the pictures I've taken.
Wanna come to my studio?
Since when have you
taken pictures of me?
Since I've met you.
Are you offended?
Who are you?
Is it that important who I am?
Ji-woo?
Ji-woo.
I'm not Ji-woo.
My name is Jung-woo.
Get out of my way!
You crazy bitch!
Damn it.
You know me, right?
It's See-hee.
Who are you?
Don't you remember?
- You know her?
- No.
- Who is she then?
- She just sat here.
Then why'd she talk with you?
I said she just sat here.
Who is she?
I don't know.
She just sat here.
Where are you, Ji-woo?
Ji-woo, show yourself!
Stop it and show yourself.
Hey!
Jung Ji-woo!
Where are you?
I know you're watching me!
Where are you, Ji-woo?
Why are you doing this to me?
All I did was love you!
Ji-woo, Ji-woo!
Ji-woo...
Ji-woo.
Hello?
Is this 911?
There's been an accident!
Just come!
I'm at Madu.
Just come quickly!
I said Madu station!
Damn it, someone's been hit!
Just come!
Call the cop!
- He jumped in front of me.
- Okay.
Miss, do you know him?
He just jumped in front of me.
Seh-hee!
Why is there blood on you?
What's wrong, Seh-hee?
You look tired.
It was wrong from the start.
Want to be totally unrecognizable?
Please look ahead.
Don't move.
I'm on my way!
I'm sorry.
I'll fix it up for you.
Hold on.
Wait here one sec.
Come on in.
I'll prepare dinner first.
- Watch a DVD if you're bored.
- Okay.
Looks very delicious.
Wait a bit more.
- How is it?
- It's delicious.
That's great.
For a guy's place,
how come it's so clean?
Then is your place messy?
Yes.
I don't have much time to clean up.
Then I'll go and clean it for you.
Can you really?
Yes.
It's delicious.
I have to go.
Thanks for dinner.
Stay the night.
Next time.
Please stay, Seh-hee.
Seh-hee?
See-hee.
Good night.
See-hee!
I'll go and clean your place later.
Excuse me.
Have any old pictures of yourself?
I wanna see you as a kid.
I don't have any.
- Not even one?
- Yes, not even one.
That's strange.
Show it to me.
I bet it's an old photo.
No.
- Show it to me.
- No.
Can't you show it to me?
I wanna see it.
How was it?
It was new to me.
It's the first time
I've felt like this.
Thanks.
Thanks for what?
Just everything.
For all the time that's passed.
Do you love me?
I don't know yet.
I just feel very happy.
Why do you keep smiling?
Because I'm happy.
You're kind and a great guy.
Thanks.
But...
Tell me.
Did you love Seh-hee very much?
Yes.
Even now?
Why?
If Seh-hee comes back for you?
She won't come back.
What if she does?
That's what I want to.
Do I look happy?
But I'm sad strangely.
My heart is gonna boom up.
What the hell?
Did you just hit me?
Yes.
Why?
I love you.
Sorry, sleep again.
Don't hit me.
I'm gonna be angry.
To Dearest Ji-woo,
I tried to forget you but I couldn't,
I want to return to you,
Meet at the cafe on the 20th at two,
Seh-hee
Tell me.
What is it about?
Don't make me so curious.
Seh-hee is coming back.
So?
I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
Are you gonna meet her?
I was very lonely after she left me.
So you're meeting me
because you're lonely?
No, that's not true.
Do you still love her?
I think so.
I can't give you up, either.
- I'm sorry.
- No.
I'll meet her and stop her.
- You can't!
- You can't, either!
Who do you think I am?
Think I'm some slut
who comforts you with sex?
Watch your mouth!
- Tell me! What am I to you?
- Get out!
Forget when you sweated on me
like some crazy horse?
Am I a whore?
Stop it!
This is embarrassing.
Embarrassing?
You're embarrassed of me?
Hey! Hey!
Damn it.
What are you embarrassed of?
Who made me like this?
- Is this who you are?
- Yeah!
This is me!
Kill me first before you go to her!
I really mistook you.
You...
You son of a bitch!
You filthy son of a bitch!
Go! Go!
The number you are calling
is not in service,
- So what do you want?
- We're not right for each other.
I thought you were
crazy about me, fuck.
Why do you always curse?
- I hate that.
- I'm sorry, shit.
How have you been?
I missed you so much.
What is this?
It was you on that island?
I wanted to see you somehow.
How could you do that?
What kind of crazy act is this?
I was scared of time.
- Time that makes everything change.
- So what the hell is this?
Were you happy playing with me?
Then what the hell am I?
What am I?
I believed if I'd changed my face
you'd love me longer.
But you couldn't forget...
your girl of the past.
And I couldn't stand
being so jealous.
That doesn't make sense.
Both of them are you!
No.
I'm not your woman of the past.
I'm a new woman.
You're crazy!
Who are you?
Damn it.
Think this place is
some theatrical stage?
What's with the mask?
And stop being so damn loud.
Haven't you heard of manners?
Think this place is your home?
What the hell is this?
Why'd you fix your face?
Are you crazy?
I was too nervous.
I thought you'd get sick of me
and find a new woman.
Think I'm some meathead
who chases after women's bodies?
I love you.
You're scary.
You're really scary.
Don't be like this.
Just take off my mask
and see my new face.
No.
You're crazy!
You got a problem?
Let's take it outside.
Fucking bastard.
Min-soo.
Get up, asshole!
Min-soo, stop it.
Let's just leave.
Welcome...
Hello, Seh-hee.
Hello.
Your face looks natural now.
Is there anything uncomfortable?
No.
I was just passing by.
Do you wanna go back
to your real self?
Doctor!
Do you wanna try it?
- How do you feel?
- I feel great.
Do you know her?
Doctor, can you have
a drink with me?
You know now, right?
About how much I love Seh-hee.
But I really can't understand her.
How could she do that?
Because I might dislike her...
how could she change the face
her parents gave her?
She must love you a lot.
But still, I can't understand her.
Doctor, you know how beautiful
Seh-hee was.
And natural.
You saw her real face.
I know of course.
That's why at first...
I showed her a dreadful surgery
on tape and tried to stop her.
You should have tried harder.
I'm sorry.
You think saying sorry
will fix everything now?
Is that your conscience?
Are you taking it out on me?
Why are you blaming me?
Think I did that for money?
What I mean is that...
how could you chop up
a person's face so easily?
Chop up?
Watch your mouth!
Whoever made her think
like that is to blame.
What, you bastard?
How could you tear up
a person's face?
Think a hospitalis
a butcher shop?
Was my Seh-hee a guinea pig?
Who the hell
do you think you are?
Want some surgery done
with my fist?
Hit me! Go ahead!
Son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch!
I'm a doctor!
I didn't buy my way
into this profession!
Watch your mouth, you bastard!
I can fix your face up so bad
no one can even recognize you.
Wanna see what chopping really is?
Crazy bastard.
Doctor, Doctor.
Please, wait, Doctor.
Please tell me what I can do.
What can I do?
Please tell me.
Ji-woo!
I thought I should let you know.
About a month has passed
after his surgery.
He's still probably recovering.
Ji-woo loves you very much.
He will show up before you
in five months with a different face.
Wait for him.
You've been taking
pictures of water.
Aren't you scared of me?
No, I'm not.
Wanna see an old picture of me?
No.
But I want to show you.
Then, can you show me?
I'm sorry.
I swear I had it before.
That's too bad.
I was a really handsome guy.
I hope you're happy.
If you want to see my new face,
come back here in five months.
Welcome.
May I sit here?
Aren't you curious about me?
- I am.
- About what?
About who you are.
Try to guess who I am.
Can I hold your hand?
My hand is warm, isn't it?
Your hand is too big.
Wait a sec.
Wait.
Who are you?
I must've gotten the wrong place.
I'm sorry.
Mind if I have a cup of coffee?
Come inside.
You took that picture at
the Sculpture Park, didn't you?
Yes, have you been there?
I took a picture of that sculpture
with my girlfriend before.
What's wrong?
I was thinking of old memories.
How does my hand feel?
Warm.
Feels like you're holding my hand?
Or your hand's being held by mine?
Being held by yours.
Do you think our palms
are touching or not?
Not touching.
Why?
You're testing something,
aren't you?
No, just because.
You look better in person.
Welcome.
May I sit here?
When was the last time you cried?
This morning.
Because of a man?
When was the last time you laughed?
It's been a long time.
Laugh for me.
Make a sound.
Louder.
How does my hand feel?
Feels like the right fit for my hand.
It's time to kiss now, right?
What was that?
Who's there?
There's too many weirdos around.
Wanna come to my place?
Come in.
Wash up first.
- Where are you going?
- Let me go!
Let me go!
I haven't finished washing up.
You can't go yet.
Let me go!
Didn't you come to my place
for a reason?
Why'd you change
your mind suddenly?
You're not the man I'm looking for.
Damn it.
What's going on today?
I've been waiting for a couple of days.
I thought you wouldn't come.
How are you?
Fine.
How about my new face?
I like it.
I'd like to show you
the pictures I've taken.
Wanna come to my studio?
Since when have you
taken pictures of me?
Since I've met you.
Are you offended?
Who are you?
Is it that important who I am?
Ji-woo?
Ji-woo.
I'm not Ji-woo.
My name is Jung-woo.
Get out of my way!
You crazy bitch!
Damn it.
You know me, right?
It's See-hee.
Who are you?
Don't you remember?
- You know her?
- No.
- Who is she then?
- She just sat here.
Then why'd she talk with you?
I said she just sat here.
Who is she?
I don't know.
She just sat here.
Where are you, Ji-woo?
Ji-woo, show yourself!
Stop it and show yourself.
Hey!
Jung Ji-woo!
Where are you?
I know you're watching me!
Where are you, Ji-woo?
Why are you doing this to me?
All I did was love you!
Ji-woo, Ji-woo!
Ji-woo...
Ji-woo.
Hello?
Is this 911?
There's been an accident!
Just come!
I'm at Madu.
Just come quickly!
I said Madu station!
Damn it, someone's been hit!
Just come!
Call the cop!
- He jumped in front of me.
- Okay.
Miss, do you know him?
He just jumped in front of me.
Seh-hee!
Why is there blood on you?
What's wrong, Seh-hee?
You look tired.
It was wrong from the start.
Want to be totally unrecognizable?
Please look ahead.
Don't move.
I'm on my way!
I'm sorry.
I'll fix it up for you.
Hold on.
Wait here one sec.