What is she drawing?
What are you drawing, Celestine?
A bear.
And what's that?
This is a mouse.
And this is her friend.
That's all wrong.
- No, it isn't.
- Yes, it is.
- No!
- Yes!
A bear and a mouse
can't be together.
Alright, what story
shall I tell you tonight?
The Big Bad Bear?
Yes, the Big Bad Bear!
In the winter, the Big Bad Bear...
sleeps.
And when he awakens?
When he awakens, he is hungry.
Right. And what's he hungry for?
Just about anything.
Absolutely anything!
Tires, lamps, bicycles,
cars, houses...
When he's hungry he will
scarf down, um, sorry,
he will eat absolutely anything.
But among all these things,
what does the Big Bad
Bear like the most?
A little mouse.
A little mouse?
Just one little mouse?
Ten.
One hundred,
one thousand little mice.
Baked! Skewered!
Sautéed!
Broth stewed! And even raw!
Raw?
Especially raw!
Alive and kicking with their
little coats and backpacks.
That's how he prefers them!
All raw! And all alive!
How can you be sure he is so bad?
Do you know the story about
the little mouse who did not
believe in the Big Bad Bear?
Everyone told her:
"Beware of the Big Bad Bear!"
But she thought she
was being clever,
that bloody... no,
that stinky little rat...
sorry, that nasty...
no, that cheeky little... brat!
She didn't believe
in the Big Bad Bear.
She would say "no, the Big Bad Bear
is just a story the Grey
One used to tell us
while endlessly sipping
her chamomile tea."
But she was wrong
because one fine day...
Did you do this, Celestine?
Believe me, children,
only in fairy tales can
bears be friends with mice
and should you ever...
- What's she saying?
- I have no idea.
- What did you say?
- I said I don't know.
- Hush, I am listening.
- You actually grasp something?
Absolutely.
You never do.
- You mean I don't grasp anything?
- You think you do but you don't.
Say that again!
Even when we all do, you don't.
Silence!
I'm hungry.
Nice little birdy. Come here,
my sweet little birdy!
Get back here,
you evil little beast!
The King of Candy
Is it safe, can we go?
Wait.
Let's go.
Look, Lucienne, look!
Leon has lost his first tooth.
Poor sweetheart.
And no trace of decay.
A shiny little pearl.
Don't cry, sweetie, it's alright.
I'll put it on the nightstand
and the little mouse will come.
The little mouse?
What little mouse?
The little tooth fairy mouse.
She comes by when you're asleep
and replaces your tooth
with a shiny coin.
What kind of coin?
A big coin. Your very
first business deal.
The base of your capital,
if, that is, you make
the proper investments.
But I've never heard of
that fairy mouse before.
Because you've never
lost a tooth before.
Gibberish!
If it's a fairy mouse,
then it can't be real.
Really? Then how do
the teeth disappear?
Well, um...
Go to sleep now. That way, the
mouse can come and replace
- your tooth with a shiny coin.
- How much?
Um, a quarter?
Two quarters.
That's my boy.
Time to sleep!
- A mouse!
- Yes!
A mouse? Where?
Behind the Teddy bears.
No way! Get out of here!
Get it, Daddy!
Out! We want no mice here.
George, do something!
Get it out of here!
- Where is it?
- It's there.
Out of there!
Get out, you nasty beast!
There it is. I see it.
My tooth. What about my coin?
Give me my coin!
Filthy creature.
Not so loud, George,
the kid is sleeping.
The garbage!
Ernest's my name and
singing's my game
But not for much longer
cuz I'm dying of honger
I'm so hungry, I could eat a horse
I haven't had a bite
for many a night
I've lost so much weight
I can't get a date
My pants are falling off my loins
Drop me a few coins
Toss some cash in my hat
Give my belly some fat
Ernest's my name and
singing's my game
No need to order A la Carte
Just drop some bread in my cart
Just one little baguette
As much as you can get
You would feel so much better
And so would I
Ernest's my name and
singing's my game
I'm feeling so light,
cuz I need a bite
That waffle's a masterpiece
So warm and ever so sweet
Mayday, mayday, it's getting away!
C'mon, please, make my day
By throwing me some money
Come!
Please be as charitable
Put a meal on my table
if you help me out
You won't think you're a lout
Beans, sausage, apple cake
I swear I'm not a fake
C'mon, please help me out
Before the cops kick me out
Got 5 days to pay.
I'm hungry!
Don't eat me! Don't eat me!
But I am hungry.
What's your name?
Ernest.
I am Celestine.
We need to talk. You cannot eat me.
Bears only eat mice in storybooks.
You're not a gullible bear cub.
But I'm hungry.
Do you think a little mouse
like me will fill you up?
Look at me, I'm all skin and bone.
Besides, eating out of
garbage bins is unhealthy.
They are full of diseases: the
flu, typhus, hepatitis, cholera...
Do you want to catch
a deadly disease?
- Well, no, Celestine, but...
- Let me see.
Snout, cold and wet.
Eyes, waxy. Fur, dull.
Let's see the ears.
How about the teeth?
Scary!
What? Am I ill?
No, but it won't be long now.
Listen, Ernest. I know a place
where you can eat only
what's good for you.
Like marshmallows?
Marshmallows, pinwheels,
nougats, chocolate,
almond paste, ok?
Ok!
Just here.
Help yourself, Ernest.
Wait.
There you go. Enjoy!
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Watch out!
Dental floss here!
It's dainty and it's dental!
C'mon, look alive!
My fondue's nice and hot,
Come and get a taste!
Don't let it go to waste!
Watch your step!
Sorry, M'am, I'm in a hurry.
It hasn't started yet.
They told us to wait here.
It smells like garbage here?
Let's hurry now! Or the
Big Bad Bear will come
and eat you raw.
Follow me now. Do you hear?
How many teeth did you collect?
Seven.
Is that all? I've got twelve.
Twelve!
I usually do better, that's
far from my best score.
How about you, Celestine?
How many do you have?
Me?
Stop! Stay where you are.
Now that's gonna hurt.
Here you go, twelve teeth.
Fine.
But I can do even better.
C'mon, next.
Only seven?
But six incisors. And
check out the quality.
I'll take one. This
one's too short.
Thank you.
Let's try this one.
Repeat after me "the Big Bad Bear
is walking above our heads."
"Fe Fig Fad Fear iv
walkik abow our headths."
Not quite there.
And now?
"Fe Fig Fad Fear is
walking above our heads."
Allow me.
Try now.
Stop!
Go on, now, "the Big Bad Bear...
"The Big Bad Bear is
walking above our heads."
There we go. It's all in the wrist.
The wrist.
What? All night long
and only one tooth?
I got stuck in a garbage bin.
Really? And how did you get out?
Actually, a bear...
A what?
No, nothing.
And would you mind telling
us what's in your bag?
So this is how you've been
spending your internship?
You're drawing,
instead of gathering teeth?
You're not going to become
a dentist that way.
I don't want to...
to become a dentist.
I see what it is.
You are behind by 50 teeth.
You've lost too many points.
Looks like you need
some motivation.
Come with me.
You see, Celestine,
we rodents, we are not bears.
Our strength is not our body mass
our muscles, our claws,
our terrifying jaws.
We are delicate creatures.
We are subtle, refined.
Our entire civilization,
our achievements
over the centuries,
what do we owe it all to?
To what?
To what do we owe it all?
Our what?
- Our incisors.
- Our incisors, exactly!
The building blocks of our society.
Thanks to them
we built the greatest cities.
Gnawed away at the hardest stone.
Built the most complex machines.
Rerouted the largest
rivers in the world.
And all this thanks to our cute,
our precious,
our delicate, our invaluable,
our perfect, our cutting incisors.
But what happens if a mouse should
lose one of their incisors?
They die.
They agonise in abominable pain.
They can no longer eat.
They die racked with hunger
and gnawed by the utmost solitude.
Let's take it from the top.
Which is the best replacement
tooth for a mouse?
- A bear's tooth.
- That's right.
They happen to have
the most solid teeth.
And the easiest ones to find are
under the pillows of bear cubs.
So Celestine...
you're going back up there
and get some more teeth
from those little morons.
And I do not want to
see you back down here
until you have collected
fifty teeth.
Fifty teeth, Celestine!
Good luck, Celestine.
Are you coming, already?
I'm coming!
Hello, kids! Everyone
alright today?
I'd like a cream puff.
Coming right up.
I'd like a bag of candy.
5 lollipops and some marshmallows.
Me too, marshmallows!
Some candy sticks.
One lemon ice cream, Dad.
Yes, one lemon ice cream!
Wait a minute!
Come this way.
No sweets, I've warned you already.
Never!
But Dad...
You are forbidden the
slightest piece of sugar.
Do you want your teeth to fall off?
End up across the street,
at your mom's shop
with rotten teeth?
Go on, now.
We'll talk about it tonight.
Mister Ranconnet, hello!
How are we doing today?
Fine, fine.
I need a tooth so I
can eat my nougat.
What can I get you? An incisor?
- A canine?
- No, I need a pre-molar.
Let me see.
Here we are!
I have just the model you need.
A pre-molar. Premium quality.
Try it out!
It is perfect. I'll take it.
- Here you go, my sweetie.
- Thank you.
And what can I get for you, honey?
Some candy sticks?
Cotton candy?
Multi-coloured bonbons?
Just some marshmallows.
Marshmallows. Yes, of course!
I'm all out.
Don't cry! I've got some
in the storage room.
Don't move, I'll be right back.
What the devil are you
doing here? You thief!
He's breaking everything.
Get back here! I am
calling the police.
Ernest?
- My marshmallows!
- They're my marshmallows!
Police!
He's stolen all my sweets.
Over here! This is him, right here.
What's going on here?
Wait, is that Ernest?
This morning you were making
noise and now you're robbing?
How did you get in there?
Well, a little mouse that, um...
A little what?
I was hungry and it smelled good.
We're taking him in.
- Get in there!
- Give me back my marshmallows!
Let go of me, you thief!
My marshmallows.
There's no respect for the
honest working folks.
Want me to...
to set you free, Ernest?
If I do,
would you do me a little favour?
A big favour. If I free
you, will you do it?
A huge favour, Ernest. If I
free you, will you do it?
The biggest favour in the world?
Yes! The biggest
favour in the world.
Some more green peas, sweetheart?
No, I want candy.
Come on, don't you
start this again.
We told you, you are not
allowed to eat candy.
But why?
Because of the laws of business.
Dad spoils teeth on one
side on the street
and mom replaces them
on the other side.
And one day both
shops will be yours.
Which means you'll be doubly rich.
As long as you smile to
the customers, of course.
And as my old man used to say
"a beautiful smile comes
from healthy teeth."
it's simple, Leon...
Wealth will come from your
fellow bears' rotten teeth.
Do you understand?
Yes.
I'm up early tomorrow
so let's all go to bed.
I must replace
everything Ernest ate.
None of that would ever
happen in my store.
Who would ever think
to steal teeth?
Over here, Ernest. Hurry up!
Here we are.
Fine.
Easy now! You're
making too much noise.
Stop it! You're going
to wake everybody up.
There we go.
Ernest! Wait!
Where are the teeth?
Probably stored in a safe.
That thing, over there?
Yes. I'll go and pick the lock.
Let me handle this.
Handle it? But how are you...
Ernest, no!
No, that's not how
you're supposed...
Ernest, stop that right now!
It's open.
Are you insane?
What, you wanted it open.
That is too heavy for me.
I'm so tired!
C'mon, you promised.
And then we're even, right?
We're even.
I'll check if the coast is clear.
It is clear, you can...
Ernest, wait!
Bears go to bed early.
Especially in the wintertime.
I forbade you to show
up until you had...
This is unbelievable.
It's fabulous!
Look at this! How did you...
Bravo, Celestine!
I am so proud of you.
Hurray for Celestine!
The Big Bad Bear!
Celestine, do you
know this... this...
Did you bring him here?
The one who didn't believe
in the Big Bad Bear!
We all warned her
"beware of the Big..."
Run or he'll devour us all!
This way, Ernest!
Hurry!
C'mon, let's jump!
He's over there.
No Ernest, this way!
Pardon me! Sorry!
The exit is through
that tunnel over there.
He's over there.
Go left, Ernest!
I don't understand.
I had everything locked up.
It's a disaster.
Look!
A disaster! I'm sure
it was locked up.
A mouse! In the van!
Ernest?
Stop it right there!
Now how do we catch them?
You blew it!
Why did you stay down there?
You've gone insane?
I dozed off. Not my fault.
Not mine either.
It is! You brought me down.
I could not carry my bag.
You should've shown me the exit.
You said you'd find it.
Did I say that? Really?
Ernest, give yourself
up, you won't get away!
We've got him.
Now pull over!
Ok! If you insist.
We're not letting you go.
Watch out for the lamp-post.
Turn yourself in, we'll
never let you go.
So long, boys. Taking a right.
National Police United we fight
This is it.
So long, Celestine.
What do you mean?
Well, I'm home.
What about me?
You? I don't know.
I've made it to my home,
you go back to yours.
I no longer have a home.
They've banished me.
Even cursed me.
Celestine, now we're even.
You said it yourself.
You set me free
and I did you the biggest
favour in the world.
So now, we're even.
Even, even... But the situation
has changed, Ernest.
Mice are not allowed in a house.
Please, listen to me.
No mice in a house, ever.
You take one in, 1000
more will follow.
You all are like that.
Ask any bear.
Scram!
But, Ernest...
I said not a mouse in a house.
Never!
You have to realize that
things have changed.
No mouse in a house!
- But...
- No buts!
- No way!
- Come on!
No mouse
in my house!
Scram!
Thank you.
You can't get rid of
a mouse. Ask any bear.
Unless you kill it, of course.
Your chocolate's burning.
Want to kill me, Ernest?
Forget the broom, I'm too quick.
You can try the mouse trap.
Not easy either. We mice all
know that old trick by now.
There's also poison or glue traps.
Glue boards are cruel.
The poor little mouse gets
stuck as it steps on it.
It tries so hard to get off
that its heart blows up.
You want my heart to
blow up, is that it?
Of course not, Celestine. But a
bear and a mouse, it's just not...
Not what? Not seemly? Not proper?
Bears up above and mice down below?
Well, yes... it's
always been like this.
Alright. Do you have a cellar?
Well, yeah, I...
So, I'll go down
and you stay up here.
No buts. So long!
And you better stay upstairs.
No, you stay downstairs! I don't
want to see you or hear you.
My chocolate!
There she is!
The one who did not believe
in the Big Bad Bear.
Everyone said to her
"beware of the Big Bad Bear!"
it's just a nightmare.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I'm not your nightmare.
It's me, Ernest.
Ernest, I am damned.
Damned? What nonsense is this?
But I am! I'm all
alone in this world.
Nobody loves me and I have no home.
And what about me? Am I loved?
Did you make this?
It is fabulous!
Exactly what I look like.
If you can do this you can't be
alone. You're a great artist.
But that's just why I am so alone.
They hate my drawings.
They want me to be a dentist.
I hear you. I wanted
to be on stage,
become a musician, tell stories.
But they wanted me
to become a judge.
Like my father, my
grandfather, my great uncle...
"Go play your music and tell
your stories elsewhere!"
"You'd be better off
studying your law books."
Look.
"No, Celestine!
"You are staying downstairs!"
"I don't want to hear or see you!"
Isn't this a nice portrait?
Take your drawing equipment
and follow me.
We're going to make you a studio.
A real fine arts studio.
This will be my first
real painting.
What will you paint?
The Big Bad Bear. What else?
There.
Look ferocious!
There you go.
Lift your leg.
Perfect.
Stay still.
Keep looking ferocious.
- Can I see?
- I told you not to move!
Are you ill?
It's just a cold.
Into bed, right away!
When you have fever, you
must drink lots of liquids.
Leave me alone!
I don't want to. Help!
Ernest, calm down.
I am not your nightmare.
I am Celestine.
Any marshmallows left?
Of course.
Don't eat them all, ok?
Of course not.
Promise?
Cross my heart.
Good night, Ernest.
Guess what? I'm cured.
Check it out.
Bet you can't do it with 4.
Do you really?
Let's do it again!
Come on!
After the Court's decision,
there is a warrant out
for the arrest of the burglars...
Are we the burglars?
And their arrest is imminent.
A matter of days.
They've already forgotten about us.
We will take no rest until we've
found Ernest and Celestine.
We'll chase them out
of their hideaway.
However long it takes,
months if necessary
but we will find them
sooner or later.
Their crimes cannot go unpunished.
They will be captured
and brought to justice.
Ernest will be judged in due form.
Celestine will be punished.
The Court is already
aware of the case.
As for Celestine, the
punishment will fit the crime.
Ernest will be tried with severity.
The sentence shall be irrevocable
for Ernest and Celestine.
Did you call me?
No, Celestine. Everything's fine.
Everything's fine.
You've made so much progress.
I'm sick and tired of
drawing the Big Bad Bear.
Really?
Do you know of a more
interesting subject?
I'd like to paint a
winter landscape.
You'll have to wait for spring.
We bears know all about
that, waiting for spring.
The snow will be gone.
Oh, you want to paint snow.
Celestine wants to paint the snow.
Now, the artist gets to work!
Thank you, Ernest.
May I introduce to you...
the Winter!
With music, it would sound
something like this.
And one and two...
Ernest, the van!
What, the van?
It's like a big red spot.
They could find us because of it.
There's only one solution.
Come see these creatures!
I've seen them already.
Do you want to see them close up?
I can see them just fine.
Come on, let's go!
The search... active...
we will not rest...
until the burglars, Ernest and
Celestine have been arrested.
Suit yourselves!
This is a call to witness.
Any person who might...
Don't worry, Celestine.
They'll never find us.
The police are still looking
for the two criminals...
and will not rest
until they are found.
- What was that?
- The little fairy mouse?
George, go see what's happened.
My van!
My shop!
What the...?
Is this paint?
Ernest!
Lucienne! Call the police!
I know where Ernest is.
Nice and sunny morning.
Mr. Big Bad Bear is
terribly grumpy.
Mr. Big Bad Bear doesn't
want to wake up.
Is the Big Bad Bear
going to devour me?
Good idea. Then I could sleep.
In that case, we shall give
him a hearty breakfast
so that I can live
to see another day.
That is yummy.
How can you sleep in
on such a sunny day?
Ernest, come look!
We have to hide you in the cellar.
We've got to hide
you too, Celestine.
Relax, I have a plan.
A plan?
Are you sure about this?
Don't worry, Ernest.
In here! He's here!
Where is Ernest?
Uncle Ernest? He's gone to
town to fetch some honey.
He said he'd be back tomorrow.
For the last time, Celestine...
Where is Ernest?
Very well.
You know what to expect.
For the last time, Ernest...
Where is Celestine?
Alright. You know what to expect.
Heave Ho!
Now let go!
Read all about horrible
Ernest's trial.
Buy Mouse Weekly!
Read all about the bear
and mouse scandal.
Over there! It's him, look!
The trial will now begin.
The accused may enter.
Is that Celestine?
Accused, please stand
and state your name.
Can you tell us where Ernest
the bear can be found?
You refuse to tell us where
Celestine can be found?
In that case you will
be charged twice.
The first for your crimes.
The second for her crimes.
What has she done wrong?
Nothing at all!
Nothing at all?
Bringing a ferocious bear into our
midst, you call that nothing?
He was dying of hunger. You
want the poor to die of hunger?
As fat as all of you are!
I had to carry her
heavy bag for her.
Silence!
She doesn't want to be a dentist.
You and your accomplice Celestine
are accused of a number
of heinous crimes.
Breaking and entering, possession
of stolen goods, auto theft.
Escaping, shipwrecking,
bodily injury.
There are countless witnesses.
Witnesses are countless!
But most of all Ernest,
you are accused of a
most hideous crime...
you frighten children.
Me? Children, do I frighten you?
Me? I frighten mothers?
Madame, do I frighten you?
No, um...
A mouse! Over there!
And now, we will hear
from the defense.
Ladies and gentlemen of
the jury, Your Honour,
what is my client being accused of?
Of being a bear?
I am here to defend my client...
- What did he say?
- No idea.
- What did you say?
- I said I have no idea.
Hush, we're listening.
- Do you grasp something?
- Absolutely.
Liar, you don't.
Order in the court!
Stop this at once!
Celestine, in the light
of the accusations...
Nonsense!
You are accusing me
of living with a bear.
How dare you?
All of you are prejudiced!
Yes, Celestine is my friend.
This is what you are
holding against me.
"The mice below,
the bears above"...
Is that your idea of raising kids?
In the fear of mice?
Want them to be idiots?
Silence, Celestine!
You're the accused, not the lawyer.
Order or I'll clear the room!
Clear the room!
The trial is not over.
Come back!
Celestine, listen to me!
Nobody questions the
foundations of our society.
Least of all a mouse!
Please listen, Your Honour!
Silence!
Sit back down!
Wait, we must help him.
He'll make it by himself.
Get your paws off me!
Back to your box!
That's an order!
But you're on fire.
That's enough!
Take your seat!
I will not repeat myself.
Get down from there.
Get back down, I say.
I will not tolerate this attitude.
Let go of me!
Let go of me this instant!
Your Honour!
Come quickly!
We have to get out.
What are you doing? Let me go!
Where is everybody?
They ran for their lives.
Come, now.
They all abandoned me.
But you did not.
Come on now, let's go.
Tell me, if we get
out of here alive...
what would really make you happy?
Finding Ernest and
living with him forever.
Alright.
But still, wanting to live with
a bear, what a weird idea!
Why, you live with
a bear, don't you?
Oh yes, I do.
Precisely, that's a weird idea.
Are you ok, Your Honor?
What happened?
You caught fire, Sir.
You saved my life.
How can I ever thank you?
- That's no big deal.
- It is a big deal!
What would really make you happy?
- Right now?
- Of course.
Finding Celestine and
living with her forever.
You are a free bear.
She saved my life.
No, Ernest.
- Yes.
- No.
Yes.
No, it is not possible.
Yes it is.
We cannot tell our story.
It is too sad.
We met in a garbage bin
and you wanted to eat me.
- I was just joking.
- It just wasn't funny.
The world must not know.
We'll just embellish.
Imagine you were a tiny thing,
abandoned and lying in that bin...
A baby. Your eyes were
not even open yet.
Now draw it.
I was a street sweeper,
sweeping up dead leaves. You see?
And that's when I
heard a faint noise.
Was it me?
It was you.
And then what did you do?
Well, I took you out of the bin
then I put you in my pocket.
And then I took you home.
And then?
Then I took care of you.
You seemed happy
so I decided to keep you.
You found your place and we
ended up living together.
That's how we met.
After this one, can we
tell other stories?
Plenty of other stories, Celestine.
Subtitles: Jean-Marc Pannetier
Subtitling: Luis-subs, Ecuador :P