Although this film was inspired by
actual events that took place in Tokyo,
the details and characters portrayed
in this film are entirely fictional
NOBODY KNOWS
Hello
We've just moved into #203
We're the Fukushimas
I wanted to meet the landlord
It's just a token gift
Thank you for taking the trouble
It's very nice to meet you
Um, my husband's abroad,
you see,
so really, it's just the two of us
I hope you'll look out for us
Oh, I see
Don't hesitate to ask
Thank you very much
Introduce yourself
I'm Fukushima Akira
I see, are you in Jr. High?
I'm in sixth grade
You're so big
Once you get to this age,
it's fine, but little ones,
we, other tenants tend
to complain about them
Oh, he's very mature
He'll be no trouble
Fortunately, he takes after his father,
and he's a really good student
But now that he's in sixth grade,
he's ready to learn English...
Mother
Hold on
Shh!
In the back room, please
The living room?
Yes
You just know
that landlord remarked
His first wife.
I bet you his first wife died,
and he went and married again
Just hold on, Shigeru
What is this!
Just hold on
Here goes
You OK? Was it hot?
It's hot
Wow, you did a great job
It was hot
This is your new home
Just hold on, Shigeru
Shall we let Shigeru out...
I'll let you out
Here comes the noisy boy
Was it hot?
Super hot
You did a great job
We're here
OK!
A huge success
What floor is this?
Our new home is
on the second floor
Apartment 203
Get back inside, Shigeru
What if they see you?
We'll have to move all over again
Get inside
Get in here!
Hey, Akira
Get back inside
Shigeru, you've got to
unpack your own toys
I'll go pick up Kyoko
at the station
Be careful, off you go
You know the way?
I know
I'm off
OK, off you go, then
Did you wait?
You're late
I'm sorry
Is the apartment big?
Yeah, it's three rooms
Pretty big
The washing machine?
On the veranda
The veranda, huh?
Kyoko!
We're home
I think I know how
to make the soup
I know how to make the soup
OK, then, you make it
Such big chopsticks!
Oh, I'll eat with these
Yeah! My favorite
Tasty?
May I have everyone's attention?
Now that we've moved
into a new home,
I'm going to explain the rules to you,
one more time
Let's promise to keep them, OK?
How many are there?
OK, first of all,
no loud voices or screaming
Can you do that?
I can
Next, no going outside
I know
Can you do that?
Not even out on the veranda
OK? Can you keep that promise?
Sure!
Can you do it,little Shige-monster?
You're the one that
has to promise hardest
Absolutely no going outside
Can you do that?
Bet you can-can
He didn't raise his hand
That's right,
remember our old home,
we had to leave because
you always threw such tantrums
So, now that we've found
a nice new home,
you've got to promise
Can you?
How's Kyoko supposed
to do the laundry?
For the laundry,
there's no choice, but for Kyoko
to sneak out quietly for the laundry
Don't go out with her Shigeru
And Akira,
you already know all this,
but Mom's sometimes late,
so you'll be in charge
That's OK, right?
And study a lot
You really have to get it, Shigeru
Do you get it?
If you don't...
it's an enema for you!
Not an enema, green peppers
Green peppers?
Why!
Make him eat peppers
Oh, that's it, then
We'll give Shigeru "The Pepper
Punishment," got that?
Next time you're up for a tantrum,
get in the suitcase
Shut up!
Like I...
That's the time to climb in
That's right, that's right
What a great idea
Put him there when he's noisy, OK?
We'll all put him in
Mother
These tatami mats smell good
The tatami?
What do they smell like?
Like leaves in nature
That's a nice smell, isn't it?
The tatami are still new,
they're still green
Make you sleep well?
Good night
Will you be late?
Today? Let's see...
What's today?
Oh, I guess I might...
Maybe I'll be late
You want dinner?
Dinner... dinner...
What's for dinner tonight?
Maybe curry
Curry? I want curry!
Save me some curry
Please
Maybe I'll eat it
Off you go
Hey, did Mom leave already?
She just left
Dangerous
The piano...
I'm going shopping
Off you go
Get me an "Apollo Choco"
Sure
150 yen
Shall I buy persimmons...
No "Apollo Choco"
There's a video arcade...
"Inageya Hardwares store"
"Near and far-sighted..."
Found it
Apollo Choco
No bag, right?
Out of 100 Yen, then
Thank you very much
Save 'em for later...
You OK?
I'm fine
The bath's ready, brother
You can go first
OK
Are there carrots?
There are carrots
None for me
No, you have to eat them
Dinner's ready, Kyoko
OK
Shigeru left the carrots, again
Elementary Japanese
Look, Mother's home
Hey there, I'm back
Welcome home
It's damned cold out there
Warm in here
Weren't you in bed, yet?
I was hanging the laundry
What a good girl
Thank you
And what do we have here?
Can I have some?
Damn. It's cold
Welcome home
I'm home
Oops
Got it?
I can't
No way
It clicked but went out
All yours
Did I get this right?
What's this?
"A nation that flourished.
"in about 300 C.C."
What don't you understand?
Just wondered if I got it right
No, it should be "300 B.C."
When you don't know,
you look it up in here
That way, you'll learn
Wow, is this Shigeru's?
Wow, what's this?
This yours? Kyoko's?
I hate math...
Six times six is...
Six-six, six-six...
Hurry, six-six
I can do it
Six-six is thirty-six...
Hello, yes
It's noisy there, awful noisy
Where are you? Karaoke?
Not now, it's too late
What? Who's there?
Oh, really, what a shame...
And-a 2
And-a, and-a 3
Hey, oh no
And-a 1, hey
And-a 3
And-a, and-a 4
Wow!
Oh, me? And-a, and-a 2
Oh, no, I'm the loser who
has to go without dinner!
You won't get sleepy
If there's no lid on,
what could be inside?
You can't tell
See, if you close your eyes
and put it in,
if you put it in but you don't know...
Mother
I want to go to school
School?
You wouldn't have any fun at school
Besides, when you don't have a Daddy,
they bully you at school
You don't need to go to school
Wow, feels really great
Great smell, did you smell t?
Stinks of sunlight
Stink s of sunlight?
Stinkls of sunlight
What a beautiful day...
Your mother,
is in love with someone now
Again?
Not again
This guy's really
sweet and serious
I think he is really
looking out for me
So, if he promises to really...
to really marry me,
then we can all live in a big house
and you can all go to school
and Kyoko can play the piano...
So just hang on a little longer
I really think this time probably...
I'm home
Here we are, sushi
I'm home, meow
Were you asleep?
C'mon, c'mon guys,
the sushi was a present
A sushi present, c'mon, c'mon
You wake up?
You wake up? You mad?
C'mon over, come over,
c'mon over, Yuki
She stinks of booze
Aren't you cold?
Were you asleep? I'm sorry
It's just that your Mommy had
a pretty good time today
Here you are, Mom
Oh, thank you
Akira
Listen, Akira...
he's starting to look
just like his father
He's got his father's eyes, exactly
You brother's father...
used to work at Haneda
You know what Haneda is?
It's a place with lots of airplanes
You know, right Shigeru?
That's where he used to work
Oh, I know, listen, Akira
Remember going to see your father?
I don't
We took the Monorail to
get to Haneda Airport
You forget?
Yeah
Kyoko your father was...
a music producer...
I know! Let's give Kyoko's...
pretty hands a nice manicure
Your mother... actually...
wanted to be a singer
And I really made it...
part way
With your father, Kyoko
Oops, way too much
I was going to cut a record...
And we were almost ready
when the deal fell apart
Your mother really wanted to, but...
Dear Akira, Your mother's
going away for a little while
Please look after Kyoko,
Shigeru and Yuki
I'm going shopping
Sure, off you go, then
And also, mother won't be
coming back for a while
Why not?
Something to do with work, I think
I'm off
Off you go
Please enter your
deposit account...
The rent... electricity bill,
phone and gas...
And also...
tissues...
Let's go to my office
Do you always do this?
No, I don't
Your first time?
I didn't take anything
Then what's a this doing here?
Your name?
Fukushima Akira
Fukushima... Akira...
School?
Your father's name?
I don't have a father
No father?
Your mother. Then?
She's gone away to work
for a while
Where did she go?
If you won't tell me,
I'll have to call the police
Sir,
I don't think this boy stole that
I think the boys reading comics
over there put them in his bag
It wasn't him?
No, I don't think so
Why didn't you speak up?
I'm sorry
Don't "I'm sorry," me
This is just between us, OK?
The meat buns are a little bonus
Hurry, give it to him
Thank you very much
Is that a plus sign?
That's right
9,824 Yen
9,824 Yen?
I forgot to add this...
Hello
Isn't this your day off?
I'm driving again tonight
No use staying home
How's your Mom?
She hasn't been home in a month
For real?
How old are you, Akira?
I'm 12
And Yuki?
Yuki's fine
She takes after me?
Yes, she does
For real...
Akira!
Shit, I'm 10 Yen short
Lend me 10 Yen
What, 10 Yen?
Why make a big deal over 10 Yen?
What's with that damned big wallet?
It's a hand-me-down
from my mother
From who?
From my mother...
You moved, right?
The new place big?
Any pubic hair, yet?
No...
Liar, got mine in 5th grade
No way
That's the truth
It's just...
What are you smirking about?
It's just that since mother's gone,
It's just, there's no money
For real? I don't have any money
What've you got left?
About 10,000 Yen
10,000 Yen is enough
I'm in a helluva jam, myself
My girlfriend, you know,
she totally maxed out my credit cards
I'm in credit card hell, man
So I'm working my ass off,
slowly paying it down, man
This is all I've got on me
This is it, the last time
Thank you
A right, I'm off
By the way, Yuki's not my kid
Every time I did it with your mom,
I used a condom. Bye, then
Bye, then
Thanks for this
Bye
Oh, no, I'm hopeless
Gotta get it in
So cold...
I spent 674 Yen
at the supermark et
I have 650 Yen left in my wallet
How many Yen were in my wallet
to begin with?
Soon, I came across Bubu the Pig,
planting turnip seeds in a field
What a nice bag you have there
My mother made it for me
Where, where, where is it?
You can't go out, Shigeru
I'm not out
I'm home!
We come home
How've you guys been?
Hey, how've you guys been?
See, I'm home
Look, presents
This one's for Yuki
Thank you
For you, Shigeru
I'm home
Akira, Akira
Wow, it's been a while
Shall I open it for you?
You can carry it on your back
Wow!
It's cute
Carry it? Carry it?
Like a backpack
You can put your things inside,
and do that...
The sides? Your ears? Out?
Ears out?
You look so neat
He looks better with short hair
Which is more becoming, Yuk?
Long or...
Long
You I like him better with long hair?
Oh, no but I'll cut it anyway
A little bit shorter's OK, right?
What's that face for?
Don't tell me,
I cut your bangs too short
You're fine, right?
Too short?
I don't believe it
Anyway, it'll grow right back out
Don't act so cool
You look cute
I mean it
Here goes!
Maribo!
A chop! The pits!
Chop Maribo!
Maribo!
Hey, what are you doing?
Kyoko
What are you doing?
Don't touch my things
It's your fault
It won't come out...
Where were you, really, Mother?
I told you I was working
A whole month?
I was in Osaka
It was just too far
I told you not to touch my things
What are you doing?
What? You see, today,
your mother has to step out,
so I'm getting ready
You're going already?
Your mother's... busy today
But listen,
I'll be back for Christmas
Only 5,000 Yen?
He could've lent you a little more,
I mean, you're little kids in a jam
But hey, pachinko parlors and taxis,
I don't draw customers
in such hard times
But you go back to him
if you need to
It's cold
And the wind's blowing so hard
It's so cold...
Did you tell the man you're seeing
about us?
I told you, I'll tell him eventually...
Sugar
You've got sugar there
God, you're irritating
Listen, I keep ask ng you,
when will you let us go to school?
What's this "school this, school that"?
Who needs to go to school anyway?
Plenty of famous people never
even went to school in the first place
Like who?
How should I know
But plenty of them...
You're so selfish, mother
How can you say that?
Selfish? You want to know
who's really selfish?
Your father's the one who's selfish,
up and disappearing like that
What is this?
I'm not allowed to be happy?
Oh, I know someone famous
Prime Minister Tanaka
Ever heard of him?
Never
You're too young
How about...
the wrestler Antonio Inoki?
I bet he never went to school
I'm not sure, but...
Sure, he did
Man, you're a drag
Hurry up and finish eating
I send you money, soon
You'll come home for Christmas?
Sure, I'll come home
I'll be right home
You take care, of them, too
Is Totoro really real?
Don't you know how big Totoro is?
I know
I know, he's really big
It'd be a real mess if
he was walking around
The police would've catched him
Think there are UFOs?
Nope
If Martians exist, so do UFOs
Martians are...
What about real Zombies?
Scary Zombies
You think Santa Claus is real?
He is, he is
You think?
There's only one Santa, right?
He can't cover Japan
all by himself, can he?
But he can
Santa Claus can manage it
That's right, there are all kinds...
Mother didn't come back. Did she?
Her work kept her away longer
Because I was so mean to Mom?
No, that's not true
Hllo, this is the
Sanwa Department Store
May I speak to Fukushima Keiko
in Menswear?
Excuse me...
This is her son
Please hold a moment
I'm terribly sorry, but Ms. Fukushima
resigned last month
How may I help you?
How many minutes, Shigeru?
Not yet
Not yet... how many more minutes?
One more minute, maybe
Maybe?
Not ready yet?
It's about ready, I think
You think?
Let's eat. Then
Thanks for the food
Off you go, then
I have to lick the lid
Taste good?
Tastes good
The super-duper best
Excuse me, I'm looking
for a phone number
Kanagawa Prefecture,
Kawasaki City, Nakahara Ku...
Hello, this is the Yamamotos
Hello... Hello?
Wonder who this is
They aren't talking...
Good evening
Have a happy new year
Kyoko's next
With the "kyo" like in Tok yo
Akira
That's right...
Mom sent us all
New Year's presents
Look
For you, Yuki
Thank you
Shigeru
Kyoko
That's for you
Thanks
4,000 Yen!
4,000 Yen! No way
It's 2,000 Yen
1,000 Yen
4,000 Yen
What do you want, Yuki?
A doll
Shigeru?
Roller blades
Roller blades?
You, Kyoko?
I'm saving mine up for a piano
You, brother?
A baseball glove
No, I'm gonna meet
Mommy at the station
She's not coming home today
I'm sure she's coming home
She'll be back next week
She's really coming next week?
She really will
How do you know?
I just do
She's coming home next week
It's Yuki's birthday, today
These?
Yeah
Just hang on
OK, let's go
Good evening
Stepping out?
Where to?
To the station to meet my Mommy
I see, what's your name?
Yuki
Yuki, I see
How old are you, Yuki?
I'm 5
5 years old? I see
She's our cousin,
just staying overnight
Oh, I see...
Off you go, then
Off we go, then
Adorable little gir
Tomato, daikon, broccoli,
squash, carrot...
There's so many
Plates...
Cups...
The butcher's...
Oh, only one left?
The last one
There's the monorail
It goes to Haneda Airport
Someday let's get on
and go see the airplanes
Yeah, let's do that
Dear Kyoko
To Kyoko
No, no, it turns on
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, idiot
No, no, it's 1, 2, 3, 45, 6
No. I swear it's on 5
No, I swear it's 6
Listen, listen, man
You couldn't even do it on
that Kamehameha thing
Yes I could
Go! No, that's too far-ish
Oh, damn you did it
You're a genius, man
Using the brake?
No brake
Hey, wow, cool
You gotta crash it
That one already burned...
We come
Your friends?
Yeah, friends
That's 197 Yen
Get off, get off
Thanks
Let's go
Bye, then
Thank you
See you tomorrow
Bye, then
Please indicate the desired amount
- Excuse us
This one, huh?
Let's do it, let's do it
Are you ready?
Start!
All right, perfect, max
What!
Take that!
What a weird haircut
Coke and what?
Coke and orange and...
CC Lemon
I'm home
We bought stuff
You're late
How far'd you go?
Coke for me
Me, too
Hey, somebody attacked
Hey, you jerk, you let 'em in
But this person attacked
Your Gas Bill is Overdue
Get away, you jerk
OK, nice
Go away
Told you so, dammit
You'll never get it that way
Butt out
Let's go to the store, Akira
I'm hungry, treat us
Sure
Hey, I wanna go, too
No, you stay home
Don't touch the game
Don't touch it
What are you doing?
Hey, hey hey, isn't this great?
Her tits are huge
Great, huh?
Isn't it great?
You swipe it?
Your turn, Akira
We're friends, right? Go
Let's go
Hey, wait
He's not your type?
No way! He's way too passionate-like
I like a cool-like guy
But that's what's so cool
Been a while
How you been?
Yeah, fine
They're too big for me
They don't fit
Mom says I'll grow any way,
so take the big ones
I hate 'em
Hey
Been a while
How you been? What's up?
Bought a new game,
why don't you come over?
I'll come over
when I have time
See you 'round
I've got cram school, sorry
See ya
See ya, then
Who was that?
Take me along to play
Yeah, but his house stinks
No way, stinks of what?
Stinks of garbage
The place is a real mess
Like rotting?
Here she comes
To Mizuguchi Saki in Heaven
Got it
Hello, there, Fukushima san
Don't worry, he's gone
How old are you?
I'm 12
You can't start working part-time
until you're 16
Shouldn't you contact the police
or child welfare, or something?
If I do, the four of us won't
be able to stay together
That happened before
and it was an awful mess
I see...
You need it for your piano
It's OK
Let's race
Don't beat me, Akira
We come
Did your mother come back?
Who's taller?
We're the same
There are seeds here, too
Take them
I'll take these, too
OK, I'll take these
Look, Akira, seeds
Somebody just left them behind
Poor things
2, 3, 4, 5...
Amazing, for real
Paper, scissors, rock
F rst is rock
I can't stop
Akira, got dirt?
Got it
Shige!
Shigeru!
Shigeru
Hey, Shigeru
The bag
It came out funny
Yu...
ki...
I'll go get some water
Brother, the lights don't work
Not in the bathroom, either
Mr. String, Mr. String,
where are you?
What are you doing?
Not going to school?
No...
I'm not either
There's a cicada hole here,
did you know?
No, I didn't
And again
Pi-ne-ap-p-l-e
First is rock
Paper, scissors, rock
Ch-o-co-la-t-e
First is rock
Paper, scissors, rock
And again!
We have suspended
your water service
I got so many
Wow, amazing
What are you doing?
Nothing special
Did you catch cold?
Your voice sounds weird
Shut up
Are you washing your hair?
Yesterday, at the park
Nice and cool?
When's your mother coming back?
She's never coming back
Probably
I'm not hot
I'm hot
I said, I'm not hot, I'm not
Thank you
Eat the inari sushi first
Shigeru
No salmon?
No, just what's there
No fair
This was Shigeru's
It died
She fell asleep
Excuse me. The door was unlocked...
I'm the landlord from the 3rd floor,
here about the rent
Where's your mother?
She's working in Osaka
Are you cousins?
I'll go make some money
What? How?
Here!
No
Why not?
Just sang karaoke with him
No!
What are you eating?
Spit it out
What is that?
Paper
That's 287 Yen
Exactly, thank you
How'd the semester go?
His report card, you mean?
A total disaster
He got a terrible grade in Japanese
My child did badly, too
Wish I could find something
Hey, where's Shigeru?
Dunno
What are you doing?
Where's Shigeru?
Dunno
Shige!
You said you wanted noodles
so I got some!
What do you want!
You watch it, buster
Don't bother coming home
Don't take it out on things
Did it break?
Amazing power
He's just an idiot
Cut it out, Yuki
I have to pee
Why didn't you pee
in the park, before?
Go pee by the bath
Don't want to
Is Saki coming back?
Shigeru! You can't just
use up all the water!
There's none left to drink
Is Saki coming to play again?
Never
What are you doing?
I'm selling these
Don't need 'em anymore
Stop it
Cut it out
Let go!
Shut up!
Move
Don't touch it!
She's never coming back
Who cares! Stay in there!
Idiot!
Miyauchi!
Don't move your legs too much!
Kato! Where's Yano today?
Cram school
Cram schoo?
Oh, man, we're short
What year are you?
Akira, #9, right field
Line up!
We're starting a game between the
White Bears and the Kenzan Fighters
Let's go!
Bow
Akira, hold your hands closer,
like this...
When the ball comes,
take a real hard slice at it, wham
Just, wham, swing at it
That's fine, nice swing...
"A big, big,
homerun, homerun"
"In heaven...
Grandpa and grandma..."
Yuki
Yuki won't get up
Yuki!
She fell off the chair
Yes, hello?
Is Fukushima Keiko there?
Just a minute.
I'll go get her
Mommy
A big, big...
homerun...
In heaven...
Grandpa and grandma
So surprised...
A big... homerun...
In heaven...
Akira
What happened?
That money...
Can I borrow it?
I want to show Yuki...
the airplanes
You all off for a picnic?
Looks like fun
That' be 1,895 Yen
OK, thanks
Kyoko, what's this?
It just arrived
To Akira, give them my best
I'm counting on you, Mother
She doesn't fit
Guess Yuki... grew
Is it good bye?
When I touched Yuki
this morning...
she was so cold, it was awful
It just felt so...
It was just so...
When I ask the midnight sky
the stars just shine
Into the black lake of my
molten heart
I can only flow
Will the angel even give me
a backward glance?
Want to splash around in my heart?
The wlnds of the coming winter
lap at the waves
calllng me into the dark
Wlth eyes as wilted as ice
I'm growing up
A jewel pungent with a stench
that brooks no one's approach
Thanks
Found one!
YAGIRA Yuuya
KITAURA Ayu
KIMURA Hiei
SHIMIZU Momoko
KAN Hanae
YOU
KUSHIDA Kazumi
OKAMOTO Yukiko
TATE Takako
KASE Ryo
KIMURA Yuichi
ENDO Ken'ichi
TERAJIMA Susumu
HIRAIZUMI Sei
Executive Producers: SHIGENOBU
Yutaka KAWASHIRO Kazumi
Development Producer:
YASUDA Masahiro
Associate Development Producers:
KOBAYASHI Eitaro Lee Bong-Ou
Associate Producers:
URATANI Toshiro KOHNO Satoshi
Producer KORE-ED A Hirokazu
Line Producer: TAGUCHI Hijiri
Cinematography:
YAMAZAKI Yutaka
Sound:
TSURUMAKI Yutaka
Art Direction: ISOMI
Toshihiro MITSUMATSU Keiko
Casting:
ARAE Yoshiko
Chief Assistant Director:
KUMAGAI Kiichi
Production Manager:
SHIRAISHI Osamu
Stylist:
KOBAYASHI Miwako
Hair and Make-Up:
SAKAI Mutsuki
Still Photography:
KAWAUCHI Rink
Pubicity Design:
KASAI Kaoru
Music: GONTITI
Theme Song "A Jewel":
TATE Takako
Production Assistance:
TV MAN UNION, INC.
Produced by TV MAN UNION, INC. BANDAl VISUAL CO., LTD. ENGINE FILM, NC. C
- style Cine Qua Non
Directed, Written and Edited by
KORE-EDA Hirokazu
English subtitles: Linda Hoaglund
(c)NOBODY KNOWS Project Team