¶ Here comes the bride
¶ Fair, fat and wide
¶ Slips on a banana peel
and goes for a ride
¶ Here comes the groom... ¶
Good morning, beautiful.
Where are we?
Just passed Wanganella.
How much further?
Nearly halfway.
You're fucking kidding.
Would I lie to you, my beautiful?
Don't call me that.
What?
'My beautiful'.
You sound like an old person.
I am an old person.
Yeah, well, pretend you're not.
I feel like I'm eloping
with my grandfather.
¶ Well, I'm goin' up
the country
¶ Babe, don't you wanna go?
¶ Well, I'm goin' up the country
Babe, don't you wanna go?
¶ Takin' you some place
I've never been before
¶ I'm goin', I'm goin'
where the water tastes like wine
¶ I'm goin' where the water
tastes like wine
¶ Can jump in the water
Stay drunk all the time
¶ I'm gonna leave this city
Got to get away... ¶
What are you looking at?
The old watering hole.
What?
Why didn't you tell me
we were nearly there?
Oh, we're not.
Wal-lum-bee.
Wal-lum-bye.
Is it big?
Massive.
Hey, Ned?
Yeah?
Tell your dad that I am an actress.
What sort of actress?
Actress-actress, shithead.
Gotcha.
I've always wanted to live
in the country,
you know, with a porch
and slaves and shit.
Well, there's plenty of shit.
Where do you reckon these slaves
are coming from?
I know. We'll go back to Wal-lum-bee...
Wal-lum-bye.
..to the red soil of Wal-lum-bee.
Yes, as God is my witness...
As God is my witness,
I will never...
Toni! Toni! Shut up!
It's a kangaroo. It's a kangaroo.
Is it dead?
Don't.
Oh, poor kanga.
Oh, shit! It moved.
OK. Get in the car.
It's got a baby.
Get in the car.
What are you gonna do?
Get in the car, Toni.
Friendly-looking folk.
This is it? This is what we drove
halfway across a fucking continent for?
It's called a home.
A place of refuge, succour.
Ah. Well, why not honk the horn?
Stir 'em up a little.
Alright. Alright.
Who is it?
Ned?
Ned! Oh, my God!
Ned, you came.
I was beginning to think
you weren't gonna come. Come in.
Shut up, Bitsie.
Let me take that.
My God, look at you.
Would you have a look at you!
Oh, come here.
Oh!
You must be exhausted.
When did you leave? Let me take that.
You didn't drive straight through,
did you? Hmm?
Bitsie, shh!
It's only Ned. Hey, how's Sydney?
Jesus.
There's still tomorrow, isn't there?
Oh.
This is my sister Sally.
Sally, this is Toni.
Hi.
Does she have a suitcase?
No, no. She's an actress.
They don't wear clothes.
Ha ha!
Oh.
Hey, Bitsie.
So is the old man still with us?
Bruce. Is he?
Yeah, yeah, course he is.
Oh, look, I'll go tell him you're here.
No. Don't wake him.
He'll want to know you're here, Ned.
We'll be here in the morning.
There's no need to wake him. Let's...
OK. Well, I'll go get sheets, huh?
OK.
Which bed do you want?
Can't we put them together?
Oh...
I'll, um...
Don't you have any doubles?
Yeah, I'll get 'em.
No, no, no. I'll go.
Who's Clifford?
That's my brother.
Is he cuter than you?
Much.
Older or younger?
Ned?
Huh?
Your brother -- older or younger?
Uh, older.
Damn. Cuter and younger
would have been perfect.
It's mine, Neddy.
Close your eyes.
Why?
This is Nelson's hair.
This is Nelson's nose.
This is Nelson's stump.
This is Nelson's belly.
Don't look!
I'm not!
And this is Nelson's... bum hole!
Shut up, Kate,
or go back to your own room.
You shut up, Cliff.
Tickle me, Ned.
Walking in the jungle,
X marks the spot.
Dot-dash-dot-dash,
dot-dash-dot.
Knife stabs you in the back,
blood gushes down.
Spider bites you in the neck,
blood trickles down.
Tight squeeze...
A cool breeze.
Mmm.
Now you've got the shiveries.
What do you do
stuck all the way out here?
Oh, I work in the community.
What community?
The Aboriginal one.
You would have passed it
on the way in.
Well, what do you do for fun?
Oh, you'd be surprised.
Anyone looking for a piss-up
can usually find one. Right, Ned?
Oh, did I tell you Dougie
sold the roadhouse?
No.
Yeah.
Wanted to be closer
to the grandkids.
Would you believe
Tamara's on her fourth?
And ride him! Ride him!
Ride the old bull! Come on!
Aaah!
Get back!
Don't go whingeing to your mother.
Now get back up, you bloody sook!
You'll never be a real bull rider
if you don't get back up, Cliff.
Come on, Ned,
show your brother how it's done.
He'll see you now, Ned.
Hey, you OK?
Yeah, course I am. Why wouldn't I be?
Good. Good.
What happened?
South American heiress
dump you?
Uh, Toni, this is Bruce.
Bruce, this is Toni.
Hi.
This the new one?
A very pretty girl.
Then I don't suppose
you ever had any trouble picking 'em.
His trouble was in keeping 'em. They
all seem to get his number eventually.
Oh, yeah? What number's that one?
Don't ask me. I'm not a girl.
Uh, so, everyone catching up?
So what's wrong with you, Bruce?
I'm dying.
Congestive heart disease.
Well, it's, uh, treatable.
Yeah, sure it is.
They thin your blood,
they put you in an oxygen tent
and you live a couple of months longer.
Big deal.
You don't look so hot yourself.
You look soft.
Oh, we're not talking about me.
We're talking about you.
Yeah, well, don't you worry about me.
I haven't come to the end
of my breathing yet.
Come on, since Ned's come all this way,
could we all just try to get along?
Yeah.
Maybe she's right. Maybe we need
to clean up our act, eh, Ned?
It's loaded.
That's the idea.
Yeah, Bruce reckons the
black fellas burnt down the meat shed
and we're next.
I didn't reckon anything.
That was five years ago.
Oi! That's enough for you.
Oh, Jesus.
Who's this?
My daughter.
She's beautiful.
Alright. Think I'll take a look around
before it gets too hot.
But all of this
has been rigorously tested.
I don’t want to comment too much on the
report the government’s about to put out.
You know as well as I do
that things get skewed in the media.
That’s not to say. of course. that the
government doesn’t have a position
that it seeks to hold as well.
Shit, missed!
Bingo! Your turn, Neddy.
Hang on, Neddy!
Hey, do you want a hand?
Ow!
Why'd you have to bring her, Ned?
Oh...
Hmm?
What's your problem?
He's waited 20 years to see you
and he's dying.
Doesn't that deserve
your full attention?
I'm here, aren't l?
Ned?
What?
Blame's a mug's game.
What, you tell him that too,
or is that just for me?
It wasn't my idea to drag you back here.
He wanted to see you.
Just give him a go, would you?
Oooh!
You gonna stay here after?
Hmm?
There's no 'here' left.
The bank's got it all.
What?
Nothing?
Nup.
Sorry to break it to you, Ned.
You won't get anything but the contents
of his workshop and his best wishes.
Yeah, that'll be the day.
Nuh, Bruce reckons
it's worth 50 grand.
You wanna see?
Nuh.
I'll take your word for it.
Have we still got those yabby traps?
Yep.
No dam, but.
What happened?
No rain.
No-one used it much after anyway.
Do you remember
when that leech went up my fanny?
Everyone thought I was haemorrhaging.
Yeah, yeah, I remember that.
I remember it crawling out
all fat and happy
and you screaming your head off.
Yeah, can you blame me?
Bruce was carping on about,
"That'll teach you all to swim in the raw."
Didn't stop Kate but, did it?
Yuck.
What is that?
A witchetty grub.
Did she eat it?
Yep.
Gross.
Here we are.
Here, Dad.
Is she coming?
Who?
Beautiful Kate.
Doubt it.
Where is she?
She's no longer with us, Toni.
Is she dead?
Well done.
Wow.
Ah, here he is --
my one and only son and heir.
Did you have a good poke around,
did you? Everything to your satisfaction?
Front loader still running?
If the blacks haven't filled
the tank with sugar. Why?
You allowed a beer, Bruce?
No. Bruce can't drink on his medication.
Course he can.
Not every day a father gets to share
a drink with his long-lost son.
Good health.
To yours, anyway.
I didn't know
you had another sister, Ned.
Yeah. Kate was his twin.
Certainly not identical.
No, no, certainly not.
But just as attractive. Right, Bruce?
Like I always said,
with his looks and talent,
he could've been famous
if it wasn't for his weakness.
Yeah, which one's that?
For cunt.
Finished yet?
Toni likes our dirty linen,
don't you, Toni?
- That's enough for you, Dad.
- Jesus.
Sal, have you got
some boots for her?
Yeah, at the door.
Cliff!
What happened?
Huh? What?
How did she die?
In a car accident.
Soon as we get all this crap buried,
we're outta here.
Thank God for that.
It's not worth the cost
of a fuckin' auctioneer.
What about your brother?
What?
Yeah, both of them. Put these on.
In the accident?
Yep. Put these on.
When?
Now.
No, when was the accident?
Years ago.
So sad, Ned.
Hold on.
OK, you ready?
We're gonna turn. Ready?
Cliff, look at me.
Now, eyes on the road, Kate.
Not too hard on the wheel, sweetheart.
OK... Whoa!
Stop, Mum. I wanna show Dad.
Dad, look! I won, Dad! I won!
Dad, I won, I won! Dad, look.
You've got a long way to go
before you're a real bull rider, Cliff.
What are you looking at?
I:ve been back all of two days.
back at my father’s house.
So where else would I find myself
but in the old schoolroom
picking at my brother’s suicide
like an old scab
and following a trail of wounds
that leads inexorably
to the bastard dying next door.
¶ Oh. my goodness. it must be Jeff
¶ Wake up. Jeff
Everybody’s wiggling
We really need you
¶ Wake up. Jeff
You’re missing all the fun now
¶ Wake up. Jeff.
before the day’s through... ¶
Ned?
- Tu aimes.
- He loves.
Il aime.
We love.
Nous...
I read in the paper here
that Gary Fraser's son
won a scholarship to King's.
Why do you think that is, Cliff?
Is it because he's smarter than my son
or just a harder worker?
Maybe because his father doesn't
make him do the work of six blacks
and all this French crap besides.
N'est-ce pas, Neddy?
Can I help you with something, Bruce?
What is this?
Can't visit my own son in my own
house? Is that against the law now?
Nope. Just thought
I'd get some work done.
Work?
Writing.
It's what I do. I'm a 'writer'.
Ah, yes. Now I remember.
Written anything worth reading yet?
No, same old tripe.
What was that last one you wrote?
'Half His Luck', wasn't it?
The one I had to hide from Sally
'cause it was so filthy.
You mean the one that's in its 3rd reprint
but that's not my last one, Bruce.
They get even filthier after that?
Oh, yeah, yeah. It's wall-to-wall
fucking now. No more smoking gun.
Always the smart arse,
even now when you're...
How old are you?
40.
Christ. Almost old yourself.
You know, we never got the chance
to talk about that last summer, did we?
What about it?
- Ned!
I never understood it.
I never understood any of it.
What's to understand?
Cliff swerved to avoid a roo,
Kate's killed, Cliff...
I know that!
- Ned!
But I thought
you might know more.
That's all I'm asking.
Huh? It was a long time ago, Bruce.
I don't remember.
Why did you run off like that then?
Can you answer me that?
Look, we couldn't do this, uh,
some other time, could we?
Do you have any idea
how much we needed you here?!
Ned!
Can you work this stupid thing?
Alright. Don't sulk.
Sit on it proud.
Stick your back in a little bit.
That's it.
Now, you squeeze in with your thighs,
stick your tits out.
That's it. Now...
Put your hand up.
Uh... hold on with this.
Hands up nice and high, right?
You know what do to with that rope.
Hold on. Tits out.
Now, smile. You're happy, right?
You're riding the bull now. Yee-haa!
Yee-haa!
Just hold on.
Just enjoy the ride.
Whoo!
¶ Bad to the bone... ¶
MAN ON P.A.: Now today’s final event.
- turn -- the 3-legged race.
Come on. girls. Choose your bloke.
Don’t be shy now.
Hey, think
I might get to cop a feel?
What was that for?
What are you talking about,
you twerp, you butthole?
You haven't even kissed a girl.
Hey, feisty. You and me, babe.
How about it?
Hey, Neddy, got a partner?
Nuh.
You do now.
You're looking all grown up today,
Neddy. I like that shirt.
Are you gonna save a dance
for me later?
I might.
Hope so.
Where you going, baby?
Come back!
Stop!
You fuckin' did that on purpose!
Now you're a real cowgirl.
Fuck you.
Now what are you doing?
I'm going to work.
What am I supposed to do?
Too fuckin' hot here.
I dunno -- have a bath,
wash your hair or something.
Fine, I will.
You want a cuppa?
Do you like being everyone's slave?
I'm sorry, you just do everything
for everyone.
No, you're right. Tea's there.
You can make it yourself.
I'm not saying you shouldn't.
Don't you get sick of it, though?
Sick of what?
Fuck, if it was me, I'd leave
the bastards to get on with it.
Probably bloody kill each other.
Well, frankly, my dear, I'd risk it.
Mm-hm. Yeah.
Hey, can I come in?
Yeah, sure. Want one?
What is it?
Mojito.
Oh, yes, I do. You got lime?
Yeah. It's in the fridge.
Welcome to the Jungle Bar,
where everyone is beautiful
and the drinks are free.
Hey, George, my brother just turned up.
Say hi to Ned.
Hello. Ned.
Your sister is hot. Red hot.
Which one are you?
Veronica.
Wow, that's really quite a set.
George is a tit man. I promised I'd go
up two sizes if he bought me a ring.
See? Bling-bling.
It's good because if it doesn't
work out, I can sell it.
If what doesn't work out?
Us.
Oh.
What? He's got his charms.
You still there
Like that!
That's Mum's ring.
Hmm? Oh, yeah.
Do you remember her at all?
Nuh, not much.
I remember one time in the kitchen,
she had a head scarf on.
She was trying to get me to help make
the Christmas cake and I wouldn't
'cause I was so mad at her
for losing all her beautiful hair.
You're a lot like her.
Yeah?
Anyway, I reckon it's my turn
to piss off for a while.
Here, it's all written down.
Where are you going?
I've got to go take care of a few things.
Bullshit. You're joking?
He's all yours, Ned.
Oh, come on.
I'm not a nurse.
I'll probably end up killing him.
Well, we'll see, won't we?
Come on, it's easy. Just watch the salt.
Keep his head above his shoulders,
otherwise he'll drown.
Don't look so tragic.
It'll only be a few days.
I'm not gonna wipe his arse.
Yeah, you'd leave that to Toni!
There you are.
Go away, Toni.
No, I don't think so.
You're the one who dragged me here.
Now you have to entertain me.
Look, if you've got nothing better to do,
you can go check on Bruce.
No bloody way.
He's not my father, and he stinks.
You come from a stinky,
stinky family, Neddy.
What are you doing here?
Just making some notes.
Jotting some stuff down.
A bit like a diary.
Oh. Well, I hope you noted
the great head that you...
Oh, you didn't get it last night.
No, I didn't actually.
Yeah.
What's this?
Oh, School of the Air satellites.
We're the red flag.
Didn't you go away to school?
Nope.
Why not?
Bruce thought he knew better
than anyone else.
You know, I am trying to write.
I don't know why you bother.
No-one reads anymore.
Is that so?
Uh-huh.
We do far more interesting things now.
Oh, yeah. Like what?
I dunno. You're supposed to be
the one with the imagination.
Oh, yeah.
Ohhh, yeah.
Is this what you had in mind?
Uh-huh. Sure.
Oh, yeah.
Fuck me.
Fuck me, Ned!
Shh.
Harder, Ned!
Shut up or I'll stop.
Uh-huh. OK.
Mmm.
Oh, yeah.
Harder, Ned. Harder!
What?
You sound like a fuckin' tart.
That's because
you fuck me like one, you shit.
How come you never look at me?
What?
How come you never look at my face
when we fuck?
I love looking at you.
You're beautiful.
Do you love me?
I'm marrying you, aren't l?
You're such a shit.
What kind of answer is that?
Toni. Toni, Toni, Toni.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Come here. Look at me.
Look at me.
Course I love you.
You silly old cow, I love you.
Do you promise?
Yes.
Cross my heart...
..and hope to die.
I'm sorry, it's...
It's just this fuckin' place, Toni.
Ned!
What are you doing?
I need help, you stupid girl.
Hey, say 'please'.
Please get Ned.
No, Ned's out.
Have you pissed your pants?
Yuck.
Come on. Put your arms up.
OK, I'm gonna pull you up.
One, two, three!
OK, one, two...
Oh! Oh!
Yeah, I've got you,
I've got you.
Jesus.
Oh, cramps!
Terrible... ah... terrible cramps.
Well, you should have
taken your pills.
Oh... Oh!
OK, and up.
Ohhh!
And up. There we go.
There we go.
Where are your PJs kept?
What?
Aargh!
Yeah, I know.
One foot in.
Oh. Oh.
I can smell burning.
Oh, it's just Ned burning the junk.
Junk?
All that junk in the work shed.
What the fuck
does he think he's doing?
I'm not dead yet.
That's my fuckin' junk.
I don't understand it.
What?
Why such a pretty girl would waste
her time kicking round the dust
with some loser
who's nearly twice her age.
Oh, well, maybe I have a weakness
for older men.
Wasted.
Girl like you should be
in Hollywood.
You reckon?
Without a doubt.
That's exactly what I've been
saving for -- go to Hollywood.
I've been taking classes.
Good girl.
Don't you wait too long.
Youth is beauty and beauty is youth.
And that's all you need to know.
I want to sleep with you.
I want to sleep
in your dirty, filthy man's sheets.
In the morning,
I'm gonna wake up and leave
while he's still asleep.
I'm gonna walk out
and never see him again.
Right now, I wanna dance.
Paula, dance with me.
Do it again.
That was very good.
Get out, you perv! Get out!
Kate, I didn't know you were in there.
Well, frickin' know next time!
Sorry, Kate, I didn't know
you were in there.
It's not fair.
Something so cute could grow up
to be just another ugly old cow.
Bulls don't think they're ugly.
Well, they are. Old is ugly.
You're getting old, Kate.
We all are.
Good.
What's so good about it?
I liked it better before.
Before what?
I dunno.
When we were kids, I suppose.
Tickle?
Have you got a cold?
No, I just like the smell.
It reminds me of Mum.
Kate, are you crying?
Kate, don't cry. It's alright.
I miss her.
It's alright. Don't cry.
Oh, my God, Kate. I'm... I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to. Oh!
Bruce?
Room service.
Toni?
"There the evidence was,
"as hot and sticky and shocking to me
as it was to Kate.
"She turned to me with disbelief
as her hand touched the semen
"and brought it up,
viscous and dangling,
"for her eyes to see."
Did you try and fuck her, did you, Ned?
Fuck your sister?
Don't be ridiculous. It's fiction.
"Then she got up slowly
"as though she had been lying with
a beast she feared to rouse again."
Give it to me.
Fucking sounds like you tried!
I'm sorry, Toni. I'm sorry.
Stay away from me, Ned.
You fuckin' pervert!
Fuckin' had it with you sickos.
I know you're in there.
You can't stay there forever.
Kate, this morning, it wasn't you.
It was...
I don't want to talk about it.
It was my fault, OK?
Just pretend it never happened.
Come here.
Closer.
Kiss and make up?
Whoo!
Ahh!
Toni?
Toni! Toni!
What did you do? Huh? Did you pay
the blacks to come and get her?
What money have I got left to give
anyone? She just got your number.
You're a fuckin' liar, Bruce.
They all do. I did you a favour.
You're a liar and a bully.
You killed Cliff and you're still at it!
Why don't you fuckin' hurry up and die
before I kill you myself
just for the pleasure of it?
Stop, you bastards!
Fuckin' stop!
Pull over!
Pull over! I'm not fuckin' joking!
I'm still here!
You hear me?!
Still here!
Neddy?
Ned?
What?
Shh.
'Night, Ned.
Don't let the bed bugs bite.
Never let your gun
pointed be at anyone.
You think I've forgotten
what you said?
I was drunk, Bruce.
I was drunk.
I could hardly stand up.
Come on, Bruce.
Cliff accidentally
killed his sister.
He blamed himself.
He punished himself.
It's the end of the story.
I'm not a good drunk.
I'm sorry.
Come on, mate.
Take your pills.
Get me out of this mess.
How does it feel to be drunk?
Liberating.
I've never been drunk in my whole life.
Never liked the feeling.
Well, I seem to.
Yes, you always did, didn't you?
Piss off, you mongrels!
There you are.
I thought you'd drowned.
What are you doing here?
What does it look like?
Go home, Kate. I'm drunk.
I don't want you here.
Tough. It's my dam too.
Boo!
Remember at the rodeo
with Tamara and you
and you wanted to cop a feel?
Well, I wouldn't care
if I never even kissed a boy.
So?
Well, that's not normal, is it?
That's what I was doing
in the bathroom when you broke in,
wondering if I'd ever be normal.
I didn't break in. The door was unlocked.
Well, anyway, when we were on the bed
like that...
I know, Kate. I was there.
What happened?
Don't.
It's OK, Ned.
It made me feel better.
For the first time in my life,
I didn't feel like a freak.
I thought you didn't want
to talk about it.
Fine, then.
I won't mention it ever again.
You can touch them, Neddy.
It'll be our secret.
Oh, God.
Oh, God, Kate. I'm sorry.
It's OK, Ned. I'm OK.
¶ If you're happy
and you know it, clap your hands
¶ If you're happy and you know it,
clap your hands
¶ If you're happy and you know it
¶ And you really want to show it
¶ If you're happy and you know it,
clap your hands. ¶
It's OK, Neddy.
Just pretend I'm someone else.
Oh, God, oh, God.
Ned!
Here.
Not a day goes by I don't...
..see her face all bloodied like that.
In my mind I hear her too.
And it's you she's calling for --
you and sometimes Cliff, never me.
I'll get your breakfast.
Do you hear her, Ned?
You know how you hear, like,
twins are connected?
Do you? Do you ever hear her?
No. Never.
Glad you could join us, Ned.
I'm not hungry.
Well, you can sit
until we're finished.
If you give us a couple
of weeks away, Bruce,
I'll re-stump the posts on the Fraser
boundary where the sheep get through.
Get it done before Christmas.
You hear that, Cliff?
At least one of my sons is prepared
to put a bit of hard work in on the farm.
I said I'll quit the roadhouse and I will.
Sure you will, after frettin' and fussin'
about it like some pathetic old woman.
I don't care what time you finish. I want
you back inside these doors by 12:00!
Sit down!
Come on, Sally.
Stop playing with your food.
Sally, pass us the water.
Oh!
Oh, Jesus.
Bruce, Jesus.
Get up, get up, get up.
What are you doing?
What are you doing,
you silly old bugger?
Come here, OK. I got you.
I don't know what Sally was thinking,
leaving me with you.
Right.
You're gonna eat something
or I'm packing my bags and going.
I wouldn't miss you,
not for a bit.
I want salt.
You can't have any.
Come on, Bruce.
Please, just eat something.
Just a little bit.
There you go,
there you go. That's good.
That's good.
Thank you.
OK.
Alright.
Well, we'll try a bit of juice, then,
shall we?
Come on.
Bruce, you've gotta get
something into you.
Just drink.
Where's Cliff?
He got home from the roadhouse
10 minutes late
and the bastard grounded him.
I brought your stupid posts.
Thanks. I'll walk back.
Nicked 'em from Bruce.
Do you want one?
Cliff'll will be home tonight.
Good for him.
Do you wanna come back
for a swim later?
Just the three of us, like old times?
I don't think so.
Well, you needn't be frightened.
Cliff will be there.
He'll protect widdle Neddy.
Jeez, Kate, how can you joke about it?
God, sometimes I think
you're from outer space.
Well, I guess I thought you were
different from the herd, Ned.
Not so fuckin' timid!
Don't bother coming back!
You won't be missed!
Aren't you going
to the Christmas party?
Nup.
Good.
We'll have our own party.
You can play Rudolph.
¶ Jingle bells,
jingle bells, jingle all the way
¶ Oh, what fun... ¶
Cliff wants to see you.
Why?
Hold these for Rudolph.
There we go.
He's waiting in there for you.
You told him?
He said he's waiting for you.
Why? Why did you tell him?
I'm asking you why!
Yeah, what?
Kate told me what you tried, Ned.
What?
That you tried to cop a feel.
Hey, Jesus, Ned.
What has happened to you, mate?
What are you gonna do
about it, huh? Huh?
Come on. Hit me. Hit me. Come on.
Hey, take it easy, mate. It's OK.
No, it's not OK. Come on. Hit me.
Hit me, come on!
Get off me, Ned.
You little friggin' girl. Fight me.
Bruce! Bruce!
Let go, Ned!
Fight me!
Come on. Fight me.
Break it up! Let go of him, Cliff.
Stop. It was Ned's fault.
- I don't care whose fault it is.
I won't have any fighting.
You hear me, Cliff? Get up.
You hear me?!
Now, you! You go
and get yourself cleaned up.
You're taking your sister
to the Christmas party.
I don't want to go.
You'll do as you're told. You'll go.
And you'll bring her back
when she's had enough.
Where's Sally?
She'll be back today.
Yeah.
Oh.
I suppose you'll be off then.
Want to finish writing my story.
Oh, yes, the magnum opus.
No, more of a record.
A record of what?
Finished?
I can imagine
what you're saying about me.
Buzz if you need me.
Alright. Here?
I'll tell you when.
Here.
Round a bit.
I know you children never cared
for me, especially you and Kate.
You're wrong, Bruce.
Like that -- calling me 'Bruce'.
You never called your mother 'Emily',
did you?
You're making it worse, Bruce.
When your mother died...
..I wanted to fill her place,
get close to you like she did.
But I didn't know how.
I thought my world would be in politics
but that didn't pan out.
But what could I do? Teach?
Not your father. Too proud.
You know what, Bruce?
I don't think that many people feel
like they've lived successful lives.
I know you blame me
for Cliff's suicide.
I thought I was helping him.
I thought it was going to be
a tougher world for Cliff...
..than it was for you and Kate.
I'm done.
Come on.
Let's get back to your record.
Thank you.
And here's one for the ladies.
¶ Maybe I didn't love you
¶ Quite as often as I could have
¶ Maybe I didn't treat you
¶ Quite as good as I should have
¶ If I made you feel second best
¶ Girl, I'm sorry, I was blind
¶ You were always on my mind
¶ You were always on my mind... ¶
- Sorry.
I don't want to stay here anymore.
I wanna leave. Will you take me?
I'm not ready to go home yet, Kate.
I didn't say 'home'.
What?
The answer's no, Kate.
You have to. Bruce said
you had to look after me.
Well, can you just
take me home, then?
Come on. Let's go.
Will she be alright?
Sure. Cliff will look after her.
I'm looking after you.
¶ I just never took the time
¶ You were always on my mind
¶ Tell me... ¶
Come on, let's go.
Ohhh!
Ohhhh!
Happy now, Neddy?
¶ Don't need lots
of people to tell me what to do
¶ Don't need long-haired ladies
to love me true as true
¶ All I need is a rock'n'roll band
¶ Somewhere to play... ¶
Cliff?
Hey, Cliff?
Oh, God.
Oh...
Oh, Kate.
Cliff!
Oh, God. Cliff!
Bitsie.
Here, let me take that.
Trip OK?
Oh, thanks.
Yeah, no -- good, good, good.
So, did you kill him yet?
Almost.
Hmm?
Hardly touched a thing.
How did he eat for you?
Oh, not much.
Hmm.
He loves his custard.
Maybe I'll get some of this into him, eh?
Sure.
Did you get what you wanted, Ned?
Yeah. Got some books.
Oh, good.
Good. I'm glad you got
what you wanted.
Sorry about Toni.
Liar.
Hey, Sal? Sal...
Hmm?
Here, let me take it in to him.
I'm going in the morning,
I'll say goodbye to him.
Ned?
Yep.
You won't make it any worse, will you?
No.
You won't tell him about you and Kate?
What?
About what happened
between you and Kate.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Yeah, you do.
Remember that night you came home
with a big cut on your head?
What did we have for dinner?
It was yabbies.
I remember 'cause
I had to go get them from the dam.
I must have been --
what was I -- 10, 11?
I thought you were hurting her.
Stop looking at me.
Don't touch me.
I forgave you, Ned, a long time ago.
How could you? How?
You wanna know something?
I don't reckon Cliff
was any better than you.
He was just more remorseful.
Mmm.
Did you know the clock
stopped on impact?
Nobody could figure out why it took them
so long to get home from the dance.
Bruce nearly drove himself crazy,
trying to put all the pieces together.
Took me a long time
to figure it out as well.
See, I reckon Cliff could have lived
with himself for killing her.
It was the other stuff
he couldn't live with.
You think...
you think Cliff and Kate...
What do you reckon
they were doing out there? Really?
You reckon they were
fuckin' stargazing?
What are you doing, Ned?
What are you gonna say, Ned?
What? That he failed again?
That his greatest achievement
was just a messed-up little girl?
Ned, please don't!
Bruce?
Ohh...
You want to know what I remember
about that last summer?
I remember the Christmas party
and not wanting to go
and you telling me that I had to go,
that I had to take care of my sister
to bring her home
when she wanted to leave.
But I wouldn't. I didn't.
You want to know why?
You remember Tamara
from the roadhouse?
It's just like you said.
It's my weakness.
So you're off the hook, old man.
Much as I wanted to nail you
for Cliff's suicide...
..I can't make it stick.
If anything, you should've been
tougher on him,
you should have squeezed every
last drop of goodness out of him
and then maybe he would have
put himself first just for once.
Maybe he would have said,
"No, Kate, I'm not taking you home.
"I'm not going to drive you home.
I'm staying here,"
and then
I would have had to drive her.
Wouldn't l? I wouldn't have swerved
for no fuckin' roo.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I'm so sorry.
I hated you.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Ned?
Dad always said no two people
would give a damn
whether or not he lived or died
but you wait,
wait till word gets out.
Half the community's
gonna be at the door.
You know, I couldn't make a decision
between the blue and the green shirt.
What do you think?
I like the stripe. It's funny, isn't it?
Now he can't argue with me,
I can't decide.
I reckon the green.
Hmm?
That looks nice, doesn't it?
Yeah.
I am going now
to prepare a place for you.
And after I have gone
and prepared you a place,
I shall return to take you with me,
so that where I am, you may be too.
This is the Gospel of the Lord. Amen.
Amen.
Ned.
I want to show you something.
Won't you be lonely?
I've got 20 kids here call me 'auntie'.
I don't reckon I can get that lonely.
It's funny, you know.
A man can live his whole life
and never cop
to his greatest achievement...
..you.
¶ There's a little bird
that somebody sent
¶ Down to the earth
to live on the wind
¶ Born on the wind
and she sleeps on the wind
¶ That little bird
that somebody sent
¶ She's light and fragile,
her feathers sky blue
¶ So thin and graceful,
the sun shines through
¶ This little bird
that lives on the wind
that somebody sent
¶ She flies so high up in the sky
¶ Out of reach of human eye
¶ And the only time
she touches the ground
¶ Is when that little bird
¶ Is when that little bird dies. ¶