- Si.
- No, no.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee:
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the...
No virgin, me
For I have sinned
I sold my soul
For sex and gin
Go call a priest
All meek and mild
And tell him Mary
Is no more a child
It's raining stones
It's raining bile
From the luxury
Of your denial
I press alarms
Place bets on truth
I'm so up and down
And now I'm growing old disgracefully
Whatever happened to Mary?
Whatever happened to
I'll spit on floors
And do more drugs
Burn every bill
Get drunk on love
Wear next to nothing...
Hey, Frankie, sweetheart! Hey, Frankie!
Let's get out of here.
I got work in the morning. I'm trashed.
Are you too tired to go home with me?
I might be tired, but I'm not dead.
I'll be uncareful
I'll cause such scenes
And I'll never talk
Of used-to-bes
Tattoo my face
I won't go grey
Be a dancing queen
I'm growing old disgracefully
I'm so up and down
And I love what's not allowed
I was lost
Now I see
And now I'm growing old disgracefully.
Oh, hi, Mom.
How do you do that?
How did you know that was me?
Of course it's you.
You have the most persistent
ring I know.
Well, I just wanted to say hi
while I'm near a phone.
- How are you?
- Where are you anyway?
Belo Quinto, near Rio.
- It's beautiful...
- Mom, hold on.
I'm getting another call.
Hello?
It's about time. Where you been, baby?
Ha, ha. I hate it when you just leave.
You could at least say good-bye.
- Why?
- "Why"?
Forget it.
Look, I got my mom on the other line
long distance.
- I'll see you tonight.
- All right, I'll see you later.
Mom? Hi, I'm back.
So how do you like Rio?
It was great. Did you get my package?
Yeah, I got it yesterday.
Well, what did you think?
Did you like it?
- Did you open it yet?
- Hold on, I'm gonna change phones.
Well, what do you think?
Did you get a chance
to look at everything?
- I'm opening it now.
- Uh-huh, and?
- Ooh! Ah, pretty postcards.
- Aren't those pretty?
- Cute brush.
- I saw a lady make that.
- A little hat.
- The ha... isn't that cute?
- It's for a little doll or something.
- A necklace.
Well, no, it's not really a necklace.
It's a rosary.
Where'd you get it?
This little village called Belo Quinto.
- I didn't even know you went there.
- I took a little side trip over here.
So what do you think of the presents?
Do you love 'em?
I'm so glad I got a chance
to talk to you.
I'm going on that cruise.
I'm not gonna talk to you for a month.
- And I have to run.
- Okay, have fun. I love you.
- I love you, too, sweetie, bye-bye.
- I'm glad you called, Mom. Bye.
Can I get two lattes, please? Low-fat.
- Yeah, got it.
- Just one. You know, I'm okay.
Let me get
a bacon and egg sandwich, too.
- To go.
- Coming up.
What's up? You're not eating today?
I threw up this morning
from the smell of tea.
Oh, God.
Late?
- Like, a week.
- A week?
I don't know, a few days.
Kinda feel weird.
You're so dramatic.
I think you're just
psyching yourself out.
I feel like my heart
went to go live in my stomach.
Okay, it's not dramatic.
- What if I'm having a baby?
- With Steven?
What if I'm bringing a person
into this world?
Man, what if? You've got options.
You know what?
I don't want to think about it.
- It's making me cranky.
- Here's your to-go.
You know what,
let's get our tired asses to work...
- Thanks. Hold this.
- ...'cause we are late.
You're always late. There's nothing new.
Father Andrew Kiernan, welcome back.
Cardinal Houseman.
These are interesting. What's the trick?
Well, to be honest, I don't know.
They probably made a fortune out of her.
And, uh, what's... what was this?
Infrared photographs of tears.
The statue is made of stone,
therefore room temperature.
But the tears show up
as white because, um...
because they're warm.
- Warm tears?
- Yes.
My lab report and analysis confirm
that the blood from the statue
is not only warm, but human.
I know what you're thinking.
But with all due respect, Daniel,
this isn't a fake.
It's a freestanding mass of solid stone.
And there is no scientific explanation.
Andrew, it's my understanding
you were sent to Brazil
in order to investigate the appearance
of the Virgin Mary
on the side of a building.
Yes, but while I was in Sao Paulo,
I heard about the statue,
- so I decided to go and investigate.
- And?
And what?
The face of the Virgin Mary
on the building.
It's an oxidation stain
caused by rainwater
running down untreated side walls,
causes an optical illusion
of a veiled woman.
Good.
We'll consider the matter closed, then.
Father Dario has your next assignment.
I was hoping that perhaps
you could send me back to, um...
to Belo Quinto.
Why?
Because I need to do
some more tests on the statue.
You're telling me you left the statue
in Belo Quinto?
Yes.
I was going to take it back, obviously,
but when I saw the effect that it had
on the people... it's amazing.
It's become almost like
a cornerstone of their faith.
Andrew, the cornerstone
of their faith is the Church,
not a crying statue.
When you're in the field,
you're a representative
of the Catholic Church
and the Congregation
of the Causes of the Saints.
Yes, I'm very well aware
of that, Daniel.
I am also a scientist
and I observe the facts.
And the facts are that this statue
has tears of blood.
Well, if that's the case,
you know the policy.
The statue is brought back
to the Vatican.
We conduct expert tests...
geologists, engineers,
medical examiners.
We've examined 50 or 60 crying statues
in the last 12 months.
Not a single one of them
has turned out...
Yes, I'm very well aware of that,
but I just wanted you to know
that in my opinion,
I think that this is different.
I'm not going to allow you
to go back to Brazil.
We'll get a geologist down there,
and if he sees fit,
we'll get the statue sent back
for further tests.
Father Dario, get me
all the information you can
on this church in Belo Quinto,
would you?
Thank you, Andrew.
Thank you.
I have never seen him this way before.
Andrew's problem is he can't decide
if he's a scientist or a priest.
Frankie, come on.
- You are gonna drive yourself crazy.
- No.
If you're worried about being pregnant,
why don't we go to the store
right now and get a test?
Well, let's just give it
a couple of days, okay?
- Are you sure?
- I'm fine.
And stop mothering me. Yes.
All right, girlfriend.
I'll call you later.
Okay, bye. Drive safe.
- Late?
- Like, a week.
You're always late. There's nothing new.
What if I'm bringing
a person into this world?
Frankie, you've got options.
Nurse, somebody needs
to tell me what's going on.
- I don't understand.
- Get out of the way!
Frankie, can you hear me?
I'm right here with you.
Let's go!
I don't understand
why there's so much blood.
- Get me a clamp right now.
- Frankie!
All right, CBC, electrolytes,
UA, tox screen.
Get me a pulse ox, STAT!
- Get me a tox screen and a STAT CT.
- Right away.
Heart rate is irregular.
Blood pressure's off the map.
195 over 120.
- Let's change cuffs.
- Where's the IV?
I'm calling it, code blue!
Get the paddles.
Get some gel. Okay, ready?
- Mark, get the paddle.
- All right, clear!
Temperature and blood pressure
are back to normal.
Who are you?
I'm Dr. Reston.
Do you know what your name is?
What happened? Where am I?
You're in the emergency room.
You were found unconscious
in your apartment.
- Do you remember anything?
- No.
Oh, Jesus.
Can I get some more help over here?
We need some four-by-fours.
We have a very deep laceration here.
Oh, my God, it's gone right through.
Miss, you can't go in there.
- I'm sorry, Doctor, I just need to...
- Please have a seat.
I just need to know
what's going on with her.
She'll be fine.
Please have a seat. Thank you.
These are puncture wounds, Frankie,
caused by the entry of a sharp object.
Are you in any pain?
No. That's weird, isn't it?
Wow, will you look at that?
It only bleeds when I touch it.
Maybe you should not touch it.
Both wounds are identical...
the same size, same shape.
She missed the main artery
by less than a centimeter.
You keep saying "she,"
but I didn't do this.
What's happening in your life, Frankie?
Do you have a lot of stress at work?
I cut hair.
Do you have any trouble
with a significant other?
- Yes.
- And that is?
I'm not very significant.
Look, how long is this gonna take?
I wanna go home.
I think you should stay here
at least 24 hours for observation.
- We need to get a handle on this.
- There's nothing to get a handle on.
Frankie, I'm not gonna kid you...
with wounds like this,
it's pretty obvious
that they were self-inflicted.
You think I did this?
It would never happen.
I love being me. Ask anyone.
Frankie, turn the light off, honey,
and come to bed.
Do you smell flowers
in here or something?
No.
Smells like jasmine
or hyacinth or something.
I don't smell anything.
Mmm. You need anything?
No.
- Good night.
Grazie, signore.
Duty-free.
- Welcome back, Andrew.
- Gianni, come stai?
Sto bene. Ah, God is good.
So how was Belo Quinto?
How do you know about Belo Quinto?
I was sent to Sao Paulo.
God lives here, remember?
We know everything.
- Oh, yes, I forgot.
- So how are you doing?
I don't know.
I travel round the world
investigating miracles.
And then I disprove them.
The real miracle
is anybody believes anything.
I don't know what I'm doing,
to tell you the truth.
None of us know what we are doing.
- So what are you working on?
- I have no idea.
Well, how can you translate something
if you've no idea?
I'm a linguist, Andrew.
I translate words, not their relevance.
But this one is a second century gospel.
How many is that you're up to now?
I've helped translate about 15.
That only leaves 20 still to go.
So there are, what, 35 gospels?
Everyone had a different experience
of Jesus,
so they all wrote different stories.
You see, all the gospels,
they're interpretations.
They're memories, dreams, reflections.
And there's no one gospel
in Jesus' actual words?
We're all blind men in a cave
looking for a candle
that was lit 2,000 years ago.
So what's in this text?
- I was only given every third page.
- Why?
The most sensitive documents are always
divided into threes among us...
one-third to the Dominicans,
one-third to the Franciscans,
and one-third to us Jesuits.
The truth of any document
is only known to a very powerful few.
That's typical of this place, isn't it?
We live in a highly competitive
world, Andrew.
- The Church is no exception.
- Hmm.
Nothing ever gets out of here, does it?
Unless, of course, they want it to.
Both wounds are identical...
same size, same shape.
She missed the main artery
by less than a centimeter.
You think I did this?
What's happening in your life, Frankie?
So, Jen, tell us about your date.
It was with a tax lawyer.
- A tax lawyer?
- Yeah.
But when I first met him,
he seemed really cool.
- Hey.
- Hey, hi, guys.
- Hey, Frankie.
- How you feeling?
Fine.
Really okay or just okay?
I'm fine.
So how's my day looking?
Well, I started your first client,
and you're booked solid until 7:00.
Thanks.
Wanna come over here?
Okay, well, go back to Jen
and dish the dirt.
So, uh, he seemed pretty cool.
Divorced, but no kids.
But he left the table
in the middle of dinner
to call his mother in Oregon.
Major points for the long-distance mom.
Yeah. You know,
I thought I'd give him a shot.
But you won't believe what he did.
Every single time he took
a bite of his steak...
he growled.
He growled!
Shit!
Stop! There's a baby!
Frankie!
- Stop! Wait!
- Hey, lady!
- There's a baby! Stop!
- Crazy bitch!
Frankie, what are you doing?!
- What's your problem?
- You crazy or what?
Where's the baby?
- Frankie!
- Watch it, lady!
- Where's the lady? Did you see her?
- Frankie.
- She dropped her baby!
- Frankie, there's no baby, honey.
- Jeez.
There's no baby and there's no lady.
- What's happening?
- No, honey, it's...
It's okay, honey.
Take the night off, okay?
There was a lady. I saw her!
- There was not a lady.
- She dropped her baby.
I swear. I swear.
I just wanna get you home, okay?
You all right?
We'll be home in a minute.
- Frankie...
- Hey, you!
- Are you speaking to me?
- Are you Andrew Kiernan?
Andrew Kiernan?
No. My name's Father Durning.
May I help you?
No one can help me now. I'm fucked.
All passengers, please exit the train.
Wait on the platform for assistance.
Somebody help!
- Ah!
- Frankie Paige?
We're gonna schedule some more tests
for this afternoon around 4:00.
Did you run a pregnancy test?
Um... yes.
Am I pregnant?
No.
- Was I?
- I don't know.
Take this, all of you,
and drink from it,
for this is the cup of my blood,
shed for you and for all men
so that sins may be forgiven.
Do this in memory of me.
This is the blood of Christ.
Well, am I psychotic or dying or both?
Well, none of the above.
Actually, I think that
you're quite rational,
and despite the wounds you suffered,
you're in very good health.
There is another possibility
that is of concern.
Epilepsy.
Epilepsy?
We've run some preliminary tests,
and all things considered,
I think it might explain a lot.
But that seems impossible.
How can you just wake up one day
and have that?
Well, you can't, but, uh, you've
described blunt trauma to the head,
disturbing hallucinations.
You're hearing voices.
These could all indicate epilepsy.
So what do we do now?
We're going to insert some electrodes
into the upper neocortex.
Wait a minute, wait.
You want to put wires inside my head?
Frankie, we're gonna do whatever we can
to find out what's causing this.
You hang in there.
Epilepsy? They don't know
what they're talking about, Frankie.
I think you should get a second opinion.
Miss Paige? I'm Father Durning.
You spoke to me on the train?
Oh. Yeah?
I'd like to talk to you
about what happened.
Why?
Do you know what the stigmata are?
Uh, Father, I gotta
get Frankie home, thanks.
I understand how you feel, but please
call me if you change your mind.
Okay.
Ah, Andrew, come in.
I think we've found
your next assignment.
I was hoping that perhaps
you'd changed your mind
about sending me to Belo Quinto.
We have no record
of a church in Belo Quinto.
What?
That's impossible.
There must be some mistake.
No mistake, Father.
I have checked into it myself.
If there is a church in Belo Quinto,
it is not one of ours.
And no record of a priest
assigned to that village either.
This was sent to us
by a Father Durning in Pittsburgh
from the train's security camera.
What, uh... what are we supposed
to be looking for?
Watch.
Stop.
Obviously it is some sort of attack.
Maybe possession.
The wrists are bandaged.
According to Father Durning,
she was whipped repeatedly
by an unseen force.
How important is this really, Daniel?
We don't know yet.
Then why are you sending me?
Because of this clipping
from the "Pittsburgh Globe."
"20 terrified witnesses,
unexplained wounds,
Catholic priest."
The publicity is unfortunate,
but I'm sure by the time I get there,
it'll be completely blown over.
We're investigating this one.
You know what I heard?
Catholic priest in the paper said
that it was some like...
- Hey, Frankie!
- Hey, Frankie.
Hey, I feel like I should do
a monologue or something.
Hey, Cheryl.
Come on over here and have a seat.
I'll just be a second.
Um, you know what?
I think I'm just gonna wait for Donna.
Oh. Okay.
- What's going on with her?
- She wants to get a second opinion.
They think she might have epilepsy.
Epilepsy? She doesn't look too good.
Why is she even at work?
Hey, would you guys stop whispering
like this was a goddamn church?
- Hi.
- Hello.
You have an appointment or...?
No, I... I don't.
Well, would you like a haircut,
a manicure,
or maybe you'd like
to have your nipples pierced?
Well, maybe if we just start
with a trim,
we could go from there?
- Thank you.
- Come on. Have a seat.
All right, here we go.
I'm gonna put this cape on
so you don't get a scratchy neck.
Ah, thank you.
So where are you from?
I live in Rome, actually.
Ooh, cool.
- And you?
- I'm from Naples.
- Ah, Naples.
- Mm-hmm.
Naples, la citta piu bella del mondo.
Naples, Florida.
- I moved here to go to school.
- Which school?
Claudia's University of Cosmetology.
- See? I'm accredited.
- Oh. Cool.
Am I going crazy
or is Frankie hitting on a priest?
What do I call you?
I feel kind of weird calling a guy
I could date "Father."
I mean, I couldn't date you,
but... you know.
Oh, no, no, no. You just made my day.
Thank you. You can call me Andrew.
Andrew Kiernan, that's my name.
Donna.
I know this is gonna sound
kinda strange, but...
I've sorta been expecting you.
So you live in Rome?
Yes, but I travel a great deal,
so I'm rarely there.
- Thank you.
- Coffee, honey?
No, thanks.
So what brings you to Pennsylvania?
Well, Father Durning asked us
to come and speak to you, Miss Paige.
Us? Who's us?
I thought you were a priest.
Well, I am a priest,
but I'm also an investigator.
I work for a division in the Vatican
called the Congregation
for the Causes of the Saints.
Do you mind if I switch this on?
- No, go ahead.
- Thank you.
What is... what is your full name?
Frankie Paige.
- And your age?
- 23.
And which church do you attend?
I don't attend church.
But you are Catholic.
No, I don't go to church
because I don't believe in God.
Well, that's... gonna be it for me.
That's all I need to know, Miss Paige.
- That's it?
- Yes.
You see, stigmatics
are deeply religious people.
- And there's no exceptions?
- No.
Well, why do they get stigmata?
When Christ died on the cross, he...
he died with five wounds.
His back was scourged by whips.
There were gashes in his forehead
from a crown of thorns.
There were nails driven
through his hands and feet.
And finally, a spear
driven through his side.
Throughout history,
only deeply devout people
have been afflicted with these wounds.
Well, why?
There really is no satisfactory
scientific explanation.
All stigmatics are haunted
by such intense spiritual pain,
in some ways it affects them physically.
They're assaulted
by their own visions of evil,
and they manifest this battle
in their bodies.
The Church, on the other hand,
regards it as a gift,
a gift from God.
A gift? Can I give it back?
Listen, Father...
ahem, can I show you these,
and you could tell me what you think?
Yes. Yes, of course.
Coffee, honey?
Well, what do you think?
Well, it doesn't really matter
what I think, Miss Paige.
What does that mean?
It means officially,
this is not a case for the Church.
To say that a self-confessed atheist
exhibits the wounds of Christ
is a contradiction in terms.
Look, you know what? Here. Read that.
I found that on my kitchen table
the other morning.
Now, I don't know what that says,
but that handwriting is mine.
It's Italian.
It says, "Split a piece of wood,
and I'm there.
Lift a stone, and you will find me."
It's quite beautiful, actually.
This isn't beautiful. This is a warning!
- It means no matter what I do...
- Miss Paige!
...no matter where I go,
I can't escape this.
Miss Paige,
I would really like to help you...
You know what? You know what?
This is not going anywhere.
You don't know what this is.
You can't give me any kind of answer.
Coffee's on me. Here.
There really is no satisfactory
scientific explanation.
Stigmatics are deeply religious people.
We're gonna do whatever
we can to find out,
but, all things considered,
I think it might explain a lot.
Throughout history, only people
who believe deeply in God
have been afflicted with these wounds.
The nearer they come to God,
the more open they are
to the torment of their demons.
The Church regards it as a gift,
a gift from God.
Whoo-hoo!
- Here's to Friday night!
- Yeah, Friday night, honey.
Frankie!
Don't worry about it.
Just order another drink.
I'll be right back.
I'm gonna go check it out.
But you just can't tell
Don't hold your breath, but the pretty
things are going to hell...
- Hey, girlfriend. What's up?
- Hey.
I thought you were staying home
to get some rest.
Have you seen Steven?
Man, forget about Steven.
What's up with that priest?
Believe me, he's all business.
Hey, can we get two doubles each?
Hey, you know what's scarier
than not believing in God?
Believing in Him.
I mean, really believing in Him
is a fucking terrifying thought.
It's Friday night.
I think you're taking things
a little too seriously.
'Cause If there is a God,
then He hates me
'cause He's ruining my life.
Come on, Frankie,
it's gonna be all right, man.
- Relax.
- You don't get it, do you?
I have fucking holes through my wrists!
I have slashes across my back!
If it isn't God that's doing this to me,
then who is?
I think you're losing it, man.
Where you goin'?
Frankie!
Frankie! Oh, God!
Frankie, get up! Get up!
Frankie...
Frankie, it's all right. Frankie!
Don't just fuckin' stand there!
Somebody call an ambulance!
Damn.
Frankie, where are you?
Get outta there!
Miss Paige?
Miss Paige!
Frankie!
- Let's get you out of here.
- Frankie.
We need to get her to a safe place.
Here, I got you. I got you.
Welcome back.
Where am I?
You're in Father Durning's church.
Hey.
I think she should get some rest.
You all right?
You look like shit.
It smells like...
flowers.
You got stuff all in your hair.
Pronto.
- Gianni, come stai?
- Andrew, how are you?
Gianni, listen, could you help me
with a translation?
- Si. Do you have it there?
- Yes, I have it here.
- Read it to me.
- I'll play it for you now.
Thama...
Well, what is it? Is it gibberish?
No, no, no, it's not gibberish at all.
Andrew, who is speaking these words?
Good morning, Miss Paige.
You're up early.
Hey. I think you made a mistake.
- What do you mean?
- I can't have stigmata.
Jesus was crucified through
the palms of his hands, not his wrists.
And look at my wounds.
They're through the wrists.
So you're wrong.
Actually, scientists have discovered
that in Roman times,
people were crucified
through the wrists, not the palms.
There's no way that the hands
could have supported the weight of body,
so they did crucify them
through the wrists.
No, wait, you're telling me
that every painting,
every statue of Christ,
every single crucifix
in the whole world is wrong?
No, no, just inaccurate.
They're impressions of the truth.
Icons are meant to be inspirational.
Miss Paige, there's something else
you should know.
The words you keep repeating
that, uh, you thought were nonsense...
well, it's not.
It's actually a very specific language.
It's a form of Aramaic.
What?
It's a form of Aramaic
that hasn't been used for 1,900 years.
It's a dialect that was used in Galilee
around the time of Jesus.
"Split a piece of wood and I am there.
Lift a stone and you will find me."
- Did you get through?
- No.
Her machine didn't even pick up.
Miss Paige?
Frankie?
Frankie...
Frankie.
Who are you?
I feel like my heart is breaking.
Why am I so sad?
It smells like flowers in here.
Like...
jasmine or...
rose or something.
- Can you smell that?
- Yes, I can.
- Who wrote that?
- You did.
- I wrote that?
- Yes.
Have you heard from Father Andrew?
No, Eminence.
He hasn't filed a report
since he got there.
What are these?
These are newspaper clippings
from our office in New York.
The first one is from Pennsylvania.
The others are from New York
and Washington.
These are even more damaging.
This one mentions the stigmata.
He doesn't seem to be
defusing the situation.
Shall I call him home?
Have him conclude
his investigation immediately,
present his report to me
in New York at the end of next week.
Frankie, can you please come over here
and have a look at this?
I... I just can't believe that
none of this means anything to you.
Frankie?
Frankie.
Frankie, can you please?
Can you please look at this?
Sometimes subjects retain
fragments or images
that can be transmitted
subconsciously and...
This subject doesn't retain
fragments of images.
You don't get it,
do you, Father Kiernan?
I don't know what the hell that means!
I don't know what the hell this means.
I just want my life back, okay?
I'm sitting amongst yourselves
Don't think you can see me
I haven't gone anywhere
But out of my body
Reach out and touch me
Make effort to speak to me
Call out and you'll hear me
Be happy for me...
Miss Paige?
Miss Paige, I, uh... I'm sorry.
Don't "Miss Paige" me
just because you messed up.
I'm not gonna let you off the hook.
Okay, but, uh... I am sorry.
You know, for a priest,
you're pretty relentless.
Yeah, I guess I stopped being a priest
and slipped back into being a scientist.
It, uh... it happens.
Hey, what kind of a scientist
is a priest, anyway?
You don't want to know.
Oh, yes, I do.
You were an organic chemist?
Okay, did you walk around
with those glasses
with Scotch tape around the sides
and pocket protectors?
I did, actually.
Anyway, one day, I just decided
that I was going to become a priest.
Well, why?
- The holes.
- The holes?
- Mm, the holes in the theories.
- What theories?
The world is six billion years old,
right?
There's been life on this planet
for three billion years,
but for three billion years before that,
there was nothing.
No life. Just a bunch of elements
swirling around.
And then one day,
for no apparent reason whatsoever,
all these elements
came together in perfect harmony,
and there was suddenly life,
living things like lilac and...
and hedgehogs and snails...
- Beer and cheesecake.
Did you know that monks
invented alcohol?
- Yeah. Everybody knows that.
- You knew that?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Okay.
Well, anyway, to get back
to the big hole.
There really...
There really isn't any explanation.
And I figured that there was
something more than...
well, more important
than organic chemistry going on,
and I figured that it was God
and that God was responsible
for all this life.
- I really can't get a line on you.
- Why not?
First of all, I can't understand
a man who's never, you know.
Never made love to a woman?
Well, ahem, this may come
as a great surprise to you,
but... I wasn't born a priest.
- But you didn't like it?
- Well, what's not to like?
- But you don't miss it?
- Yes, of course I miss it.
I mean, I'm human, you know?
I struggle with it,
but I've made a choice.
Basically, what I've done
is I've exchanged
one set of complications for another.
Frankie.
Frankie...
So this is the fourth?
- What do you mean?
- When I first met you,
didn't you say that
there were five wounds?
Well, this is the fourth.
What's the fifth?
The spear.
That's the wound that killed him.
Don't worry, Frankie.
No stigmatic has ever received
the full five wounds.
Have you ever met another person
who had stigmata?
I did make a pilgrimage
to a small village
in the mountains of Southern Italy.
There I met a priest called Padre Pio.
He first received the wounds
when he was 23 years of age,
the same age as Saint Francis of Assisi.
Who's Saint Francis of Assisi?
Saint Francis was the first person
to receive the stigmata,
in the 13th century.
He was a wild young man,
but he suddenly changed his ways
after he'd had a vision
of being crucified alongside Christ.
When he woke up,
his hands and his feet were...
were bleeding.
This priest, were his wounds
as bad as mine?
Padre Pio.
Sometimes he lost a pint of blood a day
and he suffered
terrible demonic attacks.
A priest?
All stigmatics suffer
the most intense spiritual conflict.
The nearer they come to God,
the more open they are to temptation,
to evil visions...
to the torment of their demons.
There was also a smell
which accompanied the wounds,
the odor of sanctity, the smell of...
Flowers.
Yes, flowers.
Well, what happened to him?
How many wounds did he receive?
He...
He lived to old age.
How many wounds did he receive?
Two.
I'm dying, aren't I?
This thing is killing me.
Here's a closer shot.
My guess is it's probably Aramaic.
Aspetta. I'm looking at it.
Is there a...
is there a problem, Gianni?
Yes, don't send me any more
of these pictures.
- How many did you send?
- Six. Why?
- The problem is what it says.
- Well, what does it say?
It says, "The kingdom of God
is inside you
and all about you."
Andrew, forget you saw this.
Drop it immediately.
- Don't send me any more...
- Gianni, what is the problem?
Do you remember the Gospels...
Gianni?
Gianni, are you still there? Gianni?
Do you remember the Gospels Commission?
It was closed down suddenly
by your friend Cardinal Houseman.
Yes, a few years ago, yes.
We discovered a document that looked
like it was a completely new gospel.
Well, what's the significance of that?
I was one of the three translators
of this gospel.
It was written entirely in Aramaic,
the language of Jesus and his disciples.
It may be Jesus' actual words.
His own...
Where is it now?
Gianni? What's going on?
Gianni, are you there? Gianni?
Buona sera.
What's this?
- Is that a painting?
- No, it's a mirror.
Well, who else was in the room?
I don't know.
I thought you said it was just you two.
16-A. Do you have the neg?
Who is that?
I'll be back as soon as I can.
- Cardinal Houseman.
- I'm late for a meeting with a courier.
At your discretion,
but I think this might be of interest.
What is it?
Where did you get this?
It was emailed to Father Delmonico.
- By whom?
- Father Kiernan in Pittsburgh.
- Do you know what it means?
- No.
Is it important?
Uh, will you tell the meeting
I'll be with them in a few minutes?
Who is it?
Hi, come in. The door's open.
- Frankie?
- I'm in here!
Raise me to your lips
Two undernourished egos,
four rotating hips
Hold on to me tightly,
I'm a sliding scale...
How you doin'? Want a beer?
Sure.
Check these out.
Looks like they're getting better.
- That's great.
- Mm-hmm.
Really good.
You'll be able to get
these stitches out soon.
That's great. Let me see your forehead.
Mm-hmm. Right.
- Does this... does this hurt?
- It's good.
Right, you'll...
Between us is our kitchen
Where she found my irritants itching
Been here before
Been here forever
Moving up slowly, inertia keeps
Moving up slowly, inertia creeps
Moving up slowly,
she comes moving up slowly...
Why did you paint over the wall?
Well, I got bored and I got sick
of looking at that thing.
Inertia creeps, moving up slowly...
There be no sound in my eiderdown
Awake I lie in the morning's bloom
Hold me still, my antenna in you
Nylon burns the bedspread with two
Gravity zero, see me stall
I bounce off walls,
lose my footing and fall
Can be sweet though incomplete,
though...
I really wish you weren't
wearing that uniform right now.
It's got nothing to do
with the uniform, believe me.
Well, what is it, your vow?
You took a vow to be dead
from the neck down?
Come on.
I've seen the way you look at me.
You know the way that I feel about you.
Come on, I'm not blind. It's okay.
It's okay.
No.
Why? Because I...
I painted the wall out?
Is that it?
So now I'm no use to you, right?
Answer me!
You are so proud
of your holy abstinence!
Like touching a woman would kill you!
Women are dirty little complications!
That's why you became a priest!
It has nothing to do
with your convenient little stories!
Oh, you're so proud of your church,
of virgins and eunuchs!
How's your faith these days, Father?
How's your faith these days?
This is what you fucking call God?
Blood of Christ!
I've never seen you pray before.
I haven't prayed for a very long time.
Come here.
It's okay. Come on.
Go in.
Daniel.
We've come to help.
Take her to the archdiocese
straightaway.
I'll be downstairs
if you need me, Sister.
Where did you get this from, hmm?
What does it mean?
The girl wrote it.
I don't know what it means.
Neither does she.
Why was it painted over?
What language is it in?
It's Aramaic.
How do you know that?
That's completely irrelevant.
See, what I don't understand
is why you would send this
to anyone other than me.
What are you hiding from me, Andrew?
Look, all I know is that the girl
is fighting for her life.
If she receives another wound,
she's going to die unless we help her.
Right. I'm taking over this case.
Go back to Father Durning's.
- Get some rest.
- I'm not leaving her alone.
You're not leaving her alone.
You're leaving her
in the care of the sisters.
Look, you sent me here.
I didn't want to come.
You told me to deal with her!
That's what I'm doing!
She's in no condition
to take on you or the Church.
This is not about a girl taking on me
or taking on the Church!
Why are you so concerned
about those photographs?
Why is that more important
than a girl bleeding to death?
Andrew, what's happened to you?
Where's your loyalty?
Don't you lecture me
about loyalty, Daniel.
The only reason you've been tolerated
by the congregation for so long
is because you were a good scientist,
because of your objectivity.
But you've lost that.
The last thing I expected to see
when I walked into that girl's apartment
was the two of you
lying on a bed together.
Oh, come on.
Look, I know you think
you're helping her, but you're not.
If anything, she's getting worse.
Andrew, you're in no state
to help anyone right now.
You're exhausted. Look at you.
Go to Father Durning's. Get some rest.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Why are you so concerned
with these photographs?
Father Delmonico showed them to us.
He seemed to think they were important.
What do they mean?
We've no idea, but we're working on it.
Does it have anything to do
with the Gospel Commission?
We don't know. Good night, Andrew.
Andrew Kiernan?
- I'm Kiernan.
- I want to see Alameida.
I don't know any Alameida.
Delmonico faxed me
this copy of his document.
A girl wrote this.
I saw her do it. What is this?
It's maybe the most significant
Christian relic ever found.
Why?
It's an Aramaic scroll
from the first century
discovered near the caves
of the Dead Sea Scrolls
outside Jerusalem.
Alameida and I concluded
that it is a gospel
of Jesus Christ
in his own words, Aramaic.
But there are some factions
in the Vatican
who believe that this document
could destroy
the authority of the modern Church.
How?
It was Jesus' words to his disciples
on the night of his last supper,
his instructions to them
on how to continue his church
after his death.
Why would that be so... so threatening?
When we gave our initial conclusions
to the Gospel Commission,
Houseman ordered us
to stop our work immediately.
Alameida refused.
He stole the document and disappeared.
Houseman excommunicated us
in our absence.
You have no idea where he is?
He doesn't want to be caught
until he finishes the translation.
I'll show you this guy.
That's Delmonico, me, and Alameida.
We were all translating
the new gospel together.
I've seen this man.
Three weeks ago in Brazil.
- Yeah?
- He's dead.
How do you know this?
Because I saw him in his coffin
in a church in Belo Quinto.
I'm sorry.
Then it's all over. It's gone forever.
Why was your work stopped?
What was so threatening
about this gospel?
Look around you, Father.
What do you see?
- I see a church.
- It's a building.
The true church of Jesus Christ
is so much more,
not in buildings made of wood and stone.
I love Jesus.
I don't need an institution
between him and me.
You see? Just God and man.
No priests, no churches.
The first words in Jesus' gospel are,
"The kingdom of God is inside you
and all around you,
not in buildings of wood and stone.
'Split a piece of wood, and I'm there.
Lift a stone and"'...
"'You will find me."'
Yes, Father.
Why is Father Alameida wearing gloves?
Alameida was a tormented man.
Holy man. A very holy man.
He wore the gloves to cover
the marks of the stigmata.
She has the stigmata.
That's why.
She's just his messenger.
Houseman will never let
this gospel get out.
Almighty God, bless Your humble servant.
Guide me with Your Holy Spirit
and forgive me,
for I have sinned exceedingly
in thought, word, and deed.
My sins deserve Your punishments
because they have crucified
my loving savior, Jesus Christ, amen.
Lord, do not remember our sins
or those of our forefathers.
- Where's Andrew?
- And do not punish us for our offences.
- Lead us not into temptation.
- But deliver us from evil.
Save this woman, your servant.
Spirit of lust,
by the power of Jesus Christ,
I command you, come out of her body
now and for always.
In the name... in the name
of Jesus Christ, I command you,
come out of her body now and for always.
In the name of Jesus Christ...
Be a tower of strength to her, O Lord!
Why do you persecute me?
Send her help
from the holy place, O Lord!
Give her heavenly protection!
Lord, hear my prayer!
Let the enemy have no victory over...
Behold!
Your servant, dripping with blood!
Embrace me, my child. I am the Church!
- I'm the Church.
- Stop! Stop!
No! Get away from me!
Get them out of here!
Get out of here! Get out!
- Eminenza.
- Get out!
Save this woman from woe, O Lord!
Save this woman, your servant!
Send her help
from the holy place, O Lord.
Give her heavenly protection.
Save this woman, O Lord!
Let the enemy have no victory over her!
Send her help
from the holy place, O Lord.
Frankie!
You will not destroy my Church.
You must not interrupt...
What are you doing? Get away from her!
- Get away from her!
- No! No!
Get away!
It's all right. It's okay.
- I know what...
- Andrew!
Get away from her!
You don't know what's going on here!
You get off me! You lied to me!
You tried to silence her.
You lied to me, you bastard.
- Andrew...
- You tried to kill her!
No!
Listen! I know everything.
I know why you closed down
the Gospel Commission.
I know why you had Petrocelli
and Alameida excommunicated.
I know all about the lies
you've been telling for years.
There is no way you'll get away
with what you did to her!
I will not let you destroy the Church.
I promise you, you've spent
your last days in the Church.
Are you Paolo Alameida?
Give me your wisdom.
Let me be your messenger.
A messenger believes.
A messenger has faith.
You have only doubt.
Jesus said, "The kingdom
of God is inside you
and all around you,
not in mansions of wood and stone.
Split a piece of wood, and I am there.
Lift a stone... and you will find me."
Brother Alameida,
I call upon you to release this woman.
Give her grace and let her not come
into the ways of harm.
Through Jesus Christ,
we have all been saved.
Let us not fear any ill,
for Jesus is with us
in the unity of the Holy Spirit,
world without end, forever and ever.
God bless your soul, Brother Alameida.
And go in peace.
Don't go, Frankie.
Stay with me.
Jesus said, "The kingdom
of God is inside you
and all around you,
not in mansions of wood and stone."
The kingdom of God is inside you
and all around you,
not in buildings of wood and stone.
Split a piece of wood, and I am there."
These are the hidden sayings
that the living Jesus spoke.
Whoever discovers the meaning
of these sayings will not taste death.
Your eyes, they send me
To eternity
Your heart may cast me
Down to hell
I'm bound
But lately
It's your love
It's condemnation enough
Identify
Please identify
If it's me you want
Standing by your side
Identify
These tears of mine
Am I lonely
Or am I just alive?
I let time decide
Who and what will stand this test
Of love
Your hands were speaking
No
I felt the movement
Go
The ice was breaking
So I wonder why
Did I
Identify
With you, my life?
To leave me empty
And see if I'd survive?
For every questioned hour
For every second devoured
You let me wander you
Into a myth
That I live
Identify
Please identify
If it's me you want
Standing by your side
Identify
These tears of mine
Am I lonely
Or am I just alive?