[RAIN]
[POLICE SIRENS]
[EXCITING MUSIC]
[BREAKING GLASS]
[CAR ALARM]
[POLICE SIRENS]
VINCENT: I have nothing to do.
I mean it. You must believe me.
SPEAKER:
We would like nothing better, Mr.. Stevens.
But your explanation is quite weird.
Listen, we have done it.
Everything is put in scene.
Interrogators:
So you are framed?
Is that what you want to say?
- That you yourself are a victim?
- Not in that sense... Not like...
Not like who, Mr. Stevens?
Not like it?
Not in that sense?
- Have the others have questioned?
- We are working on.
So everything is a big conspiracy,
If I understand correctly?
Why are you will
not easy and you confess?
Can you still 's tell
what happened this morning?
- Again?
- Again, Mr. Stevens.
From the beginning,
if you would be so kind.
[EXCITING, MELODIOUS MUSIC]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[PANTING AND MOANING]
[CLANG BOTTLES]
[JINGLE OF KEYS]
[BREAKING GLASS]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
- Where were you this morning, Mr. Stevens?
- Home.
- My wife is skiing.
- Not anymore. She's way.
I had the impression
she also had many questions.
You were so morning
wake up call? What time was it?
That must have been around Half-elven.
It was Luc. In panic.
I had to come,
there was something bad happened.
- Luc Seynaeve?
- Luc, yes, yes. Luc.
Where did you go?
The loft.
I had come straight to the loft.
- And he said why he was in a panic?
- No.
- Did you know why he was in a panic?
- No. Then not.
[LIFT SIGNAL]
[OPEN DOORS SLIDE]
Luc?
What is it?
Jesus.
What happened here?
I do not know, Vincent.
I really do not know.
[MOVES IN GLASS SHARDS]
- Do you have something to do?
- No. I came in and she was there.
- Do not touch. We await the police.
- Is the police?
- Not yet, but that's...
- For now no police. Okay?
Jesus, man.
- Goddamn. Has been called the rest?
- Marnix and Chris are on their way.
- Filip I could not reach.
- Keep calling. Everyone should come.
Who is that? Do you know?
- Do you know who it is?
- Of course not.
- Along what they broke?
- The door was fixed and it was off alarm.
- You can not.
- The door was locked and it was off alarm.
You can not. That would say...
I know. Someone with a
of our keys got in his.
Goddamn, Luc.
What happened here?
- SPEAKER:
Do you know the building at the Tavernierkaai?
- Luke: Yes.
- The project of your good friend Vincent.
- Vincent has many projects.
There is a loft on the top floor.
You say anything?
- No.
- Never been?
No.
Tiens... According to our information
loft that you share with your friends.
In secret.
Without women you know.
- That is ridiculous.
- Is that so?
Please note there is no company
going? Mistresses, free-range,
- The fresh fish of the day?
- This is just...
Five friends who want privacy
when the next piss pot.
No hassle with hotel bills
your wife could be found.
- That is really ridiculous.
- Interviewer: Do not you dumb, boy.
One of your buddies
has also been published.
That shock, huh?
Would not you know who?
- I do that kind of stuff.
- You see your wife happy?
Yes. I see my wife happy, yes.
- What happened to your eye?
- I am against a cabinet run.
- Have you fought?
Where were you this morning?
I had breakfast with Chris
in the city. I have witnesses.
Chris Van Outryve?
Dr Van Outryve. The psychiatrist.
A loft of your friends.
Chris is married, has children. Not
the kind of man that his wife cheating.
[LAUGHS]
Come... All good fathers.
[THERE IS WHIPPED]
- CHRIS: Where is she?
- We have a serious problem, Chris.
[ALSO MOVES IN THE GLASS SHARDS]
Goddamn.
- Filip...
- What say you, Chris? Filip?
- Do you think your brother is behind this?
- I do not know what to think.
This will end up on our necks.
Elsie, the children...
- We should call the police.
- Hold on, Chris.
You know what happens?
Do you all hear that Ellen?
There is one body.
We have no choice.
Chris, as Filip something to do
, then we must say your brother.
You do spontaneously to him?
Remember last time?
- Or have you already forgotten?
- No.
We think alike,
eh, Chris? Not?
We can help him. As he explained to us
what happened, we can...
Then we may find some? Her
body dump somewhere? Or what? Zot.
Listen, I'm not going to pay
for his stupidity, right?
[DOOR OPENS]
MARNIX: It can not.
Oh, kiss now
fuck my balls.
- We have a serious problem.
- Man...
- Do you know if Philippe has been here?
- It can not.
What are you doing?
- I want to see her.
- Oh, Jesus, man.
Stay over there.
Stay over there, Chris.
Who is it?
- Who is it?
- I do not know.
None of us here
something to do, right?
- Huh? Right?
- We find out what happened
and we see how we get out together.
This should not come. We have sizes.
[MURMUR]
- VINCENT: Ikke fl, they let everyone in here.
- CHRIS: Hey, Vince. Well done.
Ellen, that's too long ago.
You look fantastic.
Thank you, Vincent.
- It is a clever design. Congratulations.
- Merci.
- BARBARA: Hey.
- Hey, Barbara.
- Dag. Day, Ellen.
- Barbara.
- Buy an apartment doing here?
- We can not afford.
That is true. With your salary.
You're an invalid.
- Hey, we see each other soon. Okay?
- Yes, that's good.
Honey, one hours, no longer.
Then we left.
Honey, we just got here.
Do not start.
[DRAMATIC ACCENT IN MUSIC]
MARNIX: Jesus, did you see what a beautiful
voIk running around here? Boy, my coat.
- Look, look, that nigger...
- Luke: Yeah.
- Have you seen her?
- I've seen her. Calm.
That seems a hot shot. I want
it's lagging behind in the bush.
- She gets even 100 meter lead.
- Marnix, quiet. Miriam looks.
- Lap, I got it down.
- MIRIAM: What? Amuse you, thick?
Calm down, boy. We were
what the people were watching.
Let me not fall into disgrace
or I leave you here alone.
Me no false hope, fart.
With you always promise.
- Luc. Elsie is not there?
- She felt a little dizzy.
- She is here to measure its sugar.
- How is she?
- Here, Elsie. Everything good?
- Elsie: I could be anything bad,
- But it's okay now.
- If it is not, we go, huh, sweet.
'Sweet'... And she has just
its sugar measured.
Do you find that funny now?
He sits with his wife at least.
What would you do,
if I had?
But scheetje, I would you gladly
every day give a shot in your ass.
ANN: May I Now 's something?
You're a psychiatrist, right?
- Yes, Chris Van Outryve.
- Doctor Of Outryve true. That was t.
- Do we know each other?
- No, you've known my sister.
She has followed in your therapy.
Sofie. Sofie Marai.
Sorry
very much your sister.
Oh, some people are unhappy
born doctor. That you should know.
Yes... I do not know. We had
However much progress.
But that last leap
was not an immediate success.
Ten floors.
- Have you bought an apartment here?
- No, the architect is a friend.
- U?
- I? No, no, no...
I'm here with the mayor.
I work for him.
I have...
personal assistant, so to speak.
- Ah yes. Interesting?
- Not really.
- I'm Ann. Ann Marai.
- Sorry about your sister.
Can not pull it.
You do not save her.
It is a little
in the family, I fear.
You're also not planning
to do something stupid?
I do nothing else, doctor. I fall
which is always on the wrong men.
[BREAKING GLASS AND LAUGHTER]
Aah!
FILIP:
Okay. Everything under control.
Thank you.
- Hey, ça va?
- VINCENT: Filip?
- Filip?
- Thank you. Hey, Vincenzo.
Are you all of my other party?
Sorry my friend in the champagne
is flown. I imagine.
This is a colleague
from 't agency.
And that is a colleague
from beneath the desk.
Oei, oei, my brother is
give me all on my roof.
- Bye, Chris. Everything good?
- Yes. Vicky girlfriends? If you babysit?
I can not even benefit.
I'm still single.
I love to see Vicky. But I am
someone else is not evil.
It is good that you're here. I would you
like something. Come 's it.
- Where and Marnix Luc?
- I do not know.
Chris? Will not you come?
VINCENT: Voilà.
[ONE FLUTE APPROVAL]
- What do you think?
- CHRIS: Chic.
MARNIX: Beautiful, young.
What is the intention here?
Even setting. But it is here
an oasis of calm in the city.
FILIP: There is still much to your oasis.
A place where nobody can bother you,
where you can meet with whoever you want.
Would that be fun? This place
you... How could I say?
- Time can steal.
- Time steal?
- Should I be selling?
- Would you like to keep yourself?
- With a few friends, for example.
- What for?
These waiters are not here,
sure? I go back.
Give me your key. Then I let Philip
chicks all over the apartment.
Laureys, stay here.
These are serious girls. Hey.
Do you know what that cost?
- Why hire a loft?
- Nobody should know what you are doing here.
The idea that somewhere
you go, in silence.
- Do not be silly. You know what I mean.
- I'm not. You know.
- By the way, not Luc, I think.
- Are not we all a little something?
Or do not we all like
so want to be a little bit?
Yes, if you say so...
You can also your newspaper
be read, eh. What is that?
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
I have here. I can not.
- I can not stay here.
- Where are you going? Luc?!
You can not let go.
It is not the time!
- We must through. As agreed.
- Quiet!
- Luc, we must not panic.
- It's over. Realize that still!
- It's all true!
- False. We will solve that.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[VOICEMAIL]
Filip. Leaving a message.
I call back.
Shit, man. What do we do if he
not come? If he has to walk?
Filip come. He must come.
Can not otherwise.
And if it was like last?
We can not continue to protect him.
Men.
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
Man, what is that?
What does that mean?
Chris, what does that mean?
[SILENT VOICES:]
[FATUM NOS IUNGEBIT]
- Interviewer: Do you know Latin, doctor?
- CHRIS: Sorry?
If you know Latin?
Yes. Yes, I... I know Latin. Yeah, sorry.
Ah. Then you may tell us
what is written on the wall.
Fatum iungebit nos.
Yes... I can also read.
But what does it mean? Huh?
Fatum nos iungebit,
fate will unite us.
Fate. Or death. As you wish.
In its written in blood.
Now it appears that the victim
not really the type that knows Latin.
So it is possible
that somebody else wrote it.
But with her finger, huh. So.
Someone who knows Latin, doctor.
- Fatum nos iungebit is wrong.
- What do you wrong?
The imperfect future tense
of the verb commit, iungere,
is not iungebit but iunget. It would thus
should read: Fatum iunget nos.
The one you are looking for a classic
error made by the Latin.
But did you know
probably even themselves?
Do you know the word fuck you?!
That is not Latin,
but that means you too, right?
Where is your brother, doctor?
Everyone is here except it.
We get him not to tackle.
I do not know where he is. Sorry.
- It is actually your half brother, right?
- Yes.
Same mother, different father.
Sat youth settings with his sister.
They are placed
After the death of mother and...
- Filip had less luck with his father.
- Apparently.
A serious alcoholic.
Hit his children.
Much contact you had not.
And now you are the best friends.
Yes. We have...
lot to catch up.
VINCENT: What is that? "It will be our destiny
connect. " Is that for us? Chris?
Is that for us?
Where is Filip, dammit?
- Everyone is there except him.
- CHRIS: How do I know where he is?
What the fuck is this?
It is from here.
This is a knife here.
That goes to our heads
chain.
- Where is Philippe? Goddamn, huh.
- FILIP: What do you think?
Can someone tell me
what happened here?
- You, asshole. Sadist!
- What is it, friend? Hey. What is it?
Stop! It is not 't moment.
Touch me one more time
and you can lie down next to it, Janet.
- Filip, have you had anything to do?
- Why should I?
If you 're good lawyer
need, will...
- I do not need a lawyer.
- Quiet, Filip.
- Have you been here tonight?
- No.
I slept
with my parents. Call Vicky.
What took you so long?
As I stood on a building site
my father. I could not just away.
Nice when some blètsmoel
your voice is.
- "There lies my corpse in the loft."
- I don 't know.
And where have you been? For you
accuses everyone. Where were you?
- I was home yesterday.
- Yes? Witnesses?
Do not believe me? No, no witnesses.
Barbara is in Les Arcs with the children.
If any of us something
faces, that he had then said.
Now is the time. Now.
[FESTIVE MUSIC]
- VICKY: Thank you, beautiful.
- Guest: Congratulations.
MARNIX: Filip has also
to his stretcher. Since I drink.
- LUC: Who is his father?
- CHRIS: He there.
VINCENT: Ludwig Tyberghein, Dad Concrete.
Construction projects from here to Tokyo.
Stinking rich. It is his only daughter.
- So Filip is as if in a house?
- Yes... He looks very happy.
Come on, Chris, that looks
still a good girl?
Here. He is also, though.
Two Perfect Match.
Since Van Esbroeck mayor,
Tyberghein builds the city of.
- It was still open to you?
- In order to show his mug chic.
But vetpotten divide them
under their own architects.
You should not play with
the big boys? This is ugly, huh.
They would not actually do.
As you can paint houses.
Hey, my beautiful costume.
[DRAMATIC ACCENT IN MUSIC]
[LAUGHTER AND BIRDS]
[ON THE BACKGROUND]
Nice, huh? Do not you?
Such a chic wedding?
Money can not buy happiness. This is
poor people want what they believe.
- Is not that so?
- Yes...
VICKY:
Guys, you lost him now.
- It's mine now.
- LUC: Congratulations, Vicky.
- You need either a special chosen.
- I know. I will tame him.
- Hey, honey?
- Of course.
The bird is in my cage
and I have the key.
MARNIX:
But a golden cage,
eh, buddy.
- Can I say?
- Yeah, sure. Whatever.
Next month
Filip should start with my dad.
[ADORING PROCLAMATION]
Gone to two hours in your nest
to lie stink. Mee sell houses.
Watch out or I'll throw you out.
I Crapule as security for you.
Let's go
some open envelopes.
- No, I stay with the friends.
- Yes. Ok. Ciao.
Just enough kakvoIk seen.
VINCENT: Filip...
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
- My present.
- Really?
Take care.
There are only five copies.
Accepting the key,
is accepting the rules.
- Our women are here. Are you crazy?
- The loft is off.
A present from me
to all of you.
You're not, eh? If not
for now, perhaps later.
How does this life?
Lucske? Huh?
Make sure it is not
explodes in your face.
- Our own loft.
- Now have to find someone who wants to go.
There is plenty of choice around here otherwise.
Rich voIk poops clean, man.
Now, that young thing. Look, look.
With that black hair and green dress.
- That I have to pull my waistcoat.
- That is seventeen...
No, that is eighteen
go there and stay off.
- Why? You again or what?
- This is Sharon.
- Is it Sharon? Vel-on-leg-Sharon?
- Yes, yes, that's Sharon.
Is that your little sister?
This is a beautiful child become man.
A few summers and you can pick.
- Although, it is already ripe.
- Marnix, it is enough.
- What?
- It is enough. It is enough.
The seeds of a size
can not hurt, eh.
- I'm thirsty. We drink something?
- I get something.
- Pint?
- Pint.
- If you do not talk about my sister, okay?
- Yes.
I believe 't. Insert a finger from
and you're 't seed size of your lost.
- Understand?
- Yes, Filip.
Ouch!
That was a joke, eh, man. Zot.
[DUCK KWAK]
ANN: Hi, Chris.
- CHRIS: Bye.
- I do not know if you still know,
but we have each other
al 's met at an opening.
- Yes, I remember. Ann Marai.
- So you know me? That's nice.
You now also works on weekends.
The mayor should be happy.
The mayor is the pot.
You're something more
then his assistant, huh?
And what do you mean,
Mr. psychiatrist?
Have you seen something else perhaps?
- You do not really happy.
- Ah bon?
It is not really fun at
such a festival always just walk around.
Soon as you're alone with him, you
of course in the first place.
But gradually you realize
you probably
forever will be his mistress.
He says his wife
is left for me.
Is he saying that?
How long?
I 've told you so.
I always fall on the wrong men.
Shall I 's something? A secret.
Something that remains between us.
You know where he kicks,
our good mayor?
He finds' t great
at places like this
my slip to keep
in his pocket.
It excites him. If he sees me,
knowing that nothing I aanheb
under my dress.
Jesus. I do not
that you do so late.
Who says I do leave?
Perhaps it excites me to do.
Maybe I find it exciting
I tell it to you.
But not sure you catch cold.
Chris, sorry. Yes, I do not know why...
I do not know why I said that.
- Maybe I wanted to test if so.
- I do not need to be tested.
Would I 's talk with you?
In a coffee or something.
Somewhere undisturbed. Please?
[APPLAUSE]
[ADMIRING SHRIEKS AND WHISTLES]
Vincent, that key,
I would do it 's like to use.
Not what you think.
I bring him back as soon as possible.
Chris, I think it is never covered.
Have fun.
VINCENT: Wait, men, come...
Does anyone have his key?
- FILIP: Sure.
- Seriously. Let us think logically.
There are five keys.
To one to make, we have
a code. That is in my safe.
There is not broken, so the
security, everyone has his key?
You think that we distribute our keys?
It's against the rules. Your rules.
- Can anyone show his key?
- What do you mean to reach?
Maybe someone lost him. That
we exclude. Here is mine.
[JINGLE OF KEYS]
Where is your key, Chris?
- You have not received them.
- I told him not to. Good?
Where is he, Chris?
I told him not to. Okay?
I have him every day.
- But you still have it?
- That is not important.
We have only four.
Where is the fifth?
Somebody
entered with a key?
Yes? How do you explain that the alarm
cede? What does that mean?
That person who
within the code has also been hit.
- Unless... She admitted him.
- Yes. And how did they got in then?
What you talking at it,
you always come back to us.
I would like to know now gradually
Who of us remain silent.
- MIRIAM: And what's that you say?
- BARBARA: Polyamory.
- That you have different relationships.
- And your boss does that?
He has a wife and a girlfriend
and who also know each other.
He says: I see my wife happy,
my girlfriend. Why should I choose?
- And the woman accepts?
- Yes.
What a silly kalle is that?
[DRUNK]
LUC: That would fuck something
to us, boys. "Polyamarie.
Here, the thick. Can a woman not
the boss. What would you do with two?
- CHRIS: Can you show a little enthusiasm?
- ELLEN: It's your party.
- Besides, I have to cook.
- Do not.
Chris, if you per se
To invite your friends,
please be at home at least.
It took a little longer at work.
You know how it goes?
And what should I do
for a little attention?
Me into your clinic?
It is not that they see the door plate.
Come have fun while sitting.
Do it for me.
I hope not that fat
whole living under throws up.
He zuipt whiskey like water.
Does not his wife?
Well, Polyamory, all well and good,
but his wife has him get caught
- And threw him out.
- What a calf, that boss of yours.
He should keep his mouth.
You must organize, not you, Vince?
Luke: How is it over?
Now he lives in an apartment
with the woman of his life.
She is 22, blond and fake breasts.
So typically, men
fake breasts like it.
Broads, huh, that's always the same
with that stuff about fake boobs...
If that is done well,
is it good?
My mom has false teeth.
Are we also to say,
as she laughs: Oei, oei, oh, so false.
No, people will say:
That is well done.
You look better as before.
This is an improvement.
That is always the same.
These women and are always so jealous.
- Marnix...
- The greatest thing there is a beautiful woman.
ELLEN: Sorry, the level is
little too high for me.
For much philosophy
My mind is too small.
Maybe you should let it increase.
And let your mouth go up.
- That a smile is off.
- Marnix.
Well, Miriam, I really admire you.
You've selected the best.
You know what it is? That guy
had better get better organized.
That would be better.
You must organize. Eh, boys?
Yeah, okay, good.
How would you organize you?
Yes, you must ensure that you find a place
where they can not catch you.
That is the key... That is the key of...
of time. Of Stealing time.
It seems like you already have
considered. Soon we get ideas.
Hey, Vince... Vincy Boy...
Not drivel, eh, buddy.
Hey. Krik Krak. Key in the pocket.
The key of the...
Marnix.
CHRIS:
Let's get some air.
That will do you good.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry, boys.
Do not worry with. You know he
just as drunk as he has.
Why did not I guy like you?
[SNORT]
- LUC: Ouch... Sorry.
- No problem.
I was a little uncomfortable
of the starter. That thai...
This is spicy, huh.
That can cut through your nose.
Yes, indeed, yes. Whatever.
We need to get new insulin.
This is low.
Luc, is something
you must tell me?
- What would I have to tell you?
- Do you keep secrets from me?
Of course not.
Is there anyone else
you like to see?
- You can tell me.
- Why are you so weird questions?
- No, I do not cheat.
- But I asked, do you, Luc.
I asked if anyone else was
you like... Au...
Elsie, I am perhaps not so
exciting and thrilling as the rest,
but I will do
always for you. Always.
For you and for the children.
I would not know what I
should do without you, Luc.
I endured many.
LUC: What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- VINCENT: They should get out.
I can not. She hangs down.
You see that? Damn.
Can you not see what's going on?
Someone trying to manage our lice.
- Who would like us to lice?
- Think 's post.
A body attached to a cuff,
that spell, that knife. In our loft.
Who knows more of our dates?
Has anyone betrayed?
- You, Marnix?
- What? Why me?
- With your drunken balls or something?
- No. Are you crazy?
- I have always complied with the regulations.
- Also no one told the code?
- If someone typed while looking?
- No. Why you looking at me?
What do you really say?
Maybe someone wants revenge.
Someone who wants everything suits.
Who would
want to take revenge?
I do not know. Someone her husband, a
jealous boyfriend, my rejected lover.
Is there anyone of us in trouble?
[EXCITING MUSIC]
[PANTING AND MOANING]
- I love you.
- Oh, that sounds pathetic, huh.
No.
You are one of the good.
A little strange to say,
given the circumstances.
I do not know.
- Whose is this loft anyway?
- From a friend.
- He is abroad.
- Long apparently.
I love you, Ann.
To me you
not say things like that, Chris.
- I believe it.
- Yes... Why?
Because you think you talking to say?
I've never cheated on my wife.
I'm not in love quickly.
I do not want love. We see
display only exciting moments.
- This is not life.
- I would like to give it a chance, Ann.
If you are not silent,
I say mean things.
I'm sick of the lies.
All that sneaky stuff.
Ellen and I want to tell everything...
and I go away with her.
You can only hurt
who likes to see you.
I will never hurt you, Ann.
But I am talking not about you.
You know me.
- Give me the chance to meet you.
- I'm a whore, Chris. Okay?
I go to bed with men for money.
That is what I am. A whore.
- What do you say now?
- Do not worry.
I will send you an invoice
for the past few months.
- What do you say now?
- Leave it. You know half yet.
- SPEAKER: Chris his wife cheating?
- MARNIX: I doubt it, ma'am.
He is a devoted husband...
Interrogators:
And an exemplary family man, as though
your friends? Starting up a shop.
But you've surely
mispeuterd what, huh, pal?
Why does your wife
separate from you?
Separation has been said.
We're just a little while apart.
- Why?
- My wife has found out something...
- Which they... Where she is angry.
- You have deceived her?
If you do still
so technically would make... Yes.
- And how did they learn?
- The person with whom I had...
- Who have you deceived her.
- Right.
He had apparently
more expected after that incident.
She suddenly stood on our doorstep
and that stupid...
The lady in question
everything is starting to tell.
I hope my wife forgives me quickly,
because I see her happy.
Cheating is all nothing,
it is true, eh.
- Have you been with her to the loft?
- No, that's happened in Düsseldorf.
- In Düsseldorf?
- Why were you there?
There was a lounge building.
Vince had a few vipkaarten
and there were about two. A few nights
in a chic hotel, away from home.
- And you were one of the lucky ones?
- Yes... I was one of the lucky ones, yes.
MARNIX: You dare not. 100. 200.
They are all the time
watching you.
Invite them. You may have her,
I get the surplus.
- LUC: In your dreams.
- These girls do not interest me.
You can run them inside,
if you want.
- Too easy.
- Come on.
I fall more for women
which are worthwhile. The special.
- Looking like the unknown islands.
- Look, there.
The entire island group. An atoll.
Vince, Barbara knows that you sometimes
go to discovery?
- Why would I want to hurt her?
- Seynaeve, quiet, eh, man.
You need a key to the loft.
What are you doing? The dishes?
ANJA: Look, even Belgians
in the hotel, I hear.
My name is Anja. I wait
a colleague on the desk.
- It's expensive, huh.
- You want some of us drink?
Oh, yes, that is kind.
Can that be anything but a pint?
- What you drinking? Is that champagne?
- Yes.
Vince, will soon drive them
all the pretty chicks away, huh, man.
[GERMAN]
A glass of champagne.
Every ugly girl
has a beautiful girlfriend.
Yes, and if it is the most beautiful?
Look, look, look, look...
It is not true. Concrete is also Papa.
And not with Mom Concrete, apparently.
- All men are the same, eh.
- So much wisdom, as I drink.
You are a strange kwiet, though.
[GERMAN]
MR. Tyberghein: A bottle of champagne
and four glasses for the table back.
You were still
at the wedding of Vicky?
Friends of Filip.
You are the architect.
- Vincent Stevens. I have...
- I know.
Perhaps we 's agree on something.
I can always use an architect.
- Great, Mr.. Tyberghein.
- I have a big project in Antwerp.
On the Left Bank.
Apartment blocks. Luxury Apartments.
Very trendy and all that nonsense. It would
perhaps you can be.
But for
is still very secret.
So I hope that you .. can be discreet.
- It would be challenging...
- Anonymity, Mr. Stevens.
I stress.
Sapienti dictum est sat.
A good listener
has only half words.
- Are you a good listener?
- Absolutely, absolutely.
I'm in the software
and I can very discreet.
[GERMAN]
Put the drink from these people
but on my account.
- Gentlemen, nice extension.
- Thank you
Miss...
Who does this asshole think he is?
Sapienti dictum, my balls.
Here, here.
There is still a discovery.
That is the whore of the mayor,
Marnix.
[CHRIS COMPATIBILITY IN NUMBER.]
[MOBILE PHONE RINGS]
[VOICEMAIL]
Hi, this is Ann Marai.
Messages after the beep.
Who are you calling so late?
- Nothing. Nobody. Voicemail.
- Your voicemail?
And what did your voicemail? "You're a
bad liar, Chris Van Outryve?
- Why do you ask? Is there anything?
- I do not know.
Maybe I should ask you that.
Ellen...
I go to sleep.
- Do you know the lights?
- Ellen.
ANJA: Men only think
with that thing between their legs.
MARNIX: What is
Women in leaves? Two things.
What a pig men
and how to seduce them.
Why a whole pig
to take home
but if you do
a very small piece need?
[PROMISING ACCENT IN MUSIC]
SARAH: I can leave alone for a minute.
A minute? Sarah, honey,
I am here for an hour waiting for you.
Luckily I am sponsored.
Would you not think
your new friends? Huh?
- SPEAKER: Was that the first time you saw her?
- VINCENT: Yeah, that was the first time.
- Sarah Delporte.
- Sarah, yeah.
Interrogators:
What else happened in Düsseldorf?
- What do you know?
- Everything.
[LAUGHTER]
- LUC: If they catch us, we fly out.
- VINCENT: Sarah...
SARAH:
You did not need to challenge.
- Ah, voilà, the swimming pool.
- Vince, we go back?
- Soon we will be sorry.
- Come, Luc.
- It's still very exciting?
- A little too exciting for me.
Come on, Vincent. Undress.
Yes... Yes, you wanted to swim naked. We have
bet, so now I want my prize.
I feel my prawns come back.
Why? You've seen nothing yet.
Believes that you?
Anja?
[LAUGHTER]
Yes...
- Voilà.
- What, voilà!
- Still?
- Yes, still.
Yes, that's not bad actually
for an old guy.
- You like to play games.
- Who plays games like this?
So challenge me
not you need to imagine themselves.
As if all that I...
Oh... Hey!
Come on. Now you. Come.
Luc, it is always exciting
or whatever you feel more at ease?
- Good, huh?
- Blessed.
- Luc, do not you join?
- No, I'm good.
Yes, but Luc,
I have you actually... necessary,
Vincent will for now
inside me trying to do.
If you're here,
afraid he might not.
- You're a really rude nest.
- Is it right? Huh?
All throughout the evening compliments
and then that naughty look.
Do it again, you look.
That eye contact network
little too long... Really.
- Vincent, you're very kind.
- I agree.
Did you really
it 's green light was on?
- Sorry, now imagine what disappointed me.
- You really like to play games.
You know what?
I am better than you.
- Feel me?
- Yes.
Marnix? Are you here? Marnix?
I would like the key to our room.
[GROAN]
- Marnix.
- Luc, let's do, boy.
SARAH: You're scared. Flight
for what you feel. Is it not? Huh?
I will not say goodbye.
Sorry it is so
should end, Sarah.
Can you really?
Someone like?
Sorry.
- Why throw that away?
- Because it is empty.
You were here yesterday, huh, dude?
If you were here, why do you
that? We are your friends.
She was still here when I left.
She was still alive.
There, someone come after me.
Say so. You make
the situation even worse now.
We need the police.
- We can not solve themselves.
- Zot! What we say to them?
And against our women?
- Vince needs something, I think.
- Ah? What do you say, Vincent?
[DOORBELL]
Fuck.
[CONTINUE PUSHER RING]
Come on, pick up.
Hello.
Who is it?
A real estate office. For the loft.
- He's for sale.
- What?
- You see I'm right. Goddamn.
- Chris, why?
She has an appointment
with a certain Sarah Delporte.
Who is Sarah Delporte?
Guests, who is that?
And who has now put on sale?
It?
- You know her, Marnix.
- What? What do you say now?
That you know her.
And also Luc.
Sarah Delporte is there.
- I've never seen that man.
- You're lying, you know her.
- Why do you say that?
- From in Düsseldorf.
A few months ago,
that last evening in the bar.
It was the girlfriend of that Anja.
- I was fahsnickered. I know nothing more.
- I know, Marnix.
- But not you, eh, Luc?
- Is that her?
[DOORBELL]
Damn.
- Do not be silly. You've talked it.
- How do I know that she is?
I do not know who it is.
You have it reversed. Not me.
- You know her or not?
- If there is a corpse,
do you not think of a girl you
something you saw in a hotel.
He is twisting the facts.
Do you understand that?
[DOORBELL]
Ma'am? You are mistaken.
We do not know Sarah Delporte.
Come, Filip.
[SOUND OF BOATS AND MEEUWEN]
- You know her?
- I can not see shit.
Who is that young?
Who is that?
That was it, Vincent?
What you had to tell us?
We have had something, okay?
I brought her here you go.
But I swear on my eyes
children, I have nothing to do.
In the eyes of your children?
Jesus, man.
Were you here yesterday with her? Were you
person who has brought her?
I will not say goodbye.
I've been last night. Yes.
Vincent nevertheless...
[BREAKING GLASS]
I swear,
I left her alive.
And even that does not explain
why someone our loft for sale.
[EXCITING MUSIC]
ANN: Looking for something special sir
or he just looks around?
Why you call me back?
If you dump me, then I
at least the guts to say it.
Chris, how can I dump you now?
We have nothing together.
Ah, was it? Nothing? Ok.
Let us not difficult.
You know what I am.
It does not matter who or what you are.
Really not, Ann.
How many women have you
taken to the loft?
Loft that you share with your friends.
Keep your shit
that takes you to the next.
Wait. Ann, you know
I am not so. You know.
- I've already seen lying better than you.
- Wait.
Here. That I only need
if we go together.
Keep him. If you want to see me,
I hear it.
Elsie: Chris? What are you doing here?
Are you shopping for Ellen?
Day, Elsie. No,
I was here with a colleague of mine.
- SPEAKER: Does your wife that you share a loft?
- LUC: Again, I share no loft.
I am once been
at the opening of the building.
Interrogators:
You're it been? Just
you said you knew where it was.
I've never you go
taken. I thought you meant.
- Did you know that girl?
- I met her in Düsseldorf.
Did you know Mr. Stevens
something started with her?
That would surprise me.
Are you sometimes jealous when your good friend
Vincent beautiful women inside who does?
I'm married.
No, I'm not jealous of him.
No, no, not at him, sir Seynaeve.
I mean jealous of women.
What say you?
What are you doing?
Where do you get the nerve
to insinuate such things?
- Why so hard?
- Vincent is my best friend.
- It's always been like that.
- Your friend is betraying the whole gang.
Vincent would never betray his friends.
But what you say. Asshole.
- VINCENT: What do you call me?
- You heard me, asshole. Accuse me...
I told her it was over
and when I left.
- And that's it.
- That's it?
Yes.
You have
put a serious point behind.
And if you wanted to tell us,
Vince? Huh?
Put the knife down, Filip.
Do not be silly.
- Filip!
- I do not know what happened afterwards.
I swear.
I have nothing to do.
Maybe I was not the only,
Perhaps there is someone,
- And who wants to move in our shoes.
- In your shoes, definitely.
Hey! Man...
It appears that it
your problem is, Vincent.
Do not you see what happens here?
Why would they agree
with a broker for our loft?
On the day she is dead
found. But by coincidence, huh.
Men, we can not
continue. Everything comes from.
What will you do differently, Marnix?
Going it alone leave me?
[KNOCKING]
Vincent? Are you there?
Vince, let me in, please.
- Are you crazy? I'm here with someone.
- Miriam is away.
- Why, Miriam is away?
- Yes. She has let me down.
She knows he of Düsseldorf.
That fat is to tell everything.
- Vince, you must help me.
- Miriam Know the loft?
What? Of course not.
It has happened in Düsseldorf.
You were there at the pool. Vince,
Miriam is away. What should I do?
- I can not live without her, not you, Vince.
- You do not have anything yet?
Rule one, never confess. Your hurts
she mean. They understand that.
Vince, you can not even
talk to her?
Can you not say... I
and see her like that Anja is lying?
- You will believe it, Vince.
- I will try that, okay?
[HUILT]
- It's good.
- I see her a lot, Vince.
I make sure 't is in order.
But I hope fucking
she does not know that, huh.
- You have put us in this situation.
- I have never so intended.
- What now?
- They should get out.
And we all tracks.
- We can not let disappear.
- That is the only solution.
You have to hear.
You had a relationship with her
and she is now evidence
that can spoil your beautiful life.
- What kind of person are you?
- I have no lessons to receive from you.
How do you get her off the bed?
Hand abandoned?
- If you have the keys to the cuffs?
- No, I have no keys.
I thought handcuffs
were more your thing.
- What do you mean?
- You know what I mean.
[WOMAN WAILS]
FILIP: Silence!
- Shut up, damn it!
- WOMAN: Help me.
That slut think
they can play with my balls.
- Help me, please.
- Shut up.
[HUILT]
He is crazy.
- He raped me.
- Calm down.
- Give me the key.
- That bitch wanted to the police.
- The key!
- The key? Here is the key.
Here is the key.
I wanted things done.
- He has forced me.
- Shut up!
What is it?
Want more money? Is that it?
Here is your money.
Have you gone mad?
On your head cases?
It is a whore, Chris.
And you know what it is with whores?
You can not rape.
That is so. Huh?
Damn.
If you treat a wife, asshole.
No!
- What about you?
- Do not touch me.
You're certainly not me.
You should see yourself busy, dammit!
You're stiff from the coke,
you save women.
You realize that you are not us
jeopardize that? Do you realize that?
- I want police. He has beaten me.
- Stop it!
- He raped me.
- Shut up!
If you do not keep your mug,
I save him close.
You're damn
no better than your old.
Oh. Oh, Chris. Yes, yes... Chris had
more luck, eh, with his dad. Huh?
You always around the world
To help save everyone... Huh?
Where were you? Where were you when we
were beaten in each other? Huh?
And while mother did
if she heard nothing.
- Safe in Leuven. There you were.
- Goddamn.
You... You have your
never attracted to us.
Never. I had to protect my sister.
We meant nothing to you.
- We meant nothing to you!
- I knew nothing of it.
- If I had known...
- What then?
Then I had you
there away, damn!
[WOMAN IS CRYING]
Sorry.
We can not go to the police.
I'll take you
a friend of mine, a doctor.
Aah!
[WOMAN HUILT]
Vincent, give me everything you have.
Here is 700 euros. It is not enough
for what happened today,
but it may help to forget.
He is a beast! He is in jail!
- I want police.
- We fix it up.
Wait... Wait...
Take it even.
It is very valuable.
Take it.
See? That's what she wanted. Money.
I make a mistake
if you do not keep your mug.
Take your clothes.
We go to a doctor.
I do not need your doctor.
You gave me something to do today
I will never forgive you. Never.
I'll pay you the watch back.
What is the problem?
[HUILT]
Why do we know anything about?
When did that happen?
Two weeks back. We would
it to ourselves. Eh, Filip?
- Some friends we are.
- I have nothing to learn from you.
- Certainly not about friendship.
- So I was silent.
I thought you
have been received.
- Sat, stoned, reared.
- Kiss my balls.
- Would not you stop with that coke?
- Would you not stop boozing?
Enough.
You should have heard yourself.
That's what they want.
Us against each other up.
Someone wants to destroy us.
Men, I'm afraid
I also have something to say.
But would first
Filip stop anyone?
- Au!
- Filip!
You had to be good, boy.
Luc, what do you all now?
You had it asked
to be honest? Everything on the table.
- Well, I'm honest. Everything on the table.
- And where are they, Luc?
And what did you do that?
What did you do that?
[TL-LIGHTS JUMPING ON]
[DOOR CREAKS]
MARNIX: Jesus.
Say it is not true, eh. Goddamn.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
Goddamn, Luc.
So you take down everything here
happen? Every woman we take?
Not always. Sometimes.
- And if you? If the program you like?
- I do not cheat my wife.
- No, just you watch.
- You're sick.
You're sick.
You have raped a prostitute.
- I like it in pictures. You're sick.
- Filip, we sit here in.
- Remember what we said.
- Where are the pictures, Luc? Here?
Soon I want you all the material,
destroys all DVDs. Together with us.
Otherwise I can not fuck
not care whether this is correct or not.
You have pictures of yesterday?
You know what happened?
No, you do not warn us.
This is against your own rules.
As you do more
against your own rules.
Now you're scared, huh. I fear that images
have everything you've done here.
You do not worry, Vince.
I am your friend.
Your best friend. I am silent.
I always silent in all languages.
- I already knew what you were. Fatboy!
- Oh, boy.
- You lay on your horny friends.
- You know nothing of me. Nothing. Zero.
Did you see anything? Something us
can help? You know what happened?
If people who cheated
hurt each other and find
what do you think happens?
- What do you mean?
- What do you think?
[CROUPIER SUBMIT BETTING FIXED]
- VINCENT: What is it, mouse?
- I do not want to leave tomorrow.
- No sense to go skiing?
- I do not want to go alone.
- The kids go along anyway.
- Yes... You know what I mean. Huh?
You do not go, baby?
I love you.
And all the rest is irrelevant.
- Why, all the rest is irrelevant?
- Everything. Everything is not important.
Call you every day. I promise.
- CHRIS: I know. One hour. No longer.
- ELLEN: You do what you want. Do not mind me.
I just enjoy every moment
we are still together.
Have you already planned
you lose
if you choose something
you not know?
[APPLAUSE]
FILIP: Oh God, for good purpose
Concrete Mama may come along.
Have you heard anything
Left of that project?
- The planning application is approved.
- They do not call back.
I'm not important enough
for the big boys, eh.
But they know me yet.
[MURMUR]
- Ladies...
- MAYOR: That's Vincent Stevens, architect.
- From that building the Tavernierkaai.
- WOMAN OF THE MAYOR: Ah, you know?
This is a fantastic design.
Beautiful. Congratulations.
- MW. Tyberghein: Congratulations.
- Thank you
I was still on
with your husband, in Düsseldorf.
Too bad you were not there.
You then told me about a project
on the Left Bank, Mr.. Tyberghein.
You would still call me there.
We are working on. We have
submitted a planning application and so...
- We will see. We hope. Like everybody.
- Fantastic.
- Are you a gambler, Mr.. The mayor?
- And you, take you to risks?
Depends on the bet.
And what the other has to lose.
How did you weather?
Sapienti sat dictum est? Something?
Ladies, may I
very good luck in the game,
for in love you
absolutely no need, eh.
Men...
Make sure you have something to keep
for maintenance, fat.
- Miriam, what are you doing here?
- Once on step.
I need my home
do not lock?
Please, I would
love to come back.
I have committed a blunder.
I know. I was Sat
- That all had nothing to do.
- I do not understand men.
If it has nothing to do, why
do you t then? Good for those girls.
- I change.
- In what? In a frog?
Or in the mussel you already are?
How would you feel if I said
I feel like going to strange?
Maybe I already did. With
one of your friends. For revenge.
With Chris, for example.
If no... With Vincent.
You have me afgestuurd
to 's talking to me.
"Oh, Miriam. He looks so much off. "
Come on, your luck can not. You
won. But half is mine.
[EXCITING MUSIC]
VICKY: Oh, 21.
- Did you Sharon maps?
- You're hurting me.
I say no
and you give them behind my back.
- And then? Are you her dad?
- Have you seen them running there?
- Just a whore.
- I thought you geilde them.
- What?
- Leave her alone. Let her do.
They are fun. And if you want me
excuse, I will do the same. I win.
You'll 'need it.
As you hunt through your nose...
Here. The pot calling the kettle.
Save yourself enough.
You'll rapper
than I need.
You know what you doing?
Ask the separation, bitch.
Separation, Filip? And then?
While we have no children,
you get nothing. Fool.
Here. Try different 's on the roulette.
Perhaps you are so rich.
[MOBILE PHONE RINGS]
Ann?
[DOOR OPENS]
We need 's talk, doctor.
- Yes, what about then?
- Your friend, the architect...
He plays' s dangerous game.
He must watch them as great.
Would you like to tell him that he
there should be very careful?
I thought that this was going to Ann.
[DOOR OPENS]
Excuse us.
I wish you would not see her.
- And why should I do?
- I see her happy.
- You're not alone.
- U. .. You pay for it.
- I want you to let her go.
- You do realize that they make that choice.
We are poor souls who delighted
can with what they give us.
- I've never paid for her.
- That is true what you say.
- You've never paid for her. You do not.
- ANN: Alex, silence.
Do not forget the message
disseminating it to your friend, doctor?
What does he mean,
"You do not?
- I would not like you, Chris.
- What does he mean?
If he says I have not paid?
Only you
that can hurt me. Yes?
Ann, say that's not true.
Come on. Hey?
The first time was paid.
Only the first time I was the whore.
- All other times I was.
- Paid by whom?
[DOOR OPENS]
[EXCITING MUSIC]
- FILIP: Excuse me. Sharon, keep up, now.
- Filip, I'm fine.
- I want you to come along.
- Leave me alone.
- MAN: Hey, dude. Are you deaf?
- Mind your own business.
- Sharon, come.
- OTHER MAN: She will not, pipo.
Pipo? State that
on my head or what? Huh?
Hey, dude.
- It is not on, huh.
- Stop it.
It is not on. Fuck.
MR. Tyberghein: What happens?
- Okay, it's good. Los, los.
- Take him away.
Now. I want to see you again.
Have you heard right, friend?
No more. Buffoon.
Who is that girl?
Sarah, is not it...
It is not what you think.
What do I do?
This is the sister of a friend of mine.
She's just attacked.
- Are there?
- Do not be silly.
This is the sister of one of
my best friends. One child.
Who do you love me?
I'm just not.
I can not stand.
My wife is here.
- You see me happy?
- On my way.
- On your way. And if you had to choose?
- Sarah, that is not so simple.
We talk tomorrow.
Barbara is one weeks away.
Then we can safely
talk further. Okay?
I'll easily
places to choose?
Why?
Sudden short pain.
What are you doing?
Sarah.
[MUSIC SWELLS]
LUC: Oh, excuse me.
Did I hurt you?
Do not, eh.
You'll regret it.
Jesus. They know.
They are our wives.
Our women have framed us.
CHRIS: Why, Vincent?
Because they have been behind the loft.
Because they have been discovered.
Because everything is released.
[VINCENT IS TURNING MACHINE]
Why did you do?
Why what?
- I tell you so.
- We are friends.
We are your friends.
[DRUGGED]
They are our wives.
They have discovered.
LUC: Not women, but your friends.
Your friends have learned.
Oeioei... Oh...
- What, men?
- You still do not understand it, huh?
FILIP: Come on, get his clothes.
- What do you do with me?
- Did you now so leave her?
- I have done what was agreed.
- Yes? Not so with all that blood.
That was not the deal. And Latin.
Will the police believe that?
- Had it myself.
- Men, stop. Soon.
- What happens?
- You must stop.
- You have killed her.
- We have not killed her.
We have just found her.
What?
- What?
- We have been here 's been today.
Morning. Without you.
- MARNIX: Jesus, man.
- LUC: I thought at first that she was asleep.
CHRIS: And Vincent knows her?
She has a farewell letter
left for him.
- We should call the police, men.
- FILIP: What?
In suicide, the parquet come.
That sucks. Everything will come out.
"See you in your next life."
We can not know where they
lives and leave her there? Huh?
Come on, we need to help Vincent, eh.
- It is our custom, come on.
- Where is he? It is his problem.
- I have not called him.
- Why, you do not call?
Why not, Luc?
Men, I must show you something.
Have you filmed us?
Have you all gone mad?
You may hit me later in each other.
Now we have no time.
I need something to show, so you
the situation will look different.
What do you mean?
We should not pay for the situation
Vincent which has brought us.
Vincent is not always
just a good friend.
Huh? What is that?
What is that?
They arrived here late.
That night he started talking to her.
She was Sat, Marnix.
He has made of abuse.
No way.
Can you not talk to her?
MIRIAM: Maybe I
already done. In revenge.
With Vincent. You have me afgestuurd
to 's with me.
It is good.
No, no...
Is that your little sister?
This is a beautiful child become man.
- How long?
- It does...
- It started after your marriage.
They saw each other regularly now.
He was the first for her.
He has her virginity.
[COVERS TUBE]
Fuck...
Nice, huh?
ANN: You know me.
But you're not, eh?
- The first time was paid.
- Paid? Paid by whom?
He has paid her
for you to get here, Chris.
ANN: You can only hurt
by people you like to see.
It has its uses.
As everyone has used it.
[BIRDS ARE CHIRPING]
FILIP: I make him break. I mean it.
- No, I mean it.
- Just be cool, eh, buddy.
If we stick to the bargain,
we have a chance.
He may not know
what we do.
- We need to pull a rope.
- We have no choice.
- We will be questioned.
- Never admit that we have loft.
They are going to play off against each
and we can never admit.
Jesus, you sound just like Vincent.
Marnix, if this is correct,
our life is also the balls.
Chris?
Okay, I join. On one condition.
I want to make sure
he was here last night.
I want to hear him say.
I give a sign. I break something.
A vase or a glass or something.
But... nothing happens to us
one hundred percent sure. Good?
So? Yeah, what do we do now?
Now we have two hours for alibis
and to ensure every scene up.
- I 't do.
- No.
No, I do it.
Really. I'm fine.
Go.
Make sure you are seen.
- Where is the farewell letter?
- I have.
You knew it, eh. All the time.
The whole time you've looked and me.
- Voyeur.
- Filip.
It's like that?
- You're no better than he. So gross.
- Be glad you know now.
No, Luc,
I am not happy that I did know.
[CHOKED AND COUGH]
Swallowing, man.
What's here
fuck happened?
What is fuck happened here?
VINCENT: Is that your little sister?
This is a beautiful child become man.
- FILIP: How long?
- LUC: It does not matter now...
[SNIFFS]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[PANTING]
[CRIES]
- Did you leave her so? Zot.
- I have done what was agreed.
Not so with all that blood?
That was not the deal. And Latin.
Will the police believe that?
You have all put scene.
All along. All setup.
You have me framed.
Dirty bastards.
My own measurements.
Why did you do it
all done, Vincent?
Fucking hypocrites. You are themselves
all liars and cheaters.
Why? In hell,
Why, Vincent?
As it was, Chris.
Because it has nothing to do.
Because I'm up there.
I'm up there.
- Am I dead?
- No, Vincent. You will not die.
She has lured you here and numb.
Then she killed herself.
But you'll survive.
Because we have sizes. Huh?
VINCENT: They framed us.
Me and Sarah. Everything is put in scene.
- Interviewer: Weird story.
- But is it so.
I would like to believe, Mr.. Stevens,
but what we need are facts.
Findings, evidence, facts.
SPEAKER:
The fact is that only your fingerprints
have found. And those of Sarah.
They have erased all traces.
The fact is that we have traces of sleeping pills and
alcohol found in you and her.
And then there are the DVDs with your
bedprestaties. Impressive collection.
Luc has made those shots.
I knew nothing of it. Nobody.
Unfortunately
are the only pictures of you
Not the wife of Marnix,
not the sister of Philippe. From anyone.
- Do we still get away?
- Filip, you could just attach it.
- She was already dead.
- Is that a reason for her to maim?
She committed suicide.
I made it more dramatic.
Hopefully that will
us not into trouble.
What he says
against the police, keep silent.
Luc is right. That was not necessary.
I hope
that we do not regret it.
VINCENT: Under Ask them. You're it
to the question, put them under pressure.
- Marnix known. Luc maybe.
- Interviewer: We have interviewed them.
There is no reason
to assume that they lie.
SPEAKER:
And they have one thing that you did not.
They have an alibi.
- But not this morning?
- Wrong.
Luc Seynaeve and Chris Van Outryve
are seen in a cafe.
- Marnix Laureys was at work.
- But that can not.
In at least one hours that we
together. And Filip, where is that?
Filip is just coming to sign
with his father.
What is here?
He said that Filip was with him.
- Filip is later arrived.
- It is a conclusive alibi.
Sure Tyberghein says that.
I saw him with my other woman.
Filip knew I Tyberghein
put pressure on them...
Oh, now you blackmailed
Ludwig also Tyberghein?
All cheaters?
All bad guys?
When you stop with that nonsense?
Say what happened.
What we also know for a long time.
You have killed Sarah Delporte.
Murdered? That is not true.
I did not kill her!
Are you crazy? I did not kill her.
Mr. From Outryve, you may go.
Thanks for your cooperation.
We had the story
Your friend's check.
Yes, of course.
There is one thing
that bothers me, doctor.
Why does Vincent
his friends blame?
Yes, I have no idea.
I understand it either.
Could it be that he
trying to hide something else?
What do you mean?
That he killed her?
- Your colleagues said that it was for suicide.
- So it looked.
But according to the autopsy
has not died from the pills.
Her wrist has been cut,
but not by her.
No hesitation cuts
found, doctor.
Cuts, first attempt
someone who wants to cut his wrist.
They are not with her.
- Vincent would never do.
- His fingerprints are on the knife.
And there was no suicide note found.
Is there anything, Mr. Van Outryve?
[SOMBER MUSIC]
Her wrist has been cut,
but not by her.
His fingerprints are on the knife.
And there was no suicide note found.
- LUC: Where is the farewell letter?
- CHRIS: I took.
[INTENSE RAIN AND WIND]
[SHOCKED]
You do scare me.
Bye, Chris.
Is it wise
to be here to speak?
- Well, I think we have a problem.
- Ah.
I think our track
to have something good to delete.
What do you mean?
Where is the farewell letter from Sarah?
- You had that yet in your pocket?
- I thought. He is no more.
If you have stolen from my coat?
Just now, when she rang the bell?
[DOORBELL]
- The real estate office.
- I'm not them.
I think it's sad that you lost your letter
are, but I have nothing to do.
I've asked that office
who put our loft for sale.
They could just me
this number.
[MOBILE PHONE RINGS]
Yes, I called, yes.
- I thought we might as...
- Say it is not fucking true.
You have not called.
It is done. It's over. It is
succeeded. We should not be worried.
Why have you picked that letter?
The only real evidence
of 'r suicide.
Is it because the letter
did not write it?
Is that your handwriting is that?
Vincent gave us all
each cheated.
- Chris, you've seen the pictures.
- Yeah, I saw them.
Those images are so angry
we have made that you have followed.
What are you doing, Luc?
What happened here yesterday?
What have you done with that girl?
Is it because you and Vincent
stood? Was it your way?
It was not in the way, no. They do not.
Vincent was in the road.
Is there anyone else
you like to see, Luc?
[RAIN]
LUC: Sarah, wait. Sarah.
Forget him. Forget Vincent. He is
much better in those games than you.
- It hurts you. He uses you.
- And you need me to tell?
- Why?
- I tell you... I would never hurt you.
If you could give me the chance.
What do you say now?
I would never hurt you.
Never.
No, Luc, I know
that you would never hurt me.
And you know why? Because I
anything you could ever feel.
Do you understand? Never.
Maybe in a next life,
but not this.
So you were really here tonight?
I knew Vincent would see her.
Barbara was in France.
VINCENT: I'm sorry
that it must end, Sarah.
LUC: I waited until he left.
She was shocked when she saw me.
She was crying.
She said I was right about Vincent.
Comfort, I'm good for.
- You have given her the pills.
- These pills were a distraction.
SARAH: Luc, there is something...
What is going on?
- Air. I do not feel so good.
- It's okay.
Luc...
I gave her an overdose of insulin.
It works immediately and leaves no traces.
- Jesus, Luc.
- For love, huh, Chris.
I've done for love.
It hurt to see her happy.
[LUC HUILT]
Vincent And this dear,
you do not mind?
Vincent... Vincent is an asshole.
He has used us. About time
that he 's used.
Vincent will pay for murder.
Sarah was not dead
Filip her behind when we left.
- You can not.
- Yes.
- You're lying, Chris.
- No.
[FILIP CRIES]
I knew that I not only Filip
could leave with her. He is sick.
Asshole. Sadist!
- Sick.
- You're sick, Luc.
So if I understand correctly,
have you killed her brother?
Go home, Chris. Luc will
The lot is clean. As always.
You need nothing more clean, Luc.
It's over. It's all over.
Would you want the window open it, Chris?
[INTENSE RAIN]
- Come on, Chris, come. Hurry.
- Come, Luc.
Silence.
Down.
- What are you doing?
- Shut up.
Will you kill me?
What do you want me to do, Luc?
- You want me to jump?
- Come.
Stop it, Luc.
Ouch!
- Jesus.
- I want to hurt you. I swear.
[POLICE SIRENS]
That I called
Before I came to, Luc.
They are on the way here.
I have told everything.
You're lying.
You're on the bluff. I know you.
I thought I knew you, Luc.
And the letter from Sarah?
Is that along with me down? Huh?
Give the letter here. Give the letter here,
Chris. I do not even ask 's.
No! Aah. Au.
- Aah.
- Aargh!
- Ha.
- Aah!
[CRIES AND GROANS]
It's over, Luc.
Come, it's over.
Everything is over.
Come, Luc.
Chris, tell Elsie and the children
I've liked them all.
- Would you do that?
- Do not, Luc.
- Do it for Elsie. Please.
- No, Luc. Do not. Do not. Luc!
Luc!
[BREAKING GLASS]
[CAR ALARM]
[POLICE SIRENS]
[MURMUR]
Miriam: No, never have each other
seen. See that you do so.
- MARNIX: They are together.
- Come on. Look how he looks at her.
- They are married.
- But that is not true.
- No way, that his arrests managers.
- How can you see now?
How he is to drudge
and how she puts her head in her neck.
- Those are arrests managers.
- Persistence wins, eh.
Here, Mr. persistence. Crying
I have taken him back home.
Yes. This crooked shit is nothing,
it is true.
- Do not start, thick.
- That you should just say.
- Well, I just go.
- You drive people away with your nonsense.
I must leave. I have children
this weekend. I have many plans.
Leave me alone with my wife?
- You drink something there?
- We will drink a lot.
[SQUEALING TIRES]
ANN: Chris?
Day, Ann.
- Long ago.
- Yes.
I still have a key
that I have to give back.
I do not think that still fits.
Vincent lives there now.
That is all he
should love his wife.
- And what about your brother?
- The case is next month.
We'll see, huh.
- And you? Everything okay?
- Yes.
- Most of the time.
- Most of the time...
Yes...
I made you hard.
And I'm sorry. Really.
You can only hurt
by those who see you happy.
- I learned from you.
- I do not know whether I still believe.
You get lost by many.
Yes.
I have changed.
You even changed jobs,
I've heard.
- So you follow me a little?
- A little, yes.
A little...
You may want to me a little
to follow for a cup of coffee or something?
I am changed, Ann.
Ok.
But...
I still drink coffee.