You little motherfucker.
Get up, Zack.
Come on, I don't wanna be late
for work.
- Ahh. Get out.
- Jesus, fuck.
Close the door
if you're gonna take a shit.
- It was closed.
It was closed over,
it was not closed.
- Close the door, Zack.
- Okay, okay.
- God.
- Fine.
- What's that thing?
- It's a hand warmer.
We're going now.
- You smell that? Is
that the car? Fuck.
Oh, goddamn it.
- What? What?
- Oh, it's wedged in my taint.
- What is?
- It got wedged in my taint.
- What?
- It's stuck under my balls.
- It's between my
balls and my leg.
What's happening?
- Please, pull over.
Pull the fuck over.
Okay, all right. Jesus, okay.
- It's about to
move up to my ass.
What?
The movement makes it hotter.
It's tucked under them.
It's stuck under them.
Oh, fuck.
I think I burned
my ball hair off.
It's not funny.
Can you help me pick
out an outfit...
for tonight?
I'm working till 6.
- Well, I can try
stuff on at the store.
The store?
No, how about instead,
you get a friend?
But you are my friend.
I mean a girl friend, jeez.
Mr. Delaney,
can you work for me tomorrow?
Tomorrow's Thanksgiving.
Then you must come
in the next day.
I tell you.
- It's Black Friday.
- Black Friday?
It's the biggest
mall-shopping day...
of the year.
And since the mall is
just up the street.
I would like you to
come out and work.
- On Black Friday.
- Oh, yeah.
All right, you want me to work
on Moolie Monday too?
- I'm sorry?
- How about Nigga Tuesday?
- Nigga Tuesday?
This a new holiday?
You come to a brother
and tell him...
he gotta work on
Black Friday. You...
got any idea how
racist that sounds?
Telling me to work.
What, you think you own me?
- I never said
this, I tell you.
But you thought
it, didn't you?
You thought,
'I'm gonna lay down the law...
for this nigga, I put
food on his table,
clothes on his
nigga baby backs,
and he ain't gonna say shit.'
- This ain't Amistad.
- You shut up.
You goddamn right
this ain't Amistad.
I can't wait till
the post office...
settles my disability
suit because then
I'm gonna be out
this motherfucker.
I'm gonna be Oprah rich.
Y'all can kiss my ass.
You know what? Fuck you.
Fuck you, and suck cock.
- To hell with you.
- Zachary will
work. Zack, my boy.
Yeah.
- The customer
with the harelip--
Oh, yeah.
- -speak me, say
you were playing...
baseball here the other night.
Wiffle ball.
And, uh, no, that wasn't me.
Maybe the harelip...
makes it sound
like 'baseball.'
Yeah, maybe you
hear with an accent.
- Fuck you, okay?
- Okay.
One day, I'm gonna
put a camera...
over there, and
then I can tell--
I'll know everything you do
when I'm gone.
Everything.
Scratch your balls,
take a shit, everything,
I tell you, okay?
Okay. Fucker.
I hate both of you
ebony and ivory...
motherfuckers, I tell you.
- Why is he so
fucking high-strung?
'Fuck off, I tell
you. Very good.'
Can you believe that
Gandhi motherfucker,
telling me I gotta
work on Black Friday?
Ain't that some shit?
- Yeah.
Like I don't
wanna do shopping.
Biggest sales day
of the year. I'm...
getting a flat-screen
TV, believe that.
That's my fault, I
should tell you. I...
asked for Friday
morning off, I'm sorry.
- For what?
I actually need a
lot of recovery time.
Tonight is me and Miri's
ten-year high school reunion.
I'm just gonna
get fucking alcohol poisoning.
- Reunion? Tomorrow's
Thanksgiving.
Isn't that fucked up
that they do that?
They say it's the best chance
to get everyone together.
People come back in town
for the holidays.
But they could have it
in the middle of the summer...
at a blowjob contest
that I was judging,
and it would
still be retarded.
- So why you going, then?
- Miri's making me go.
Why you always...
bending over backwards
for that girl,
- knowing she ain't
giving up no ass?
We got a good thing going.
She pays half the
rent, does dishes,
she wakes me up
in the morning.
Why complicate that with sex?
Besides, man, I've known her
since the first grade.
You don't fuck someone
you met in the first grade.
Excuse me,
I met my wife in kindergarten.
We got married senior year,
and she has been the queen
of my world ever since.
- What if you could
do it all over again?
I'd jerk off and
live by myself.
That woman is the bane
of my existence.
- See?
Excuse me, can I
get a coffee, black?
Can't you see we
talking, white?
If you're gonna continue
to emasculate me...
with this Barbie
dress-up shit.
I'm using your laptop.
Don't forget to smack it
when you turn it on,
otherwise the screen
doesn't come on.
Why don't you spring
and get a new one?
Same reason I don't
spring for clothes...
for tonight, I'm broke.
There's a chick who works...
at Teen Juice at
the mall, you know.
I gave her a good
deal on yarn,
- so she's letting me
borrow this stuff.
Yo, bro.
- What?
You're buying a
vibrator online.
- What's wrong with
the one you have?
It died last week.
Look at the size
of those fucking panties.
Shoot that shit. Shoot it.
My God, who even knew
Amazon sold shit like this?
This is incredible.
- Those are fucking
granny panties.
Okay.
A, I don't appreciate
you violating the...
sanctity of my Amazon
Wish List page,
and B, I'm not
buying that thing...
from Amazon,
because it turns out
I don't have a credit
card they take.
- Oh, shit.
I'm sorry, guys.
Am I in the way?
You're a fucking
faggot, all right?
Let's go to Starbucks.
- He's a shitty
barista anyways.
Cock.
- And he throws like a bitch.
- You know what else I throw?
My nut sack in your coffees,
so how did that taste, fucker?
We saw your girlfriend
in her underwear, cunt nugget.
Well, too bad she's
not my girlfriend,
you little fuck--
Oh, they're gone.
Are you still talking to me?
Uh, just said, I'm gonna...
look up more fuck
toys on Amazon.
Oh, holy shit.
- They sell the
Fleshlight here too.
What's that?
It's a fucking pocket pussy...
that is shaped like
a flashlight...
'for discretionary
jacking off.'
That way if you get caught,
no one thinks it's weird.
You're just a guy
who likes to fuck...
his flashlight.
I am totally buying this shit.
Whoa, if you've
got money to burn,
how about paying
the electric bill?
- That's due already?
November's is
probably due now,
but I was talking
about September's.
Tell me this doesn't rock.
You kind of look
like Ronald McDonald.
That makes me want
some McNuggets.
Why would you wanna buy a...
pocket pussy anyway?
That is so sad.
What? Excuse me,
I forgot about the nobility...
that accompanies coming
with a fucking vibrator.
Think a kid in Darfur
gets saved every...
time a vibrator
makes you come? No.
- 'Real feel
action'? Oh, my God.
Yeah.
If you start fucking machines,
I'm moving out.
What do you think
a vibrator is?
It's a machine.
How come you get...
to fuck something
with a motor in it?
I've never met a man who can...
make me come like
a vibrator does.
That's bullshit.
You get to be Buck
Rogers having sex in
the 25th century...
with fucking Twiki
and Dr. Theopolis.
I'm stuck to a
bottle of Jergens...
in the bathroom.
Holy bejesus. You do not use...
my Jergens to jack
it in our bathroom.
No, you know what
I do actually,
is I light a bunch
of candles...
and I sprawl out on my sheets
and I listen to Sting.
No, I'm a guy. Give me...
two Popsicle sticks
and a rubber band.
I'll find a way to fuck it,
like a filthy MacGyver.
Oh, my God, I'm so
glad I'm not a guy.
How about this?
I don't get why you're putting...
so much effort
into this thing.
I thought we were
just gonna go to...
sit around and make
fun of everybody.
I can't wear anything
that I already own...
and expect to bring
home Bobby Long.
Bobby fucking Long? No way.
Didn't that guy call
you 'Stinky Linky'?
Yeah, that was then, okay?
Maybe now he can
save me a fortune...
in Amazon bills.
Maybe you can fuck
our landlord...
so we can at least keep a roof
over our heads.
You don't have the rent?
Zack, it's your month.
Hey, I bought skates
with last week's paycheck...
- and I need those
to skate with.
Oh.
And this week's will
barely cover...
the past two
water bills, so...
Is this sexy?
Yeah, in like a To
Catch a Predator...
kind of way, it is
pretty fucking sexy.
Then we're done.
What the fuck? Zack.
- You want me to come in?
- What happened to the water?
- They shut it off.
- Oh, shit. Just, uh--
Help me get this
shit out of my hair.
Just use the water
out of the toilet.
- There's poo in there.
- Not that part.
- The back part of
the toilet thing.
Oh, that makes sense.
Take the cup there...
and then scoop it
in, there you go.
Here, I'll lean back
and you can just,
you know, pour it down
like-- Like that.
You're harshing my buzz,
you know.
This is so lame.
Don't look. Don't look.
Don't look.
Whoa.
All right, one hour tops,
then we're gone.
Or I had an idea.
We could just not go at all,
which would rock.
Even though we're broke...
and we've never
amounted to anything,
we're still better
than these people,
right?
No. Not at all. We're probably...
not even as good
as most of them,
unless one of them
is a crackhead...
or something.
Just tell me I'm prettier
than when we graduated.
You look about the same.
Definitely not prettier,
but around the same.
I'm thinner, though, right?
A little?
Not really.
Well, good pep talk. Fuck.
- Ta-da.
- You don't
recognize us, do you?
Um, no, sorry.
Zack Brown, Miri Linky.
Were you the one they called
Stinky Linky?
Oh, no, no one ever
called me that.
Oh.
- Great. What does yours say?
- What the fuck? Come on.
- I'm sure I had a
nickname. Nothing?
All right, you
have a great time,
and before you go,
don't forget...
your copy of The
Roving Roe-Ver.
What the fuck's this shit?
That is not shit,
that would be...
our bi-monthly newsletter.
- Awesome.
- It updates you...
- on what everyone's doing.
- Finally.
I love your enthusiasm.
Here you go.
Write your e-mail
address on that...
and I'll be sure to add you...
to our 800-member-strong
mailing list.
We had 800 people
in our graduating class?
Yes, and only 250 R.S.V.P.'d.
Doesn't that suck, Mary?
- Miri.
- You married, Bets?
- I am. Two kids.
- Wow, that's beautiful.
- Awesome.
- You wanna fuck me later?
- Uh, no, I'm married.
Okay, cool. If you
change your mind,
- I'll be in there
getting shitfaced.
He will.
- Just so you know,
I eat the pussy.
He does.
Ah, tempting. Again, no.
- Shall we?
- Sir. Bye, Bets.
Think about it.
¶ 'LET ME CLEAR MY THROAT'
by DJ KOOL ¶
Enjoy.
Can I get two beers, please?
You want a beer?
- Yeah.
- Three beers.
- Thank you.
- Here you go.
Is that Zack? Or am I Zack?
Whoa, ho, ho.
Oh, wow.
- Never gets old, huh?
- The other Zack.
Oh, in my world,
nobody calls me
'the other Zack,'
now that this guy's not around
anymore, huh?
- Get the fuck off of me.
- There can be only one.
- What?
- Highlander, man? The Kurgan.
Remember? I'd yell it
at you whenever...
we passed each other
in the hallway?
Like it was yesterday, man.
Awesome. Awesome.
Awesome. God, you guys have
so much to catch up on. Whoo.
- No.
- I'm gonna let you get to it.
- Bitch.
¶ 'SEX AND CANDY'
by MARCY PLAYGROUND ¶
Have you seen that
big blowup picture...
they have of me?
Yeah, it's--
My hair is terrible.
I can't believe
I even wore my hair like that.
That's before I knew...
about styling
products, you know.
It makes a big
difference in life.
But you live and
learn, though, right?
I mean, ten years
ago, Pittsburgh,
who knew anything
about fashion?
Back in the day,
our hairstyle, oh...
Hey, stranger.
- Whoa. Stinky Linky.
Yeah. Although it's
just Miri now.
- Give me a hug.
- Oh, okay.
- Hi, heh, heh, heh.
- Hi.
Wow.
- How have you been?
- Great, great.
- Yeah?
- You look fantastic.
Wow, that is not
something that you...
would have said to
me ten years ago.
- Well, I've grown up.
- Yes. Yes, you have.
You just look...
Ooh, heh, heh.
- Well, listen to
you. Thank you.
No, don't thank
me, just fuck me.
¶ 'STEAL MY SUNSHINE'
by LEN ¶
Roxanne. Hey.
Someone I like,
what are the odds,
huh?
Zack Brown, we had four years
of Spanish together.
Why does no one recognize me?
- Am I thinner? Is that it?
- Look at him.
- Who?
- My stupid husband.
No fucking shit.
John Butterfield?
You actually married
- That's amazing.
- Don't ever get married.
It sucks. You stop
appreciating each...
other and run out of
shit to talk about...
after the first year.
But look at him now,
chatty as fuck.
Flirting up a storm with that
cheerleader nimrod Monica Von.
You want me to maybe
flirt with you...
so he can see it,
even it up a bit?
I don't wanna get even.
If I was gonna do anything,
I'd wanna one-up the asshole.
You can give me a handjob
in the girls' locker room.
- Fine, but make it fast.
- Fuck, yeah.
Are you staying in town
for a while or--?
Just tonight. I fly back
to L.A. tomorrow.
L.A., wow, Los Angeles. Gosh,
Bobby Long, coming
up in the world.
- With Mrs. Long, I bet, huh?
No, no, no. No
Mrs. Long for me.
- Then can I be
honest with you?
Sure.
Um...
Whew. I think I need a drink.
Do you need a drink?
Because I need a
drink to say this.
- I've got a beer
already, so--
Oh, great, thank you.
I think there's a
cigarette butt in there.
Yup.
Sorry about the elbow.
¶ 'SMALLTOWN BOY'
by BRONSKI BEAT ¶
There can be only one.
Can I get a beer, please?
Thank you very much.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
My friend's making
an ass of herself...
hitting on her
high school crush.
Oh, God, that's so sad.
It's so Miri, is what it is.
I'm Zack, by the way.
Brandon.
Don't worry, we weren't
in the same class or anything.
- Okay. Lucky you.
- Are you a Monroe-ver?
Well, I went here,
let's just leave it
at that, I guess.
Do you have one of the large...
blown-up pictures of
your younger self...
- hanging around here?
- I do, kind of. Right there.
- Gorgeous.
- Good times.
What do you do?
What brings you here?
I came with somebody
who went to school here.
- Really?
- Bobby Long.
No shit. That's who my
friend's hitting...
on right now. See right there?
- Really.
One dressed like
Hannah Montana?
In L.A., we call that look
'Nickelodeon chic.'
- Wait, L.A.? Los Angeles?
- California.
That's awesome, man.
What do you do out there?
- I'm an actor.
Wow, that's really impressive.
- Thank you, thank you.
- In fucking movies?
'Fucking movies.' Pretty much.
Look at you. What--?
Anything I've
seen? What movies?
Oh, all sorts of movies
with all-male casts.
All-male casts.
Like Glengarry Glen
Ross? Like that?
Like Glen and Gary
Suck Ross' Meaty Cock...
and Drop Their Hairy Nuts
in His Eager Mouth.
- Is that like a sequel?
- Sort of.
- It's a re-imagining.
- Oh, like The Wiz.
More erotic and
with less women.
No women, to be exact.
I apologize in advance
if I am out of line here,
but are you in gay porn?
- Guilty as charged.
- Are you fucking with me?
- I thought you
recognized me, that's--
Oh, okay, I get it.
You're not in my demographic,
so I'm not insulted.
- Not really. Who's
your demographic?
Do you love pussy?
- I do.
- Then not you.
Oh, okay.
I came here tonight...
hoping to seduce you...
and bring you back
to my apartment...
and sleep with you to, uh,
get back at you,
you know, for calling
me Stinky Linky...
all those years ago.
Wow.
That is a weird revenge plot.
- You must be a
terrible lay for that.
What? No, I'm great.
I mean, I've had
enough practice...
and everything. That--
Wow, that sounded not good.
I fuck a lot. That's
what I meant to say.
That doesn't sound
good either. Wow.
You're a lot funnier
than I remember.
Thank you. Gosh,
you turned out to
be such a nice guy.
It just-- You know,
it makes it even...
easier to just--
To just say this.
Would you like to
come back to my...
place and maybe open
a bottle of wine...
and have ourselves
a real high school reunion?
- I--
- Hello, Miriam.
Beat it, we're talking.
- I wanted to introduce
you to Brandon.
Salutations.
- Bobby's boyfriend.
- Bobby who?
- Bobby me.
- Bobby Long.
Brandon is the star
of such adult fare...
as-- What was that
one called again?
You Better Shut Your Mouth
or I'm Gonna Fuck It.
That's right.
I'm surprised I forgot that.
Are you fucking with me?
No, they're fucking
with each other.
Oh, my God.
- No.
- What?
Granny Panties?
- Excuse me?
- How can you tell?
This is so crazy.
I was literally just
watching you, like,
right before we got here.
This is so crazy.
This is you, right?
My name's Granny Panties,
and nobody wants to fuck me.
Nothing's whiter
than my big gay ass--
Where'd you get that?
Oh, I entered 'gay' and 'ass,'
and it was the top hit.
It's had 200,000
views in three hours.
Honey, you are, like--
I'm jealous right now...
because you're,
like, super famous.
Baby, please take our picture.
I get a picture with
Granny Panties.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- This is awesome.
- All right, smile.
Okay, got it.
Did you get it?
- Oh, thank you very much.
- E-mail me that.
Oh, because he's the worst
photographer. Okay, good.
- You're gay?
- Yeah.
And I'm on the Internet
wearing a diaper?
Who knew you'd come
to Pittsburgh...
and meet a celebrity?
I'm gonna binge-drink now
until I pass out.
Okay. She'll be
fine. So you guys...
suck each other's cocks, huh?
Oh, like crazy.
Okay, that's enough, I think.
I'm embarrassing him.
I love when he's embarrassed.
He's not living out loud,
so he gets all like, ooh.
- You are totally in
love, aren't you?
Zachary, we are.
Wow, I--
Oh, God, I just
wanna eat him up,
yum, yum.
Save some for me,
yum, yum, yum.
- I can't keep my
hands off him.
You've had one too many.
Although he does most
of the eating in...
the sack. In the sack
and of the sack.
All right, that's enough.
Look, you've drunk too much.
You do this every
time. You get too
Mary for everybody
in the room...
- and you can't
contain yourself.
Oh, I'm sorry.
And by containing
myself, do you...
mean containing
myself in a closet?
In a closet of
denial? Is that--?
No, no, no.
Holy shit, this just got real.
This is exactly why
you haven't met my mother.
You don't know how
to ease people...
into this situation.
- You just force your
way in every time.
I thought, maybe
for one second...
in this godforsaken town,
I could be myself.
I'm so sorry.
No, you're right, I
should just butch up...
and pretend that I
don't love it when...
you shove your
dick in my mouth.
- This is the best
night of my life.
Am I making a spectacle?
- I could make a
much bigger scene.
You really are.
I'm sorry. Pittsburgh.
Listen up, Monroe-vers.
My name is Brandon St. Randy,
and I love Bobby Long.
- Fucking A.
- Is that enough?
Is that enough of a scene?
I could start doing
worse than that.
The reason you
haven't taken me...
to your mother's--
Your mother with her
makeup and all...
her drinking, she's
in the closet too.
- They fight just
like real people.
I thought I'd be a
conduit for you--
Thank you.
- Are you being sarcastic?
- No, I'm not.
- Thank you.
- I love you.
- I'll e-mail you.
Zack, it was so
nice to meet you.
And I will be
patient with you.
I will be there
on your journey.
I will be your Sherpa
up the mountain of gayness.
Well, might as well
see how many hits
Granny Panties is up to, huh?
Did I do that?
Thanks, George.
What kind of evil fucks
turn off your power the day--?
No, the night before
Thanksgiving?
Who does that?
Can you get an
advance on your card?
Fleshlight maxed-out
my $200 limit.
Not a wise purchase,
I'll give you that.
This is bad. If we
don't come up...
with rent, we're
gonna get locked out.
Who the fuck wants
to live there?
There's no water or power.
Which means by the time...
we get home, there's
no heat either.
Well, I think it's
time we put what...
we always talked
about into effect.
- You're gonna have
to start hooking.
You know, you jest,
but these are the
exact circumstances...
people find themselves in...
right before...
they start having
sex for money.
- Yeah.
- Or making porn.
- Oh, my God, yeah.
- What? You got an idea?
We could make a porno.
- Not the idea I
was looking for.
What?
No, that is a
fucking awesome idea.
Are you shitting me?
That's a rad idea.
That guy, Brandon
St. Randy, who's
Bobby Long's awesome
nice boyfriend,
he said he makes
a hundred grand a year...
because he shoots
and distributes...
his own porno flicks.
If it's so easy,
how come everybody
doesn't do it?
Because other people
have options...
and dignity, which
we do not have,
which puts us in an amazingly
advantageous position.
Fuck you, I have dignity.
Where? Is it hidden
in your gigantic underpants...
that are plastered
all over the Internet?
Is that where you
hide your dignity?
Every woman has a
pair of those...
period panties.
That's, like, a fact.
Okay. Families.
I bet people don't make porno,
because they have families.
But luckily, your
parents are dead.
Sorry. My grandparents
are dead.
- Sorry.
- Thank you.
So who are we
gonna disappoint?
Porn has gone mainstream now.
It's like Coca-Cola or
Pepsi with dicks...
in it. Look at Paris Hilton.
She throat-fucks a
guy in night vision,
now she's selling fragrances
to tweens.
And I'm pretty sure
she's legally retarded.
That's for tweens?
Have you seen that
Joe Francis guy...
who made Girls Gone Wild?
That guy is the biggest
fucking idiot...
piece of shit in the world...
and he has a jet and
a fucking island.
Look, there's got to
be a less extreme...
solution to our
financial woes here.
- Give me a better option.
- Get a paper route.
- I don't have a bike.
- Be a waiter.
No one wants me
around their food.
Would you eat food
that I gave you?
I would not eat food
that you gave me,
that's true.
I mean, nobody
wants to see us fuck, Zack.
Everybody wants to
see anybody fuck.
I hate Rosie O'Donnell,
but if someone said,
'I got a tape of
Rosie O'Donnell
getting fucked stupid,'
I'd be like, 'Why aren't we
watching that right now?'
Because she's famous. Hello.
So are you.
You're fucking Granny Panties.
My underwear and your ass
are famous, we're not.
So who the F
would wanna watch us fuck?
- At least 800 people.
The jerks we went
to school with?
- Are you serious?
- Of course.
If you heard...
that someone we
graduated with...
was in a fucking porno movie,
you'd watch it, right?
I'd watch that guy Brandon
suck a cock, I just met him.
With this mailing list,
we have almost a
thousand people...
that would definitely
buy a porno...
we were in just to be like,
'Hey, I sat next to
that guy in Civics.
Look at his fucking dick.'
We sell a thousand
copies at 20 bucks...
a pop, bam, we have
paid off our bills.
- So, what do you think?
I don't think I wanna
fuck a stranger.
Oh, wow,
like you've never
done that before.
How many guys have
you met in a bar,
taken home,
banged with your mouth...
and then never
talked to again?
That's what we
call a stranger.
Dude, I don't
one-night mouth-fuck...
anybody that I
pick up in bars.
You don't wanna fuck
a stranger in the...
porno movie for
some weird reason.
I guess...
We could fuck.
- Ew.
- Fuck you.
I mean, you're a ni
ce-enough-looking...
guy and everything--
Holy fuck, thank you.
You're an
all-right-enough-looking girl.
- How does that feel?
- Dude, I'm just saying...
it'd be weird and
wrong, you know,
like fucking my brother.
Okay, seriously,
we're just talking
about sex, okay?
It's for a purpose.
It's for getting rich.
Only my dick and your pussy...
would be doing
something weird.
Our bodies and brains
would be acting.
- Wow.
Just explain to your
private beforehand,
'Look, this doesn't
mean anything.
We're just doing
this for cash.'
- Oh, my God.
- What?
You're just doing this
because you've...
always wanted to
fuck me, aren't you?
Yes. I've gone my whole
life pretending...
that I want nothing
to do with you,
just hoping one day...
we'd be in such dire
financial straits...
that I could use it...
to finally make
my move on you.
- You're just being sarcastic.
- I am.
See, I was pretending to cry
right there.
I guess it's not
like it'd be creepy,
like if we got way
too drunk one night...
and accidentally
fucked, you know?
No. We'd be going in...
with the understanding
that it's--
A business decision.
Strictly a business decision.
It's a means to an end.
- Right.
- And by end.
I mean, I'll be
waxing your ass.
Fuck you.
I'm not even letting
you see my ass.
I've seen your ass
and the rest of you...
naked around a
billion times already.
- That goes both ways, buddy.
- You've never seen my dick.
Have you seen my dick?
You've never seen my dick.
Are you kidding? That
party we went to...
where you got blasted,
and Houls dared you
to give yourself head,
and we all watched
you try for,
like, an hour.
Oh, yeah. Thanks
by the way, for...
fucking letting me
do that. Thank you.
Oh, God. We really
do know too much...
about each other.
See, and this would really
just be one more thing.
I mean, look at us.
It's Thanksgiving...
and we're huddled
around a flaming...
fucking garbage can
like a couple of steno bums.
I mean, this could
give us a chance...
to pay off our
debt, pay our bills,
get a fucking nicer apartment
with heat in it maybe.
What are you doing?
Miriam Linky, will
you have sex...
with me on camera for money?
I will.
- A producer?
- Yeah.
- Guy who gets to
finance the movie.
You think I got
that kind of money?
We just need that.
What you're about...
to spend on the flat screen.
Now I can't get
my flat screen?
Fuck that.
No, no, no. With your
cut of the profits,
you're gonna get
two flat screens.
One in your living room,
one in your bathroom.
One in the bathroom?
You know, it's always
been my dream...
to watch shit while I shit.
Everyone with an ass...
loves to watch shit
while they shit.
- I'm gonna make
that happen for you.
I don't know, man.
What else the producer do?
- Um, they help
with the casting.
What's casting?
Finding the people
to be in the movie.
- I get to help
pick the women?
Yeah.
Like, I can look at
a titty, make sure...
there ain't no moles on there?
- You can look at
both titties, man.
Man.
I've been looking at
the same busted...
titties for the past
almost 20 years.
- I'm due for
another new titty.
Please help us. Please.
Please.
Yes. Yes. I love you.
Well, don't mind that smell.
We had some homeless people
squatting in here.
You know, they'd
void their bowels...
everywhere but the bathroom.
Anyway, you pick up the poop...
and you've got yourself
a movie studio.
Why don't we shoot
in your apartment?
No power.
You wanna pay our
electric bill?
- You motherfuckers...
- We'll take it.
- Bring it back.
- Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Oh, Jesus. Oh, Jesus.
Oh, God. Come on.
Why the fuck do I have to
do everything? Fuckers.
Hey, what is that?
Fucking guys. This fucking
team, man. They fucking suck.
I'm gonna hatefuck
the shit out of you, ref.
- Dude.
- It's cool.
- He's my cousin.
- Hey.
Didn't you used to
videotape the varsity...
basketball games
in high school?
Just the away games.
I did it because
I was trying to
fuck a cheerleader.
Which one?
Whichever one wanted
to fuck the guy...
who taped the varsity games.
- Aw.
Still know how to
work a camera?
- Who cares what the title is?
The porn I liked
when I was a kid,
it was always, like,
a spoof of a popular
movie, you know?
Like, um, Edward Penishands.
Okay, so we need
a mildly clever,
vaguely dirty title,
that sounds like
a real movie...
- and sums up what
you're gonna see.
Correct.
An American
Werewolf in Brenda?
Fuckback Mountain?
- Too soon? A
Cock-in-Lips Now?
Next.
Cradle the balls.
Work the shaft.
Jerk my come-crayon
and let me color you white.
I need cock and I need it now.
I'm fucking you in the puss.
It's 'puss' as in pussy.
Oh, because I was like,
who would wanna fuck puss?
I want to slam my
ham in your can,
woman. Scene.
- This guy is amazing.
This guy's great-looking too.
I wanna fuck him.
Hi, my name's Delaney
and I'm a producer.
I really don't know
what it means. I'm...
gonna be honest, this
is my first time.
You don't have to
worry, I'm not gonna...
touch you or
nothing like that.
- All right.
- I have a wife, you know.
We're happy. I
mean, not happy,
but it's cool, you know.
Just so you know,
there will be some fucking.
- We'll talk about that
if you get the part.
Okay.
I mean, not-- We
won't be fucking,
there'll be fucking
in the movie.
Like I said, I got a wife.
She don't play that shit.
- She is a crazy bitch.
- Yep.
It's my job as the producer
to see what you got.
So if that makes
you uncomfortable...
in any way,
you don't have to
show me anything...
you don't wanna
show me, because--
I love the movies.
- Lawrence of a Labia.
- No.
- Oh, come on.
- Dawn of the Dick.
Yeah, but how are
zombies doing it...
at all sexy?
I want to eat your brain...
and your ass.
- Dude.
- Sci-fi.
Yeah. Close Encounters
With a Turd From Behind.
- I don't know
what that means.
Just asses.
Fucking deep in asses.
What?
We're making a porno
and we just need to know...
what you would be
or would not be...
interested in doing.
If anything.
- No anal.
- Oh, definitely no anal.
Anal and hugging.
I don't do ass stuff.
- Anal.
- Ah, fuck.
- Oh, wait, oral. I like anal.
- Yay.
Okay, well,
so, uh, do you have
any special skills?
Special skills?
I can get a boner really quick
and it sticks straight up.
- Is that really
a special skill?
I think.
- Can you show us
what you mean?
Sure.
Oh, that is special.
Yeah, you're hired, Mr. --...
- Who are you again?
- Lester.
Lester 'The Molester'
Cockinshtuff.
- No.
- Wow.
That is the best porn name
I've ever heard, man.
I can have a porn name?
- Then I'll be Pete Jones.
- Okay.
Are you Granny Panties?
- She is.
- Get the fuck out of here.
The panties
are actually in the house.
- I'll get them.
- Whoa.
- Star Sex 2: The
Wrath of Cunt.
We never made a Star Sex 1.
I guess we can
lose Star Sex 3:
The Search for Cock, then.
- Cocunt.
- What's that?
It's Cocoon with a cunt.
So Delaney tells us...
you have a special
talent of some sort.
I don't know if I'd call it
a special talent,
but it's a little
something I picked up...
doing bachelor parties.
It would probably be easier
if I just showed you.
- Great.
- The floor is yours.
So a movie, huh?
That could be fun.
Holy fuck.
Her name, Bubbles.
- Invasion of the
Potty-Snatchers?
That's like MAD
Magazine stupid.
Well, fuck you, okay?
You try to think...
of a good sci-fi porno
title. It's hard.
There's gotta be
one we haven't...
thought of that
would say it all,
not be ridiculously filthy
and off-putting,
and still have
instant recognition...
with our audience.
- I got it.
- Star Whores.
- Yeah. It's funny, right?
See, we figured
this opens us up...
to an even bigger
sales market...
beyond the people we went
to school with.
People who like
comics and sci-fi.
Comics? Like 'Ziggy'?
'Ziggy'? Is that even
in fucking papers...
anymore? No, man.
Fuck you.'Ziggy' is a comic,
right next to 'Family Circus.'
No, like Spider-Man and shit,
you know?
There's always a
shitload of Star Wars...
nerds at those
comic-book shows.
So we sell them a
Princess Leia...
they can really
fucking jerk off to.
- That'd be me,
Princess Lay-Her.
Who am I playing?
You, my friend,
are the lead role of
Lubed Guy-Baller.
Man, he's gonna
be balling dudes?
I thought you said
this was boys on girls.
If I have to fuck a guy, okay,
but I'd rather fuck a girl.
What's wrong with you, boy?
- We'll change the
name to Sky-Baller.
Sky-Baller.
I will be Hung So-low.
Delaney, my friend,
you are On-Ur-Knees Bend-Over.
Man, I can't be in no porno.
My wife will kill me.
Hump me, On-Ur-Knees
Bend-Over.
You're my only hump.
On the other hand,
fuck my wife.
Unfortunately,
On-Ur-Knees Bend-Over...
does not have any
sex in the movie...
but the droids do,
I-CUP and R2-T-Bag.
I robot.
And Stacey over here
is gonna play Darth Vibrator.
- I'm the bad guy?
- She's not a guy, Zack.
I know that...
because I'm not
a fucking idiot.
In our movie,
Darth Vibrator
is a bad girl...
who wants to fuck the galaxy,
literally, and it's up
to Lubed and Hung...
to stop her with their cocks.
- You and me get
to have sex, then?
Yeah.
- Cool.
- I know. Isn't that awesome?
Hold up, hold up. So
who's all having...
sex with who in this movie?
As of last night,
I was having sex with Zack.
What? Han Solo ain't
never had no sex...
with Princess Leia
in the Star Wars.
Guys, this isn't
a literal adaptation here.
It's more of an
erotic re-imagining.
Kind of like The Wiz
or like a parody.
With lots of anal.
- Cool.
- I know, isn't that awesome?
I have a question, do
Princess Lay-Her...
and Lubed Sky-Baller have sex?
Uh, no, because
they're brother and sister,
and according to Miri,
brothers and
sisters can't fuck.
But you said,
that this wasn't a
literal translation,
so that means
Lester's character...
could have sex with
Miri's character.
Because I would love
to fucking eat...
her ass and fuck her
silly in the movie.
Dream on, pal,
it's never gonna happen, okay?
- No, I'm fine with it.
See, she's fine-- Wait, what?
Yep. I mean, everyone
else is having...
sex with more than
one person...
in this movie all of a sudden,
so I think it's, you know,
not fair if I'm
only fucking you.
Guys, read amongst
yourselves, okay?
Can I talk to you for a sec?
Look, Miri,
we got plenty of sex
going on in this...
thing, you don't
have to do that.
Zack, it's fine. I
mean I have slept...
with way worse-looking
guys than Lester.
I just wanna do my
part for the movie...
like everyone else.
You're having
sex in the movie,
you don't need to
fuck someone else.
- You're good.
I'm only fucking you, though.
So don't we need to vary it up
to keep it fair?
Fair for--? I don't-- What?
Fair for who?
What are these,
blood diamonds
we're talking about?
Fair for everyone else...
who is fucking more
than one person,
a.k.a. you, in the movie.
- I mean, fine--
All right. I mean,
if you don't care--
I don't fucking care
if you fuck him.
Fuck. I don't give a shit.
Like you said, you know,
you've fucked bigger
idiots than Lester.
Holy shit. Are we really gonna
shoot this in outer space?
Maybe not bigger idiots.
Thank you.
- Cut. All right,
guys, that's it.
Yeah.
Make sure you leave
your costume...
so we know they're
here for tomorrow.
Mostly, everybody,
thank you so much...
for helping us get
ready, you know.
Cleaning this place
out, building the...
sets, sewing the
costumes, it's just--
I mean, it's really
amazing. Thank you.
Seriously, thanks.
But this is just
the beginning, guys.
If Star Whores
works, and it will,
we are set up for
sequels galore.
The Empire Strikes Ass.
- Return of the Brown-Eye.
- The Phantom Man-Ass.
And Revenge of the Shit:
The All-Anal Final Chapter.
- Okay.
- Revenge of the Shit.
- You got it?
- Yeah, no, we got it.
Ew.
- Fuck you, motherfuckers.
- We'll talk about that one.
We're gonna have a lot of fun,
but more importantly,
we're gonna make
a lot of fucking money, okay?
- Yeah.
So get ready for
greatness, people.
Tomorrow we start
principal photography.
- Whoo.
- Yeah.
- All right, good
night, you guys.
We got a movie.
- What?
- Nothing.
I think someone
should acknowledge...
how insane and
amazing this is...
- and it's all because of you.
I don't know. It's
just a porno.
You know what I mean.
You've really come
into your own.
Shut the fuck up.
So speaking of
coming into things,
ready for tomorrow?
Twenty years,
we're finally gonna
know what it's like...
to have sex with each other.
You say that like
you've been wondering...
what it'd be like
to sleep with me...
for a while now.
Why the fuck do you think
I started hanging
out with you?
I knew it. Here, help.
Let's just promise
that it's not gonna...
change anything
between us, okay?
- Like what?
- I don't know.
Some guys
can't keep sex in perspective.
If anyone's gotta keep this...
in perspective,
it's you, okay?
I don't want you
getting all mushy...
and gooey on me...
after I give you
the best orgasm...
you've ever had.
Oh, like you know
what you're doing...
down there at all.
I actually don't.
Where's the clitoris?
Is it in your ass?
Just, you know,
make sure you kind
of whoop it up...
and act like I'm a
stud who knows...
what he's doing,
okay? Just be a pal.
Oh, dude, I am gonna
Meryl Streep the...
fuck out of this
tomorrow, you watch.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
No. Really, thank you.
For everything.
You're welcome.
Less than 12 hours...
and we make
Monroeville history.
- I really hope
nothing goes wrong.
It's a movie. What
could go wrong?
What are you doing?
- What's up?
- What the fuck?
What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- Wait, wait.
- Wait.
- Stop. Stop.
- No, no, no.
- What the fuck is going on?
Condos is what's going on,
as soon as this
shit-hole's demo'd.
No, you gotta stop
it right now.
We rented this
place for a month...
from Mr. Jenkins.
Sounds like your Mr. Jenkins
was full of shit.
Luxury Homesteads
bought this place a month ago.
I'm gonna kill that
lying old fuck.
You're gonna have
to go Florida,
that's where he moved.
We've got thousands of dollars
of equipment in there.
- Please.
If you wanna sift
through this rubble...
when we're done, be my guest.
Hey, get that
fucking beam down.
This is the last thing
you wanna hear.
If you don't get an advance.
I don't think we're gonna keep
a roof over our heads.
I got an advance already.
It went into all the costumes.
- So all our money's gone?
- All your money?
Never mind what my
wife's gonna do...
when there ain't
no new snow tires,
or when she sees
I charged a video camera.
I'm sorry I dragged
you into this, man.
I just wanted to see
some free titties.
That's all. But there's
no such thing...
as free titties,
is there, Zack?
- Is there?
- Fuck this noise.
Why don't we get
another camera,
and shoot something else?
Where are we gonna do that?
Got another sound stage?
Sound stage? We had
a shit-covered...
garage we turned
into a sound stage.
We find someplace new
and we do it again.
How? Okay, I'm broke, man.
No, make that, I was broke.
Now I am really tapped out.
I have to get another job
to pay Delaney back.
So please tell me,
how can I afford
to start over?
- What can I get you?
- Yeah, can I get a, uh--?
Too fucking late.
Cappuccino, 3.50.
I don't know
what the fuck I was thinking.
I mean, I'm a total loser...
in every single other
aspect of my life.
What made me think
I could do something...
as simple as filming
people fucking?
We have no money left,
nowhere to shoot, no sets,
we have no fucking
cameras. Here.
It's time I go back
to my regular life...
where I am a quiet fuckup...
who doesn't cost
anybody any money...
and knows his goddamn position
behind this fucking counter...
making cappuccinos
for this fucking guy.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
What are you doing?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Fuck, yes.
Zack.
You sneaky Indian
motherfucker.
I tell you, yes.
Swallow My Cockuccino.
- What?
- That's it. That's the movie.
Why didn't I think
of it before?
We don't need sets or a stage.
Look at all this
production value,
waiting to have balls on it.
Hold up. You wanna shoot...
a dirty movie here,
where we work?
Yes.
Fuck, yes, I do.
You know how many...
stories I have
from working here?
How many times I've been laid
right there after hours?
You've never gotten laid here
after hours.
I know. Thank you
for reminding me.
But I always wish I had,
and that's what porno
is. It's fantasy.
It's taking the normal...
and making it abnormal
by fucking it.
Don't do that.
The little dog
don't like that.
How did you get a camera?
By being a terrible,
untrustworthy...
employee, that's how.
Give me today, I'll
bang out a script.
Meet me back here
after closing.
We're gonna launch
arching ropes of...
jism all over this
motherfucker. Peace.
I like that guy but
if he tries to...
fuck that little dog
tonight for real.
I'm calling the
Humane Society.
It's called Bean-N-Gone,
so get the fuck out
of here. Hey, Barry.
- Stand by, Stace,
picture's up.
Okay.
Roll tape.
Swallow My Cockuccino,
Scene 12, Take 1.
And action.
I'd like a double espresso
so I can stay up all night...
because I'm in
the mood to fuck.
Well, I am a
whore-ista, so I love...
to fuck. Would you
like to fuck me?
Holy fuck. You mean,
after you're done
with your shift?
I mean during my shift.
- Sorry.
- Keep going, keep going.
With your shaft.
Let us fuck.
Cue music.
Okay, open up to camera,
guys. Let us see it.
More tongue.
Little less tongue.
Oh, that was good.
Cue effects.
Oh, yeah, like that.
Oh, yeah.
See, I told you it would work.
Didn't I tell you?
It looks amazing.
It's incredible.
Oh, the beans hurt. Easy.
- Move in for coverage.
- Nice.
That's why we got him.
- Nice. I'm impressed.
- Get in there, Deacon.
- Come on.
- Like that? Like that.
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh, yeah. Look at that.
- Pull out a bit, actually.
- That's hot.
No, not you, Lester.
Put it back in.
Kiss the muscle.
- I kiss the muscle.
- You kiss the muscle.
- Can he slap
her ass a little?
Don't be a fucking
pervert, dude.
- Stir, come on. Stir.
- Yeah, stir it.
Stir it, baby.
Hey.
- Holy.
- Shit.
Are you guys still open?
No. We close at 9.
I need coffee so
I'm drive home.
- Okay. Yeah.
- Thank you.
That's a cute kitty.
Okay.
Hey.
- Hey.
You guys see the
game? I was at it.
Fucking Roethlisberger,
the quarterback,
was all fucking,
'Hug it, chug it,
football. All night.'
Heh-heh.
Okay, pal, here you go.
On the house.
- I love you.
I love you too.
Have a good one.
- Yeah, I'll have a cold one.
- I said, have a good one.
Oh.
- Okay. Keep moving.
- You and your little dog.
Go Steelers.
Action.
Oh, yeah. Yeah,
yeah, like that.
Oh, fuck it, chuck
it, football.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, God, this is good.
You take it. You take it.
Take it, Barry. Oh, take it.
Take it, Barry. Take it.
I'm disturbed
at how turned on I am by this.
- Shit, dude, it's almost 6.
- Oh, fuck.
Okay, that's a wrap,
everybody, yeah.
Let's give a hand
to our hotties...
with the bodies
from last night.
Stacey, Lester,
Bubbles, Barry, whoo.
- Yeah.
- Nice.
Okay, when we come
back tonight,
we finish up the
venti-vulva scene, and...
then we get into me
and Miri's stuff.
Again, amazing first
night, everybody.
Thank you so much.
Let us fuck.
- Hey, how'd it look?
- How do you think it looked?
It looked like shit
going into other shit,
in focus.
What an artist. That
was Kurosawa's...
motto.'Shit going
into other shit.'
Oh, man,
I can't believe
you gotta work now.
It's okay. You know, honestly,
I don't think I could sleep.
- I'm pretty, like,
pumped up right now.
Right? It was amazing.
It was awesome.
I think the cast and
crew had a good time.
- We were getting great shit.
- Yeah, it was so fun.
I just wanna keep shooting
people boning all day.
I don't think I've ever met...
the ambitious Zack
Brown before.
- Well, I'm trying to
pay the bills, so...
It's not a bad thing.
I think it looks good on you.
Come on, hurry.
Come on, come on, come on.
Wait a minute.
- You guys never
did it before?
It's fine.
You know, we talked about it
and it's just for the movie.
We're friends, you know,
we're just friends.
And we will always just be
just friends, so...
Listen, I have some extra lube
from last night.
I understand it's kind
of hard getting...
wet when everyone's watching.
At least it was for Barry.
- I don't know if
I am gonna need it.
Really?
Yeah, I think
I'm just excited.
Uh-huh.
At the idea of
people watching,
not because of Zack.
Oh, God. Zack could
never have that...
effect on me in
a million years.
- Hello, Miriam.
- Oh, hey.
Wow.
- Your face.
- Yeah. Weird, huh?
I don't think I've
seen your face...
since senior year.
I think I made a mistake.
I did it for you
so you wouldn't...
get road rash
during our scene,
but I should have asked first,
I look like a
fucking beluga whale.
I think I'll be going now.
Okay.
All I keep thinking is...
we should've done
a trial run...
at home last week
or something.
- Oh, my God. Right?
- I know.
- You're still cool to
do it, though, right?
Yeah, um. Totally. Are you?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know, I'm, uh...
- Honestly, I'm a little
nervous, I guess.
You are?
- It's kind of a big deal.
- It is?
Yeah, you know,
it's our first
time together...
since our auspicious debut
on viral video.
Oh, yeah.
That's a fuckload of pressure
for a director.
As a director,
please. What about...
the anxiety I'm
feeling as an actress?
- Did I pick the
right project?
Yeah. What about
this follow-up?
Julia Roberts followed
Pretty Woman...
with Sleeping With the Enemy.
I'm following Granny Panties
with Swallow My Cockuccino.
Only difference is...
this movie's about
cock-sucking...
and her movie
just sucked cock,
period.
- The only difference, yeah.
- The end was pretty rad.
I liked that.
- When she kills him.
- with a gun.
- Yeah.
- She calls the cops first.
- She calls it in first.
- It was so awesome.
- Awesome, yeah.
So I guess we should do this.
I think we should
probably wait just...
until I lose another
20 or 30 pounds.
Stop it. You look good.
Thanks.
So, what about
me? How do I look?
I mean, you look beautiful.
You always look so beautiful,
so I guess it's
not a big deal,
but you look amazing.
- Okay. Let's go make a porno.
- Okay.
Swallow My Cockuccino,
Scene 8, Take 1.
- Come here.
- I'm over--?
All right, settle.
Action.
Who could it be?
- Hi.
I'm a delivery man
and I have some cream for you.
Wow, that cream looks heavy.
You must be strong.
I work out.
So do you want me
to give you your cream now?
I've been waiting
for it all day.
- Fuck. Come on.
- Oops.
Keep going.
I spilled my cream.
Do you mind?
I don't mind.
Especially if you
spill it on my face.
Let us fuck.
- Fix my shirt.
Think I should?
Okay.
Let me see them titties.
Actually, you
know what? Sorry.
I don't think we
should show them.
- What?
We shouldn't show
your breasts.
- Aren't you gonna
take your shirt off?
I'm just gonna open it.
You're not gonna take
it off? Why not?
My tits are bigger than yours.
I don't wanna show that.
She's not gonna show her tits?
I showed my cock
and my asshole.
- Okay, I'll do your pants.
- Back and forth. okay.
- Holy shit.
- Where's that delivery?
I can't believe this.
I was delivering...
cream, and look
what's happening.
- Jesus, what is
that, a rumba?
What's a rumba?
That awkward movement.
- Should I take your
underpants off?
Yeah, take them off.
What the fuck?
How does this work?
They're just
like-- I'll do it.
- I'll do mine, you
just-- You do yours.
I'll do my pants.
Granny panties.
Just get on with it already.
I'm gonna fuck you
with my pecker.
Dude, that's really dirty.
- That's too dirty?
- That offends me.
- Penis?
- Fine.
- I'm gonna fuck
you with my penis.
I can't wait.
For my penis.
Be careful, Miri.
Okay, there we go.
Just keep rolling,
keep rolling.
- I'll walk forward.
- Fucking cream is coming.
This is the worst porno
I've ever seen.
- Get over here, delivery man.
- Let's fuck on these beans.
- You okay?
- Yup.
- Okay, all right.
Just leave them.
- They're really distracting.
- You should leave them.
- You gotta get
your-- There you go.
Okay, okay.
- Okay, okay.
- Okay. This okay?
Okay.
Okay, uh.
- We'll start kissing
on three, okay?
Okay.
One, two, three. Go.
I'm ready.
- I'm ready.
- Okay.
Deacon.
- Deacon. Deacon.
- What?
Did you see Lost
this week, man?
I missed it. What happened?
They're on the island,
off the island.
Who can follow that?
I think they're in hell.
Would you all shut
the motherfuck up?
I want you to come.
- I want you to come with me.
- Okay.
Oh, God.
Cut.
That's it? It's over? Ain't he...
supposed to come
on her titties?
Well, it wasn't what
we'd shot-listed,
but that was nice.
- It was so romantic.
- Way to fuck, Zack.
Thanks, Lester, uh.
It wasn't just me,
though, guys. Give...
it up for my radiant
costar here, Miri.
- Nice.
- Um, show's over in here.
Let's move out,
start lighting the next scene.
- All right.
- Let's do it.
- You looked so beautiful.
- Thanks.
I thought they were gonna
be fucking hard.
- It was pretty.
- Pretty don't sell.
- Good job.
- Thanks.
You good, Mir?
You need anything?
I'm just gonna take
a minute, okay?
Okay, uh. I'll
just be out there.
Yeah.
- That was fun.
- Yeah, fun.
'Fun.' You fucking douche.
Wow.
- Hey.
- You working on a rewrite?
Yeah, just for
tonight's scene.
- I'm ready to go
when you are, though.
Okay.
You know, before we go, I...
I'm thinking that, uh,
it's a good idea...
if we talk about
what happened last night.
- Oh.
I mean, we don't have
to, but I think--
Okay, yeah, uh.
I kind of dropped
the ball on that.
I guess, huh?
- No, no. It's...
- To be honest, it was...
You know, I didn't realize
how weird it would be for me.
Weird? Like-- Weird how?
Acting and directing
at the same time.
It's a lot to
process, you know.
For the first time,
I thought my balls...
didn't have enough
hair on them.
That's not what I meant.
I know what you meant.
How you feeling about it?
I guess, um...
I feel like...
Like we...
- Holy fuck.
The power's on.
Did you do this?
How did this happen?
I burned the bills.
How could we have done that?
- The water.
Come on, come on, come on.
Yeah.
- We can shower in
our home again.
We are liquid.
Greetings.
Have you heard the
good news about...
our Lord and Savior,
Jesus Christ?
Oh, my God, did
you guys do this?
We got tired of you
taking showers...
at our places all the time.
So we took up a collection
amongst ourselves.
And chipped away
at your mountain of debt.
You guys paid off
our massive utilities bills?
- How did you afford that?
I stole my old lady's
bingo winnings.
And Mistress Bubbles...
did a bachelor
party tonight...
at which yours truly
was a guest star,
thank you very much.
- Oh.
- Whoa.
Don't get too excited.
We didn't pay off...
your whole bill. Just
a month of each.
They agreed
to turn everything back on?
At 9 at night? How
does that work?
Stacey knows somebody
that works at Power and Light.
- You guys...
- This is amazing.
You didn't have to do this.
You didn't have to put us
in your movie.
- Or let us shoot it.
- Or produce it.
- Or put us in
your movie either.
We said that already.
Guys, honestly,
I don't know what to say.
You can start by saying
we can take tonight off...
so we can have our wrap party
right now.
Guys, we're not wrapped.
We still have four
days of shooting left.
Excuse me.
In my 'producorial' capacity.
I'm shutting the movie
down for a night...
so we can get a little silly.
¶ 'PARTY UP (UP IN HERE)'
by DMX ¶...
¶ 'HEY' by THE PIXIES ¶
Go, go, go.
- Yes.
You all drink.
Was it just amazing with him,
after all those
years of not knowing?
It was, um, weird.
- But good.
My scene with Zack's tomorrow.
You don't say.
But I'm a little nervous.
I was thinking...
about trying to get
with him tonight.
- Really?
- I mean, if you don't mind.
You are just friends and all,
so I didn't think it
would be a biggie.
- It wouldn't be a
biggie, would it?
No.
No, no. It's not a
biggie. What? No.
Are you sure?
Yeah. Stacey,
I'm not married
to the guy, so...
I don't know. You
guys just looked...
kind of intimate last night.
- We did?
- Yeah.
Well, we're just
better actors than
I thought, I think,
so you know what?
If you wanna get with him,
you should just go ask him.
- He'd be really
excited to hear that.
Yeah? For real,
you don't mind?
- Yeah.
- Cool.
All the quarters
are on the ground.
- Hey, Stace.
- Hey, Zack.
Come on,
are you guys playing or what?
Well, I'm bummed,
but I totally get it.
It's no problem to work...
with Lester again.
He has a nice cock.
Well, you're a trouper, Stace.
Oh, but if I start
making weird faces...
or anything during the scene,
it's just because
I've been constipated all day.
Oh, shit, uh. We don't have
to shoot the scene tonight.
No, I want to. Anal's great
for when you're constipated.
It totally loosens you up.
I use ex-lax,
but good to know.
Okay, I never thought
I would have that
conversation.
So are we starting...
with Lester and
Stacey tonight?
We were supposed to start
with Lester and Miri.
I know. She-- We're
not gonna do that.
I don't think Miri's gonna...
...do that.
Hey. So where are
we shooting this?
Over here?
- What are you doing here?
- Me and Lester.
Our scene's tonight, right?
Can I talk to you for a minute
in the back?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
What do you want
me to shoot here?
Start with the
close-ups of Lester...
and Stacey. Give
me a second, man.
What an artist.
Okay, uh. Did I do something
wrong to you?
No.
Then why are you here?
I'm here for the same reason...
you're here. To
make the movie.
Okay, just, like,
for your own personal
information,
you're acting really
weird right now.
I'm acting weird?
I think you're acting
weird right now.
Oh, I'm acting--
How exactly am I acting weird?
You've been trying to keep me...
from fucking
anybody but you...
since we started this thing.
Maybe I was thinking
about your feelings.
Were you thinking
of my feelings...
when you were banging Stacey?
Because that'd be really sad
for Stacey.
She told me that
you told her that...
that was okay.
I told her that it
was okay to ask you.
Holy shit. I get it.
I fucking get it.
It was a test. That
whole thing...
was a fucking
test, is that it?
If it was, how do
you think you did?
We had a discussion, Miri.
We had-- Actually, we had many...
discussions about how
it was just sex...
- and how we wouldn't
let it get weird.
I'm not acting weird.
You're acting like a
jealous girlfriend...
is what the fuck
you're acting like.
- I am not your girlfriend.
- I know that.
You're not my boyfriend,
so why are...
we having this
conversation right now?
Because you're about
to fuck Lester...
to spite me, it seems like.
Did you fuck Stacey
to spite me? No.
You fucked her...
like you fucked
every other bitch...
and never gave a shit
how I felt about it.
- Well, that was before.
- Before what?
Look, don't fucking
pretend that the...
other night, you
and me, right there,
that that didn't mean
anything to you,
that you didn't feel it too.
Oh. You're not
getting all gooey...
on me here, are you, Zack?
You know what?
If you were any other bitch
I didn't give a
rat's ass about.
I would tell you...
to go fuck yourself
right now...
because I fucking hate
this game-playing shit.
But you,
you mean more to me than that,
so I'm just gonna lay this out
on front street.
I know you felt something big,
something real
the other night...
when we were together
because I felt it too.
We tried to fuck and instead,
we wound up making love.
So if this is what
you need to hear in...
order to keep you
from fucking Lester,
if this is what you
need, then fine.
Here it is, I'm gonna say it.
I love you, Miri.
Happy?
Oh, Jesus.
You better get ahold
of yourself, Zack,
because we just fucked.
Okay.
What if I didn't fuck Stacey?
But you did.
You know what?
I don't fucking give a shit.
Wait--
All right, don't
forget I'm down here.
Watch that pullout, huh?
Yeah.
Mmm.
This is some damn good coffee.
- Where you going?
Getting the fuck out of here.
We gotta finish this movie.
Yo.
You believe this shit?
Do you believe this shit?
What the fuck just happened
in there?
I'll tell you what
just happened in there.
That chick frosted me
like I was a fucking cake.
Zack.
Okay, seriously,
get a picture of me right now.
I'm hunting humans.
- Dude, check it out. Ooh.
- Oh, shit.
Seriously,
let's shoot the shit
out of this bitch.
- Where you aiming at?
- Cock shots?
Cock shots.
We shot you in the
balls, cunt nugget.
Well, it's my job to get shot...
in the balls, so--
Oh, they're gone.
Excuse me.
Didn't you used to work at...
the Bean-N-Gone
in Monroeville?
I sure as shit hope
this pays better.
I tell you.
So why don't they
just shoot you...
with a puck?
What do you mean?
I mean, what does paintball
got to do with hockey?
Nothing, I guess.
- So ain't no prizes or--?
- No, no.
So, what are they
paying $5 for?
To shoot a Broad Street Bully
in the balls.
White people are fucked up.
Yup, they sure are.
It's a living. You've
been getting...
the checks I've been sending?
Yes, thank you very much.
I appreciate that.
Probably didn't
save you from a...
brutal tongue-lashing,
though, huh?
You know, the wife...
never found out
about the camera,
because I paid off the bills.
How did you manage that?
- Because now I'm Oprah rich.
- No way.
- The post office
fucking settled?
Hundred-sixty large, son.
- Nice, man. Congratulations.
A beautiful day,
thank you very much.
I thought
you made that whole thing up.
No, no. It was very real.
You can believe it.
Even though she's
spending all of it.
Well, since you
ain't gonna ask me.
I'll just go ahead
and tell you.
- No, I have not seen Miri.
- I wasn't gonna ask that.
Oh, I suppose you
weren't gonna ask...
about your movie, neither?
Look, that's why
I came down here.
I need you to come
take a look at it.
- I'm not interested. Sorry.
You'd better get interested...
- because you
still owe me money.
What's wrong with the movie?
The story doesn't make sense.
- The story?
It's a fucking
porno movie, man.
What story?
It's a movie, dog,
and a movie's gotta
have an ending,
which we don't have
at the moment.
Come shot, credits.
There's your fucking ending.
Do me this favor, okay?
When you're done
getting your nuts blown off,
come back to humble
Monroeville...
to my crib for a couple hours,
check out the flick,
you tell me what's missing.
No.
I'll tell you
what, you do that,
you don't owe me shit no more.
- Really?
- Really.
- Is your wife home?
- Yes.
- Maybe I should
leave the pads on.
You got some extra ones?
Hey, honey.
Where the fuck you been?
And who in the
fuck is this now?
Would you calm down, woman?
Goddamn.
You already left one white boy
down in my basement...
while you off
gallivanting and shit.
What if this motherfucker...
- was all grabby on me?
Ain't nobody
wanna grab on you.
Oh, what in the fuck
is that supposed to mean?
- Ain't nobody
wanna grab on you.
White boys love me.
White boy.
- I said, white boy.
- Yeah?
You'd fuck me, wouldn't you?
- Should I say yes?
- Just say yes.
Yeah.
- Why don't you,
uh, head downstairs?
Oh, okay.
It's just through
this hallway.
- Nice to meet you.
- You too.
What the fuck you looking at?
Why you gotta be yelling at me
in front of my director?
- Oh, he's a director?
- Yeah.
I didn't know that.
Shit, he's a director.
Well, why don't he
direct my ass to a...
new husband? How
about that shit?
- That's the bedroom.
- Keep talking, maybe he will.
Oh, don't nobody
want them saggy-ass balls.
Saggy balls? Look at these...
sagging-ass titties
you got around here.
- You could tie
these together.
Motherfucker, we match.
Oh, shit.
Where's my paintball gun at?
Look at you, editor and DP.
You got your shit
covered, man.
Please, don't ever
say 'shit-covered'...
to me again.
Roll the film for
the man, please,
so we can see what he thinks.
Just jump through it. I ain't...
got all night. The
bitch is on me.
'Nigga Rich
Productions.' Classy.
- Yeah, DreamWorks was taken.
- Was it?
Plus, it sounds like
an underground...
gay fuck club.
'I met a guy at
DreamWorks.' Yeah.
All right, so we got
Lester and Stacey fucking.
Then we got
Barry and Bubbles fucking.
And then this boring bullshit.
Okay, just, uh, go
to the next scene,
would you?
Uh...
- What next scene?
The one with Miri and Lester?
We never shot it.
- Why not?
Because after you
left that night.
Miri came out of the backroom
and said she couldn't do it.
- We wrapped after that.
- Wrapped? So...
- Wait, so Miri--
- Never fucked nobody.
Just you.
Now, I wonder
why she did that.
- Hm.
You see, there was
a time when I was...
just a bitter old
fuck making coffees,
and Stacey was just
a lap dancer...
and Barry and Bubbles
didn't know each other...
and this fool here,
hell, I don't even
know what he was.
- A white supremacist.
- Man, fuck you.
Then two people come along...
and showed us something
we didn't know existed.
A world of possibilities...
where plain old people
just like us...
could do something special.
Even if it's
something as simple...
as filming people fucking.
Sometimes we just
need someone...
to show us something
we can't see for ourselves...
and then we're
changed forever.
So as you can see,
our movie ain't got no ending.
Every movie needs an ending,
don't it?
Peace.
Delaney,
you're a slick
cupid motherfucker.
Ain't love grand?
Why the fuck is this white boy...
running through
my goddamn house?
Sometimes.
Miri.
- Miri.
- Zack?
- Miri. I'm sorry.
- Get out.
- Close the door.
- It was closed.
- It was closed over--
Just close the
fucking door, Zack.
I never slept with
Stacey that night,
okay? I swear to God.
When we got into my room,
you know what we did?
We talked about you, and us...
and how things
were different...
and how I was
too much of a fucking pussy...
to just tell you how
I felt about you.
And I know-- I know
that that's only...
because of all the
stupid shit we said...
about how we wouldn't let sex...
change us, but it
did. It changed me.
That has to be love, right?
It has to be love...
and just so you know,
I can't go back...
to being just friends anymore,
- because I just can't.
- Good.
And I think--
I think that you
feel the same way.
Because that night
after I left,
you didn't fuck Lester.
What's up, Zack?
You know what?
I don't care that
you're fucking
Lester, okay? How's that?
- Oh, shit.
I don't wanna be
with anyone but you.
So I will wait
forever for you, okay?
I will wait the
rest of my life...
because I love you, and I have
for as long as I can remember.
And I would rather die...
than be without
you, Miriam Linky.
Miri's last name is Linky?
You're gonna fuck a guy...
who doesn't know
your last name?
Or that you beat up Carl Roth...
in the sixth grade?
I know that.
Or what your senior prom dress...
would've looked
like had we gone...
but we decided not to,
and we got drunk
alone instead.
Or that you washed your hair
in the toilet.
We're not fucking, Zack.
Or that you're
not fucking Zack--
What?
I asked her to fuck me.
She wouldn't do it.
I even tried to talk
her into giving me...
the fucking Dutch rudder.
Shot me down on that too.
- And a Dutch rudder is?
Don't know what
a Dutch rudder--?
All right, you grab your dick,
then you have someone else
work your arm.
Here, let me show you.
All right, grab my
arm. I'm grabbing...
my dick, you're
grabbing my arm.
Now work it. Work my arm.
See that shit? Work
it up and down.
It's like someone else
is jerking you off.
Okay.
There's the double
Dutch rudder,
which, I grab my dick,
you grab your dick,
you work my arm,
I work your arm,
same time.
It's like jerking off together
but not gay.
We're not touching dicks,
each other's dicks anyway.
I'm touching my own dick.
You're working it,
and I'm loving it.
It feels good, sir.
Try me, come on.
Sorry to change
the subject on you.
Lester,
but if you're
not fucking Miri,
why is your dick
out right now?
Because I live here now,
and I like to be naked.
- What?
- When you moved out,
she couldn't afford
to pay her rent...
by herself, so I
moved in to help.
But you just came
out of her room.
That's my room now.
She moved in your old room.
Wait, wait, wait.
She changed rooms?
Yeah, she said she
did it because she...
missed the smell of
you or some shit.
I don't smell anything.
But you know what?
That probably means
she loves you.
- Night, Zack.
- Night.
Do you?
Then why are you crying?
Because I missed you so much.
Me too.
I love you.
- I love you, I love you.
- I love you.
I don't mean to alarm you...
but I think I just
jerked off Lester...
a little bit.
- The Dutch rudder?
- Yeah, it's ingenious, right?
If you ask me nicely, I will
Dutch-rudder you the
rest of our lives.
Good. I'm getting tired
of fucking the Fleshlight.
- You fucked it?
- Yeah.
- What'd it feel like?
- Like fucking a flashlight.
- Wrong room.
- Oh, God. That's gross.
Let us fuck.
Hello.
Welcome to Nigga
Rich Productions,
home of
Zack and Miri Make Your Porno,
the production house
for the couple...
looking to put a little spice
in their sex life.
- Shall we take a look around?
- Fuck me so hard. Oh, God.
First, you'll meet
for a consultation...
with one of our
romance-ologists,
who'll coach you...
through that initial
awkward stage...
before you're camera-ready.
So we will start off...
with some erotic
massage and some--
Dude. Some light petting.
That sounds good.
Are you guys sure
you don't wanna do...
some, uh, butt-sack work too?
- Uh, let's move on, shall we?
- Why?
From their break-out hit,
Swallow My Cockuccino,
to the multi-million selling
Swallow My Cockuccino II...
and the award-winning
Star Whores saga,
including Revenge of the Shit:
The All-Anal Final Chapter.
Zack and Miri have proven
time and again...
that they know
how to shoot hot sex.
As an actor, I've
sometimes brought...
my work home with
me inappropriately.
When you're telling
your real-life lover...
in the bedroom,
to, you know, bend over...
while you cake
your hand in K-Y,
it is a sign that
the romance is dead.
I think.
Then we turned to
the professionals...
at Zack and Miri
Make Your Porno.
Oh, my God,
they totally saved
our civil union.
They filmed what
was inside of us...
and not what was
coming out of us...
necessarily.
It helped me see
his asshole...
as not just a come dumpster,
but a sign of his
beauty, his flower.
It became a, uh,
gorgeous orchid.
Orchids grow...
in sort of the
filthiest conditions.
That's what his
asshole became to me.
This beautiful
flower amidst shit.
- Honey, they
get the metaphor.
I don't think they do.
Let's just say,
thank you to Zack and Miri.
It's helped us out,
it's helped our friends.
Enrique? Park?
Park? Enrique?
Can we get a little love
for Zack and Miri?
They don't even know
what's going on,
they're so pilled up.
But don't take
his word for it.
Just ask our co-founders.
- Hi. I'm Miri Linky Brown.
- I'm Zack Linky Brown.
Here at Zack and Miri
Make Your Porno,
we're dedicated...
- to committing your love--
- Or lust.
- -to high-end,
quality production...
digital video.
A forever keepsake
of your passion.
That's right, Miri.
Why set up a camera...
at the end of your bed...
and settle for one
unflattering angle,
when you could let
the professionals...
dazzle and delight
your senses...
with an array of shots
so masterfully rendered...
you'll swear
Martin Scorsese snuck
into your room...
and caught you fucking?
And remember,
we're not just
the presidents...
of Zack and Miri
Make Your Porno.
We're also clients.
Call now to set up
your appointment...
or find us on the web
at www.ZackandMiri. com.
Way to fuck, Zack.
Subtitles by "ladyhawk"