Hello? Who!?
No. I'm sorry,
I don't know anyone by that name
No, listen,
I get about a hundred customers a night.
I can't keep track of them all.
Do you know...
well tell me what he likes to eat
Cause I remember people
by what they order.
Not by their names.
"Meat Loaf? "
Well, I know a Meat Loaf
with Mashed Potatoes.
I know Meat Loaf who likes
Well, with Cheese Fries,
Pouched Egg, Onion Rings.
What? He doesn't like potatoes?
Why don't you, well,
yeah give me your number
And if I see him, I'll
tell him to call you
Yeah, I promise. I will. Ok bye.
He's 5'11 with dark brown hair.
Sorry, I can't think of any Meat Loafs
with Cheese Fries
or Onion Rings or Pouched Eggs.
Or Fried Fillet of Fish
that match that description.
Last time we were here,
I think he had the pork chops.
Oh why didn't you say so?
That's because we supposedly
have the best pork chops in the city.
You ever tried them?
No, I haven't.
Why not?
What, are you religious or something?
Listen, have you seen him or not?
5'11 ". Dark brown hair. Pork chops
I have actually.
He came in here for dinner last night.
He ordered two pork chops.
One with mashed potatoes and
one with string beans.
I guess he was hungry.
No, he didn't eat both of them.
Our portions are too big
for a person to eat two
No, one was for him and one was
for his girlfriend
Look! Just get to the point...
Don't... Don't change the subject!
Are you seeing someone else?
Who is she?
I hope you both drop dead!
If someone comes in here looking for me
give him these keys.
What do I tell him?
Tell him he's an asshole!
Taxi!
Hey, did he pick up the keys?
No, not yet
Do you have an extra cigarette?
Sure.
Rolled it myself.
Thanks.
You okay?
Yeah.
I haven't had one in a while
I only smoke when I get stressed out.
Well, you shouldn't worry so much.
That way you'll avoid lung cancer.
Do you think she's pretty?
Who?
The girl he was in here with.
Oh, she was okay I guess... I mean.
Not the type I would prefer
to have my pork chops with
but "each man to his own", right?
Yeah right.
Hello.
Hey.
I need someone to talk to.
Do you think he'll pick up the keys?
I don't know
I've had customers
leaving keys here for years.
Sometimes they pick
them up in a few days.
Sometimes it takes a few weeks.
Well, what about most of the time?
Most of the time, the
keys stay in the jar.
Well why do you keep them?
You should just throw them out.
No.
No I couldn't do that.
Why not?
If I threw these keys away
then those doors will be closed forever.
And that shouldn't be up to me to decide.
Should it?
Guess I'm just looking for a reason.
Well, from my observations
sometimes it's better off not knowing
and other times there's
no reason to be found.
Everything has a reason.
It's like these pies and cakes.
At the end of every night
the cheesecake and the apple pie
are always completely gone.
The peach cobbler
and the chocolate mousse cake
are nearly finished.
But there's always a whole
blueberry pie left untouched.
So what's wrong with the blueberry pie?
There's nothing's wrong
with the blueberry pie.
It's just people make other choices.
You can't blame the blueberry pie.
It's just no one wants it.
Wait!
I want a piece.
With ice cream?
Leave it to me.
Here we go.
I hope you enjoy it.
Thanks.
It's not bad.
Really?
You should try some.
No, I'm alright. I have my own.
Will you tell me the stories
behind those other keys?
What for?
I just wondered how
they all ended up here.
Pick one.
Those belonged to a young
couple a few years ago.
They were naive enough to believe
that they were gonna spend the
rest of their lives together.
Well, what happened?
Life happened.
Things happened. Yeah, time happened.
It's pretty much always
the case more or less.
Or maybe one of them ran off
with someone else.
Maybe the feelings just went away.
What about these?
Those belonged to a little old lady
Her best friend would pick them up
and come to visit her.
She dropped them off
and I never saw her again.
I presumed, I mean, she was pretty old.
I presumed she passed away or something.
What about these?
These keys used to
belong to a young lad
from Manchester England
who made plans and had dreams
of running every
marathon in this country
starting in New York.
He was going to write a journal
about his experiences
and ended up running a cafe.
Later they were given to a Russian girl
who loved collecting keys
and watching sunsets.
Unfortunately,
she loved sunsets more than the keys
and ended up disappearing into one.
Why didn't you go looking for her?
When I was little
me mum used to take me to the park
on weekends
She said if I ever got lost.
I had to stay in one place
so that she'd find me.
Does that work?
Not really.
She got lost once looking for me.
Eh, you want some more ice cream?
No thanks.
You sure?
Yeah I'm fine. Thanks.
You're late.
Same as usual?
No thanks.
Can I have my keys back?
Yeah, sure.
So...
You two have patched things up then?
Thanks.
Lousy bloody camera.
Hey!
Alright. Come on. Break it... Alright!
Take it outside. Take it out...
None of your business cupcake!
Don't start with me mate!
Don't you start... Come here!
Right you come here
Get out of my place!
Don't start with me!
Get out!
Hey you haven't paid yet!
Can I have a tissue?
What happened?
Did he hit you?
No!
Well what?
I got mugged on the subway.
I thought Pork Chop lived around here?
He does.
What were you doing on the subway?
Well...
I just needed some
time to prepare myself.
I was gonna get off in a few stops.
I don't know, I just.
The next thing I knew,
I ended up in the Bronx.
That's a very interesting
way to prepare yourself
I've never been very
good at confrontation
Some people enjoy it.
Not me.
Hey, are you alright?
Should we call the police or something?
No.
No, he didn't get away with very much.
Especially after I
kicked him in the balls.
You didn't.
Wait, what happened to you?
I ate too much chocolate .
What's wrong with your camera?
Oh, I don't know.
It's been in a lousy
mood these past few days.
It doesn't really keep
people from stealing, does it?
No.
Not really.
But I like having it around, 'cause
for me it's like my diary.
You know?
Some nights, I watch the tapes back and
I'm amazed at how much I've missed.
That's going on right in front of me.
You must have a lot of tapes.
I don't keep them all.
I'm not that weird.
Only the highlights
Can I take a look?
Sure.
Come around.
She left behind her set of keys
and disappeared that night.
How do you say goodbye to someone
you can't imagine living without?
I didn't say goodbye.
I didn't say anything.
I just walked away.
At the end of that night.
I decided to take the longest way
to cross the street.
Dear Jeremy.
As you can see by this postcard
I'm now in Memphis, Tennessee.
Hey Lizzy, hurry up with
those damn pick-ups will ya!
Coming!
Come on hustle it!
It took me a long time to get here
And I'm not sure how
long I'll be staying
During the day, I work
at a diner downtown
I haven't been able to sleep at night
so I've also taken a
waitressing job at a bar
It's kind of a dive,
but the tips are pretty good
Working two jobs is exhausting
But at least it keeps me busy
and most importantly,
it keeps my mind away from him
Hi girl
Hey Sandy
You going home?
Let me put it this way
I'm getting up out of here
I wish I could go
What's wrong?
That guy at the bar
I don't think he's ever gonna leave
Oh you're talking about Arnie?
Child, don't worry about him.
He probably just lost track of time
But now if you need to get going
You just bring his check to him,
have him sign it
Travis runs a tab for him
Well, does he always stay this late?
Always
You stick around here
you see for yourself
Have a good night darlin'
You too. Good night
Here's your check
Just eight?
I coulda sworn I had at least nine
No, just eight
Do you have a pen?
Yeah
I don't recognize you
You new around here or something?
I just started a few nights ago
Oh
Have you got a name?
Lizzie
Well, it's been a pleasure getting
to know you Lizzie
What do you mean?
You won't be seeing much more of me
from now on
Why's that?
Well I don't have much reason
to come back here anymore
Tonight was my last night of drinking
Oh
Yeah
So, you just give that to Travis
Tell him I'll cut him a check
Ok
That's for you
Thank you
Bye
Oh, hi
Do you have a twin sister?
No
I wish I did
Yeah? Well, I'm glad I don't have a twin
One of me's plenty
Well, let's see I'm just gonna
have the chicken fried steak
and a side of string beans
Ok
Coming right up
Hey! Knock that crap off over there!
This is a restaurant,
not a damn dancehall!
How come you're working so hard, Lizzie?
I'm trying to save up for a car
Where are you going?
Well, I don't have any specific
destination in mind, but
I'm just gonna go until
I run out of places to go
I wish I could do that
Here's your change
You put that towards a Buick
Thank you
Hi
Wait what are you doing here?
What?
What are you doing here?
Oh, I'm celebrating
What are you celebrating?
My last night of drinking!
He's not giving you a hard time, is he?
I think he just wants to talk
That's funny,
'cause he almost never wants to talk
He's not hitting on you, is he?
No. I don't think it's like that
It's too bad
Be nice to see him take
an interest in a woman
I thought he was married
Yeah, that's precisely the problem.
He still thinks he is
Holy shit
Travis, how's it hanging?
Always a pleasure, Sue Lynne
You always say that to me
and I never know whether you mean it
I'm just dropping in
to use the ladies' room
Do I have to buy a beer first?
Your money's no good here, Sue Lynne
Have you got a moment?
I got nothing to say to you
Arnie?
Yeah?
I know its none of my business
but have you ever thought
about cutting back.
Have I thought about it?
What are these?
A group I go to sometimes, Lizzie,
has this system.
After a meeting,
they invite the new
people to come down and
pick up a white chip.
You take it as a
symbol of your intention
to stay sober.
And if you
slip up and drink again
you got to come back
and pick up another chip.
This one is for ninety days.
I got that far.
Once.
See all those white chips, Lizzie?
I am the king of the white chip.
Dear Jeremy.
I thought about what Arnie
said about the sobriety chips,
how to focus your
attention on something else
in order to cure your addiction.
If I was an addict, I'd choose
blueberry pie as my chip.
Writing to your boyfriend?
No, just someone I know.
Why not pick up the phone?
Some things are better on paper.
Oh you think so?
What are you doing?
Well, you know
I listened to what
you said the other day.
So I'm trying to write
a letter to my wife.
We don't talk to each
other much anymore
so I thought maybe I'd try your method.
Randy!
Oh my God!
Arnie! Arnie! Stop! Arnie!
Okay I got. Easy now, watch your back.
You'll be alright, man!
Hello, is that the
Memphis Bar and Grill?
It is! Great.
Listen, I wonder if you
could help me please.
I'm looking for a young
woman called Elizabeth.
Yes. I realize that. I'm not
calling to order your food.
I'm sure it's delicious.
I wonder, does a woman
called Elizabeth work there?
Elizabeth!
Elizabeth.
That's what I said, Elizabeth.
E- L-I-Z-A-B-
No, alright, thank you.
Thank you.
Good God, it's Jeremy!
Yeah it's me!
I never thought I'd
hear your voice again.
Well, you see I got your postcard and...
This sounds ridiculous but...
Well I traced every
Memphis bar and grill.
There must be at least ninety.
I know its crazy and...
I just wanted to say
thanks for staying in touch.
I miss you. I miss your company.
I never thought I'd
hear from you again!
It's not really you is it?
No I know you don't know me.
But your name's Elizabeth.
Well, I just... I just wanted
I just wanted to say
hello really, and...
I wanted to speak to my friend.
Yeah.
No no, I don't want to
order any fried chicken.
Thanks.
Thanks for listening.
Bye.
Goddamn son of a bitch...
I need to talk to you!
Not in here. Let's take this outside.
No! I want to talk about it right here!
So you feel more like a man now do you?
You feel all big and strong.
I mean you could have killed him!
Yeah, no body ever said sleeping
with someone else's wife
was a safe vocation.
Oh goddammit Arnie!
We're, we're separated!
I don't live with you anymore!
I don't talk to you anymore!
You are my goddamn wife!
And I am still your goddamn husband!
No, no you're not...
Not anymore.
Well then what am I?
You're nothing.
Nothing to me.
Sue Lynne, please, please, please baby.
Don't do this, don't do this to me.
I love you, I love you so much.
I just, I just need a little more time.
Goddammit Arnie!
No, no you gotta let me go.
I can't do it anymore.
You gotta let me go now.
I'm gonna go, I'm restart my life
and I'm gonna get me a job.
You're gonna get a job, right?
Yes I am.
You don't need a job...
What with all those
boyfriends of yours.
All you gotta do is
just start charging.
You bastard!
YOU GODDAMN BASTARD!
You bastard Arnie!
I'm through with you!
You hear me? I'm through!
It is over! It is over!
You understand me?
Sue Lynne,
I swear to god,
if you walk out of here,
I'll kill you.
Then what?
Arnie, be calm now...
you don't want to do this.
It's over!
It's too much.
Nuh uh.
No no no...
You're saving up to buy a car, right?
Well, I... I don't want you
driving around in some
junker.
So some cop can pull you over
for a failed inspection.
Thank you.
Wait.
You forgot these.
Yeah... you can just get rid of those.
The police said it was an accident.
He couldn't see where he was going
and he skidded off the road.
Can you give me a vodka?
This is my first drink in six years.
Haven't touched the stuff for six years.
Hey everybody!
Let's all drink to Arnie Copeland.
He was guardian of our highways
and defender of our freedom!
Well, this stuff tastes
pretty darn awful.
But I guess nobody drinks
it for the taste, right?
Give me another one.
Cheeseburgers?
Whiskey?
This isn't mine.
It's Arnie's tab.
What am I supposed to do with this?
Put it in a frame and hang it on my wall?
Travis wants you to settle it.
Travis!
What are you giving this to me for!?
This is Arnie's tab, not mine!
Why are you giving this to me!?
He was your husband.
Or does that matter at all?
He's dead!
So if you want your money,
you better call his lawyer.
Don't give this to me!
Oh God, what a piece of work you are...
God only knows what Arnie saw in you.
I hate you Travis!
I hate you...
Lizzie!
Make sure she gets home safe.
Go on now.
Go on!
Hey Sue Lynne?
Sue Lynne?
It's late.
Come on let me take you home.
I was
seventeen when he pulled me over.
High as a kite.
"You been drinking, Miss? "
So I smiled.
Bat my eyes.
Who'd have thought we'd be married.
In love with a cop,
and stuck in this godforesaken town.
He was so crazy about me.
I couldn't breathe.
So we tried
drinking our way back into love.
But it never made sense in the morning.
So I ran.
And every time I came back,
he was here.
And he was still crazy about me.
You know,
I used to daydream about him dying.
I thought it was the
only way I'd get clear of him.
You must have hated him.
I didn't hate him.
I just wanted him to
let go of me.
And...
now that he has,
it hurts me more than
anything else in the whole world.
This is where we met.
Right here.
Well, I heard you had a day job
I'm saving for a car
Well, I'm leaving town for good so
I wanted to take care of a few things
Arnie's tab came out to eight hundred dollars
I guess you can give it to Travis and
he can mark the debt paid
I'll give it to Travis tonight
Shock might give him a heart attack
I have a favor to ask you
Could you keep his bill hanging?
So they don't forget him too soon?
OK
I guess for Sue Lynne,
leaving this town was like dying
I wonder how people
would remember Arnie
When you're gone,
all that's left behind are the memories
you created in other people's lives
or just a couple of items on a bill
I began receiving postcards
from her regularly
Instead of calling strangers,
I decided to change my strategy
It was tiring writing the
same words over and over again
but all worth it
if only one of them reached her
I always had the feeling
I could say anything to you.
Enclosed is a bill I've created for you
in memory of our time together
I wonder how you remember me
As the girl who liked blueberry pies
or the girl with the broken heart?
Still rolling your own cigarettes?
You want one?
Yeah
Tastes different
It's probably just been
in my pocket too long
It's a shame you can't
smoke in cafes anymore
You can't smoke anywhere anymore
You should've changed the place
It's not that much different
I've been meaning to buy new chairs
but I couldn't never
find any that match
the tables and the tiles
Shouldn't be hard
Maybe you're just looking
in the wrong places or
maybe you're just sentimental
You look lovely
I'm starting to look like my mom
It's better than looking like your dad
I've seen photos of him
You still have the keys?
Yeah... I always remember what you said
about never throwing
them away, about never
closing those doors forever. I remember
Sometimes, even if you have the keys
those doors still
can't be opened, can they?
Even if the door is open
the person you're looking
for may not be there, Katya
A few years ago, I had a dream
It began in the summer
and was over by the following spring
In between, there was
as many unhappy nights
as there were happy days
Most of them took place in this cafe
And then one night
a door slammed and the dream was over
I should be going
I have to catch a flight in the morning
Thanks for the smoke.
You know,
I didn't even think you'd still be here
Why'd you come?
I guess I just wanted to see
if I could remember
what it felt like
Goodbye, Jeremy
Bye, Katya
Cocktails?
A screwdriver, please
Here you go
Dear Jeremy
I've always been
fascinated by card players
They risk everything on
their instincts and their luck
I wonder if I would be
able to make the same moves
in their position
Or would I just fold?
Sweetheart, do you mind?
Uh-oh look at that
She gets another one this kid
You know Leslie you got that fancy Jag
you working on a Rolls Royce now?
Aloha, you forgot to tip the waitress
Actually I didn't forget dick
Because I never tip
What do you mean you never tip?
I mean Harlan can afford
to pay his own people
I don't know why I have to
You can be cheap or you can be lucky
but you can't be both.
Not in the long run
Here ya go, toots
That is from Mr. Aloha over there
He's gonna pay me back,
he doesn't know it yet
Thanks
Your luck just went south
Who's blinds?
Working long hours in the casino
makes you lose track of the time
And I'm never sure
whether it's day or night
But at least I don't have to worry
about my sleeping problem anymore
Somehow it's gone away
How much you got left, sweet cheeks?
Because that's what I bet
Eighteen-twenty
You on a big draw, Aloha?
Because otherwise
you're just about dead
You are on a big draw
Twelve outs twice
You wanna do business?
Make me an offer
How about you take six
hundred and I take a thousand
and we gamble for the rest?
I say I need more than that
Doesn't seem fair to you?
I feel like gambling
So what do you want me to do?
You heard the man.
He wants to gamble. Deal
Bet you wish you took that
six hundred now,huh Aloha?
Don't get too cocky little girl
Five of hearts still in that deck
Oh come on
We can all dream, Aloha
I wish you luck
Why don't you deal the card?
Fine
Wait, wait, how did you do that?
Ok I swear I wasn't cheating
I had the deck in my hand
Pass it to the sugardaddy here
I'm telling my grandkids about that one
Maybe
A salad. That'd be healthy, right?
I don't think I could get it down though
All that chewing and swallowing
Maybe I'll get some eggs
Protein, right?
How would you like them?
Tied in a knot and nailed to the floor
Or maybe you can just
crack 'em over my head
and let 'em trickle down my cheeks
Beth
Why don't I just go ask them right now?
So who is gonna lend me a grand
so I can get back in?
Sam, come on, this is
me we're talking about
Why can't you just advance me the cash
and I will wire you back the money
within 24 hours
You won't even have a chance to miss it
Yeah?
Well fuck you very much!
Rough night, huh?
You could say that
How did you wind up in this hellhole?
The bus just dropped me off here
Where'd you come from?
New York
You came all the way here
from New York on a bus?
Sounds awful
Actually, I was on quite a few of them
You must love buses
I wanna get a car but
it's not easy saving money
How much you got?
About twenty-one, twenty-two hundred
Hey Beth
I've got a proposition for you
What kind of proposition?
See, I need a stake
There's a man I could call in Vegas
but I don't want to do that
I'm gonna win that game
I'm a stronger player than any of them
If you give me a chance
I'm gonna clean their clocks.
How much do you need?
Well your twenty two hundred
would get me back in
And then, once I cash out
you'll get your money back plus a third
of my winnings
But what if you lose?
If I lose, you get my car
It's a brand new Jag
This way
whatever happens
you've got your ass covered
from here to Houston
You got to give me a minute here
It's been a long night
I got an empty stomach.
Just give me a minute
You take your time
I wouldn't want you
choking on your food
Shit it's cold!
I know
I'll do it
Oh my, look who's back
I thought you'd be halfway to Vegas
in that fancy ass Jag of yours
I figure why not let you pay for my gas
Gotta raise again
Five hundred
Oh one of these days
one of us is going to have
something when you raise!
Listen, why don't you just wink at me
when that happens
so I know, alright?
Raise
I'm all in
You want to give me a count on that?
Fifteen... Fifteen thirty-five
Too rich for me
I don't know what's worse
That cute smile or that ugly shirt
I'll give you some action
Hey
Hey, what happened?
The car's yours
You've got to give me a ride though
So where we going?
Vegas
She said she knew some people
in Vegas who could stake her
get her started again
But she didn't seem
to be in a hurry to get there
Hey Leslie, are you asleep?
No
I keep playing old
poker hands in my head
You?
Same
Except for the poker
What are you replaying?
Just some stuff that happened back
in New York
Hey, the man you told me about in Vegas
that could give you the money
Yeah?
Is he a boyfriend?
No
I haven't had very much
luck with boyfriends
I've had a few but
none that I could ever ask
for anything, let alone money
Now you want to know
who the man in Vegas is
but you're too polite to ask
No
It's not important
He's my father
Taught me how to play poker
He had me figuring odds
around the same time
other kids were learning how to count
He used to tell people
that I thought the number
that came after ten
was Jack
So I can ask him for
money or anything, but
I won't
Trust everyone but always cut the cards
Best thing my father ever taught me
You know what that means?
It means never trust anybody
If you're so good at reading people
Then why did I lose?
Yeah
Because you can't always win
You can beat players
but you can't beat luck
Sometimes your rhythm's off
you read the person right
but still do the wrong thing
Because you trust them?
Because you can't even trust yourself
Shit
Nobody I want to hear from
Nobody?
Nobody!
How did you get this number?
You know this is the third time
this month I've have change it?
Just leave me the hell
alone! Stop calling!
Dammit!
Beth, answer it for me
What do you want me to say?
Tell them its the wrong number
and not to call again
Okay
Hello?
Sorry, you have-
From where?
Okay
Okay... you sure?
Okay, thank you... bye
It was someone from a hospital in Vegas
They said your dad's there
And they said he's dying
Son of a bitch
That man... always dying
It's a trick, okay?
He's pulled this on me before
Says he has to see me, he's dying
And then
you know how many times
I've fallen for that?
But it was someone from the
hospital that called it wasn't him
So what Beth?
You think he couldn't pay someone
to make the phone call for him?
I swear, is there
anyone you don't trust?
Well he must really want to see
you to make up a story like that
Geez, you are just
dying to ask me something
What?
I didn't say anything
You didn't have to. I can read you
I can even guess what you wanna ask
You wanna ask
"What if he is dying? "
"What if the message is legit? "
Well what if he is?
The thing is Beth
I don't care
He lives, he dies
whatever
I don't fucking care
You're lying
I'm not going in there
What?
I can't. What- what if I go in there
and he's just sitting up in his room
with his dead beat
friends playing gin rummy
or, I dunno, detoxing,
getting a mole removed
You know it's more serious than that
No, I don't know that and neither do you
Listen, you do me a favor.
You go in there for me
Me?
Why me?
Because you are safe.
There's no way he can hurt you
Go, c'mon
Fine
I am sorry
You know we tried to phone a couple days
but couldn't seem to reach you
He was-
You should've come earlier
He put you up to this!?
How much he pay you huh!?
Jesus
You're so good at reading people?
Can't you see it in my face!?
Leslie, he's gone!
You're lying
Beth
I can't give you the car
Why?
Because the car
the car belonged to my father
Look, he won big one day in a
Hold'em game at the Riviera, and
went out and bought the next day
It was his pride and joy
Til one day I stole his keys,
and an hour later I stole his car
I don't know why I did it
Maybe I just
wanted to see what
he would do, you know?
Was he gonna report it?
Get his daughter arrested?
He did something better than that
He waited until he found
out where I wound up
One morning
a FedEx guy comes
with an envelope for me
Inside the envelope's the title
and registration of the car
Son of a bitch signed it over to me
So
I'm gonna drive this
car until it falls apart
At least until I do
So what am I supposed to?
Well, Beth
I told you I lost everything
back at Harlan's, didn't I?
Yeah
Well, that's not
exactly how it went down
See, I beat that game on its ass, Beth
I knocked them off their feet
The cards turned just like I knew they would
I read the other players just right
I walked away with all their money
So you lied to me
Maybe I didn't want to share
Maybe I just wanted to see how trusting
and gullible you were
Maybe I just wanted company. You know?
It's a long ride, Beth
I didn't want to go alone
Can't do it.
Thirty-five hundred's the best I can give ya
Three thousand. That's my top
Can't. Gotta have thirty-five hundred.
Sorry
Thirty-two hundred.
Take it or leave it
You know what?
I'm sure we can find a better deal
someplace else. Let's go
I don't think you will, ladies.
Suit yourselves
Thank you!
Don't look back
Beth, where are you going?
I want that car
Beth not at that price!
We can get it for three grand
by the time we get to my car
I don't think he's gonna come down
And I think that's the car I want
Have you learned nothing
from your time with me?
You have to stop taking
people at their word!
Maybe you should start
You're hopeless
You're hopeless too
Dear Jeremy
In the last few days,
I've been learning how to not trust people
and I'm glad I failed
Sometimes we depend on other people
as a mirror
To define us and tell us who we are
And each reflection makes me
like myself a little more
Elizabeth
Hello, Cafe Klyuch
Rent
You still open?
No reason for me to
still be here if I wasn't
I heard this place has the best coffee
and pie in town
Where'd you hear that?
I get around
You wanna come inside?
It's cold
What are you doing out here?
It's freezing
It's a beautiful night.
I wanted to get some fresh air
Have a seat
Isn't this reserved?
Reserved for you
Want something to eat?
Yeah, I'm starving
What's good tonight?
What about a steak?
That sounds good
Does it come with home fries?
Or mashed
They both sound good
Half an order of both?
I'll get the home fries with the steak,
medium rare
and a side of mashed potatoes
Coming right up
Learning something about me?
There's something different about you
Or maybe it's me that's changed
Where are the keys?
You don't keep them anymore?
Been trying to give
them back to their owners
Do you want yours?
No. I don't need them anymore
What about your keys?
I got rid of them
Good night, Jeremy
I'll see you tomorrow
You know I came here the night I left
but I didn't make it past the front door
I almost walked in but
I knew that if I did
I would just be the same old Elizabeth
I didn't want to be that person anymore
Hope you enjoy it
Are they still left untouched at the end
of the night?
Yep, more or less
Then why do you keep making them?
Well I always like having one around
just in case
you pop in and fancy a slice
Do you remember that last night
you were here?
When you practically ate an entire pie
all by yourself?
Really?
I remember getting really drunk and
having a god awful
hangover the next day
Nothing else?
No, nothing else
Or don't you have a tape I can watch?
I do... but...
I've watched it so many times
that the picture started fading
to black and white
And now it's completely unwatchable
Must have been an interesting night
It was
Never seen a girl eat
so much in all my life
Like this?
No, it was more like this
It's good pie
It took me nearly a year to get here
It wasn't so hard to
cross that street afterall
It all depends on who's waiting for you
on the other side