www.titlovi.com
Catch a falling star
and put it in your pocket
Never let it fade away
Catch a falling star
and put it in your pocket
Save it for a rainy day
For love may come
and tap you on the shoulder
Some starless night
just in case you feel
you wanna hold her
You'll have a pocketful of starlight
Catch a falling star
and put it in your pocket
Never let it fade away
Catch a falling star
and put it in your pocket
Save it for a rainy day
For love may come
and tap you on the shoulder
Some starless night
And just in case you feel
you wanna hold her
- You'll have a pocketful of starlight
-Pocketful of starlight
Catch a falling star
and put it in your pocket
Never let it fade away
Catch a falling star
and put it in your pocket
Save it for a rainy day
For when your troubles
start multiplying
And they just might
It's easy to forget them
without trying
With just a pocketful of starlight
Catch a falling star
and put it in your pocket
Save it for a rainy day
You keeping busy?
Yeah, I've been busy.
You know.
- Busy doing what?
-Busy in the garden.
In the garden. You know what?
You're missing work. That's what.
-I can see that.
-No, I'm not missing work.
Yeah, you're missing the buzz and
the jokes and the guys. I know that.
-Don't tell me that's not true. Yeah.
-Maybe a Iittle.
Are you gonna buy some meat
or what?
Yeah, I'm gonna buy some meat.
I'm Iooking at some meat right now.
-I want to get some real good steak.
-I got a special here on the rump.
oh, forget the specials.
I got the children visiting me
this weekend from all over the country.
Got them all around the same table,
all four of them.
Clean up aisle five.
Clean up aisle five, please.
Excuse me.
Do you know about these wines?
-The wine? These wines?
-Yeah.
I stock this section.
Why? Is there a problem?
No, I just wanna get some expensive
bottles of wine for my children.
-This isn't for children.
-I know it's not for children.
It's for my children
that aren't children anymore.
What would be the best one...
ones of this?
Well, we got wines
from all over the world.
We got English wines,
you know, from France.
We got Italian wines
from all over Europe.
I wanna make a good impression
on my kids.
You will. Definitely.
It's got a built-in
tenderizing gauge
for steaks and poultry
with seven different grades.
And there's an automatic spritz
to calm flames if the oil catches.
It is guaranteed for five years
with a premium protective seal.
It has an automatic rotisserie,
and when the Iid is closed,
the oxygen's reduced to a Ievel
that does not support
or encourage the fats to ignite.
Yeah.
-Is that what it's going for?
-648. That's the sale price.
That's a heck of a deal for this model.
That's as Iow as I can go.
-How about 6?
-Done. Sure. Absolutely.
-Where do I...
-You can just put it right in there.
-Looks Iike somebody's having a party.
-Yeah, it's just the family.
-Hello?
-Dad, it's Robert.
Robert.
Dad, listen,
things aren't looking very good...
-Sorry.
-oh, well, that's a shame.
That's a real shame.
Yeah, you're gonna miss out
on having some fancy wine
-and filet mignon steak and...
-Have you heard from the others?
Yeah, so far all of them are coming.
Some Friday night,
some Saturday morning.
-I'm sorry again, Dad.
-Yeah, I'm sorry, too, Rob,
but you gotta get back
to that orchestra, Son.
-I will. You take care. Okay.
-okay. You take care, too. okay.
okay.
Dad, hi. I can't stop right now.
I'm back on stage in a few minutes.
The producers are flying in from Paris
and wanna see the original cast,
so I just can't get away this weekend.
I'm sorry. I know I haven't been home
since the funeral,
but I'm trying, I promise. I love you.
I'm thinking of you.
Big kiss.
Hey, Dad. It's Amy.
I'm really sorry to have to do this,
but things have just gotten really crazy
at the agency
and jack's sick with a fever.
He missed school today.
So between one thing and another,
we're not gonna be able to make it
this weekend.
I'm really sorry, Dad.
And to make things worse,
I spoke to David today,
and he can't make it, either.
He's got a lot going on,
a painting or something, but...
Anyway, I promise
we'll make it to you soon. Okay?
Love you.
Well, you can't.
You can't just go flying
all across the country,
-not in your condition.
-Who said anything about flying?
What about buses? What about trains?
I'm worried about your Iungs, Frank.
Don't worry about my Iungs.
Worry about your Iungs.
My Iungs are fine.
Fibrosis of the Iungs requires you
to take things easy.
Now, you know that.
I'm just going on the buses,
on the trains...
You picked the wrong job, Frank.
I mean,
breathing in humidified
all those years...
You know, it's just about seeing
the family. You know, I...
Jean always kept in touch
with everybody, and now it's...
You know how it is.
Now it's down to me.
-How are you managing on your own?
-I'm fine.
-You're fine? Yeah, fine?
-Fine, yeah. I'm fine.
You know, when I Iost my wife,
I found myself talking to her
Iike she was still there.
It went on for months.
"Where the hell are my shorts?"
No, no. There's nobody there.
No. Talking to myself.
Crazy, huh?
-You do that, Frank?
-No.
-No? No?
- Not yet.
Look, I hear what you're saying, I do,
but this trip,
it's not what you need right now.
You gotta take things easy.
You do. Stay home.
You know what you should do?
Spend more time in the garden.
Ed said it was fine.
He said just take enough medication
and stick to trains and buses.
And I' take plenty of pictures,
and I' bring home the news.
I' start with David in New York.
And if anything goes wrong,
I' be right home.
Got my keys, got my wallet.
My keys, got my medication.
Camera.
Got my keys.
Next.
New York City. one way, please.
-$87.
-$87. There's 1 00.
-I'm going to see my son.
-Very good.
-You know what he does?
-Absolutely no idea.
-He's an artist.
-Gate 7. Thank you.
-Next.
-Thank you.
Uh, what do you think of my work?
You've been Iooking at it
ever since we Ieft the station.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
No, don't Iook at me.
Look back out the window.
Tell me what you see.
-Wo Cars?
-No.
-Trees?
-Well, yes, but no.
Houses?
Just remember that
you've been Iooking at it
-ever since we Ieft the station.
-oh, the window. The glass?
No. Not bad, but it's a start... But...
-Birds?
-Uh, no. Not birds.
-Rocks?
-Not rocks. No, that's ridiculous.
Rocks!. You're just guessing.
I'm gonna stick with this Iady here.
I think she has an idea.
No, honestly,
I really have no idea what you mean.
You know, just Iook for the rhythm.
-The telephone poles?
- ose. ose.
-The wire?
-Yeah. Keep going. Keep going.
-Really, I give up.
-No, no. okay. That's it. That's it.
The wire, that's good.
I mean, I didn't make the wire,
I didn't hang the wire,
but I coated the wire.
I protected it with  coating
against the rain, the moisture, heat,
stuff Iike that.
So, what you actually see
is not the wire. It's my  coating.
I ran 1,000 miles of wire a week,
non-stop.
-Wow.
-Non-stop.
If you just think for a minute,
all the conversations
that have taken place over that wire.
Breaking good news and bad news.
Yeah.
-I' show you something.
-Sure.
These are my children.
Robert, the conductor.
David, the artist. Rosie, the dancer.
Amy, very high up in advertising.
A million feet of wire
to get them where they are today.
-Wo It's a nice picture.
-Thank you.
Million feet of wire
to get them where they are today.
-Rocks?
-Yeah, right. That's right. Rocks.
They were all...
They were all supposed to visit me,
and we were gonna have
a family reunion,
and instead they all canceled on me
at the Iast minute.
Hoo You Iock yourself out, honey?
No, I didn't Iock myself out.
My son Iives here.
I'm just waiting for him.
You can come wait with me if you want.
I know a place.
oh, thank you.
That's nice of you, though.
-You sure?
-Thank you.
You wanna see my Ieg?
You wanna see mine?
1 : Come on.
2: Are we here?
1 : oh, man.
-Dude, I can't believe you, man.
-What?
I can't believe you, all night...
David.
What are you gonna do
when you grow up? Huh?
I wanna be a painter
and do my pictures.
No, not a painter.
Christ, painters paint walls,
and dogs pee on walls.
You're gonna be an artist.
Artists paint pictures
that change people's lives.
So what are you gonna be?
An artist.
That's right, an artist.
So, you gonna work hard?
Yes, Dad.
You gonna make me proud?
I'm trying, Dad.
Unfortunately, it's going to be
on top of the coast sometime tomorrow.
Right now, Hurricane Alice is packing
winds of 1 65 miles per hour.
We've got
a Category 5 hurricane. The pressure...
Looks Iike a bad storm.
-Huh?
-A bad storm.
I'm 94.
-I keep away from the doctors.
-Boy.
I have three children, six grandchildren.
They're busy.
They're too busy to talk to me.
I gotta make an appointment.
They got Iost someplace.
They don't need anybody.
People changed, Iife is changed.
Today, you shake hands
with somebody,
you gotta count your fingers
to make sure you got five fingers back.
Wo Hi.
Hi.
Wo Can I help you?
Do the bells work?
Wo Yeah.
My son Iives in apartment 9.
I'm not sure if he's home.
Wo  right.
Thank you.
David?
Through my sleepless days
I found
That in my dreamless sleep I'm bound
To one night hear the sound
Of you calling
Do not stumble through tonight
Have no fear of falling
We won't stumble through tonight
Drowning in their laughter
Amy, it's Rosie.
-Dad's not answering his phone.
- Well, don't call him.
Not till we know what's going on
with David.
Is there any more news?
No.
I just had that one call from
Mexico saying he'd been arrested.
I keep leaving messages,
but no one's calling back.
I think we should tell Dad.
Not until we know
what's going on.
just avoid talking to him
for a couple of days
-till we know the facts, okay?
- Okay.
-oh, my God!
-Surprise.
Yeah, definitely. Come on in, Grandpa.
-Man, does Mom know?
-No, I hope not.
Well, hey, Iook at you.
I thought you were supposed to be
in bed with a fever.
-I don't know, am I?
-That's what she told me.
Yeah, I think I was...
-It's got a handle.
-of course it's got a handle.
-I didn't know that.
-It's got wheels.
-Yeah. Look how big you got.
-I know, right?
-Gee.
-Hey, Iisten. I'm online.
-I' be back in a minute.
- right. You do your thing.
-Mom's out back.
-okay, good.
No, I need to get down there. Yeah.
Can you check out some flights
and see what's available?
Amy!
Dad?
What are you doing here?
What do you mean,
what am I doing here?
Everybody didn't show up for the visit.
So I said, "If you don't come to me,
I'm gonna go to you."
You crazy man.
Look at you. You haven't been well.
You shouldn't be traveling.
-Did you check with the doctor?
-I checked with the doctor.
-You checked with him?
-of course I checked with the doctor.
-Jeff home?
-No, not yet.
Let me find out
when he's coming back.
So everybody dropped out of the visit?
I didn't realize. I had no idea.
How did you get here?
-You didn't fly, did you?
-No, of course I didn't fly.
I took a train to New York to see David,
and he wasn't there
so I took a bus here.
-You took a bus? To Chicago?
-Yeah.  by myself.
-oh, my God. I can't believe it!
-Yeah. Jack got better fast.
Yeah, no, he did.
Definitely, it was a 24-hour thing.
oh. Hmm.
I Iike the house.
-Yeah? But you've seen pictures.
-I've seen pictures.
I haven't seen the house,
not the real thing.
-Hey, everyone.
- Hey, Jack.
-How's it going?
-Good.
Jack, why don't you take Grandpa
outside and show him your golf?
-You play golf?
-Sure, I'm a natural.
-Yeah, I'd Iike to see that.
-You wanna see that?
-Where are you hitting it?
- To that flag over there.
the way out there? oh, boy. okay.
-My record's three.
-Three?
I' believe that when I see it.
Come on, Iet's go.
-You watch.
-okay.
Whoa!
Not bad.
-Beat that.
-I' beat that, easily, but...
right.
Now I' just have to show you
a few things.
Yeah, that was good,
but not good enough. Frank, the pro.
-Come on, Tiger Woods.
-You ready?
- Take your time.
-okay, ready? Yeah.
-oh, shit! Sorry.
- What was that?
Shot that...
That was just a practice shot.
Give me another one of those.
I'm going after this.
Here we go.
-Ah! Shit! Christ! Sorry.
-oh. Whoa!
-You hit the spice garden.
-one more. Come on.
This is the Iast one. Come on. This is...
I'm your guest. one more. Let's go.
Come on. one more. one more.
Let's go.
-This is my Iast one.
-one more.
-Don't Iose this one, too.
-Give me another ball.
Put it down. Be a sport.
-I wanna watch this baby fly.
-Ready?
-Impress me.
oh, shit. Damn. Fucking Christ.
Sorry. Sorry.
Can you just...
Yes, Chinese food would be fine.
No, of course not.
No, he doesn't know anything.
So, I hear you're doing
very well at school.
- Nah, not really.
-What do you mean "not really"?
Your mother says
you're at the top of your class.
-Does she?
-Yeah.
-You have to work hard at school.
-Yeah, I know.
I' tell you what I used to tell
your mother when she was your age.
About being the best
and getting to the top?
-That's right.
-Yeah, she warned me about that.
-Jeff's home.
- okay.
- Hey, Frank.
-Hi, Jeff.
What's all this? Come here, come here.
-Surprise.
-Big surprise. Big surprise.
-Look at you. You're Iooking so well.
-You, too.
It's good to see you.
oh, my God! What a day!
You don't wanna know.
I'm sorry I'm so Iate.
-Can you believe this?
-Can I believe it?
Well, nothing surprises me
about this guy.
Well, the place
was really crowded today.
I can't believe
I was able to get out of there alive.
Don't just eat your rice.
Make sure you eat your chicken.
okay?
Let me get you a fork.
You don't know
how to use chopsticks?
Yeah, I can use them.
I can use them to beat you at golf,
that's how well I can use them.
-You Iike making fun of me, don't you?
-Yeah, you're funny.
-Yeah, I'm funny, huh?
-Try this.
Thanks. A fork. A regular fork.
Now I can eat without dropping this
all down my shirt.
Jack, can you pass Dad the chili sauce,
please?
Jack?
No.
-Jack, pass him the sauce.
-I'm not passing anything.
Don't be silly.
I don't really want it. It's fine.
I don't need it.
- You sure?
-Stop asking him.
He's not stupid.
If he says no, he means no.
If he changes his mind,
he knows where it is.
-He can get it himself.
-  Jack.
-I'm sorry, Dad.
-That's okay.
So, what are your plans?
Well, I thought that I would stay
a day or two or so,
and then head on out to see Robert.
Surprise him on his tour.
That would have been so great.
It's just, this week's really difficult.
I feel awful. I got this huge pitch
to oversee at the agency,
and Jeff's flying out
on business tomorrow.
We should arrange it properly,
another time.
Well, maybe I can just spend time
with Jack?
Yeah, that would have been great, too,
but he starts school again tomorrow,
and then he's off on a field trip
for three days.
-A field trip? Where are you going?
-I don't know.
Nobody tells me anything anymore.
Well, you know, Iook,
that's what happens
when you show up unexpectedly.
I understand. You're busy. That's fine.
Look...
oh, God, I feel awful.
Any other time but this week.
Listen, I've had a good time.
I've seen the house.
I've seen Jeff and you,
and I Iet this guy beat me at golf,
so all in all it's been a pretty good trip.
-I'm really sorry, Dad. Really.
-No.
I'm gonna call Robert tonight
and find out where he's gonna be at.
I just... He's really busy.
He's on tour, and I just don't know
if it's gonna be possible. What?
No, don't call him,
because I wanna surprise him.
oh.
-okay.
-Promise?
Yeah, promise. Absolutely. Yeah.
I'm putting Dad
on the train tomorrow.
He'll be with you in Denver
the next morning.
What? No, I'm rehearsing.
I haven't got time to meet him.
Well, he can't stay here!
I need to get on a flight to Mexico
to see what's going on with David.
Is he okay?
Have you spoken to him?
No, but I got through
to the police today.
No surprise.
They said the arrest was drug related,
but they won't give me
any more details over the phone.
So I'm gonna try
and get on a flight tomorrow.
Amy, listen, I don't know
if I can lie to Dad
about David when he gets here.
Well, just make up an excuse
to get him to Rosie's.
Say you're flying off to Europe
for a concert or something.
That's too obvious.
I'm not gonna do that.
Well, think of something yourself!
Are you okay?
Jeff, come on!
Jeff, come on.
Dad's waiting to take a photo!
Just get it out,
and I' Iook at it when I get there.
- right. okay, bye.
- I' take one of you two first.
-okay.
- right. Here?
Little over this way.
okay. Little...
Together. Everybody together.
Together.
-Where's the...
-It's the silver button on top.
-oh, my God. This is film. This is great.
-Smile.
Watch your finger.
Your finger's on the edge.
Yep. okay! Give me a beautiful...
right.
You said Jack was
at the top of his class,
-but he says he's not doing that well.
-Well, he was at the top of his class.
He's struggling at the moment,
that's all.
I tell you the good news
and spare you the bad.
Isn't that what Mom used to do for you
when we were kids?
It doesn't matter what your mother did.
Tell me the bad news
as well as the good news from now on.
-Do you understand?
-Fine.
-You doing okay at home?
-Huh?
-Fine.
-You sure?
-Yeah.
Are you sure?
I didn't realize there was
so much to do around the house.
Mom would have Ioved
to hear you say that.
Yeah.
What was all that at dinner Iast night
with the chili sauce?
Jeff just doesn't Iet Jack
get his own way all the time, that's all.
They always fight.
I checked the train times.
There's one in a few hours.
I just gotta drop by the office first.
-Advertising?
-Advertising agency, yeah.
-Your agency?
-Part mine.
Amy. Wait, wait, wait.
To your Ieft a Iittle.
To your Ieft, to your Ieft.
-okay.
-one more. It's okay.
Just hold on.
-A Iittle to your Ieft. Left, Ieft, Ieft.
-I'm so sorry.
That's it.
-I got it. Yeah.
-You got it?
Yeah, no, that's a fish.
It Iooks great.
ToM: It Iooks good.
-I think it works perfectly...
-So remind me of the market.
ToM: Yep. It's home owners,
blue collar to middle class.
-Like my dad.
-Um, I guess, yeah. Sure.
I guess.
ToM: Just Iike your dad. Sure.
So, pitch it to him.
Let's see what he thinks.
Hey, Dad. Come over here.
-ToM: Right now? Sure.
-Yeah.
-Hey. Tom.
-Tom? Hi, Tom. Frank.
-Frank, I'm Steph.
-Steph?
-Hi, Dad. "Dad" 'cause of...
-Hi. Frank.
We got a  commercial.
They're gonna pitch it to you. okay?
-Um, To...
-Sit down.
-Sit here?
-Yeah.
-In your chair?
-Now you're in charge.
-Nice chair.
okay, so it's an ad for ,
for a financial organization...
-Yeah, don't tell him. Just pitch it.
-I'm so sorry.
okay. So there's a guy by the Iake,
and he is fishing just Iike this.
Pine forests.
Snow-covered mountains.
And he's wearing a quilted jacket
'cause, you know... It's, Iike, really cold.
What do you do when it gets cold?
Put a quilted jacket on.
-He's a Iittle nippy.
-A couple Iayers.
okay, here we go.
Big fish jumps out of the water.
I'm talking a big mother
with big beady eyes.
-Kind of Iooks Iike... Right?
-Just Iike that.
Looks at the guy, right in the eyes,
and he says,
"Hey, brother, you Iooking for me?"
Voice over.
"Ever wonder why Iife wasn't this easy?
"At Crest and Landing, transferring
multiple Ioans to one company
-"can be this easy."
-ToM: okay.
We cut to a shot right here of this guy
by a campfire.
We see that big fish right above
some coals, right? ose-up of the fish.
Boom, right there! As he says,
"Hey, buddy, I'm done on this side.
Wanna turn me over?"
That's...
-You Iike it?
-Yeah, it's funny.
It's funny.
The fish talking, it makes me Iaugh.
Yeah, it's funny. It's very funny.
Fish usually don't talk. That's why it's...
The fish with the face and the voice.
It Iooks Iike a fish. You Iook Iike a fish.
oh, my God, I just said that to him
yesterday. That he Iooked Iike...
His mom Iooks Iike a flounder.
-What was it for?
-What, the fish?
-No, the spot. What was it selling?
-Yeah, the Ioans.
That...
It's... Transferring the Ioans
to another company,
it's as easy as getting
the fish out of the water.
Good. So, does the client Iike it?
-Likes it, but doesn't wanna go with it.
- Why not?
They feel uncomfortable about saying
that it's easy to transfer your debt.
-Because...
-Because it's not.
-It's actually a nightmare.
-It's, Iike, really hard.
-It's Iike an impossible dream.
- It's Iike sudoku.
okay, but he's not paying us
to advertise the fact
that he has
a perfectly average product.
He's paying us to be economical
with the truth.
So tell him from me
he's gotta go with the talking fish.
By the way,
your daughter is really good at her job.
-I know. That's the way she is.
-And she has great hair!
-ToM: It's healthy.
-okay.
I know. Yeah, but you know what?
It was fine.
But it would be really awesome,
I would... No.
There was a Iine. Sorry.
My watch is off by an hour.
Should I change it?
Uh, you came from New York, so,
yeah, you need to go back an hour.
Use Central Time.
You were Iaughing on the phone.
That was nice to see.
-I was?
-Yeah.
-It was just work.
-It was nice.
-Was it the fish?
-The what?
-The fish?
-Yeah, the client went with the fish.
They said they should give it a name.
I said we should call it Frank.
-Because of me?
-of course 'cause of you!
-No, not because of me. Really?
-Yeah. For real.
-Frank the fish?
-Frank the fish.
-No?
-What?
-Hi.
-Hey.
Hey, you should be at your desk,
shouldn't you?
Dad, this is Tom,
one of our creative directors.
-Tom, this is my dad, Frank.
-Hi, sir. Nice to meet you.
-Tom.
-So, what are you up to?
I was supposed to be heading
out of town to meet a client,
but the train got delayed.
-Hey, why don't you sit down?
-No, no, no, I'd be interrupting you.
-No, it's fine. It's fine.
-Really?
-Yeah. Sit down.
-ToM: Well, thank you.
So, do you Iive here
or are you just visiting?
No, no, I'm just staying the one night.
-Here, this is for you.
-What is it?
-You' see.
-Well, tell me.
No, you' see. You' see.
I didn't wanna send it in the mail.
-You' see.
-okay.
You know what I'm trying to do?
I'm trying to get us
all around the same table.
The same table.
Yeah, Iike we used to at Christmas.
Are you happy?
-What do you mean?
-Are you happy?
Yeah, of course I am. I'm...
Good. Good. Good girl.
A happy one. First one on my Iist.
Isn't it terrible about ice?
-ice?
-The storm sweeping up the coast.
Hmm.
My name is ice, so I took an interest.
-It's Greek, I think, ice.
-Is it Greek? oh.
-It means truth.
-Truth.
Yeah, well, I heard about it. I...
I was there a few days ago.
I must have just missed it.
-You're Iucky, then.
-Yeah, well, I'm always Iucky.
I'm always Iucky.
Amy, have you seen David?
No, not yet.
Why not?
Well, I had an appointment
with a guy at the prison,
but he didn't turn up.
And I went to the embassy
and found a lawyer,
but he can't meet till the morning.
I've just been running around.
Hopefully tomorrow
I'll start to get somewhere
-and we can tell Dad.
-  Okay.
Look, I'll call you as soon
as I know what's going on.
But, listen, don't worry. Okay?
Oh, sweet morning
Is your head not right
Did you heed my warning
This is the time of times
And your head feels like your body
Your mind is close behind
There's a teardrop on your shoulder
Says this is the time of times
Could you take a picture of me
in front of this?
Yeah.
And one more just to...
Like... Could you... Yeah.
CooR: okay, everybody,
it's a new day,
an opportunity for all of us
to make amends.
So, why don't we start
at the beginning?
Horns, trumpets,
very percussive in the first section.
Strings, more energy in those bows.
Ready?
-It's fine. I' take you right through.
-Thank you.
They're rehearsing right now.
-Hey, Dad, what are you doing here?
-What am I doing?
I've come to see you conduct.
-What are you doing?
-I'm rehearsing.
-Aren't you conducting?
-Not today. No. I'm...
-You're playing the drum.
-I am. It's percussion.
It's what I do.
-I thought you were conducting.
-Not today. I' explain.
I should get back.
You just walked off the stage
and nobody noticed?
Come on, stop it.
What are you doing here?
I'm visiting. It's a surprise.
I came to spend some time
with my son, the conductor.
-That's my cue.
-Well, get back, get back.
okay.
-Ro That's very good.
-Very good. Yeah.
Never hit a drum in my Iife,
but suddenly I'm very good.
Without training, without skill,
without all the musical talent
that you have.
Never said I was conducting, Dad.
Yeah, well,
your mother said you were doing well,
that you were conducting
and composing and doing your music.
I am doing my music. It's percussion.
It suits me just fine.
But the drum?
It's Iow pressure, and I enjoy it.
I get to travel, the money's fine,
I got no ties.
Everybody said that you had a talent,
that you had a future.
People are polite, Dad. You know,
they don't always tell you the truth.
The truth is,
I was never quite good enough.
But all that education,
and now you're disappointed?
I'm not disappointed.
I'm not disappointed,
but you obviously are.
No, I'm not disappointed.
It just seems Iike a waste, that's all.
of what? What's it a waste of?
of your telephone wire?
No, no. It's not that. I didn't say that.
You know, I still compose,
and I conduct in my spare time,
but nobody wants to employ me
to do that professionally.
That's just the way it is.
Well, I guess I'm just saying
it's never too Iate. You could...
You could keep at it
and go back to studying,
-and I could help you out.
-It doesn't work Iike that, Dad.
If it was going to have happened,
it would have happened by now.
Besides, I'm not sure it's what I wanted.
I think maybe I was doing it for you.
I don't believe that.
Dad, the point is, this suits me just fine.
This is what I want.
Hey. Hey.
Are you managing okay at home?
-Yeah, I'm cooking every day.
-Cooking? Yeah?
-Do you know what you're doing?
-No, I just make it up, but...
Well, I thought we could spend
a couple of days together.
I... Dad, I fly to Europe this evening.
It's a big trip.
We gotta pack up this afternoon.
I wish I could, honestly, but you know...
I'm sorry, Dad.
That would have been great.
Well...
I went to see David in New York.
Is he still at the same address?
Yeah. I think so.
Yeah, I want to check his address
and phone number with you.
Sure.
Ro I need some fresh air.
right.
-Robert, come on. Don't smoke.
-What do you mean, don't smoke?
Don't smoke. You know better.
Come on.
Don't smoke.
right, I won't smoke.
Not in front of you.
Not if it upsets you,
but you know I do smoke sometimes.
Just so you know.
-Anyway, you used to smoke.
-I know I used to smoke.
That's when I didn't know any better.
Now I do.
Your mother made me stop, too.
You know, I will, too, but occasionally
I do smoke. When I wanna quit, I' quit.
-Hey, Robert.
-Hey, Dave.
Let me get this straight.
You worked in a wire factory
smoking a couple of packs a day,
but me being a percussionist
and having an occasional cigarette
-isn't good enough for you?
-Come on.
You know, Mom used to say,
"Make your dad proud.
"He works so hard for us."
And I know you're not proud of me.
I know.
-That's not true.
-I can feel it. It's fine.
I'm working hard here.
I'm doing the best I can.
-Have your cigarette.
-What?
Have your cigarette, you need it.
No, you know what? I quit.
-Hi, Robert.
-Hey, I just quit smoking.
-Good job.
-Thanks.
I'm not quitting
because you want me to.
I'm quitting
'cause I know you don't think I can.
-Just to make that clear, okay?
-okay.
Anyway, you sounded good
on the drums.
I missed a beat
when I heard you coming in,
bumping your bag.
You kind of threw me off there.
Well, anyway,
what's a missed beat here and there?
It's good, sounded very good.
Yeah. Thanks, Dad.
We don't see
each other very often. I wasn't trying to...
I'm sorry, you know. I just...
Look, you just gave up smoking.
You're gonna be a Iittle edgy.
Is that...
Is that what it is?
-Well, anyway, I'm sorry.
-Yeah, well, I'm sorry, too.
Hey, James,
I want to introduce you to my father.
-of course.
-This is James Green,
-famous conductor.
-Hi, James.
This is Frank, my dad.
Very famous dad.
-Nice to meet you.
-Nice meeting you.
-Good Iuck with everything.
-Thanks.
He's busy.
You got a girlfriend
you wanna tell me about?
-There was someone up until recently.
-But not anymore?
You know, she wanted to settle down.
She started talking about babies.
It's difficult with the traveling,
you know?
There's some girls in the orchestra.
-I noticed.
-oh, yeah? You noticed?
-I got my eye on a couple of them.
-Couple, yeah?
Well, you Iook...
You Iook after yourself, Robert.
I'm getting the whole family together.
Amy's gonna call you.
But if not, if she forgets, you call her
and you stay in touch with each other.
I will. I will.
-And you're happy?
-Happy, yeah.
I get paid to bang a big Ioud drum
all day. of course I'm happy.
okay, I'm...
Hey, I'm sorry that we couldn't spend
more time together.
Maybe I'm wrong
Amputate sympathy
Strength of my tongue
It's taken that liberty
Ro I don't know. He's...
I'm watching him right now.
He's buying his ticket.
He arrives in Vegas at 1 0:00
tomorrow morning, okay?
Okay. I'll be there.
No, no, no.
He doesn't want you to meet him.
-He wants it to be a surprise, okay?
-Of course I'm gonna meet him.
-If I want to meet him, I'll meet him.
-Rosie, he doesn't...
okay. But, you know,
he's not gonna Iike it.
How are you? Are you okay?
Yeah, I am, I guess...
You know, I wanted to spend some time
with him.
I'm free tonight and tomorrow,
but I just can't. I can't do it. I can't do it.
-I don't know what to say to him.
- I know. God, I know.
-Rosie.
-What?
-He's asking about David.
-Okay, I won't say anything.
Ro No, I mean, there's nothing
to say. What are we gonna say?
We don't know anything.
Play devil's advocate
Never I fear
Pay for it afterwards
How do I feel?
A glorified refugee
Nobody ever says goodbye
But I don't mind
just come home
Where you heading?
-Where you heading?
-Las Vegas.
Not from here you ain't, not tonight.
Let me see your ticket.
-What time you got?
-1 0:55.
The ticket office said that there was
a bus going to Las Vegas,
Bay 3, at 1 1 :00.
Well, now, all we know for sure
is that your watch ain't being
completely honest with you.
There was a bus at 1 1 :00,
but now it's nearly 1 2:00.
-1 2:00?
-Where you just come from?
New York, Chicago, Denver.
Seems Iike you put your watch
back one too many times, my friend.
There ain't no way you gonna catch
a bus that Ieft here an hour ago.
-There's no other bus?
-There's no other bus.
Not this time of night.
There's a truck stop
1 00 yards up the road.
If you're Iucky, you might pick up a Iift
and catch the night train.
okay. Thank you.
I'm wondering, "Why is this guy
trying to see his whole family,
"all over the country,
all in the same trip?"
Well, I'm not dying,
if that's what you're thinking.
Hey, I'm not thinking anything.
I'm just trying to visit the kids
and surprise them.
Their mother's always kept an eye
on them, and now it's up to me, so...
-You Iost your wife?
-About eight months ago.
I Iost my husband.
Just over a year now.
I Iost him to drink, but it was my fault.
I was stupid.
Ignored all the signs,
you know how you do?
I Iisten to that radio all day in this cab.
We got ourselves an epidemic
going on out there.
You know, people eating too much,
drinking too much,
killing themselves, basically.
Making up excuses all along the way.
Because facing up to the truth
ain't always easy.
-No.
-Man, people Iike things easy.
-That's what they're used to.
-Yeah.
-No one Iikes to get hurt.
-Hmm.
No. Nobody Iikes to get hurt.
I stop off in Reno.
There's a night train from there,
gets you into Vegas in the morning.
otherwise, there's a cheap Iittle motel
where I shut down,
if you don't wanna travel
through the night.
Don't get all shy on me.
That wasn't a proposition.
-No, I...
-Yeah, I sleep in the truck, all right?
-Co Take care, Frank.
-I appreciate it. Thank you.
-Are you all right?
-Don't touch me.
-I'm not touching anybody. I'm just...
You okay?
Do your parents know where you are?
If I give you some money,
will you eat something?
Yeah, I'm clean, man.
-Do you need some money?
-I could use some money.
I mean,
everyone can use some money, right?
okay. Here you go. Here.
You're okay?
- Yeah. What's with the questions?
-Well, you could say thank you.
-Could what?
-You could say thank you.
I gave you some money.
You could say thank you.
Hey, you're right.
I'm sorry, man, you're right.
Yeah. I forgot my manners.
You got a couple of hundred dollars
in there and this is my thanks.
Need that?
ease don't do anything. Just...
I need... That's my medication. No. No.
oh, God, no.
j
I'm not here at the moment,
and Frank is probably in the garden.
Leave a message,
and I'll call you back.
David?
of all my children, you're the one
that I worry about the most.
I'm trying, Dad.
-Dad!
-David!
Tell me when I can see you.
Dad?
Robert, Dad wasn't on the bus.
What?
I met the 10:00 bus
like you said,
and everyone else got off,
but he's not on it.
Well... Well, did you look
in the station? I mean...
Yeah, of course,
I looked everywhere.
I don't know what to tell you.
He was doing the 1 0: 00.
So how can he not be on it?
Are you all right, Frank?
Listen, the damnedest thing happened.
I was brushing my teeth this morning,
and I left my bottle of pills
right on the edge of the sink.
Well, I knocked the whole thing
right into the sink, and it got all wet.
- There's nothing left. In the sink.
- In the sink. Gee, God damn it,
-you're as bad as me, you know that.
- The damnedest thing.
Listen, I'll write a new prescription,
all right?
just pop in. I'll leave it in the reception.
Is that the only way to get them?
Go to reception?
I have to come in?
The garden is doing... Is great... I'm...
It's doing... I'm Iooking right at it.
Looking really good, really good.
Hello?
Hey, it's me. Are you home?
No. I'm waiting for you.
Where are you?
He told you I was coming,
didn't he?
No.
I told him not to tell you
I was coming, and he told you.
-Hi, Dad.
-Hi, glamour girl.
-Welcome to Vegas, Dad.
-Yeah. Thanks.
Ro I didn't order a stretch.
I just wanted something comfortable.
It's good. No, it's got plenty of Ieg room,
that's for sure.
That's why they call it a stretch.
-I missed you.
-I miss you.
-I've been worried about you.
-Tell me about your show.
okay, we were at the Bellagio,
and it was a big production.
Lots of underwater dance scenes,
and I was the mermaid,
-the Iead.
-of course.
-And you would have Ioved it.
-Well, when can I go?
-It finished Iast week.
-It finished?
Yeah. Next time you have to fly out
and come see me. I just...
I didn't wanna bother you this time
because I knew that
you weren't feeling well,
-but Iook at you.
-Well, Iook at you.
A dancer in a Las Vegas show
on the big stage,
just what you always wanted.
Are you happy? Hmm?
-Very happy.
-Yeah?
So, the only thing missing now is...
Anything?
-A man. I know.
-Well...
- Papa loves mambo
-Papa loves mambo
-Mama loves mambo
Havin' their fling again
Younger than spring again
Feelin' that zing again, wow
-This is where you Iive?
-No, this is an elevator.
Very good.
I think you' Iike the apartment.
It's very spacious.
-Well, I'm happy sleeping on a couch.
-Really?
-Really.
-okay.
-Wow.
-You Iike it?
-It's...
-Very me?
Very you. Very impressive.
-Well, do you wanna see your room?
-Sure.
okay. Come on.
So, bed or sofa? Sofa or bed?
-This is my room?
-Mmm-hmm.
-It's huge. Look at that television.
-I know.
oh, I've booked us dinner
at a place called the Stratosphere.
-Do you know what that is?
-No.
It's a revolving restaurant
800 feet above the ground.
-Stay just Iike that.
-okay.
okay, one more time.
I' just get that.
Stay there, I' be right back.
I'm gonna take another picture.
-Jilly, hi.
-Hi. How are you?
Good. Come on in. I want you to meet...
I need a favor. I have to go
pick up Paul from the airport,
-and I haven't got the car seat.
-okay. I want you to meet my dad.
-Great. Hi.
- Hi.
-Dad, this is my friend, Jilly.
-How you doing?
-Hi. I'm Jilly.
-What was it?
-Hi, Jilly.
-It's a pleasure to meet you.
-How are you doing?
-How are you doing? Who's this guy?
This is Max,
and we could really use a favor.
Could you watch him for a few hours?
Yeah. Well, the only thing is, is that we
were gonna head out Iater for dinner.
You know, it's fine.
You know, I'm gonna pop downstairs.
-I can just see if Helen's around.
-We could stay in if you want.
No. I think you guys should go out.
No, you're tired. It's fine.
-I'm easy, whatever it is.
-We' take him.
-You sure? You sure?
-Here, give him to me.
Thank you so much.
Well, Iisten, I should be back in time
for you guys to go out anyway.
It' just be a couple of hours.
But thank you again.
Ro okay, yeah, it's fine.
Well, I can bathe him.
okay, I' call if I need anything.
Honestly.
I' be all right. okay. Bye.
Hmm?
Um, slight problem.
-Jilly?
-Yeah.
Paul's flight was cancelled,
so he's stuck in
and she's going to pick him up.
So, that means
we have Max for the night.
-okay.
-Is that okay?
It's okay.
What's the matter?
Ro okay, just stay up.
Give me your arm.
-Do you want me to get that?
-No, Dad, just Ieave it. It's fine.
-okay.
-Ro Thanks.
Keep your eyes closed.
Hi. I'm not here right now,
so please leave me a message.
It's me.
Look, I need the apartment back
sooner than I thought. So call me.
Ro  Stop splashing!
A nice apartment.
Yeah, it's a Iittle big, though.
-You bought it?
-No, I'm renting it, but I got a good deal.
Mmm-hmm.
Listen, I'm gonna Ieave tomorrow.
I'm gonna go back home.
-But you just got here.
-I know, but it's been a Iong trip.
I'm running Iow on my medication.
I just thought I'd...
Well, can't we get you a refill?
It's been a Iong trip, honey.
Yeah. You Iook tired.
I'm okay. I should get home.
Would you be okay with that?
Yeah. Course.
You should do what you want.
Here, take that.
I was thinking of flying.
-You never fly.
-I know.
Ro Thank you.
-Cheers.
You didn't really wanna eat out,
did you?
No. I didn't. Not 800 feet above
the ground in a revolving restaurant.
Remember when your mother
taught you how to eat spaghetti?
Yep.
Sometimes I pick up the phone
to dial her number,
and then I remember.
Keep calling next time.
The number's still the same,
and I'm still on the other end.
-okay.
-Yeah?
-Yes.
-I don't know what it is with you kids.
You always told
your mother everything.
You never told me anything. You were
always on the phone with her.
I'd pick up the phone, I'd say, "Hello,"
you'd say "Hi, Dad. Mom there?"
It wasn't that bad. It was just that
Mom was easier to talk to
and you always worried so much
-if everything wasn't perfect.
-No, that's not true.
-We could just talk to Mom.
-oh, but you couldn't talk to me?
Well, she was a good Iistener.
You were a good talker.
Well, so that's good.
We made a good team.
Yeah.
You wouldn't change anything,
would you?
You pushed us pretty hard.
No. That's not true. I...
You didn't all feel that way, did you?
I think David felt it the most.
Yeah, well...
I can see that.
He so never wanted to Iet you down.
I know.
I was never any harder on him,
as far as I could see.
You were all different,
and Iook at him today.
Did I tell you
I went to see him in New York?
-No.
-Yeah, he wasn't there,
but I saw some of his artwork
downstairs in a gallery
below his apartment. It was right there
on display. It was just beautiful.
So Iook what happened to him.
He turned out okay.
You turned out okay.
I don't know, Dad.
How can you say that? Look at you.
You've wanted to be a dancer
ever since you were a Iittle girl.
You were gifted,
and nobody pushed you.
-What about your plans?
-It all worked out.
What did you wanna be
when you were my age?
I didn't have any plans.
I just wanted to hold down a job
and find somebody crazy enough
to marry me, Iike your mother.
But when you guys came along,
things were different.
There were opportunities.
What kind of father would I have been
if I hadn't pushed you? Huh?
So there wasn't anything you wanted
to achieve?
No, I didn't really think much about it.
Never really gave it much thought.
I wanted to do
was just be a good father, that's all.
Ro So you've got
your boarding pass,
and you're all checked in,
and we know your gate.
So?
I' come visit you as soon as I can,
I promise.
I'd Iike that. I wanna get us
all around the same table together.
-At Christmas?
-or before, it's up to you.
Great. Count me in.
oh.
Here.
What's this?
I had to give it to each of you.
-Well, shall I open it?
-No, open it Iater.
-Are you sure?
-Sure I'm sure.
okay.
-Be good.
-Just for you.
-I will.
Bye, Dad.
Have a good flight.
Rosie, where's Dad?
He's on his way home.
I just left him.
What did you find out?
David was caught
buying some drugs in a bar.
No.
He got sick so quickly
that they now think
he may have panicked
and swallowed some of the drugs
when he was arrested.
Is he okay?
Have you seen him?
Not yet.
He was taken to a hospital.
I'm there now,
but they're not being very helpful.
What do you mean?
I keep asking if he's here,
but I can't get a straight answer.
Listen, the lawyer's with me
and the guy from the embassy's here.
I need you to call Robert.
I promised I'd call him
before his concert,
tell him what's going on.
Can you do that for me?
Yeah.
Excuse me?
How much Ionger before we Iand?
Forty minutes, but there's a storm
so it might take a Iittle Ionger.
-A storm?
-It's okay.
We go around it, not through it.
-Can I have some more water, please?
-Sure.
Excuse me.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the captain
has turned on the seatbelt sign,
so we ask you to please return
to your seats as soon as possible.
Sir, you need to push your table up.
Thank you.
Sir, is everything all right?
okay, sir. You're gonna be fine.
You're gonna be fine.
Just breathe for me.
Come on, it's ready.
Everybody sit down.
Hey, David. Come on!
-Thank you.
-How come you're home, Dad?
-I took the day off work.
-But you'd never do that.
I know, but I wanted to spend
some time with you guys.
-Is anything wrong?
-No, nothing is wrong.
Well, you know,
actually there is something.
You know,
I've been asking myself a question
that's been Iike a puzzle,
and I can't figure it out.
Let's stop eating for a minute.
I keep asking myself
why you all Iied to me,
all of you.
Amy, Jeff wore the same shirt to work
the morning after I stayed.
He doesn't Iive with you anymore,
does he?
He Ieft home about three months ago.
There's another woman.
That's why Jack hates him.
When that man Tom came over to me
at the station and shook my hand,
he wanted to make an impression,
didn't he?
You pulled a chair up before he came
over 'cause you were expecting him.
Tom was waiting at the station.
I wanted to know that you'd met him.
I didn't want to miss the opportunity.
In case I get sick
and we never get the chance to meet?
Robert.
I think we should go in.
I think I felt some rain.
There were posters all over the city.
You weren't going to Europe.
You weren't even performing that night.
We could have spent time together.
But you Iied to me.
You didn't wanna be with me.
No, the truth is, Dad, there are
Iots of things that we don't tell you,
but that doesn't mean
that we want to hurt you.
Mom didn't always tell you everything
and you know that.
Don't blame your mother for this,
and wipe your mouth.
Rosie, the baby is yours, isn't it?
I was going to tell you.
-Go on. Tell him the rest.
-Robert, shut up.
-Go on. I' tell him.
-Shut up.
She doesn't know
if she Iikes boys or girls.
Ro Robert, stop it.
Did your mother know
you were pregnant?
And she kept it from me.
Why would she do that?
We were going to tell you,
but then Mom got sick.
I didn't wanna disappoint you.
David, do you still Iive in New York
at that apartment?
No.
-Then where can I find you?
-I can't tell you.
Tell me where I can find you
and when I can see you.
I don't wanna see you, Dad.
No, stop... Do not Iaugh at me.
Tell me the truth.
Wipe that smirk off your face.
Wipe the smirk off your face!
I have your skateboard right in the shed
over there. I know exactly where it is.
I' burn the damn thing! You hear me?
-Don't Iaugh. Don't Iaugh. Quiet!
-A two-by-four with wheels!
After everything I've done for you,
this is all you can do is Iaugh?
When I'm asking you about something
that's worrying me?
Jesus! David!
Your mother always asked me
why I was so hard on you.
This is why. This is exactly why!
Have some respect!
-So what am I supposed to do?
- Act as though nothing's wrong.
That's what Mom did.
It's best for all of us.
I can't do that.
I can't act as if nothing happened.
What do I tell your mother?
What do I say?
Anyway, she won't ask or anything
'cause she's dead.
David!
That's it. I've had enough!
-I'm out of here.
-Me, too! I'm out of here!
Come on!
Tell her nothing.
-How can I do that?
-If you Iove her as she Ioves you,
then you' tell her
what she wants to hear.
Tell her that we are all fine.
Dad?
At Iast. I finally have my family
in the same room.
Is David here?
Rosie's here, and Robert.
How are you feeling?
-Was it a heart attack?
-They're not sure.
Amy, is he telling the truth?
Ro The doctors are waiting
for some test results.
Come on. You don't have to Iie to me.
I always find it so hard
to believe all of you now.
Come on.
They suspected a heart attack.
They ran some tests,
and they got the results,
and it was a heart attack.
-A mild one.
-Good. A start, at Ieast.
I didn't wanna worry you
until you had a chance
to come to terms with what happened.
Well, you can worry me, all of you.
I'm a father of four, I expect that.
I know you all have problems.
I know that, and I can see
you've been keeping things from me.
-But right now, there's something...
-Dad, maybe you should rest.
No, I will rest,
but I need an answer to a question.
You were honest with your mother,
and I want you to be honest with me.
It's all right. I'm okay.
I can handle it.
I... I know David is in trouble,
and I just wanna know where he is
and how soon I can see him.
So who's gonna tell me?
Why don't you take it...
Why don't you rest for a while?
What is it?
Just tell me the truth.
Dad, I'm sorry.
David died, Dad. I'm sorry.
No, I... That's not true.
-Tell me that's not true.
-Ro I'm sorry, Dad.
No.
Ro He moved out
of his apartment and...
No.
Ro...we knew that he was traveling.
And then we started getting calls
from Mexico.
There was a Iot of confusion. We didn't
wanna tell you until we were sure.
No, no...
Ro He had a Iot of problems.
He wasn't happy, Dad.
He's been having a tough time
since Mom died.
We've all been worried about him.
Yeah, but not for sure. I...
It was Mexico. It could be anyone.
It could be a mistake.
-It could be.
- I flew out there after you visited.
-Huh?
-I flew out there after you visited, and...
That's why you couldn't stay.
That's why we all made excuses and...
No. No, no, no...
Not my son. That's not my son.
How?
They said it was an overdose.
No, not my son. That's not my son.
What are you gonna do
when you grow up?
I wanna be a painter
and do my pictures.
No, not a painter.
Painters paint walls,
and dogs pee on walls.
You're gonna be an artist.
You gonna work hard?
Yes, Dad.
You gonna make me proud?
Sorry about
how everything's worked out, Dad.
It's not your fault.
I've been thinking about
what I wanna do when I grow up.
Yeah? And what did you decide?
I might still be an artist or I might
just do a normal job, Iike a painter.
I'd be proud of you
no matter what you did.
-Really?
-Really.
Good.
I told Mom I wouldn't be Iong.
-Give her my Iove.
-I will.
Well, I' see you, Dad.
-David?
-Hmm?
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault, Dad.
David?
Well, it was a big trip.
And if you ask me what I Iearned,
I'd have to tell you I'm not sure.
I know if I could do it all over again,
I would ask Iess of the kids.
As Iong as they were happy,
that would be fine with me.
I know I have to stop thinking of them
as if they're still children.
I can't tell them what to do anymore.
They have to find their own way.
And sometimes
you talked to me about things that
I should have Iistened to you
more carefully.
You presented me with the details
of our children's Iives, and I...
I... I ignored them.
And for that...
But that isn't what you want to hear,
I know.
What you want is the news.
Well, the news is this.
Robert, Amy and Rosie promised
to visit me for the holidays,
and you know what?
This time I believe them.
And David...
David...
I hope he' spend Christmas with you.
I went back to New York
to buy David's painting.
The portrait, I know which one
you mean, but I'm afraid it's sold.
It is sold?
Well...
-Were you familiar with the artist or...
-Yeah, I...
Yeah, not as much as I would
Iike to have been, but, yeah.
Thank you.
Why don't you give me your details?
If anything of David's comes in,
I' Iet you know.
Excuse me?
I just saw your name. I'm stupid.
I should have realized.
That's okay.
I'm sorry.
You know, I knew David. He used to
hang out at the gallery all the time,
and he used to say
that if it wasn't for his dad,
that he never would have
become an artist.
He said he would have
ended up painting walls
and that dogs pee on walls.
Look, we might have something of his
in storage. I can check if you'd Iike.
-okay, sure.
-okay.
Now, I won't pretend
David's work was very commercial.
Here it is.
He had his own style,
and he wasn't concerned with fashion.
But for what it's worth,
I thought he was really special.
Thank you.
Hello, this is Frank. I'm not out...
I mean, I'm not here at the moment.
I'm probably out shopping
for the holidays.
But if you leave a message,
I will call you back. Thank you.
Don't laugh, but I promised to cook
the turkey for the first time this year.
I got the whole family coming.
What's the biggest bird you got?
Half a dozen of them.
And treat the children to some
expensive wine.
-You got some reds on the right.
-Excellent choice, if I may say so, sir.
-That's the sale price. Yeah.
-It's the sale price?
I'm even thinking
of replacing the old tree.
If I gave it to you for any cheaper,
I wouldn't be making any money.
Let me tighten it. It has to...
You're Ietting it droop too much.
I need a Iittle more slack to
get around... How does this Iook?
-Dad's side's perfect.
-Ro You kidding me?
Yours needs work.
Ro oh, yeah?
Ro Yeah.
-Thank you.
-Ro What's that sound?
-What's that?
-Turkey.
-You're timing the turkey?
-Yeah.
Ro That's so efficient.
Hey! Jesus!
Now you're...
It's not cooked yet, Dad.
I just checked it.
-You just checked it?
-Yeah, the juices are still red.
Well, why don't you stick
to the potatoes and I' do the turkey?
okay.
This is you!
Look, it has your name
and the third grade written on its butt.
-Do you remember that?
-I remember when I made this.
Ro Yeah.
-Ro Hey, Dad, are you okay?
-Yeah.
Check that turkey, Grandpa.
Dad, that's a big bird.
You'd better cook it properly.
-Just check the Ieg, Dad.
-Don't worry.
-Just to make sure.
-I will. I will.
Well, Mom actually would have cooked
it for at Ieast another 30 minutes.
Yeah, well, there's something I
need to tell all of you about your mother.
As much as I Ioved her
and as a good cook as she was,
in all the 41 years we've been married,
she always over-cooked the turkey,
every single year.
I just never had the heart to tell her.
right. Perfect.
Hi, honey.
Will you help me get him burped?
There we go.
This one's yours,
if you want, Robert.
Yeah, that would be great. Thanks.
-I'm kind of on a diet anyway.
-Ro Good boy.
-Where's his tray?
- Grandpa, watch out.
Watch out. okay, that's hot.
Your family is making its way
in the world,
and you can be proud of the children
and their achievements.
And, if you were to ask me,
I would have to say in all honesty,
-everybody's fine.
- Are you hungry?
Everybody's fine.
- Babysitter.
-Yeah, I know.
For so long
I was out in the cold
And I taught myself to believe
every story I told
It was fun hanging on to the moon
Heading into the sun
But it's been too long
Now I wanna come home
Came so close
To the edge of defeat
But I made my way in the shade
Keeping out of the heat
It was fun shooting out of the stars
Looking into the sun
But it's been too long
Now I wanna come home
Home, where there's nothing
but sweet surrender
To the memories from afar
Home, to the place
where truth lies waiting
We remember who we are
For too long
I was out on my own
Every day I spent trying to prove
I could make it alone
It was fun hanging on to the moon
Heading into the sun
But it's been too long
Now I wanna come home
Home
For so long
I was out in the cold
But I taught myself to believe
every story I told
It was fun hanging on to the moon
Heading into the sun
But it's been too long
Now I wanna come home
Yeah, it's been too long
Been too long
Now I wanna come home
Extracted By : Abu Essa
Preuzeto sa www.titlovi.com