I've never gone parking before.
I'm really not that kind of a girl.
Well, I'm not the kind of a guy
who would go with that kind of a girl.
That's so sweet!
- I think!
- There's nothing to be scared of.
I knew this would happen
if we made out!
Good shot, sir!
General,
I think he's surrendering.
Fire at will!
Keep firing! Keep firing!
Keep firing!
Kill every last alien!
You'll all become my alien zombies!
What did tell you about
these kind of movies?
It was almost over.
¶ Lollipop lollipop
Oh, lolli lolli lolli! ¶
¶ Lollipop! ¶
Lollipop performed by Sophie Green
¶ Lollipop lollipop
Oh, lolli lolli lolli! ¶
¶ Lollipop! ¶
He only looks just like his father.
Just like his father!
¶ And when he does
his shaky rocking dance ¶
¶ Man, I haven't got a chance ¶
¶ I call him ¶
¶ Lollipop lollipop
Oh, lolli lolli lolli! ¶
¶ Lollipop! ¶
¶ Sweeter than candy on a stick ¶
¶ Huckleberry, chimry or lime ¶
¶ If you had a choice,
he'd be your pick ¶
¶ But lollipop is mine ¶
¶ Lollipop lollipop
Oh, lolli lolli lolli! ¶
¶ Lollipop! ¶
I hate the rain.
It's raining rocks and dogs!
Great!
¶ Sweeter than candy on a stick ¶
¶ Huckleberry, chimry or lime ¶
¶ If you had a choice,
he'd be your pick ¶
¶ But lollipop is mine ¶
¶ Lollipop lollipop
Oh, lolli lolli lolli! ¶
¶ Lollipop! Lollipop! ¶
Space.
Universe of mystery.
Well, today the mystery
will be unveiled.
Thanks to science.
We now know, the universe
is nearly 500 miles long.
And it contains,
you're not gonna believe this...
...over one thousand stars.
Lem, come on,
liven it up!
And still,
the only known intelligent life...
...is right here on our planet.
No! No!
Not today...
What was that?
That's our planet after the attack
from the Humaniacs.
They're gonna eat our brains
for dinner!
- Is that true?
- Everybody, please!
- That's ridiculous!
- Totally ridiculous.
Brains for dinner?
Come on!
Brains are for breakfast
with cereal and milk.
Dinner's organs and eyeballs!
Okay, everyone... everyone!
Please listen up.
We're not getting eaten.
Or harvested.
Or having our brains barbecued.
The universe isn't scary.
It's really amazing.
And... don't forget to
pickup your planetary yo-yo's.
We've got one for each of you.
You are looking at the
new junior assistant curator!
High four!
Well, it's part-time now and
a full-time after I graduate.
How did you do, Lem?
- Got the job!
Knew you would.
Hey, I can see my whole life!
A house, a car...
two kids.
They'll grow up and have kids.
They will come home to
visit us on holidays.
Well?
- Got it!
Lem?
Congratulations on that job.
- I knew you could it.
- Yeah, thanks.
There it is...
just two more days!
Humaniacs III.
The final battle for our world!
- Victory or extinction!
If you guys go in costume,
I'm pretending we never met.
Did you just say
what I think you just said?
I'm a planetarium professional now.
I don't have time for
kid's movies anymore.
Kid's movies?
I suppose next you'll say
aliens don't exist?
Yeah!
Just as I thought.
You are not Lem!
You're an alien zombie
like in Humaniacs II!
Skiff,
I'm not a zombie.
Yeah, that's what you zombies are
programmed to say.
Tell me something
the real Lem know.
Well, I know,
Skiff is the only nutcase...
...who thinks the government is hiding
a whole alien evidence in Base 9.
And, you give candy to your puppy
so he'll poop jelly beans.
It was just an experiment.
With all due respect...
I put in the hours and done
a lot of alien research at work.
What? What are you talking about?
You work in a comic book store!
The greatest source of
scientific knowledge.
Skiff!
Try to unpack the fake alien poop!
Right away, Mr. Oglob.
You'll believe me, Lem.
When aliens put you
on the take-out menu.
Skiff!
I love fake alien poop day!
So, um...
Eckle, do you think
your sister's home?
- Why?
- I thought of may be...
I thought I might tell her
I got the job.
- Why?
- Forget it. You tell her for me, okay?
Okay, but every time you tell me
to tell her something...
...she asks why don’t you
just tell her yourself.
What?
- And then my mom says...
...because you like her and then
she says that "Oh, that's so cute. "
And why don't you just ask
her out, already?
Because she's been waiting for you,
to ask her out,
...ever since we moved
the next door to you.
She... she has?
The girl of my dreams likes me?
This is the best day of my life!
Yeah, you gotta see
the kids throw up!
Hey, he did it!
He got the job!
We're so proud of you!
I hear, it's just one easy step-up
to senior assistant curator.
¶ Oh, my love ¶
Unchained Melody performed by
The Righteous Brothers
¶ My darling ¶
¶ I've hungered for your touch ¶
Wha...?
- Come on, soldier!
Take that hill!
Hey, Neera.
- Hey, Lem.
I wanted to tell you...
- I got the job.
- Lem, that's great!
- Maybe it's time that you and me...
- Yes?
I mean,
would you wanna...
Hey, hey, Neera!
I've been looking all over for you.
You've been looking for me?
The "cause" needs you!
- The "what"?
- The "cause".
Glar's involved with something
he calls "protesting".
It's like, when you shout about stuff
that makes you upset.
Yeah, like our school pictures.
Why do they have to be our faces?
I mean, what a bummer!
That means, it's not good.
Neera, we need you,
righteous mamma!
I'm so honored.
But, Lem was about to
ask me something.
Yeah, man!
What you wanna ask her?
- It's kinda private.
- No problemo, man.
I mean,
I totally respect that.
So, Neera...
Neera and Lem
had a private conversation.
And don't wanted
anybody else around.
- Yeah, you know, we can talk later.
- Okay.
Peace.
That means see you later.
Bye!
- Bye!
The "cause", man!
I'd like to "cause" him some pain!
I don't wanna hear a single bubble.
Especially, you bubbles.
¶ Well Be Bop A Lula
she's my baby ¶
¶ Be Bop A Lula
I don't mean maybe ¶
¶ Be Bop A Lula she's my baby ¶
¶ Be Bop A Lula! Be Bop A Lula! ¶
Call the General!
Resistance is futile.
Surrender or die!
Come on, Eckle.
Go, help your father.
¶ Mister sandman, bring me a dream ¶
What the...?
A duck?
Mom! Dad!
There’s a ship in the...
Open wide or the big bad
monster will get ya.
The battle for our world...
...has begun.
- Captain, mobilize the army.
- Yes, sir.
Right, men! Move it!
Are they hostile?
Will our species survive?
One thing we do know is...
...that they show no respect
for our parking laws.
And speaking of survival,
...how will you survive
without a sparkling smile?
Give your smile that special glow.
Try the sparkle action of DentaPro!
You know, you're really good
as that toothbrush.
Yeah, but what I really do best
is a suppository.
Now, let's see.
"Invasion by giant ants. "
"Invasion by sea monsters. "
"Invasion by 50 foot women!? "
Here it is.
"So you've been invaded by aliens. "
Keep your eyes out for aliens!
- Aliens!?
All right, class.
Let's try it one more time.
Aliens are coming!
Flarc, you were too slow.
Go join the zombies.
I told it!
The only question is...
Should I be terrified because
this is the end of the world
or happy because
I totally told it.
Me, I have a plan.
They're gonna need a native
to run the mines.
I'll befriend them,
show my executive skills...
...and "Bam" I'm in.
Speaking of the amendment...
A cork?
It's your best defense against
the alien's favourite form of research.
"The Probe. "
You put it in...
Yeah! Yeah, I think I get it.
Wait! This is yours.
I already used that one.
I just remembered, my job.
I gotta go.
- You know, my boss.
- Your boss?
No problem.
You guys can share.
Uh, Neera, you have to choose.
It's either me or Glar.
Oh, Lem, there's no question.
It's you, of course.
Come on.
Come on! Come on!
Hello, this is the alien hotline.
Yes, hi, I found the alien.
They're here
and no weapon can stop them.
You gotta be kidding.
- Hello?
- Yes, hello.
I found the alien!
If you've spotted an alien fleet,
dial one.
For pod-people, dial two.
I can breathe! I can breathe!
You speak my language.
That's amazing!
Yeah, that's what I just said.
You just said,
"that's what I just said. "
- Say something else.
- Like what?
Like... what.
They're gonna freak back at Kennedy.
I'm Captain Charles T. Baker.
Astronaut.
As-tro-naut.
- Ass...
- tronaut.
Lem.
Lem...
Either your name is Lem,
...or you wanna mate with me.
Houston, we have a little problem.
What do you...
what do you want?
Thanks for asking.
Coffee light, two sugars.
Do you've frapuccino up here?
Any puff pastry too. Thanks.
No, I mean, are you...
...here to take over our world,
...and like, eat our brains?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on!
What kind of sick planet is this?
First of all, it's supposed to be
uninhabited, okay?
Not full of sea monkeys
dancing to the oldies!
My mission was to plant Old Glory,
whack a few golf balls and...
...head back for
the Kids Choice Awards.
I'm getting slimed.
- What?
- You were just talking alien.
- Hey, I'm not the alien here, you are!
- Me? You are!
- No? You are!
- You are! You...
You came to my planet.
An alien planet!
- Hello!
- Hello.
Not "hello". Hello!
- Hello, what?
- What?
Let's start over.
Look. There’s a command module
in orbit right now.
It's running out of fuel.
It has to leave in 74 hours.
And if I'm not on it,
it goes back to Earth without me.
Capish?
I have to get to my ship
and go back up in space.
Can you help me?
You want me to take you
to your flying saucer?
No. If they catch me helping you
who knows what they'll do to me.
I'll lose everything.
My life is just getting perfect.
Kid...
You're a kid, right?
I mean, you're not like
a 1000yrs old Yoda or anything?
Never mind.
Look, you're my only hope.
But I suppose you could
leave me stranded.
My wife will have to support the kids.
Eleven... we have eleven kids.
Always hungry.
But, hey, they'll get by without a father.
The important thing here is
you avoid a little trouble.
Alien hot line.
What's the nature of your sighting?
Hello! Are you there?
Hey, fella!
Who wants a donut?
Silly dog!
Get back!
There's your flying saucer.
Now what?
Okay.
Here's the plan.
You knock out that cop.
Then, you overpower those two.
You neutralize that one and handcuff
the big guy to the steering wheel.
That's your plan?
- What if they start shooting?
- You're one of their own.
- They probably just aim for your legs.
- My legs?
- Don't your legs grow back?
- No!
We're not like your kind, okay?
I tell you what.
Eat this.
- You'll become invincible.
- Oh, good, then you do it!
I can't be seen breaking the law.
I've got the Right Stuff.
- The what?
- The Right Stuff.
It means I have lot of courage.
Now go!
Go on! Go! Go!
Hey, hey, Lem!
Something wrong?
Move in! Move in!
Move in!
As you can see,
the army has taken it's position...
...for the fight
in the War of the Worlds.
Getting ready for our first
moment in...
...with invaders from outer space.
Attention!
So they have came.
Captain!
- Sir!
Have your men search
the flying saucer.
Yes, Sir!
- Move!
- Sir.
Now our brave soldiers
are entering...
...the alien spaceship.
It doesn't look big enough
to be a Space Destroyer.
It's dark in here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey, look!
No sign of the pilot, sir.
I've never seen such a hideous weapon!
We're up against a
cruel, sadistic enemy!
Seal off the town!
I want that alien pilot found!
I protest!
They're bumming me up
with their bad vibrations.
Well, there's one thing you gotta do.
Never mind, Captain,
the alien is right here.
- Grab that prisoner!
- Yes, sir.
Glar's not the alien!
Oh, no?
Then what do you call this?
- Hair. He likes it long.
- Very unusual.
You might even say...
...very alien!
Excuse me! General!
He does go to the high school.
Glar's just trying to say
the aliens might be friendly.
Lem!
Lem, you know astronomy.
If an alien came all this way...
...wouldn't it be smart enough
to come in peace?
No! No, no, no!
I mean...
They... they have come to
harvest our organs.
- To make us slaves!
- Me?
We should all... all of us,
right now, go home and hide.
That's a sensible young man.
Let him go.
And the rest of you,
go to your homes.
And wait for instructions.
Hurry up! Go, go, go!
Great! Just great!
Look, I said you'd take you
to your flying saucer, okay?
Well, there it is! Now leave!
I'll get you a blanket and
a pillow for the night.
It's a miracle, I'm gonna need.
You like the stone?
Go! Go!
There it is! Stop!
There it is!
¶ I'm gonna tell Aunt Mary about Uncle John ¶
¶ He claims he has the music,
but he has a lot of fun ¶
¶ Oh baby, yeah, baby ¶
¶ Ooh baby, having me some fun tonight ¶
¶ Well, long tall Sally,
she's built for speed ¶
¶ She got everything that Uncle John need ¶
¶ Oh baby, yeah, baby ¶
¶ Ooh baby, having me some fun tonight ¶
"What To Do When Aliens Invade"
Aliens are quite like us.
Except they have two sets of teeth,
...hypodermic fingertips,
And hypnotic eyes to
control our brains and...
...turn us into an army of zombies
and destroy our world.
What?
Remember,
anyone caught helping the aliens,
...will go to jail.
Jail?
This is great!
Yesterday my life was perfect.
And now, I'm the most wanted
super criminal in the world.
At least you have a world!
I probably will never see mine again.
Our preliminary procedures
have been completed, sir.
The spacecraft is quarantine.
We're looking for a, uh,
place for your headquarters, sir.
- And, uh...
- Still no trace of the alien, sir!
Where would you hide
if you were an alien?
Hide?
An alien invader spends over $500
to fly across the universe...
...to hide!
You clown!
He's here to takeover our minds!
Even yours!
Diabolical!
Captain, place me under arrest!
Not so fast, General!
I've trained my superior intellect
to recognize alien mind slaves.
You're clean!
But he is a zombie and...
...those two!
How we know who is a zombie?
Well, zombies don't feel any pain.
- You're clean!
- You too!
General, you must capture
the alien alive...
...and bring it to me.
I'll unlock the secrets
of it's marvellous brain.
Captain, search the town!
Go door to door, if you must.
But find that alien!
Hello, "Plark",
if that really is you.
Have a nice day, "Serbok".
Or should I call you
by your alien name?
Why I have to go to the dentist
if it's the end of the world, ma?
Invasion or not, you gotta go!
My mom's a zombie!
Help!
Grab!
We're getting it right, uh...
So this is last
street we gotta do today.
Okay, let's start at this end.
Wait. I think I'm a zombie.
I'm hearing an irritating,
piercing voice in the back of my head.
- Oh, shut up! It's me.
- It's there again!
It's me, you moron.
Hey, what's that?
Hey, look!
That's funny.
Look at this!
Look at the dog!
Mom?
Mom... mom, don't come in!
Rover?
Boy, am I glad to see you, Rover!
He is a probe we sent to take
pictures of your world.
A planet full of aliens...
...and you send back
pictures of rocks?
Bad boy! Bad boy!
Mom, don't... don't come in!
- The alien! Wow!
Can I get your autograph?
Eckle, this isn't a comic book,
okay? It's serious!
I don't mind. Comes with
being a national hero.
And... and my humaniacs poster?
And my... and my chest?
How... how about a snapshot?
Get one of me looking up
at the stars.
Mom!
- I saw the alien last night!
I'm so in!
I got this guy wrapped around
my little finger!
Let me tell you,
this alien is not so scary.
It's...
Your personal chef
reporting for duty, sir.
May I give some
tasty suggestions for tonight?
I've got the list of
the fattest teachers in my school.
Incase you're looking for a light snack.
Skiff, stop!
He's not here to eat us or anything.
He's harmless,
to everyone but me.
Better let me do the talking.
I think, he's eyeing you for desert.
It's kinda cute the way
he does that.
Great, let's just have a party!
We're doing a routine search
for the alien.
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
It's trying to control our minds!
What do we do?
Don't look in it's eyes!
That's how it take over your brain!
Brains?
That's right, brains!
You are my zombie slaves!
- I want to control your brains!
- It's inside my head!
His will is too strong!
Command us, Master!
Command me, too!
It's not real.
I think I know
when I'm being mind-controlled.
Maybe they can get me on my ship.
I lean toward probably not.
But I think I know who can.
...just to the left of me here.
Everything is checked
and double-checked.
The High Command taking
control of the situation...
You want our home
for your headquarters?
That would be a great honor!
Honey, tell Lem we have guests.
Lem, there's someone
you would like to...
Kiss the ship goodbye, Rover!
You really think,
you can get me on TV?
You're the biggest story in history!
The whole planet will watch!
The whole planet?
Interesting.
I left my hair products on the ship.
But I could improvise.
You know,
astronauts have to deal with...
...any kind of emergency.
I get it.
We could tell everyone, he's peaceful.
All we need is a safe place,
...a TV reporter and then
we can all get on with our lives.
Skiff, the comic bookstore,
let's go there.
Okay...
But if he's not house,
you're cleaning up his mess.
We need a slogan.
Like something that says it's a bummer
to make war on the aliens...
...when we should make, uh...
Hey, Neera!
- Hi.
- Hi!
- You kill any alien, Lem?
Kill any...?
Oh, no, you don't understand.
These soldiers aren't...
Oh, great!
This day gets better and better!
General Grawl,
you better take a look at this.
Professor, take a look.
This is obviously alien writing.
It says, uh...
Surrender or die!
And this is a list of surrender terms.
Diabolical!
What are you doing in Lem's room?
I'm afraid your son is a zombie.
Hey, kid, what's bugging you?
Neera.
What is that,
like an alien hernia?
Well, sort of...
It's the girl of my dreams.
And now me hates me.
Wow, hate's a strong word.
Maybe she just...
...dislikes you.
Plus there's another guy.
Glar.
Okay. You know your problem?
It's not Glar.
Or Neera.
It's Lem.
Look at you,
you're so left brain.
Or is it right brain?
Whatever, you're like
the chief of control.
You gotta loosen up.
We got a little time.
You, my friend, are in luck.
The doctor...
...is in!
Me and Green bean need to talk.
Before we begin,
I have a technical question.
Are you considered very...
...ugly on this planet?
- What?
- Because I can tell.
- No.
I mean...
- I'm okay.
- Good, good.
Why do chicks dig me?
Because I'm handsome?
Because I'm an astronaut?
Yes and yes.
But it's also because of
Chuck Baker's three steps...
...to romance.
Spot your prey.
Make your move.
Show no mercy!
Hey baby,
I saw you across the bar.
Are sparks flying
or is this place on fire?
- You're sure are not ugly, right?
- I think so.
Maybe tomorrow I'll go up in space,
...maybe never to return.
Let's make our last night,
...a night to remember.
Lem!
The cork! The cork!
Remember the plan!
The only plan here
is to get Chuck on TV.
I'll be right back with the reporter.
I'm leaving you in charge.
In charge?
You heard him!
Things are gonna be
different around here.
My wish is your command!
Come on, boys!
Let's track down the story.
We need an alien
for the 6 o'clock news.
- Let's go!
- Hey!
We're really upset!
Upset we really are!
Are we upset, really?
- We're really, really upset.
- Neera, I need to talk to you.
I thought you were after the alien.
- That's not what's going on.
- Then what is?
- I...
- Lem!
Mysterious Lem!
Tell us the secrets of your heart!
I can't say.
Lem, I always thought
we'd be together,
...but I need someone who doesn't always
believe what he's been told.
It's like Glar says...
The times...
...they are a different.
Maybe you should go.
Hey baby!
- What?
- This place is sparking or...
...this fire making
this a night or...
...show no mercy.
Did I happen to mention
I'm not ugly?
What?
Are you crazy?
Is this guy giving you bad vibrations?
Lem was just leaving.
Are you kidding me?
- If you have to do number one,
...use these papers.
If you had to do number two,
go outside.
And if it's number three,
I can't help you.
Got you, alien!
- Victory or extinction!
- Oh, yeah?
In space
no one can hear you scream.
- Missed!
- Crush! Kill! Destroy!
Crush! Kill! DestrØy!
Hey, master,
we wanna be destroyed too.
Quick, cover the camera.
If it's get damaged again
we will have to pay for it.
You're afraid of a little storm?
It's nothing. See?
Rover!
Sit, Rover!
Sit, stop, heel!
Rover, come back!
Listen!
You can't escape the
It's pulling you to your doom!
Six o'clock news, here we go!
Soon we will crush the rebel alliance...
...and control the galaxy!
Thank you, thank you!
Thank you!
You're a rebel spy
and a traitor to the empire.
Take her away!
Skiff!
Hasta la vista, baby!
You’re terminated!
General, over there!
Aren't those comic books?
Captain, get your men!
We gotta get out of here now!
Move it! Move it!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
Chuck, come on!
Sorry, too dangerous! Out!
- But...
Shoot him!
Don't you ever run off like that.
What if they take to the pound?
How do I find you?
Lem?
Oh, boy!
We better run!
Let's move!
Move it! Move it! Move it!
Let the doctor handle this.
Ladies,
Who wants to meet an astronaut?
- Please, one at a time.
- Chuck!
I'm on facebook.
Look there! The monster!
He's getting away!
Rover! No!
All right, quick, hot-wire the car!
What? Hot-wired, who?
When are you, green goopers,
gonna evolve?
Attention all personnel!
What's the matter?
Why did he do it?
I was gonna teach him to fetch.
Amazing!
The alien's brain is so powerful
it's controlling them even now.
What is it telling you to do?
I think I'm supposed to dig
a hive for the alien queen.
Yeah, I'm supposed to blow up things.
I mean, unless you need help
with the hive.
- Oh, no, I'm good.
- You sure?
- I'm good.
- Never mind them, Professor.
This thing has all the answers.
Where's your master?
Talk!
The flying saucer is going to an
undisclosed location...
...to be taken apart and studied.
This reporter is now going to
reveal to you where that location is.
This reporter has just been told,
...that if I do that,
I'll be taken apart and studied.
Oh, look, that's perfect.
That's great!
Oh, just great! Perfect!
John Glenn goes around the world...
...he's a Senator for life!
I went across the freaking universe!
I should be Governor, minimum!
But no, I'm marooned here
on this stupid rock!
This "stupid rock" is my home.
Or was until you came along
and ruined everything.
I want my life back!
Unless, I don't know, maybe there's
something else you want to ruin.
Who's that?
My boss.
Sorry, Mr. Hucklo,
it's just for one night.
Maybe a week.
I really hope this doesn't affect our
working relationship.
Oh, great! Just great!
Fired!
Why don't you just
harvest my organs and...
...get it over with.
Great, now look what you did.
You made him really upset.
Lem?
You're looking right at my home..
See that star,
the little red one?
Circling that star is a planet called Earth.
It's about 20 billion miles away.
- Give or take.
- There's no way space is that big.
What?
Are you kidding?
There's billions of galaxies.
And each galaxy has billions of stars.
Next to that, kid,
our planets are just...
...dust in the wind.
So, nothing I knew was right?
Come on, you knew about Neera.
I mean, look at her.
Lose the antenna,
get some plastic surgery...
...she's a hottie.
I don't have the right stuff
like you.
Kid...
I never had the right stuff.
I'm a button pusher.
Spam in a can.
I don't even fly the ship.
It's all automatic.
I only got this far on charm
and my rugged good looks.
You risked everything to help
a stranger from another world.
You are the one
with the right stuff.
Finally, we been looking for you.
Guys!
Great hiding spot!
- I go for the closet!
- No way!
Let's go fight the army.
How's your species at hiding?
Can you change your skin
to this colour?
Your call Captain Baker.
What's it gonna be?
Fight or hide?
Neither.
I think Lem said
he wants the closet.
I tell you what's it gonna be.
We're gonna go get Chuck
back to his ship.
Skiff, you were right about Base 9.
- That where they have his ship.
- But, we don't where it is.
Yes, we do.
Rover found me,
...he's also programmed
to find my ship.
Wait.
Where is Rover?
It's too painful to talk about!
It's okay.
They've got him
at the comic book shop!
Well, then we've gotta go get him!
Hold on.
The whole army's looking for you two!
You can't just stroll through town.
Wait! Wait!
That new movie...
...doesn't that open tonight?
Yeah...
Why?
The citizens of Glipforg
are undaunted by alien invaders.
And bravely going about
their normal routines.
Gotcha!
There's the comic book store.
Let's go!
What great costumes!
You two are finalists.
Up on stage!
No, we're not here to
enter the contest.
Then why are you dressed
like aliens?
We're here...
...to win the contest.
- What?
- Yeah! Good.
Private, come here.
Hold your fire, soldier.
Take us to your leader.
Welcome to the "Humaniacs 3"
costume contest!
Really upset!
Well, here we got the finalists.
What are we supposed to do?
Give them their
daily minimum dose of Chuck.
Hello, Humaniacs!
Greased Lightning performed by
Lance Ellington
The alien!
Lem!
Over here!
All these costumes, sir.
How do we find the alien?
It's simple, Captain.
Like us, the alien is in uniform.
Grab him!
I got you!
Chuck!
No! No! Get up!
Hey, keep back!
Time to meet the monster.
Face to face!
Look at it, Professor.
It's hideous!
And it smell!
Hey, you try wearing the same suit
for three weeks.
What a remarkable brain
you must have.
An incision here.
And here.
It should pØp right out.
No, you're making a mistake!
He's friendly!
This poor boy is obviously a zombie.
I’ll remove his brain too.
You are no longer needed slave!
I release you!
Return to your puny life!
Kid, I'm going down anyway.
There's no need for you
to come with me.
Thanks.
For everything.
How about it, Professor?
Difficult to tell.
Do you still believe
the alien is friendly?
No.
This boy is free!
We're so glad you're not a zombie.
What about the alien spawn, sir?
I want it destroyed.
One little piece at a time.
All right. Let's get these
aliens to Base 9.
Not that it exists.
Move it!
Get in!
We're here to honor a young man...
...who survived a harrowing ordeal...
...at the hands of the alien monster.
Lem, come on out!
All right?
So, Lem, I understand you'll be working
right here after you graduate.
Teaching about the mysteries of space.
Give us a preview of
what we'll learn.
Well, we know everything
about our universe.
It's 500 miles long.
500 miles!
Remarkable.
I can't.
Space isn't 500 miles!
It's not. It's so much bigger
than we can imagine.
There's billions of galaxies and
each galaxy has billions of stars.
And next to that,
our planet is just...
Excuse me.
Lem?
I know I was kinda harsh.
I'm really sorry.
Hi, Neera.
What are you doing?
It's called hot-wiring.
It's how they start cars on Earth.
Lem, um...
I was thinking... well...
You know, now that
this is all over...
- Yeah, Neera?
- Maybe...
We could...
Lem!
You left everyone hanging.
I'm gonna go find Chuck.
But how?
It's impossible without Rover.
My little Rovy.
I can still hear his
waging little antenna.
Rover?
Rover!
You're alive.
But... how did you get out?
Good going, boy.
Rover... Rover, can you find Chuck?
Where's Chuck?
You're going with me?
- Hm-Hmm.
All right!
So you thought you could
take over our world?
Your kind knows no decency.
You mean Jake Mankins?
No, aliens.
Tell us your invasion plans!
And don't bother taking over my mind.
If you do...
Captain Kizno has orders to shoot me.
If you take over Captain Kizno's mind,
Lt. Groit has orders to shoot him.
If you take over Lt. Groit's mind,
Sergeant Yerk will shoot Captain Kizno,
Lt. Groit and myself...
...along with these three soldiers.
Each man has a designated
target in the squad.
Should you succeed in taking over
all of our minds,
Corporal Hisk has orders to
electrocute everyone.
If this fails,
the entire base is rigged to blow...
...at the touch of a button.
General, sir, am I supposed to shoot
Hecknavar or Kolski?
- I shoot Kolski!
- No, you shoot Meckavoy.
Well, then who shoots Kolski?
I can shoot myself.
That won't be necessary.
Hecknavar, you shoot Kolski,
Captain Kisno and graze Corporal Hisk.
- Yes, sir.
- Not yet!
- Drop your weapon!
- You!
- Him first!
- I'm not taking my eyes off Kisno!
- Drop it, Dirt-bag!
Hold your fire!
Captain Kizno...
...get everyone out of here.
You're not thinking
all this is my fault, right?
All right.
You won't tell us.
There's another way to unlock
the secrets of your brain.
Professor Kipple!
He's all yours.
He thinks we found him.
Hang on, Chuck.
We'll find you.
There you are.
I was just warming up for you.
I'll have that brain of his, no time.
You don't want my brain,
it's useless.
I spent four years at a party school.
Trust me, it's mush.
Hello?
Anyone here?
Skiff, what are you doing?
Come on, no one's around.
I'm not gonna get caught.
What, what, what?
I'm paying! I'm paying!
The thing with the...
I mean, it just went over the...
Wow!
Base 9...
This is amazing!
I was right again!
How do we get in
without being seen?
Hold now!
- What?
But I'm sorry, officer,
your rules ain't good for me.
One thing you gotta do that's
stick it to the man! Stick it to the man!
Stick it to the man! Stick to...
Now!
Cool...
I don't suppose your planet's
invented pain killers?
Good work, RØver!
Guys, this is so Luke Skywalker!
By the way,
...you're not brother and sister, right?
How much time is left?
- Just enough.
Rover here will take us
right to my ship.
That's a funny place for his antenna!
Captain, I want the whole base
on red alert.
Yes, sir!
General, you must save its brain.
I'm more concerned with
saving our world.
Move it out! Move it out!
That professor's a genius!
I feel... positively effervescent.
In fine fettle.
What a salubrious experience!
Well said. Cheers.
My ship.
Hey, way to go, kid.
Step away from the flying saucer!
And put your hands in the air!
There was never a chance
for you to getaway.
You'd destroy the whole base...
...just to get me?
That is sick!
Actually, it's kind of flattering.
Sick?
Sick, young lady, is helping the
enemy of your world!
Sick is befriending a creature
that's so completely...
...different!
Sick is...
Well look, it's right in front of you.
I'm sorry, Professor.
It's too dangerous to let
the alien live another minute.
Wait, wait, wait! Stop!
General...
I know what you're afraid of.
And... it's not Chuck.
It's not monsters or...
or aliens.
It's the unknown.
I've spent my whole life
running from it.
And...
I think maybe you’ve too.
But I'm telling you...
...the unknown isn't something
to be afraid of.
It can be your best friend.
And just when you think that it means
the end of everything you know...
It's really just the beginning.
Base destruct...
...2 minutes.
What... What are you looking at?
Run!
Take that!
Everyone on board!
Let's go!
Attention all personnel.
Evacuate Base immediately.
What are you doing?
- I can't leave him here!
- Why not?
- Because he's got the right stuff!
Base destruct,
60 seconds.
There's no time for auto-pilot!
What's the matter now?
I'm gonna have to pilot this bucket.
Base destruct in 15 seconds.
She is so heavy!
Ten...
nine...
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One!
You guys should check this out.
Hey, what do you think?
- It's such a big universe.
I'm definitely coming back here!
Am I a zombie now?
This guy reads too many comic books.
Hey, Neera.
Now that this is all over...
- Would you wanna...
- Yes!
But you didn't hear what I...
Gross!
Strap in, everyone.
Because I'm taking you home.
Hey, it's Lem!
Hi.
The monster!
Hey, it's all right, Chief.
He's with me.
Soldiers, attention!
There is among us... an astronaut.
Captain...
Thanks for coming back for me.
A pleasure, General.
Maybe next time you have guests,
you'll throw a better party.
Kid, how'd you like to be president...
...of the local
"Chuck Baker party maker" fan club?
Be a good bØy.
And don't forget to drink your oil.
Rover.
You coming?
Or you wanna stay here?
Rover!
My little big boy.
Lem...
You saved my life.
And you saved mine, too.
That was a, uh, man hug just there.
It's very big on my planet.
Hey, take care of this guy, okay?
You're a great planet
and your '50s are fine.
But give me a call
when you get to the '60s.
Because that's gonna be fun!
Subtitle by silentFØX