Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Ron is down.
He needs a medical evac.
Where is it? Is it there?
- Oh, the drive is gone.
- Are you sure?
It's gone.
Give me a minute.
They must have it.
Get off to them.
- I'm stabilizing Ronson.
- We don't have the time.
- I have to stop the bleeding.
- Leave him!
Have you got him?
He is in the black Audi.
- What about Ronson.
- He's been hit.
I'm sending an emergency
evacuation squad.
They'll be too bloody late.
Have they seen us?
Medical Evac for Ronson,
five minutes away.
It's alright?
You'll wait using it.
I wasn't using that one either.
Keep your head down!
Just get clear!
Tanner, which way?
Keep going.
I can direct you from here.
We both know what's at stake here.
We can't afford to lose that list.
Yes, ma'am.
Where are they now?
They're on the top roof
of the Grand Bazaar.
Take the left, there's a bridge.
You can cut him off.
- What happened?
- They're on the train, ma' am.
What do you mean on the train?
I mean they're on the top
of the train.
Well, get off to them, for God's sake.
He's going out of range.
We've lost tracking.
We are blind here.
- What's going on?
- I'm still with them.
Skip to satellite TV.
What was that?
VW Beetles, I think.
He's un-coupling the cars.
- 007, are you alright?
- Just changing carriages.
What's going on? Report!
It's rather hard to explain, ma'am.
007 is the follow-up.
This side there isn't much more road.
I don't think I can go any further.
I may have a shot.
It's not clean.
Repeat. I did not have a clean shot.
There's a tunnel ahead.
I'm gonna lose them.
- Can you get into a better position?
- Negative. There's no time.
Take the shot.
I said, "Take the shot!"
I can't. I may get Bond.
Take the bloody shot.
Agent down.
It's like being summoned
into the headmaster study.
It's the new chairman.
Just standard procedure.
Bloody waste of my time,
that's what I'd call it.
I'm sorry to have deal with such...
a delicate subject
at our first encounter...
but...
I have to be frank with you.
And it would be a good idea.
The Prime Minister is concerned.
You can tell him my operatives
are pursuing every avenue.
Have you considered
pulling out the agents?
I've considered every option.
Forgive me,
but that sounds like an evasion.
Forgive me, but why am I here?
Three months ago
you lost the computer drive
containing the identity
of almost every NATO agent
embedded in terrorist organizations
across the globe.
A list which,
in the eyes of our allies,
never existed.
So, if you'll forgive me,
I think you know why we're here.
We are to call this civilian oversight?
No, what we are to call this is...
a retirement planning.
Your country has
the highest respect for you
and your many years of service.
When your current posting
is completed,
you'll be awarded to JCMG
with full honors.
Congratulations.
You are firing me?
No, ma'am, I'm here to oversee
the transition period...
leading to your voluntary retirement
in two months' time.
Your successor has yet to be appointed,
so we'll be asking you...
I'm not an idiot, Mallory.
I know I can't do this job forever.
But I'll be damned if I'm going
to leave the department
in worst shape than I found it.
M... you've had a great run.
- You should leave with dignity.
- Go to hell with dignity.
I'll leave when the job's done.
Yes?
Now?
Main alert from Q Robson,
He's trying to decrypt
the stolen hard drive.
We are tracing the encryption signal.
Localizing now.
It's sent from here in the UK.
London.
Get us back to base
as soon as possible.
- It's coming from MI6.
- What?
The data back,
it is linking to our network.
This is behind our firewall.
- We should shut down.
- No, track it.
We have to know
where it's coming from.
Strip the header and trace the source.
How the hell did it get
into our system?
Getting trace right now.
- It is addressed to your computer, ma'am.
- Shut it down.
What is this?
For God's sake!
Just get out of the way.
- Don't you recognize the car?
- Madam...
I will find who ever did this.
Where the hell have you been?
Enjoying death.
007, reporting for duty.
Why didn't you call?
Didn't you get the postcard?
You should try it sometimes.
Get away from it all,
it really lends perspective.
Run out of drink.
Were you awarded?
What was you said?
Take the bloody shot.
I made a judgment call.
You should have trusted me
to finish the job.
It was the possibility
of losing you...
or the certainty of losing
all those other agents.
I made the only decision I could
and you know it.
I think you've lost your nerve.
What do you expect,
a bloody apology?
You know the rules of the game.
You've been playing it long enough.
- We both have.
- Maybe too long.
Speak for yourself.
Ronson didn't make it, did he?
No.
So, this is it.
We are both played out.
Well, if you believed that,
why did you come back?
Good question.
Because we are under attack.
And you know we need you.
Well, I'm here.
You'll have to be debriefed
and declared fit for active service.
You can only return to duty
when you've passed the tests.
So take them seriously.
The shower might be in order.
I'm going home and change.
Oh, we sold your flat.
Put your things in storage.
Standard procedure...
on the death of an unmarried
employee with no next of kin.
You should have called.
I'll find a hotel.
Well, you're bloody not sleeping here.
The assailant hacked into the
environmental control system
locked out the safety protocols
and turned on the gas.
All of which should have been impossible.
On top of that they have hacked
into her files.
They knew her appointments.
They knew she'd be out
of the building.
They weren't targeting her.
They wanted us to see it.
- Where are we, Tanner?
- New digs.
The old building was declared
strategically vulnerable.
That's putting it marvelly.
He was able to breach the most secure
computer system in Britain.
So we are on war footing now.
This is part of Churchill's bunker.
They are still discovering tunnels
dating back of the 18th century.
Quite fascinating,
if it wasn't for the rats.
- When do I see M?
- Tomorrow you'll see M...
and Mallory too if you're lucky.
Who is Mallory?
He's the chairman of Intelligence
and Security Committee.
A charming man. I think you and him
are really going to hit it off.
Welcome to the new MI6.
We've have attempted to trace
the computer message, but...
it was sent by an asymmetrical
security algorithm...
which bounces the signal
all over the globe
through thousands
of different servers.
And now that they've accessed
M's code,
it's only a matter of time
before they are able to decrypt the list.
Q branch has been analyzing pictures,
but so far nothing.
General feeling it's probably
someone from her past.
Perhaps when she was running
things in Hong Kong.
- He's no idea what it all means.
- And you believe that?
The truth is we don't have
a clue who took the list...
or what they plan to do with it.
We can always do this later.
You know what? Let's.
I'd like to start with some
simple word associations.
Just tell me the first word
that pops into your head.
For example I might say "day",
and you might say...
Wasted.
All right.
Gun.
Shot.
- Agent.
- Provocateur.
- Woman.
- Provocatrix.
- Heart.
- Target.
- Bird.
- Sky.
- M.
- Bitch.
- Sunlight.
- Swim.
- Moonlight.
- Dance.
- Murder.
- Employment.
- Country.
- England.
Skyfall.
Done.
This is going well.
Get these analyzed.
For her eyes only.
She's ready for you.
I'm sorry. Have we met before?
I am the one who should say "sorry".
It was only four ribs.
That's nonetheless vital organs.
Nothing major.
No enough excitement in Istanbul?
I've been reassigned.
Temporary suspension
from field work.
- Really?
- Something to do with killing 007.
- Well, you gave your best shot.
- It was hardly my best shot.
I'm sure I can survive your best.
Perhaps you'll get the chance.
Would you do me a favor, will you?
If they'll do let you back out there,
warn me first.
I'm assisting Gareth Mallory
in the transition...
and then I'll be back in the field.
- That's what you want?
- Yes, of course.
- It's not for everyone.
- Ah, 007...
This way.
In your defense...
a moving target
is much harder to hit.
Then you better keep moving.
The whole office goes up in smoke
and that bloody thing survives.
Your interior decorating tips
have always been appreciated, 007.
007, Gareth Mallory.
I hope I haven't miss anything
the P.M.does place a lot in the crisis.
- Bond.
- Mallory.
I have just been reviewing
Bond's tests.
Seemed you passed. By the skin
of your teeth.
You're back on active service.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- I'll be outside.
- I only have one question.
Why not stay dead?
You have the perfect way out.
Go and live quietly somewhere.
Not many field agents
get to leave this cleanly.
Do you get out in the field much?
You don't need to be an operative
to see the obvious.
It's a young men's game.
Look, you've been
seriously injured.
There's no shame in saying
you have lost a step.
The only shame it'd be not admitting
until it's too late.
Hire me or fire me.
It's entirely up to you.
If he says he is ready,
he is ready.
Perhaps you can't see at all.
Maybe you will.
What exactly are you implying?
You are sentimental about it.
As long as I am at the head
of this department,
I'll choose my own operatives.
Fair enough.
Good luck, 007.
Don't cock it up.
We've analyzed
the scharpnel fragments.
You're lucky it wasn't a direct hit.
It would have cut you in half.
It's a depleted uranium shell.
Military grade.
Hard to get,
extremely expensive
and only used by a select few.
Recognize anyone?
Him.
Okay, the name is Patrice.
He's a ghost.
An unknown resident
or country of origin.
How do we find him?
Well, luckily we stil have one or two
friends left in the CIA.
They're after him for the Yemeni
ambassador's murder.
And they're getting close.
Intel is he's gonna be in Shanghai
in two days time. Probably a new job.
You have to go there
and wait further instructions.
If he turns up, it's yours.
Find out who he worked for
and who has the list.
- Then, terminate him for Ronson.
- With pleasure.
Is there anything else
you want to tell me?
No.
Report to the new Quarter Master
for your documentation.
He hasn't set up shop yet, but
Tanner will put you two together.
Good luck.
Thank you.
007...
You are ready for this?
Yes, ma'am.
I didn't know Bond passed the tests.
He didn't.
Always makes me feel
a little melancholy.
A grand whole warship been hit
ominously all the way to scrap.
Inevitability of time, don't you think?
What do you see?
A bloody big ship.
Excuse me.
007...
I'm your new Quarter Master.
You must be joking.
Why, because I'm not wearing
a lab coat?
Because you still have spots.
My complexion is hardly relevant.
And your confidence is.
Age is no guarantee of efficiency.
And youth
is no guarantee of innovation.
I can do more damage
on my laptop
sitting in my pyjamas before
my first cup of Old Grey
than you could do yourself
a year in the field.
So why do you need me?
Every now and then
a trigger has to be pulled.
Or not pulled.
It is hard to know which
in your pyjamas.
Q...
007.
Ticket to Shanghai.
- Documentation and passport.
- Thank you.
And this.
Walter PPK, 9 mm short.
There's a micro dermal sensor
in the grip...
encoded to your palm print,
so only you can fire it.
That's a random killing machine
more than a personal statement.
And this?
Standard radio transmitter.
Activated to broadcast
your location.
Distress it.
And that's it.
A gun... and a radio.
Not exactly Christmas, isn't it?
Were you expecting an exploding pen?
We don't really go in
for that anymore.
Good luck out there on the field.
And please,
return the equipment in one piece.
Brave new world.
Who's got the list?
Help me!
Who are you working for?
He has posted the first five names.
Their cover is blown.
They're in danger. Get them out now.
Room service.
I didn't order anything.
Not even you.
I have got some new information.
Are not you a little too qualified
to be delivering messages?
It's all part of the learning curve.
And Q is afraid of flying.
So, whoever stole the list
has already decrypted it.
They posted the first five names
on the web.
- It was only a matter of time.
- That should be the start.
They're posting five more next week
and the week after.
It's some kind of sadistic game.
Cut through razor.
How very traditional.
All I like is to do something the
old-fashioned way.
Sometimes the old ways
are the best.
Are you putting your knife
in my hands again?
They've already briefed me
on the list...
raising the tantalizing question
of what you are really doing here.
The official directive was to help...
in anyway I can.
Like spying for Mallory.
You know, Mallory is not as bad
as you think.
He is a bureaucrat.
You should do your homework.
Gareth Mallory
was lieutenant colonel...
lieutenant colonel in Northern
Ireland Hereford regiment.
He spent three months
at the hands of the IRA.
So there's more to him
that meets the eye.
We'll see.
Keep still.
This is the tricky part.
That's better.
- You know the part now.
- Mmh, mmh.
And what part is that?
Old dog...
new tricks.
Good evening.
Don't you touch your ear.
There are three exits.
And lots of blind spots.
I've got them covered.
You look beautiful in that dress.
It's amazing what one could do
with an extra pair of hands.
You're telling me.
You gamble?
Don't you like a little flat
now and then?
He doesn't like to take chances.
Good evening, sir.
How may I help you?
I'd like to cash these, please.
One moment, sir.
Good fortune tonight, sir.
Let's hope so.
With compliments of the house.
Thank you.
Now you can afford to buy me a drink?
Maybe I could even stretch it to two.
I guess I've got 4 million euros
in here.
Not bad.
- I like this game.
- Why don't we play another?
I don't gamble.
I'm not very lucky.
With lucky old friend in Shanghai.
I've been waiting to see
who will redeem for chips.
You made such a bold entrance
into our little drama.
Do I have a complicated plot?
Who doesn't appreciate
the occasional twists?
- Mr...
- Bond. James Bond.
Severine, so Mr. Bond...
shall we discuss your next
performance over that drink?
Not bad.
Will your friends be joining us?
That I'm afraid... is inevitable.
- She's pretty.
- No, no.
Do you like that ass, don't you think?
I'll keep you posted.
Perfect.
Would you mind if I ask you
a business question?
Depends on the question.
It has to do with... death.
A subject in which you're well versed.
How would you know that?
Only a certain kind of woman
wears a backless dress
with a Beretta .70
strapped to her thigh.
One could never be too careful when...
a handsome man in tuxedo
carries...
I'm correct in assuming
you killed Patrice?
Yes.
Might I ask why?
I want to meet your employer.
Be careful what you wish for.
You are scared.
Thank you for the drink...
Mr. Bond.
You put on a good show.
But ever since we sat down here
you haven't stop looking
at your bodyguards.
Three of them is a bit excessive.
They're controlling you.
They're not protecting you.
Tattoo on your wrist...
is Macao's sex trade.
You belong to one of the Houses.
At 12?
13?
I guess you're imaging a way out.
Perhaps you thought you were in love.
But that was a long time ago.
You know nothing about it.
I know when a woman is afraid
and pretending not to be.
How much do you know
about fear?
All there is.
Not like this.
And... not like him.
I can help you.
- I don't think so.
- Let me try.
How?
Bring me to him.
- Can you kill him?
- Yes.
- Will you?
- Someone usually dies.
Perhaps you can.
When I leave,
they're going to kill you.
If you survive, I'm on the Kimera.
North Harbour...
berth 7.
We cast off in an hour.
Very nice to have met you,
Mr. Bond.
Good luck.
Good luck with that.
Thank you.
Put it all on red.
That's the circle of life.
Yes?
It's time to cast off.
Right.
I like you better without
your Beretta.
I feel naked without it.
"Good evening."
"The controversy surrounding
the Ministry of Defence..."
"has escalated today"
"as images of the Hussein
assassination continue to circulate."
"We should warn you, some viewers
might find these images disturbing."
"Captain Hussein, an MI6 operative
embedded in the Middle East"
"was one of the five agents exposed
in what is now been considered"
"the greatest internal security breach
in modern British history."
"The Prime Minister continues
to express public support for MI6"
"while the opposition has taken
the position..."
has taken the position where a bunch
of antiquate bloody idiots
are fighting a war we don't understand
and can't possibly win.
Look, three of my agents
are dead already.
Don't you embroil me in politics now.
The Prime Minister has ordered
an enquiry.
You'll have to appear.
Standing in the stocks of mid day?
Who is antiquated now?
For Christ sake, listen to yourself.
We are a democracy...
and are accountable to the people
who are trying to defend.
We can't keep working
in the shadows.
There are no more shadows.
You don't get this, do you?
Whoever is behind this,
whoever is doing this, he knows us.
He is one of us.
He comes from the same place as Bond.
The place you say doesn't exist.
The shadows.
They abandoned it almost overnight.
He made them think there was a leak
at the chemical plant.
It is amazing the panic you can
cause with a single computer.
He wanted the island.
So he took it.
Does he always get what he wants?
More than you know.
I'm sorry.
Hello, James. Welcome.
Do you like the island?
My grandmother had an island.
Nothing to boast off.
You could walk along
within an hour.
But still it was,
it was a paradise for us.
One summer, we went for a visit...
and discovered the place
had been infested with rats.
They'd come on a fishing boat
and gorged themselves on coconut.
So, how do you get rid of the rats
off an island?
My grandmother showed me.
We buried an whole drum
and changed the lead.
Then we wired the coconut
to the lead as bait...
and the rats would come
for the coconut, and...
They would fall into the drum.
And after a month
you've trapped all the rats.
But what did you do then?
Throw the drum into the ocean?
Burn it? No...
You just leave it...
and they begin to get hungry.
And one by one...
they start eating each other...
until there are only two left,
the two survivors.
And then what, do you kill them?
No.
You take them
and releasing them into the trees.
And now they don't eat
coconut anymore.
Now they only eat rat.
You have changed their nature.
The two survivors.
This is what you made us.
I made my own choices.
You think you did.
That's their genius.
Station H.
Am I right, Hong Kong?
'86 to '97.
Back then, I was her favorite.
And you're not nearly the agent
I was.
I can tell you that.
Just look at you.
Barely held together by your pills...
- and your drink.
- Don't forget my pathetic love of country.
You're still clinging to your faith
in that old woman...
- ...when all she does is lie to you.
- She never lied lied to me.
- No?
- No.
- What do you score your marksmanship evaluation?
- 70.
40.
- Did she tell you the psychologist
cleared you for duty?
- Yes.
No. No.
Medical evaluation, fail.
Physical evaluation, fail.
Psychological evaluation, alcohol
and substance addiction indicated.
Pathological rejection
of authority
based on unresolved
childhood trauma.
Subject is not approved
for field duty
and immediate suspension
from service advised.
What is this, if not betrayal?
She send you off to me,
knowing that you're not ready
knowing you will likely die.
Mommy was very bad.
See what she's done to you?
Well, she never tied me
to a chair.
Her loss.
Are you sure this is about her?
It's about her...
and you and me.
You see, we are last two rats.
We can either eat each other.
Or eat everyone else.
How you're trying to remember
your training now?
What's the regulation to cover this?
Well, first time for everything.
What makes you think
this is my first time?
Oh, Mr. Bond...
All the physical stuff's so dull.
So dull.
Chasing spies.
So old-fashioned.
Your knees must be killing you.
England...
the Empire, MI6.
You're living in the ruins as well.
You just don't know it yet.
At least here there are no
old ladies giving orders...
and no little...
gadgets from those fools
in Q print.
If you'd want it,
you could pick
your own secret missions
as I do.
Name it.
You destabilize a multinational
by manipulating stocks. Easy.
Interrupt transmission
from a spy satellite over Kabul.
Done.
Rig an election in Uganda.
All to the highest bidder.
Or a gas explosion in London.
Guess the point, anglic.
Well, everyone needs a hobby.
So what's yours?
Resurrection.
Let me show you something.
Tells a story, doesn't it?
They left the island so quickly
that couldn't decide what to take
what to leave, what was important.
And this every day reminds me
to focus on the essentials.
There is nothing...
nothing superfluous in my life.
When a thing is redundant,
it is... eliminated.
Fifty-year-old McCullan.
A particular favorite of yours,
I understand?
So... what's the toast?
To the women we love?
Darling...
Darling, your love is out here.
No, no, no, no...
Stand up straight, keep still
and whatever you do,
don't lose your head.
Don't lose your head.
Time to redeem your
marksmanship shoot scores.
Let's see.
You can be the first...
to knock the glass from her head.
And just to be sporting,
I'll let you go first.
Let's see who it's up on top.
Oh, I can't believe it.
Can't believe it.
Did you really die that day?
Is there any,
any of the old 007 left?
My turn.
I win. What do you say to that?
A waste of good scotch.
What are you going to do now?
Take me back to her?
All on your own?
Who says I'm on my own?
Alright, time to say hello.
You are smaller than I remembered.
Whereas I barely remember you at all.
Strange, for me it feels just...
like yesterday.
- Are you surprised?
- Not particularly.
But then you've always were
a slippery one.
Maybe that's why
you liked me so much.
- You flatter yourself.
- No remorse.
Just as I can imagine it.
Regret is unprofessional.
"Regret is unprofessional"...
They kept for five months
in a room with no air.
They tortured me.
And I regretted your secrets.
I regretted you.
But they made me suffer...
and suffer...
until I realized...
it was you... who betrayed me.
You betrayed me.
So I had only one thing left.
My cyanide capsule
in my back lift molar.
You remember, right?
So I broke the tooth...
and bit into the capsule.
It burned all my insides...
but I didn't die.
Life climbed to me like a disease.
And then...
I understood...
why I had survived.
I needed to look in your eyes
one last time.
Well, I hope it was worth it.
Mr. Silva...
you are going to be transferred
to Belmarsh Prison...
where you will be remanded
in custody...
until the Crown prosecution service
deem you fit to stand trial...
Say my name. Say it.
My real name.
I know you remember it.
Your name is on the memorial wall
of the very building you attacked.
I will have it struck off.
Soon, your past will be
as nonexistent as your future.
I'll never see you again.
Do you know what it does to you?
Hydrogen cyanide?
Look at what you do,
Mother...
Let me know what you recover
from his computers.
Has he transmitted the list?
If such, to who?
- I want this resolved.
- Yes, ma' am.
His name is Tiago Rodriguez.
He was a brilliant agent.
But he started operating beyond
his brief, hacking the Chinese.
The hand over was coming up
and they were haunting him, so...
I gave him up.
I got six agents in return...
and a peaceful transition.
We should go, ma' am.
Board Enquiry begins in thirty minutes.
I want to know
what's on that computer.
Now, looking at Silva's computer
it seems to me he's done a number
of slightly unusual things.
It's established
fail safe protocols...
to wipe the memory if there's
any attempt to access certain files.
Only about six people in the world
can program safe guides like that.
Of course there are.
Can you get past them?
I invented them.
Right then.
Let's see what you got for us...
Mr. Silva.
We're in.
Sir...
what you'd make of this?
This is Omega site.
That's the encrypted level it has.
Looks like obfuscated code
to conceal its true purpose.
Security through obscurity.
Ladies and gentlemen,
if I might have order.
I'd like to begin proceedings.
We are gathered today
to address some important issues
concerning the future
of our national security.
Going somewhere?
So you believe your stewardship of MI6
during the recent crisis
has been up to scratch?
Well, I believe we've have
apprehended the responsible party
undertaking the necessary steps
to ensure that the sensitive
information is contained.
Such a job well done.
I'm not saying
all gone perfectly, but...
You forgive me for not putting up
the bunting.
I find rather difficult to overlook
the monumental security breaches
and dead operatives which you were
singled handedly responsible.
He's using a polymorphic engine
to mutate the code.
Whenever I try to gain an access,
it changes.
It's like solving the Rubik's cube
that's fighting back.
Stop.
Go in now.
Grandsborough.
Grandsborough Road,
it's an old...
tube station on the metropolitan line.
Been closed for years.
Use that as a key.
Now, look at it. It's a map.
It's London.
Subterranean London.
What's going on?
Why the doors open?
Can someone tell me how to hell
he got into our system?
Oh, shit.
Shit, shit, shit.
He hacked this.
Oh, no.
Q...
He is gone.
I'm on the stairwell of the low isolation.
Are you with me, Q?
I can hear you.
I'm looking for you.
I've got you.
Tracking your location.
Just keep moving forward.
Enter the next service door
on your right.
If you're through that door,
you should be in the tube.
I'm in the tube.
Bond, this isn't an escape.
This was years in the planning.
He wanted us to capture him,
he wanted us to access his computers.
It was all planned.
Roving up HQ,
only emergency protocols...
now we have retrieved down here.
I got all that.
What it's got planned next
it worries me.
Going through that post, it should be
a service door on your left.
Got it.
It won't open.
Of course it will.
Put your back into it.
Why don't you come down here
and put your back into it?
No, it's stuck.
Not good.
There's a train coming.
I'm through.
I told you.
We've alerted security.
The police are on the way.
Where are you now?
Trampled in the tube station.
Together with half of London.
Oh, I see you.
I know where I am, Q.
Where is he?
Give us a second. I'm looking for it.
There's still many people.
I can't see him.
Welcome to rush hour on the tube.
Something we do not know much about.
The train's leaving.
Do I get on the train?
Don't get on the train unless he's
on it. Wait a minute.
Do I get on the train?
- Bond...
- What?
Get on the train.
He's keen to get home.
Open the door, please.
Open the door.
I'm from Safety. Carry on.
- Where are you?
- Take a wild guess, Q.
He's in disguise, now.
Disguised as a policeman.
Of course he is.
Where is he going?
He's going for M.
Tell Tanner. Get her out of there.
You overlooked or chosen to ignore
hard evidence
and consistently, almost obstinately...
Silva has escaped.
Bond is in pursuit.
We need to get you to a security
station immediately, ma'am.
I doubt I can now show my back.
Are we straining your attention?
No. Please, Minister. Proceed.
Excuse me.
It's as if you insist on pretending
we are still living in the golden age
of espionage
when human intelligence
was the only resource available.
I find this rather old-fashioned belief
demonstrates a reckless disregard...
Excuse me, Minister.
I don't mean to interrupt.
But, just for the sake of variety
might we actually hear
from the witness?
Of course.
Thank you.
I won't miss next time, Mr. Silva.
Not bad.
Not bad, James,
for a physical wreck.
Oh, thank you.
You got me.
Now, here's your prize.
The latest thing
from my local toy store.
It is called "radio".
I do hope that wasn't for me.
No.
But that is.
Chairman, Ministers...
today I repeatedly heard how
irrelevant my department
has become.
Why you need agents
for 00 section...
isn't it all rather quaint.
Well, I suppose I see a different
world than you do.
And the truth is that
what I see frightens me.
I'm frightened because our enemies
are not longer known to us.
They do not exist on the map.
They're no nations.
They are individuals.
But look around you,
who do you fear?
When you see a face, a uniform? No.
Our world is not
more transparent now.
It's more opaque.
It's in the shadows.
That's where we must do back.
So, before you declare
this irrelevant, ask yourselves.
How safe do you feel?
Just one more thing to say.
My late husband was
a great lover of poetry.
And...
I suppose some fit some kin
despite my best intentions.
And here today, I remember this.
I think... from Tennyson.
"We are not now that strength"
"which in old day moved
Earth and Heaven."
"That which we are, we are."
"One equal temper of heroic hearts."
"Made weak by time and fate."
"But strong in will..."
"to strive, to seek, to find"
"and not to yield."
Move.
Move. Move.
007, what the hell are we doing?
You're kidnapping me.
That will be one way of looking at it.
Too many people are dying
because of me.
If he wants you,
he's gonna have to come and get you.
We've been one step behind Silva
from the start.
It's time to get out in front
and change the game.
And I'm to be the bait?
All right.
Just us. No one else.
Q, I need help.
I'm tracking the car.
Where are you going?
I got M.
We're about to disappear.
What?
I need you to lay
a trail of breadcrumbs
impossible to follow
for anyone except Silva.
Think you can do it?
I'm guessing
this isn't strictly official.
Not even remotely.
So much for my promising career
in espionage.
Well, I'm not hiding in there,
if that was your brilliant plan.
We're changing vehicles.
The trouble with company cars
is that they have trackers.
And I suppose
that's completely inconspicuous.
Get in.
It's not getting comfortable, is it?
Are you going to complain
the whole way?
Oh, go on and eject me.
See if I care.
Where are we going?
Back in time.
Somewhere we'll have the advantage.
Really not easy.
With the breadcrumbs too small
and we might miss it.
Too big and Silva will smell the rat.
That's why you think even Silva
will be able to spot that?
He's the only one who could.
Sir...
What are you doing?
We just... monitoring...
creating a false tracking
signal for Silva to follow.
Well, sir...
Excellent thinking. Get him isolated.
Send him on the A9.
It's the direct route.
You can monitor his progress
more accurately.
You can you confirm it
with the traffic cameras.
But... what if the P.M. finds out?
Then, we're all buggered.
Carry on.
This is where you grew up.
Mmhh...
How old were you when they died?
You know the answer to that.
You know the whole story.
Orphans always make
the best recruits.
Storm's coming.
Christ...
No wonder you never came back.
James...
James Bond.
Good God.
You're still alive.
Nice to see you, too.
M... this is Kincade.
Kincade is keeping here
since I was a boy.
- Please to meet you, Emma.
- Mr. Kincade.
You are a tad late. They sold the place
when they thought you were dead.
Seems they were wrong.
What are you doing here?
Some men are coming to kill us.
I'm gonna kill him first.
Then we'd better get ready.
Do we still have a gun room?
They sold a lot to a collector
from Idaho or some such place.
They were shipped up weeks ago.
There's just your father's
old hunting rifle.
We couldn't let that go.
And this is what we've got.
There might be a couple of sticks
of dynamite from the quarry.
But, if all else fails, sometimes...
the old ways are the best.
So, who we are supposed
to be fighting?
No "we", Kincade.
This is not your fight.
Try to stop me,
you jumped-up little shit.
Now, remember what I taught to you.
Don't let it pull to the left.
I'll do my best.
What did you say you did
for the living?
Emma...
I brought you some things.
The nights get cold here.
Thank you, Mr. Kincade.
It's a beautiful old house.
She is.
And like all great ladies...
she still has her secret ways.
Let me show you this.
A priest hole.
Yes, from Reformation times.
The tunnel leads under the moor.
If you get in danger,
this is the place to come.
The night I told him
his parents have died...
he hid in here for two days.
But he did come out
he was no boy anymore.
Ehm, we must get on.
I fucked this up, didn't I?
No.
You did your job.
I read your obituary of me.
- And?
- Appalling.
Yes, I knew you'd hated it.
It could be an example
of the British fortitude.
That was all right.
Are you ready?
I was ready before
you're were born, son.
Welcome to Scotland.
Did he drop something?
Are you hurt?
Only in my pride.
I never was a good shot.
He's not here...
and he's not here.
Always good to make an entrance.
Each of you, go to the kitchen.
Now!
Go behind the yard.
Go to the chapel. Use the tunnel.
Everyone listen to me.
Don't you dare touch M.
She's mine.
Can't you just come out and say hello?
Come on. This way.
I always hated this place.
Are you getting warm?
Just make sure Bond is dead.
Now it's me and her.
You see what comes of all
this running around, Mr. Bond?
All this jumping and fighting.
It's exhausting.
Relax.
You need to relax.
Well, Mother's calling.
I'll give her a goodbye kiss for you.
Of course.
It had to be here.
It had to be this way.
Thank you.
- I can't find it, though.
- Don't.
Please.
Don't.
You're hurt. You're hurt.
What have they done to you?
Free both of us.
With the same bullet.
Do it.
Do it!
Only you can do it.
Last rat standing.
007.
What took you so long?
I got into this deep water.
I suppose it's...
too late to make a run for it.
Well, I'm game if you are.
I did get one thing right.
Wow. I didn't even know
you could come up here.
I hate to waste a view.
I can see why.
I thought you were going back out
on active service.
I declined.
You said it yourself.
Field work is not for everyone.
If it helps, I feel a lot safer.
Her will was read today.
She left you this.
Maybe it's her way to tell you
to take a desk job.
Just the opposite.
Thank you.
You know, we've never formally
been introduced.
Oh, my name is Eve.
Eve Moneypenny.
I look forward to our time
together, Miss Moneypenny.
Me too.
I'm sure we will have
one or two close shaves.
Good morning, 007.
- Good morning, Tanner.
- He'll see you now.
How's the arm, sir?
It's fine.
It'll get better.
All pretty shocking for someone...
unused to field work.
So, 007...
lots to be done.
Are you ready to get back to work?
With pleasure, M.
With pleasure.