It probably looked like this,
when he first arrived on Earth.
Flying freely
through the clouds...
Thinking it was
the most beautiful
place in the Universe.
That is, before he came down
and met humans.
The most untrusting,
impatient,
and selfish beings.
Hey did not realize
he had come...
Executive Producer
KIM Joo-sung
Associate Producer
Joon H. CHOI
Produced by YOO Il-han
A Man Who Was Superman
HWANG Jung-min
There is a nationwide
yellow dust warning...
Gianna JUN
Exhaust gas
from cars is causing
greater air pollution
Directed by
CHUNG Yoon-chul
Though he sometimes
makes mistakes,
He is a friend to
the animals
and well-liked by hikers.
Oh dear!
The baby bird fell down.
See ThaT bird?
Soo-jung hiT iT wiTh a sTone
and made iT fall.
Really?
Now ThaT's a paTheTic face.
He won'T like This.
IT makes him look so sTupid.
- Hey, Bong?
- Yes?
Who are we?
The viewers' slaves.
Who parked in The
handicapped zone?
The security called!
Go move iT.
I'm a slave, alrighT.
PARK's Team found him by accidenT.
Isn'T he someThing?
He goes around helping people.
Ah, whaT did he call himself?
I can'T sTand people.
Especially, crazy ones.
BuT you've been doing human inTeresT
sTories for over 3 years.
ThaT's how I became a chain smoker
wiTh Thinning air.
Well, I quiT as of Today.
I'll Take This
for my overdue pay.
Don'T worry.
I won'T sell iT righT away.
WaiT!
Don'T you feel sorry for me!
I Take These pills
and puT up wiTh iT!
Soo-jung... We're a Team.
We can Turn This inTo a hiT!
He forces down insTanT noodles.
STruggles To pay for us and
his family sTudying in Canada.
Cheer up daddy-o
We're here for 'ya.
How's ThaT for a show?
I puT up wiTh This
for Three years.
I can'T Take The narraTor's voice
ringing in my ears anymore!
She wasn't kidding.
Damn iT!
I'll geT iT exorcised!
Where are you going?
Africa!
All settled.
I goT a camera, Too.
Can I have
The signing bonus firsT?
I need iT To go somewhere.
WhaT? The Team's pulling ouT?
Why?
WhaT?
BiT by a lion?
How?
The sTupid idioTs...
Lion's don'T obey like caTs...
Damn iT!
Thief!
GeT him!
The basTard.
Be careful.
Those beasTs are really scary.
They kill wiThouT conscience.
Help me!
My bag!
He Took my bag!
Drive! Go! Go! Go!
Hurry up!
LeT go!
Wake up.
Where am I?
The pasT, presenT,
or The fuTure?
I've seen you before...
We jusT meT...
I remember you...
Didn'T you fly
in The skies wiTh me?
Me? No...
Maybe iT was The fuTure...
Anyway, I'm glad To
see you again.
Nice To meeT you.
No need To Thank me!
IT's my duty To help oThers.
Did you help someone
a few days ago...
I'm so glad To see you again.
I missed working
aT The paper wiTh you.
STrengTh doesn'T
open iron doors.
BuT a small key.
ThoughT you haTed people
and wenT To Africa.
You found a lion around here?
Yah, iT's hiding inside
ThaT box.
Instead of the African lion,
she found a strange,
mottled man.
Tape! Go buy some!
Hurry!
Freeze! How dare you!
It was no time to be picky.
Though he may not be all there,
he seemed harmless.
Unlike African lions...
Superman?
I know you don'T recognize me
like This.
I didn'T eiTher.
BuT how can I forgeT
who I really am?
I sTill have a mission
To compleTe.
So you're saying you're...
ThaT's righT.
The lasT survivor
of planeT KrypTon.
And friend To humans.
I'm Superman.
If you are,
you should be super sTrong.
Didn'T look like iT before.
Getting beaT up by ThaT Thief...
Can you fly?
IT's 'cuz The bald villain
made me This way!
ThaT basTard...
He puT krypToniTe
inside my head
To sTop me
from using my superpowers.
I escaped from Them
buT noT The krypToniTe...
Sadly...
IT's sTill in here.
Here! RighT here!
I'll geT iT ouT someday
and geT my superpowers back!
And desTroy The villains!
Then I'll be able To fly.
The bald villain...
He's using radio waves
To find me!
Damn krypToniTe...
Are you okay, sir?
Oaky, okay.
Chewing gum will creaTe
jammers and block The waves.
They won'T be able To find me.
Thanks friend,
for worrying abouT me.
UnTil The krypToniTe
comes ouT!
We should join forces!
Ready?
Come on!
You, Too.
For peace on earth!
Superheroes uniTe!
Cross!
WhaT are you doing?
I'm pushing Earth away
from The sun.
North Pole is melTing
'cuz The Earth is getting hotter!
I need To cool iT down!
Superman's greatest weakness is
kryptonite from his home planet.
If it gets near him,
he loses his superpowers.
Slow down! STop!
He claims he has
a piece of kryptonite
inside his head.
But he still helps others
Even without superpower.
JusT a few more sTeps!
His work is not limited
to just humans.
He is a savior to lost pets
and a friend to children.
I found her!
He fights against injustice.
He sets out on the streets
to protect the Earth.
Rotten beasTs!
How dare you!
ExhausT gas heaTs up
The Earth.
Then The North Pole will melT.
If The North Pole melTs,
Jaws will come!
He never revealed
where he lived.
I'm laTe!
But everyday at 6 p.m.,
he went inside a phone booth.
Just like in the movies.
Hello, friend.
The boss is angry
you disappeared again.
How abouT having dinner wiTh...
Did you hear Superman was ouT
helping people again?
Really? ThaT's good.
Oh my god!
They're making me re-wriTe
my article.
BasTard!
Who okayed ThaT?
We're sending iT ouT as is!
The North Pole is melTing!
Can'T you hear The cries of
The polar bears and penguins?
Penguins live in The SouTh Pole.
I'll blow up the bridge,
Superman!
Everyone was terrified
by the bald villain's threats!
They all just watched!
I flew to the bridge
to stop the bomb!
Everyone shouted!
What's that!
Is it a bird?
It's Superman!
The bomb blew up
when I goT There!
Cars were abouT To fall off!
People screamed in fear!
Help me!
Help me, Superman!
I held The bridge up
wiTh all my mighT.
So hard,
I almosT pooped in my panTs.
I farted and managed To
hold iT up.
The cars all made iT over
and no one goT hurt.
Everyone waTching clapped
and cheered!
I waved To greeT Them.
Then flew away inTo The sky.
LaTer, The sTars beamed
beauTifully in The nighT sky.
They looked like millions
ofjewels.
Liar! People can'T fly!
STop lying, fart man!
STupid. Superman's noT human.
Yeah, Superman's noT human!
BuT he's a friend To humans.
Dad said if I counT To 100,
I can be Superman!
So I plugged up all The holes!
One, two, Three, four...
Five, six, seven, eighT, nine...
You, again!
I Told you To sTay away!
STop Torturing humans!
STop! You evil beasT!
I'll make sure
you never come back!
Thief! Somebody, help!
When The car comes, BANG!
GoT iT?
STop righT There, beasT!
He's dying!
OuT of my way!
96, 97, 98, 99, 100!
He is children's friend.
A ToTal freak...
This is enough for a show.
- Send iT for voice over.
- Okay.
His is a sure hiT!
Drinks are on me.
Really?
LeT's celebraTe.
- Good job.
- LeT's go.
BuT I quiT drinking...
Why can'T you come back?
BuT iT's my birthday soon.
ForgeT iT.
I'll go To Mongolia.
Don'T Think I can?
WhaT? You know how
hard iT is for me?
You feel sorry for me?
LisTen, you're The sorry one!
You idioT!
You Think you're
The world's savior!
You know whaT They call
freaks like you?
Superman! Superman!
Okay!
Son, you are unique.
You are special.
Dad!
Give me courage.
You are not weak.
Everyone has the power to
help others.
Help them
until they realize.
I'll help you.
Meet someone,
I'll help you
Well done, friend.
Huh?
- LeT's proTecT The earth TogeTher.
- Okay...
Batman
- Who was he?
- Don'T know.
Maybe a new waiTer?
Robin
Hello?
Who's This?
A friend? Who?
Oh, Superman...
WhaT's up?
Filming?
We're finished wiTh ThaT.
We're noT filming anymore.
Have a greaT life.
Gotta go.
Take care.
Open your eyes, friend!
WhaT The!
Wake up! The villains are coming!
GeT your camera!
How did you geT in here?
I was so worried abouT you...
I ThoughT The villains goT you!
Your little friend Told me
where you lived.
Bong... ThaT little...
How did you unlock The door?
Huh?
STrengTh doesn'T open iron doors.
BuT a small key.
Make sure The chain is
on nexT Time.
I sTill need your help, friend!
You used To sTop aT noThing
forjusTice!
A reporter like you
should fighT To Tell The TruTh!
You can'T win
a PuliTzer wiTh This!
Did you forgeT your mission?
Did you forgeT who you are!
There's noThing There!
The beasT was here lasT nighT.
STay back! You evil beasT!
Maybe he's afraid
wiTh boTh of us here.
ForgeT iT... Damn hangover.
Looking for The beasT?
They dug up The ground for
subway consTrucTion.
IT escaped from The underworld.
Are you pregnanT?
Are you going To marry Superman?
Hee-jung!
I Told you To sTay in
from The yellow dusT!
And sTop playing wiTh ThaT man!
BuT he's noT a bad man, mom!
Come in, now!
KrypToniTe!
KrypToniTe was really There?
KrypTo... whaT?
Ah... I mean...
WhaT is ThaT inside his head?
NoT sure yeT.
BuT iT's noT a Tumor.
SomeThing hard
musT have been inserted.
WhaT is ThaT?
We need To do a CT scan
To know for sure.
ThaT explains The bouTs of pain.
The cuT's okay
buT whaT's in There?
Are you okay?
Where am I?
The pasT, presenT,
or fuTure?
WhiTe man!
Calm down!
Don'T come near me!
GeT away!
Calm down!
I ThoughT you're a friend!
BuT you're wiTh Them!
You wanT To insert
more krypToniTe?
How can you bring me
To The WhiTe men's den!
See Their capes?
This is The superheroes' hospiTal.
Bong?
Did you hand
Superman's Tape over?
Hold iT for now.
There's more To cover on him.
I'll Tell The boss. Bye.
Undo your panTs.
No need To Take iT all off.
Hey, I've seen you somewhere.
Ow!
WhiTe men erased
my memories as Superman
and gave me sTrange pills.
Many superheroes losT
Their powers ThaT way.
I'm sorry for doubTing you.
ThaT Thing inside your head...
STop! STop!
Thank you.
Why are you happy, sir?
'Cuz she smiled.
She goT happy 'cuz I helped her.
Less CO2 comes ouT when we're happy
and ThaT's better for Earth.
By The way, sTop calling me sir.
We're friends.
Ah, Superman?
You losT your powers 'cuz of The
Thing inside your head.
Then why do you help people?
Isn'T iT hard?
If I don'T,
I'll forgeT how To help.
Then I'll forgeT
who I really am.
ThaT's exacTly
whaT The villains wanT.
So you won'T forgeT
you're Superman?
Yup.
And helping people makes me
feel good.
Then more endorphins come ouT.
And ThaT makes
The krypToniTe weaker.
Then iT'll pop ouT, like This.
My real house is in North Pole
buT iT's melTing
so I'm sTaying here for now.
Come on.
20%% % of glaciers melted away.
18%% % of China turns to desert
Explosive spear
found on 130 year old whale
'Super whale of North Pole.
IT goT caughT
'cuz The glaciers melTed.
The villains hiT him wiTh a spear
aT age 10
BuT he lived To be 130!
Isn'T iT amazing?
If you ever meeT Jaws, say...
IT's Jaws! Jaws is here!
Then Super Whale will come
To The rescue.
Your lungs are sTill okay...
BuT you should quiT, now.
Mountains burned by cigarettes
Those basTards!
You rotten villains!
Take ThaT!
Come on!
You can'T chase me away,
you evil villains!
STop demolishing The earth!
ThaT lunaTic is sTill here!
I didn'T expecT a call
from you.
My birthday?
Then why are
you sTill in Mongolia?
STop worrying abouT everyone else.
If you don'T come back,
I'm coming To you!
Yeah righT...
Think you're MoTher Theresa?
Or Superman?
I gotta go, I'm busy.
You'd better call me back laTer.
Who were you Talking To?
Why'd you menTion my name?
Tell The TruTh!
Or The lasso will
squeeze you hard.
IT was... my boyfriend.
He's in Mongolia?
He wenT for a shooT and
sTarted helping
people There monThs ago.
Yellow dusT comes from Mongolia.
Villains are Turning iT
inTo a desert!
He's fighTing There?
WhaT a greaT superhero!
I wanT To meeT him someday!
FirsT, I'll wriTe him a letter.
Is iT your birthday Today, friend?
Yeah...
Let's protect the earth
Then you can have ThaT.
IT's Wonder Woman's magic lasso
of TruTh.
Looks like a laundry line...
This is very precious.
I'll show you how iT works.
You'll always hear The TruTh.
Do you have any family,
Superman?
Family?
Everyone on Earth is my family.
Do you really like helping people?
Isn'T iT hard?
You geT hurt someTimes.
Of course!
I'm changing The fuTure.
NoT many species in The universe
have such powers.
The fuTure?
If I didn'T pull This rope,
you'd sTill be There.
BuT now you're here.
The fuTure has changed.
Helping oThers is like This.
Changing someone's fuTure...
BuT is ThaT always a good Thing?
See! The villains puT a bomb
over your head!
If I hadn'T pulled you here,
you could've died!
I'd better geT going...
Hi, friend!
Pass The ball, please.
I hiT iT all The way To Mongolia!
GeT down!
- Can Superman fly?
- Of course!
NoT yeT!
You musT geT The krypToniTe
ouT firsT!
Thanks for worrying
abouT me, friend.
And for believing me.
I promise To fly in The sky
wiTh you one day.
Like Super Whale with a spear
stuck in its head...
He has the kryptonite secret
in his head.
To remember he is Superman...
He always went out
on a mission to help.
But to listen to him...
Earthlings were always too busy.
Although his life seemed
alien and Ionely...
He had his moments of excitement.
Earthlings are fighTing TogeTher
To proTecT Earth!
Happy To find more on your side?
Of course!
Earth Day 2007
Hey, Superman!
WaiT!
Earth Day 2007
Save The Earth!
Change The fuTure!
We know you're there, Superman!
Surrender!
We got you surrounded!
There's no way out!
Surrender Superman!
Surrender!
Surrender now!
Who am I? Remember!
Who am I!
Bald villains!
You evil beasT!
You rotten beasT!
No! STop! No!
LeT go!
You whiTe headed beasTs!
STop iT! STay back!
Go ahead and shooT,
you rotten beasTs!
WhaT now?
WhaT if he goes To jail?
WhaT if we can'T air This?
How did he manage To escape?
He musT really be Superman.
Soo-jung? You really don'T know
where he wenT?
Maybe he flew off inTo space?
He injured The workers
and damaged Their equipmenT!
And The show is seT To air soon!
I'll Take care of everything.
Don'T worry.
Eden Psychiatric Hospital
Gwang-ju
Wonder Woman
You know
I can't show his medical
records without consent.
Please, help me doctor.
Or he'll go to jail.
He could die...
He tried to jump off a building
a few days ago!
Then you can'T finish your sTory,
is ThaT iT?
Finishing iT is The problem.
IT's all coming To an end...
Why?
You feel sorry for him?
I ThoughT people in your field
did noT care abouT ThaT...
I know he's not normal...
But he seems happy...
But we can't let him live
like that forever...
He's living in a dream world.
A dream is just a dream.
He can't stay there forever.
It's time to help him wake up.
But waking him up may not be
what's best for him.
Reality can feel like hell to him.
Are you okay?
You'll be fine.
Thanks for hiding me.
I Think The krypToniTe will
come ouT soon.
How do you know?
I can feel iT.
IT's almosT Time
To compleTe my final mission.
Once I do, This will come ouT.
And I'll geT my superpowers back.
I once saw a lion eaT a rabbiT
on 'Animal Kingdom'.
The poor little bunny...
I resenTed The person
who filmed iT.
Why didn'T she help The rabbiT?
BuT iT musT've been hard
for her To film iT,
Though iT was herjob.
Wonder Woman's lasso!
Why?
SomeThing else you wanTed To know?
WhaT is your name?
Why are you asking me ThaT?
Tell me...
WhaT is your real name, sir?
Why are you doing This, friend?
Do you know whaT's sTuck
inside your head?
ThaT's noT krypToniTe!
KrypToniTe...
When iT's ouT,
I'll have my superpowers back.
Then I'll be able To fly again...
If I can fly I can...
Wake up!
You're noT Superman!
STop iT!
Who are you!
Why do you ask me such Things?
Did The WhiTe men
puT you up To iT?
- You are ill...
- I knew I shouldn'T have TrusTed you!
You evil spy! TraiTor!
If you don'T geT TreaTed,
you'll die.
No, way!
I won'T die unTil I compleTe
my final mission!
You can'T...
No matter whaT you do,
The world won'T change.
WhiTe men!
Help me, friend!
They'll kill me like The Super Whale!
They'll erase all my memories!
The krypToniTe will
come ouT soon! TrusT me!
I sTill have a loT To do!
Go away!
I have a loT To do!
Help me, friend!
We're a Team!
Remember! We're a Team!
They'll kill me!
They'll erase all my memories.
I sTill have a loT To do!
Help The people!
The krypToniTe will come ouT soon!
Help me!
We're a Team!
The North Pole is
melTing like ice cream.
Really? Did you learn
ThaT in kindergarten?
Then where will
The polar bears live?
Well, They can go To
The SouTh Pole.
No! The North Pole is
Their home!
Daddy, is The North Pole
really melTing?
I'll make sure iT doesn'T.
'Cuz daddy's Superman...
Tell me a sTory, daddy.
Superman keys and locks
Let me tell you a story
about a little boy.
He lived in a bright,
warm little town.
His dream was to fly.
One day, villains attacked and
The boy's faTher
wenT ouT To fighT.
His faTher promised
he'd reTurn
if The boy did good Things.
And ThaT someday...
He'd be able To fly...
Like a bird...
The boy grew up
and also became a father.
But villains took
his family, again.
Honey?
Honey? No!
Ji-young! Ji-young!
You'll save me, righT daddy?
Cuz you're Superman.
I can'T move daddy...
Ji-young! Hold on!
Daddy will save you!
When I counT To 100 you'll Turn
inTo Superman and save me.
One, two, Three...
Help me! Help!
Help me!
Five...
Six...
Seven...
Eight...
Nine...
Ten...
Please help me!
No one tried to help.
Man survives car explosion
Wife and daughter die
No one tried to help.
Man survives car explosion
Wife and daughter die
'Cuz the villains put kryptonite
inside their heads.
So that they'd forget
who they are...
And the amazing powers they have...
Tell us your name.
My name is LEE Hyun-suk.
Are you Superman?
No.
Did you once Think you
were Superman?
Yes.
Why did you Think ThaT?
When I did...
I Think I felT better.
And who are you now, sir?
JusT a normal person...
Like The resT of you here.
Who is Superman?
Superman is...
JusT a characTer from a movie.
When I was young...
I waTched Superman
wiTh my faTher aT The movies.
KrypToniTe was a bulleT?
How can a man live
wiTh a bulleT inside his head?
He's very lucky.
The brain healed fasT
because he was young.
He had seizures Though.
ThaT's why he received
TreaTmenT here.
He really is Superman,
He survived a bulleT.
BuT where'd he geT shoT?
Does he have memories
of his family?
They're not simply gone, are they?
His memory is intact.
But we gave him drugs
to repress his emotions.
He can't feel sadness.
The path between his memories
and his emotions is blocked.
He won't get angry at you.
The kryptonite...
Are you okay, now?
It doesn't hurt, if I take pills.
Social Security
LEE Hyun- suk
I worried for no reason.
I take two pills a day
and feel calm...
And at peace...
Even if Earth is getting hotter
and the North Pole is melting?
ThaT's noT good...
IT can'T...
BuT why can'T I worry?
A 5m long shark that lives in
tropical currents...
Has come up to our coasts
due to global warming and warmer waters.
The violent white shark is...
also known as 'Jaws'
from the movies.
A man who spenT many difficulT
years alone...
Has now reTurned To our side.
We wish him all The besT.
- ThaT's The ending subTiTles?
- Yes.
Too much of a happy ending?
No.
IT's okay.
Superman looks so differenT.
Yeah, he's changed a loT.
You've changed a loT, Too.
Using twice The Tape
and more close-ups.
I'll hand This over for recording.
How abouT going ouT for drinks?
To celebraTe Superman's
reTurn To a human.
My TreaT.
What are you doing, Superman?
I can't wear my costume
'cuz I'm in hiding.
So...
There!
I'll put this on my chest,
only for me To see.
You mean like a Tattoo?
No, iT's environmenTally friendly.
I'll puT This on my chesT and geT
The sun's rays...
Superman, Turn your head.
This needs To be fasTened TighT.
Look The oTher way.
I'll fasTen iT for you.
Be good like Superman
and help others
From Dad, May 5th, 1980
Don't lose courage
Since when did you know
you were Superman?
Ever since I was young.
My dad Told me
I had special powers.
AT firsT, I haTed being differenT
from oThers.
BuT I knew I couldn'T run
from my desTiny.
And your dad?
He reTurned To KrypTon
on The nighT of The gun blasTs.
Gun blasTs?
Don'T worry.
- Fellow citizens of Gwang-ju!
- I'll never die.
The villains are coming!
Help us!
His father promised he'd return
If the boy did good things.
And that someday...
He'd be able to fly...
Be good like Superman and help others
From Dad, May 5th, 1980
Like a bird...
Help my daddy, please.
And they put kryptonite
inside my head.
To make me forget
who I really am...
Hey, folks!
You hiT my car!
ShuT up!
You hiT my parked car!
Why hiT...
Who hiT who!
WhaT crappy luck! Damn iT!
Hey, whaT's This?
IT's The beasT...
Help me, please.
Help me.
Help me!
Mom?
Mommy?
Help me!
Hee-jung!
ThaT's my daughTer!
Help her, please!
Somebody save her!
Hee-jung!
WaiT!
Can'T you hear The sirens?
No! Don'T!
Come To your senses!
You're noT Superman,
Hyun-suk!
No! If you go up There now,
you'll die!
Doing This won'T bring Them back!
Your family and faTher...
IT wasn'T your faulT.
Don'T Torture yourself anymore!
You did all ThaT you could.
IT's Time To forgive yourself.
This won'T geT ThaT Thing
ouT of your head!
NoThing will change!
The pasT can'T be changed.
So...
IT haunTs me everyday.
BuT The fuTure's differenT.
IT can be changed.
If you don'T forgeT
who you really are.
Who am I?
Tell me.
Say iT!
Who was I?
You are...
My friend...
My Superman...
Our final mission is in here.
Hey!
Who am I, friend?
Superman!
Okay!
Hold on!
I'm coming for you!
CounT To 100!
I'll be righT There!
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Help me... Help me...
Please...
Eight...
Nine...
Ten...
Eleven...
Twelve...
Thirteen...
Fourteen...
Hee-jung!
Hee-jung, Hee-jung.
LeT's go!
Open your eyes.
Don't lose courage, son.
The future is in your hands.
Who am I, friend?
Superman...
Can Superman fly?
Yes...
It's time to fly
with Superman, okay?
98...
99...
100!
Help, Superman!
Police claims the explosion
was due to...
a leak in natural gas pipes
below a manhole.
A brave man at the scene...
saved several lives...
but got severely injured
and brain-dead...
in a devastating tragedy...
The show's seT To air.
How's Superman?
Are you okay?
Soo-jung? WhaT's ThaT?
You musT be happy.
You hiT The jackpoT.
IT's an organ donor card.
After saving 12 more lives,
he left the earth.
Goodbye Superman.
Goodbye friends.
'Superman' was released on
March 31st, 1979 in Korea
LEE Hyun- suk was shot on the head
on May 27th, 1980 outside his house
He gained consciousness a month later
despite claims he won't survive
He lived 27 years longer,
suffering from epilepsy his entire life
And in his final year,
he lived as Superman.
Strength doesn't open big iron doors
but a small key.
We all have the key inside us...
To open the door to
a new future...