Hi, it's Keeley.
Leave a message.
Keeley its me.
What are you doing?
I've left three messages.
I said sorry didn't I?
You know me. I was pissed off
.
Get back to me, bitch.
Tyler, what are you doing?
What does it look like?
Yields, Mia!
Keeley is not there.
I have a message for her.
His father is a big motherfucker!
I'll get you one day!
You'd be so fucking lucky!
You waited a long time
Now I'm here
I know I should not have
Making you wait that long
I had much to do
But I imagined
All I want you to
I know all the guys
s Story  through me
Like no other girl
They know I'm good
They fantasize about me
But you're the only
What I want today
And you want me too
What's your problem?
You dance like a dung.
Do not bother, Mia.
So Keeley
you hang with tuna?
You've seen, dirty gypsy?
You're going to complain?
Get out!
Get out, bitch!
If you want more,
Come get me!
Bitch!
Get out!
What are you doing?
You think?
Get out!
Hello. It's me.
Police looking for you.
This girl has a broken nose.
- I have not started!
- Dirty liar!
- It's his fault.
- You bet! You'll see ...
Let me go, Mom.
Let me go!
I let you go, little bitch!
What's your problem?
It is you, my problem!
is my beautiful room.
Joanne will kill you.
The headboard is beautiful.
It was carved for me
heart shape.
I love hearts.
There,
is my casual clothes.
Y  all my jeans,
and I have a max.
You had to stay here.
My sexy tracksuit  ...
Do not be afraid.
Hello.
- It's private property.
- My ass!
She wants to have fun.
We gonna party.
In addition, she has enough booze.
- Why did you that?
- To nail you dick.
You mijotes something.
Give me that!
We'll have fun.
Let me go!
Calm.
It is not partying.
Touch me!
It has a little fun.
Leave me!
Let me go!
Let me go, assholes!
Go ahead, mug it.
Stop fidgeting.
Let me go, fuck!
We just want to laugh.
Do not worry about me, continue.
I enjoyed it.
Exactly.
You make eggs?
No.
For what, water?
I make tea.
I am a friend of your mother.
You dance like a Black.
It's a compliment.
Where'd you get that?
I watch videos,
like everyone else.
And it makes you a specialist?
You're answer to everything?
What's your name?
As you wish.
You know your world charm.
See you later.
I met one of your daughters.
And you're still around?
You made me tea!
What are you doing?
Never mind, little bitch.
Never mind yourself, big bitch.
I'm already late.
Go, stay.
See you later.
- You play what?
- At the door.
I can go out?
Must pay to open the door.
- How?
- 2 lbs.
Holy shit, is not given.
Here.
Stop!
Give me the money!
I want a discount.
Okay. A book, dirty rat!
OK. Deal.
I love you.
I'll kill you last.
Tyler! Let me go.
He said, "See you later."
Your lovely kid coming back?
I invited some friends.
You go into your room
or outside.
One like the other.
It has nothing to fuck
of your friends.
They're all fat morons.
You look like a giggle!
Bitch!
Call SOS Children Beaten.
You too, you're a slut!
You got the nerve to come back.
Shut up.
Good.
You're the pot
my brothers are not there.
They took my business.
That's not what you think.
She is old.
You've dropped your dog express
yesterday?
He is strong.
Did you get the bowl
not bite you.
That's right, sucker.
My guests are there,
finished but I prepare myself.
They make themselves up to death.
It's super gross.
It must be his house.
You see?
It is his mother?
Damn, the big pile!
They are tainted.
His smile is atrocious
She has yellow teeth.
Definitely green.
Soon they will be pink.
She might like it.
When I enter the tent
and be admired,
will be magic.
This cider is perfect,
There's no denying it.
There will be short.
Hello shame!
Dirty bitch friquée.
Fat bitch.
Shut up, Mia.
You, your mouth.
I leave in a minute.
Hello, beautiful.
You're a big acorn.
If it was so large
I could convert.
Can I come?
're Unrecognizable, dressed.
- You're really a dick.
- I know.
You're late.
But I'm here.
- I'm more.
- I had to change.
In your room.
We recognize it
when she sleeps.
- Shoot it.
- It's good.
I'll handle this.
You're too nice.
At the end of the corridor.
She treats me like a kid.
At your age,
we live with my mom more.
I was kicked out of my house.
Go get dressed.
I am dressed.
You're almost naked.
You do not care, usually.
Here, it bothers me.
Go get dressed.
Why do you take that voice?
It moves?
- You go where?
- Nowhere.
So why did you say,
"It moves?"
We will drive around.
Want to come?
- Both?
- Forget it.
I want to come.
It goes nowhere.
I do not care, I want to come.
Go get dressed.
Thank you.
And you?
It said nothing.
Check in 20 minutes.
You're better to do.
You know what? That tells me much.
- Where are we going?
- Good question.
At the orphanage.
That sucks, you're not nice.
First
'd have at least been able to shave.
Why?
Out of respect for me.
- I like that you like me?
- You got too much hair.
Me, I think you're beautiful.
Thank you.
What?
You're weird stuff.
Anything.
Really weird.
Bobby Womack
is anything but bizarre.
You're how old?
The age thing.
I will have to
your education.
Mets thoroughly.
At your command.
leaves are brown
And the sky is gray
I walk aimlessly
By a winter's day
It would  sweeter
If I  L.A.
I dream  California
For this winter's day
I saw a church
I stopped
I knelt
And I began to pray
The priest blesses the cold
Because he knows that I'll stay
It's called an airship.
It's too good!
Mom!
I have seen.
We see more.
Look.
Too good.
It's super cool.
In what animal
you want to be reincarnated?
In monkey.
In white tiger.
Somewhat bitch.
What kind of dog?
Race.
You're already a bitch.
Stop!
Me, I'd be an eagle. "
Your animals are terrestrial.
You would not fly?
You'd get shot.
Why not?
We could shoot you,
true.
I want to pick blackberries.
I want a drink.
It is.
Let me show you something.
- Come.
- We show what?
Come on, moron!
Wait.
So, you like it?
I would have been better in flip flops.
You are perfect like that.
Come here.
Hey, lovers!
It's nice here!
There must be millions
dégueus insects.
Stop! You're not interested!
There's a dragonfly, Mia!
Look there.
On the worksheet. You see?
Mashed, it has six legs!
1, 2, 3 ...
- Shut up.
- I see it.
Soaring.
I'll catch a fish.
- Are you kidding?
- I go. You coming?
You're dreaming!
Without me, thank you.
Sissies.
You're grounded.
I need help.
You can scratch you.
- We'll end up with water.
- No way!
No way.
Nobody ever comes here.
Fish are animals,
will be easy.
I expect to see.
Super.
Come on.
Always ready, that one.
It is dirty?
Running Your cost me 20 pounds.
It is not possible.
Bravo.
Come.
Go gently.
She can not swim!
Your feet atrocious
will drive them away!
They believe
it's a fish-off
who comes to eat!
Moving slowly toward me.
Did he affected?
You'll have a poissonite!
You see the fish?
You go ahead ...
Not yet.
Slowly.
Stop.
He caught one!
He glides, that bastard!
He died?
You think he dances, woodcock?
What are you doing?
- It's brutal.
- It's better for him.
You bet!
We eat?
I would not even touch.
It's like fried fish.
No, he is whole and full of shit.
- I do not eat it.
- I do.
Bravo.
It would have surprised.
Help! AIDS!
Watch.
You will survive.
Mom hates blood.
Your socks will have AIDS,
Connor.
Who's Kelly?
On your arm.
Just one example.
There's a spider.
Mia
Wait.
Climb on my back.
You all right?
I have nothing more to say.
We made the turn.
I do not know.
Well, okay.
Pass me a while ago.
You okay?
The family bullshit.
We'll have to go.
You've promised to cook the fish.
- Your mother was not bored.
- I know.
I'll drop you.
We just drink a nightcap?
Please. Go!
Go. It's me who pays.
Okay, a little manipulative.
I hurry.
See if you can dance it.
It is zero!
This is not true. I saw it.
Can you do that?
I'm barefoot.
What a stupid excuse!
This is not dancing!
Move!
It will not be accepted?
I'm going to pee.
Continue!
Shut up!
It was nice to you.
I do not care.
I have the right not to love.
It's a pain in the ass, I told you.
- She thinks not.
- I love you not!
There is no mates in two days!
You know us!
She is barefoot.
It's not far off, it will kill it.
I like dogs.
We'll talk
when you have eaten the arm.
There's someone down for you.
Stand!
All right.
I'm up.
Do not bother, I come!
Here it is.
Good morning. I'm Carrie.
Will you talk about?
What?
In ancient history, cretin.
- I can drink before?
- Sure.
You're making
in this special school.
When she was born,
she cried for days.
One would think she had
malice in the blood.
You have another daughter?
Yes. Tyler.
She sticks the same cotton.
It too would
by being kicked out of school.
It's hard when you're alone.
You can tell.
The place where she goes,
like?
How far?
I have no car.
Come back here!
You kidding me?
I will enter this shop
and when I go out,
I'm different.
Different!
You dig? Different.
Unlike other, you,
worldwide.
Club Luxury
seeks talented young dancers
Is it me or it schlingue here?
It beats serious.
Some of us should
take a bath.
You got the eye swelling.
Your father missed your mouth?
You bars?
Touch me or I'll
another black eye!
Get out!
You got that face!
Hello.
I was passing by.
How did you know where I work?
You said.
What's New?
I thought you hated me.
You're a puzzle balls.
Thank you.
Not enough.
And your foot?
Okay.
Hold on.
Take off your shoes.
- I can do.
- Not as good as me.
That ever happen to wash?
It is like new.
What are you doing with your days?
I have things planned.
You are going?
- I know.
- Go ahead, you're good.
Say nothing to my mother.
I'll have what in return?
You need a camcorder?
They say to send a demo.
I can lend you my camera.
On one condition.
Which?
You'll smile on the video.
You're pretty when you smile.
I'm back to work.
I will chum with you
some time.
Does it bother you?
Your mother has fired?
More or less.
It's me, Tennents big moron.
Is not blocking you
you cut it there-
You go on Guarded Centre
in 2 weeks.
You've got a camcorder?
You scared me.
Give me one second.
Who's the best?
Thank you.
- How does it work?
- It's easy.
You light up here.
Forget not to lower the cache.
Red button to record.
You press and it filmed.
You will take the shot quickly.
Awesome.
How do you think?
Honestly?
Sure.
From fox piss.
You deserve a beating, girl!
For me spied.
For your insolence.
To be planted
social worker.
Connor!
You worry tires cheap,
this time.
Dinner.
I'm coming.
I was spinning my camcorder to Mia.
She'll break it.
If she does that, look out the beating.
It smells good.
I've done a good steak.
My name is Mia Williams.
My number is 07700 900 542.
My name  Mia Williams.
My number is 07700 ...
Have you nearly finished?
What I meddle, microbe?
I'm going to pee.
Go ahead, I look at it.
No.
Or you close your eyes.
I can not, I might cut myself.
Wait for me.
You follow me?
Yes, so what?
How is your mare?
Did you hear?
That's not what you think.
I think what?
Let her starve.
It seems, anyway.
She is old, I told you.
Where you going?
Search for something.
What thing?
You're as curious girl.
Can I come with you?
If you want to.
Give me that.
Take support here.
It is not bad.
It's just a show.
What are you looking?
A Volvo 940.
It looks like what?
In a Volvo 940.
Very clever, head node.
And here. Volvo 940.
This is a car like any other.
There's not often.
They are super strong.
You want more?
Keep watch.
I like not here!
I for one minute.
I know where to find the Bethune
to buy a drink.
to buy a drink!
Good!
I.
You have much luck, you know.
Come on.
We will tear.
Hold on.
All right, get up.
Fuck your mother!
Gotcha!
Descend.
Come down.
You're not funny.
I'm supposed to work there.
What do you want?
We need Bethune.
Oh yeah?
You're stuffed?
You got a 5 bill?
I paid
to transfer the pochetrons.
Do not shit.
I have nothing on me.
Look.
This boy is very thin.
It was the slab, we must eat.
I'll pay you back.
- I'm not a kid.
- That I know.
There's something to eat?
Have you seen the time?
Do you believe in coffee?
In Thailand? Aggressiveness zero.
Japan? Same story.
But in Russia  ...
we feel first in Russia,
is anger.
I hate nothing but think again.
You're still my camcorder?
You want it?
So it is safe ...
He is.
Some streets
stink of money, full nose.
snow.
The chicks are covered
to the eyes ...
You go out with this boy?
Why?
It looks a bit old for you.
It is 1 9.
It has never been a guy.
I just hit me up there.
It is elegant.
You can talk.
It goes to bed?
In bed, the Sleeping Beauty.
Is your new school.
You'll live.
You'll be able to type
all the lads that you want.
It's smart.
I will not go.
They may teach you
politeness.
It's none of your business.
Did you need discipline.
You've already said.
Who are you to lecture me?
It's only two weeks.
I can not believe it.
It is super easy to live.
There's this thing ...
As soon as I saw him I knew.
Stop your bullshit!
Anything.
They are only good for one thing
and I can tell you
it assures that side.
I know!
Stop angst around,
you meet someone.
Are you going to Ann Marie?
At 21 pm?
At any hour.
You have a new message.
Mia Williams
Your demo we liked.
Can you hear
next week
Remember us at 01708 665 001.
I'm Val.
Put your arm here.
It's good. The other arm.
Climbs the stairs.
Sorry.
I took one.
I know.
I must sleep.
You think it'll be tomorrow?
Do not worry.
It will be fine tomorrow.
You swear?
I swear.
You're still standing?
I had stuff to do.
We again become friends?
What?
You were weird with me.
You, you were weird.
Really?
Maybe.
Your mother is in the polish.
As usual.
You like booze in the family.
It's pretty, your hair loose.
It's better than your ponytail
usual.
I got a hearing.
Bravo.
It surprises me not.
I've borrowed a CD.
What song?
California Dreamin '.
You had spent in the car.
This is my favorite song
the world.
You show me?
You're dreaming!
Go.
If not you'll get there before me,
how will you
before all these people?
Especially since I found
you-insured
You know.
I licking this evening.
It is not yet ready.
It was to help.
It's up to you.
I am only here for now.
Come here.
It was really good.
You say it like that.
I'm serious.
If it were me, I advise.
I bet it's not like that
with your boyfriend.
Its tail is as big?
I'm drunk.
We screwed up.
No.
It must remain between us.
I know.
I'd better go to bed.
I'm wiped.
We'll talk tomorrow.
Connor is gone.
Connor!
I told you that I almost
abort you?
I even made an appointment.
You're going to call?
It will not.
You know shit.
Si I'm going to tell Mom.
I have nothing to fight.
Here  Connor. Leave a message
and I'll call you.
118 008.
Can I help you?
Wickes, Barking.
moment.
I put you in relationship?
Mia
I was looking for.
Wickes, Barking. I listen.
Me want to talk to Connor
it is a security officer.
Where are you going?
Connor O'Reilly
He is on leave.
It is when?
next Friday.
- When?
-  Next Friday.
Where's that, Tilbury?
It is on the A13 in that direction.
Can I come?
I have personal stuff to do.
See you later.
Excuse me. Danton Road?
In the new subdivision,
on the right.
Damn!
Come here.
Come
How you found me?
It is not smart.
You do not answer the phone.
I have more battery.
I was going to call you.
You're not even my number.
You know I love you.
Why you're gone, then?
You know very well.
You have 15 years.
It's irrelevant if you're in love.
I'll take you to the station,
we speak in the car.
Wait for me. Hold on.
When is the audition?
Tomorrow.
You'll provide.
I have no money.
That should be enough to return.
Come here.
Fits well.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Shoot!
Come on, sweetie.
It's yours.
Keira sings for Dad.
I said no to love
and its torments
I tried my luck
whenever vain
The days marched
and my heart froze
But something new
happened with you
My heart back to life,
the evidence was there
people around me
cry to dementia
No matter what they say,
is you I love
They can not
cons obviously
Bravo
Mouse candy.
Make a smile for Dad.
Keira! Not on the road.
I know.
Keira.
Your mom told me
to take you to buy an ice cream.
Come.
Let's go.
Race you?
We'll go through it.
Give.
My scooter!
It is not practical here.
You will take to return.
Mom!
It's a game
Quickly, you must run.
- Keira?
- Mom!
Advance.
I do not want!
Forward or I'll shoot.
I want to go home!
Keira, advance.
Enough. Advance.
You're scaring me!
Hurry!
Stop it. Climb.
- Raise your legs, brothel.
- Shut up!
Go.
Wait for me!
Stop!
Stop run away!
You think that's smart?
Poor little idiot.
I can do the same.
Stop run away!
Let me go!
You're no better than your father!
Stop hitting me!
You okay?
I'm cold.
You're cold?
Go on, get.
It was sublime, honey.
Absolutely sublime.
You shall be called.
Thank you for coming.
- It is great.
- Who's Next?
Is that Mia is there?
Mia Williams?
What song?
17.
You can remove your hair,
please?
It's much more feminine.
You do not have a body?
Shorts?
It's okay.
Go.
What is this story?
Hello.
It's your car?
Still missing parts.
You forgot your hat.
And your mare?
She was sick.
He took it down.
She was 16.
She had outlived its usefulness.
Should see
if the engine goes the distance.
I know people in Cardiff.
Wales.
Why do you take all this?
If.
And Center
of Special Education?
I leave my place.
I want to.
There's that Gogol there.
I'm going.
It's one of your CDs.
Not bad.
Is Nas. It is good.
Keep it.
Go.
Fuck off.
What you waiting for?
Where are you going already?
Wales.
You have not changed my mind, then?
This is my sister, Tyler.
Hi, Tyler.
You're a gypsy?
Shut up.
Bitch.
I hate you!
I hate you too
See you later boy
See you later
All right?
Hello, bitch!
Dont forget to text me
Say hello to the welsh for me