[whimsical orchestral music]
♪ ♪
♪ Once a native maiden
and a stranger met ♪
♪ underneath
the blue Tahitian moon ♪
♪ The stars were in her eyes ♪
♪ gardenias in her hair ♪
♪ and they vowed
to care forever ♪
[muffled explosions]
♪ Then one lonely day ♪
♪ the stranger sailed away ♪
♪ with a parting kiss
that came too soon ♪
♪ And now the trade winds sigh ♪
♪ when ships go sailing by ♪
[man on radio]
This country
is at war with Germany.
[sirens wailing]
♪ Once a native maiden
and a stranger met ♪
♪ underneath
a blue Tahitian moon ♪
♪ The stars were in her eyes ♪
♪ gardenias in her hair ♪
♪ And they vowed
to care forever ♪
[man on radio]
Many are bombed
out of their homes-
Today of the evacuation
of London's schoolchildren.
Aircraft were launched
in two attacks against London
and South East England.
A good hundred feet
below ground,
but they feel safe.
♪ When ships go sailing by ♪
♪ Underneath
a blue Tahitian moon ♪
[sirens wailing]
[voices overlapping]
(woman)
You're not a coward.
(man)
I don't want to die.
And why should I?
And if I don't,
why should anyone else?
Yet still you wouldn't
make peace now.
Not now.
You wouldn't support that.
You couldn't.
We've only got the one life,
Anita, just the one.
Dylan?
Is it?
Dylan Thomas.
It is, isn't it?
You might at least
have lifted my veil.
My God, still love me?
Did I ever?
Lift the veil, Vera,
lift the bloody veil.
Look at you.
Not been called up?
Just because I haven't got
a uniform.
It's me that puts the heart
in the nation.
Ammo factories, I sing in.
- Down the tubes right now.
- I always loved your voice.
Always.
Amongst other things
I loved about you.
Don't you come it,
Dylan Thomas!
- You haven't changed.
- 'Course I have, thank God.
You can't.
And don't, not ever.
If you do,
I won't let you.
I heard you on the radio.
Like going home, it was,
your poems.
Like going back.
Where's the posh accent from?
You should've looked me up.
- Should I?
- Mm.
If I can get all my friends
to donate five bob each-
this is the plan, see.
If I get them all to do that,
then I don't have
to sell my soul
writing bloody propaganda films.
I can write my bloody poetry.
You'd have
to join the army.
Grade Three sitting here
before you, Vera.
Lungs raddled
like a Sunday whore.
So... lend us five bob.
I'll give you a snout,
Dylan Thomas,
that's all you'll get from me.
Oh. Give us, then.
Silver's for the lonely,
Vera Bera.
Who says I'm lonely?
Well, where's the man
who'll give you gold?
That an offer, is it?
It's always been shares
with you and me.
You never had anything to share.
Yes, but if I did,
if ever I did,
you'd be the first.
There's no folks
like home folks.
And folks you've
grown up with...
they're the best of all.
You win.
Goody.
Forever and always.
You won't, will you?
Won't what, lovely?
You won't get lost again?
(man)
Ta, mate.
[whistling]
(man)
Hello, love!
(Dylan)
I have longed to move away
from the hissing
of the spent lie
and the old terrors'
continual cry,
growing more terrible
as the day goes over the hill
into the deep sea.
I have longed to move away
from the repetition of salutes.
For there are ghosts in the air
and ghostly echoes on paper.
This is Dylan Thomas
for the BBC Home Service.
- Hello, darling!
- Where you going?
Tension, four hundredweight.
(man)
The commentary
has to persuade women
to join the balloon defenses.
"Shaft a Jerry,
and maybe one of our
boys in blue will shaft you."
That do you?
Your talents really
are wasted here, Dylan.
We could have a drink
if you like.
After.
- 'Course we could.
- I'm not a bloody dog, Dylan.
It's the brunette,
isn't it?
I had a golden childhood,
Anita.
And here it is turning up
all unexpected.
Now I can't look a golden
childhood in the mouth, can I?
The commentary, please, Dylan.
Myselves,
the grievers grieve
among the street,
burned to tireless death.
A child of a few hours
with its kneading mouth
charred on the black breast
of the grave the mother dug
and its arms full of fires.
Oh, please,
spare us
the bloody tragedy, man.
I need something hopeful here.
The lion once known
as Jehovah...
Oh...
Rose up and cocked
its leg over.
The lioness roared,
Jehovah had scored
all over
the living room sofa.
Dylan, I require
a commentary.
Dylan!
Caitlin?
I thought you told me
you couldn't live without me.
Where's our son?
Chopped up
in little bits
and packed with my knickers
in the suitcase.
Oh, dear,
the police'll be chasing you.
Don't pretend
you want him here.
Well, there's bombs,
isn't there?
It's nothing
to do with bombs.
You don't want him,
so I didn't bring him.
I've never been
a father before, Cat.
That's the thing.
It's not straightforward.
Still the light of your life,
am I?
In the New Forest, is he?
What are you asking for,
Dullun?
You know damn well
our son's with my mother.
I love you, Cat.
Give us a fag, then.
I'm out of bleeding fags.
Give my head a good scratch,
please?
Oh, lovely.
- Where are we living?
- Nowhere.
Ow! Velvet your
bloody claws!
Scratch your own
bloody head!
- Come here.
- No.
- Yes.
Kiss me.
Excuse me,
you dropped your handkerchief.
No, I didn't.
Yes, you did, right there.
It's not mine, sorry.
You're supposed
to take the hankie,
I'm supposed
to introduce myself,
buy you a drink.
I don't want a drink.
Nice try, though.
I've actually
never done this before.
No, you've just never
been caught out before.
Hmm.
Hello, darling.
Sod you, then.
Oh, dear, picky,
picky, picky.
You're late.
I know.
It's all her fault.
Who's your friend?
Queen of Ireland,
love of my life,
mother of my child,
Caitlin Thomas.
Your wife, Dylan?
The one and only.
He didn't mention.
Well, he wouldn't...
would he?
You made that,
didn't you?
I might like you.
Then again, I might not.
I'll await your decision,
shall I?
I won't hold my breath, mind.
Got a mansion
we could share with you?
Yes, two little homeless orphans
you're looking at here.
I've only got a room.
Bugger.
Condemned to her sister's, then.
I'll be having that,
sailor boy.
- Needn't let-
- Small matter of a wife?
Nothing should ever
come between us.
Oh, God, Dylan.
Soul mates, we are, Vera,
always were.
Don't.
Stop talking about me.
There's a phone in the hall
where I stay, you know.
If you want me,
he's got my number.
What does it mean
when she smiles?
I don't know, never did.
[knocks on door]
God help us.
It's the Visigoths from Wales.
Your sister's here.
(Dylan)
Back from strangling Germans,
then, are you?
Left all the other little boys
playing with
their little pistols,
all ging-gang-gooley
and yo-ho-ho.
That what you call
poetry, is it?
Look, give us a bed and we'll stay out from under your feet.
(Vera)
♪ Maybe it's because ♪
♪ I kissed you too much ♪
♪ Maybe that is why my kiss
means too little ♪
♪ Maybe with a love so great
and a love so small ♪
♪ Maybe I'll be left
with no love at all ♪
[applause]
Sometimes I can nurse
a single pint all night.
But that's sometimes.
Thank you.
(man)
Oh, yeah!
I thought it was hilarious.
I'll get them in.
You pay, though, Vera, eh?
Fair dos.
Support the starving poet.
You are not a bloody poet,
Dylan.
You write films
about barrage sodding balloons
for your living.
There is a war on.
You know,
you're not the man I married.
I did cartwheels
in a rubber corset
in Peter Robinson's window
one time I was hungry.
You were never hungry.
You've always had a man
to feed you.
Demonstration purposes it was.
Bet you can't beat that.
Bet I can't.
He's following me.
Don't you have
all the luck.
Watch this.
Causing chaos, my lovely?
What do you need knickers for?
You've only got to wash them.
Looking for a good time
with a couple of showgirls,
are you?
Three more, please.
Your drinks are here, chaps.
Oh, chief stag's beaten off
the main competition.
William Killick.
Vera Phillips.
She's very pleased to meet you.
Rums all round?
Mmm, goody.
Four rums, please.
Do you do cartwheels?
On the seashore I might.
Ah, I'll take you there.
You're busy,
by the looks of you.
I could do
with a bit of sea air.
I'd like to sit
on the beach with you.
Don't you know a brush-off
when you get one?
(Caitlin)
Got any smokes?
I enjoyed your show.
- Did you?
- Yes.
- Hey?
- Hay's for horses.
Come for a gallop.
Used to call it busking,
singing in the tube stations.
Coppers used to move you on.
I'll come again,
if I may.
Free world.
[explosion]
[laughter]
Keeping those rums to yourself?
We're in danger
of breaking a thirst.
(Vera)
I don't melt
at the sight of a uniform,
that's all.
Sod it.
I don't like nosy parkers.
(Caitlin)
It was a civil question.
I could have said,
"Are you after my husband?"
But I didn't.
Heartache, that's what I see
in a uniform.
I'm not gonna love someone
just to have them die off on me.
Who's talking about love?
Don't you ever get lonely?
My work's all I need.
I used to think
I'd be a dancer.
Danced night and day.
I know, you're one of those.
No.
No! God!
Not one of those,
for God's sake!
Not that I'm averse.
One of the ones that never
got over her first love.
'Course I am.
[sirens blaring]
Didn't your mother
teach you any manners?
All I said-
You can walk on your own,
I know.
Keep your hand
on your ha'penny,
that's what
my mother taught me.
I'm not touching you.
Well, don't look at me either.
Fine.
No, don't do that!
What have you got against me,
Vera Phillips?
You might be dead tomorrow.
Live while you can,
live all you can.
I won't see you again.
Of course not.
I'd like my torch back.
Please.
Don't let the light out!
Light of your life.
Has to wipe its feet
before it comes back in again.
No!
(Dylan)
Cat. Cat.
Little dog needs the toilet.
Go bark somewhere else.
(Dylan)
Come on, Catty.
Have you got a poem for me?
You still owe me
for the last one.
[laughs]
I am not a sodding
deposit box, Dylan.
What do you think this is?
- Well, it could be a scribble.
- Could be.
It could be
a bloody limerick, Dullun.
Could be.
Among Those Killed In The Dawn
Raid Was A Man Aged A Hundred.
Happy piece, is it?
Do you want to hear it?
Do you?
Oh, heavy.
"When the morning
was waking over the war,
"he put on his clothes
and stepped out, and he died.
"The locks yawned loose
as a blast blew them wide.
"He dropped where he loved
on the burst pavement...
- Lived.
- What?
Lived.
Oh, no, it's-
it's loved.
You can't read
your own bloody writing.
Lived. Lived.
Loved.
He's a hundred
sodding years old!
He can't remember love.
For Christ's sake,
the bloody word's only there
because I bloody wrote it!
"Dropped where he loved
on the burst pavement."
It's mine, isn't it?
What you write.
All my words
and every heartbeat,
they're all for you.
Really?
Come here, then.
Come on, you.
[giggling]
[footsteps approaching]
Get out of bed
and come and see
what he's done this time!
Oh, dear, naughty doggy Dylan.
Do you know what that is?
That's animal behavior,
that's what it is.
Nicolette, I'm-
I'm-
[laughs]
(Dylan)
Hello,
is Vera Phillips there, please?
- Just a moment.
- Thank you.
[Vera on telephone]
Hello?
Hello, darling.
Dylan?
'Course it is.
There was a young hero
called Killick
who marched
to the top of a...
hillick.
He stood legs astride
and whipped out his pride
and spread Brylcreem
all over his fillick.
What's a fillick?
Oh, dear,
showing your ignorance now, Cat.
William will have a nice one,
whatever it is.
(Caitlin)
Not that you're
seeing him again.
He'll still have a nice one.
Come here, Vera Bera.
Come on,
come and have a cuddle.
Go on, you're welcome to it.
I don't want him.
Don't change, Vera Bera.
You're the star
in my dark sky.
Don't you ever change.
What am I in your sky?
You're on my earth,
Caitlin,
just where I want you to be.
Come on.
Come and have a cuddle.
[laughing]
What are you laughing at?
What?
What is it?
[laughing continues]
Oh, no, no.
It's like living with children.
[laughing]
- Oh, God!
- I'm going to the pub.
What's it like having a son?
Oh, exhausting.
I can't imagine it.
He's a whole world
away from here...
safe and sound.
(William)
You could die in an air raid.
(Vera)
I'm not going to.
You might.
This is not how I would choose
to seduce someone.
My firm intention
is to live forever.
Is that a promise?
Cross my heart.
You only think
you're in love with the poet.
You know that,
don't you?
His name's Dylan.
You can say Dylan,
can't you?
So, you admit
you're in love with him?
What are you,
a bloody lawyer, are you?
I'm not saying
I'm the better man,
but I'm not married,
Vera.
And you'll admit
that gives me an advantage.
I'll admit nothing.
On the grounds
that it may incriminate you?
You're trying to provoke me,
aren't you?
First love's all right
as far as it goes.
Last love, that's what
I'm interested in.
Oh, you think you're
so damn wise.
[giggling]
What do you want, Vera?
Oh, the moon
from out of the skies,
the stars in all their glitter.
What else?
It makes you know you're alive,
wanting.
That's what I think.
Oh, I'm alive all right,
every last bit of me.
Oh, stay there.
Right, stay still.
All right.
Still.
I'm as good as he is.
Good as who is?
Dylan, the bugger.
He thinks that
I am put on this earth
to nurture his talent,
cook for him,
have his children,
clean for him.
That's all I'm here for.
Who's nurturing my bloody
talent?
What about your talent?
Will William nurture that?
I'll nurture my own.
Cut off his trigger finger,
that's what I'd do.
I would.
I'd come up
quietly in the night,
and I'd tie him down,
and I'd...
maim him.
Look at us.
How do they live up to us?
They don't, dirty tarts!
[sirens blaring]
[giggling]
[grunting]
My brother died
for the likes of you!
I didn't bloody ask him to,
did I?
Bleeding conchie,
lick my boot.
Lick my bleeding boot!
Welsh seamen,
you can smell them a mile off.
I ain't got no quarrel with you.
(William)
Damn right, you don't.
What are you protecting him for,
scum, he is?
Get back to your drinking.
Now.
Go on.
He's right, you know.
Contamination,
that's what I am.
I'd stay well clear.
No, no, no, I'm just gonna
stay down here a moment.
Just-just
a little moment.
You're lying in piss, Dylan.
I've had worse beds.
I wouldn't like to get
on the wrong side of you.
Well, see you don't, then.
You bloody warriors.
You're a bunch
of buggering yes men.
You don't even know
what you're fighting for.
To live without fear,
me and mine.
Ta.
[Dylan grunting]
Oh, God.
Terrified, I am, of not-
not doing.
War, see, it's useful.
It gives the terror a focus.
Is she in there?
Vera?
All you heroes,
you think the women
just fall at your feet
at the sight of you, don't you?
You think they don't?
Of course,
if I could be born again,
I'd have a word with God.
"Make me a hero," I'd say.
This way is far too much
bloody hard work.
Come on.
What, go on living?
I've a cure for funk.
Death, that's the only cure.
- Double?
- You offering?
(William)
♪ There was a young poet ♪
♪ called Dylan ♪
♪ Who swore that he never
would kill 'em ♪
♪ When called by his country
to serve at the front ♪
♪ He said he would
rather make... ♪
[together]
♪ Fillums ♪
(Dylan)
"Possessed by the skies
"and taken by light
in her arms
"at long and dear last,
"I may without fail
suffer the first vision
that set fire to the stars."
Touch her,
and I'll kill you.
Caitlin's territory,
is she?
Caitlin's friend.
[heavy breathing]
[cheerful piano music]
♪ ♪
♪ Hang out the stars
in Indiana ♪
♪ Up in the sky
of midnight blue ♪
♪ Hang out the stars
in Indiana ♪
♪ To light my way
back home to you ♪
Here.
I can buy my own drink.
Just take the bloody thing.
[muffled explosion]
♪ A melody just meant for two ♪
- Care to dance?
- I'd love to, thank you.
Don't worry, they won't get us
down here.
♪ How could I find in things
I sought for? ♪
♪ No wonder
they were all denied ♪
♪ The very happiness
I fought for ♪
- My round.
- Don't be childish.
Gin drinkers, are they,
the children you know?
Dance, come on.
I'm an independent woman.
I can buy a round if I want to.
And a fight?
You can have that too
if that's what you want.
All right, then.
After a dance.
♪ Hang out the stars
in Indiana ♪
♪ To light my way
back home to you ♪
I won't always
do as you say.
Thank you
for the warning.
I won't.
Just dance.
[laughs]
[explosion]
[glass shattering]
[man coughing]
[screaming]
[muffled explosion]
[coughing]
[screaming]
Come on, this way.
(man)
I need some help over here, now.
Vera!
Vera.
Vera, you can leave her now.
No, the pavement's wet.
No, she won't feel it.
Hmm?
Leave her now.
Come on.
It's all right.
All right.
♪ Have every robin
sing a love song ♪
♪ A melody
just made for two ♪
♪ For in my heart
there'll be a love song ♪
♪ A song I long
to sing to you ♪
I bet you lay this
on the ground.
Why would I do that?
For all the girls.
You won't get me on-
Those people, William.
Shh.
All those people.
You've got a raindrop
running down down your cheek,
just like a tear.
Make love to me.
No harm will ever
come to you.
Not from me.
Not from anyone else.
Not while I'm here.
No word of mine
will ever hurt you.
That sounds like a vow.
(Dylan)
"A stranger has come
"to share my room in the house.
"Not right in the head.
"A girl mad as birds,
"she has come possessed,
"who admits the delusive light
through the bouncing wall
"possessed by the skies.
"And taken by light in her arms,
at long and dear last,
"I may, without fail
suffer the first vision
that set fire to the stars."
(Caitlin)
I don't like it, Dylan.
I've another couple of lines
in my head
I'm not sure where to put.
It's not finished, then?
No, strictly speaking.
Don't write poems
for me anymore?
It's just a phase.
[crumpling paper]
Come here.
Bring that body back to me.
[knocks on door]
- Oh.
- Now.
Shh!
[clears throat]
It's a marriage license.
Special one.
No.
What?
You can't make me.
What if I can't love you?
I've been posted, Vera.
Well, that's a hell
of a proposal.
I...love...
you.
(Vera)
I am not marrying you.
No, you don't make
the decisions any more.
No.
- Now, say yes. Say yes.
- Uh-uh. No.
- Say, "I'll marry you."
- No.
Say it. Say yes.
Say yes. Yes!
Yes!
Say yes!
[together]
Yes!
- Say yes!
- Oh, for God's sake, say yes!
My first was Augustus John.
Seduced me when I was 15,
the old goat.
It doesn't mean anything,
fucking.
It's not love.
I get an itch,
it's got to be scratched.
I'd do it myself,
only I'm too lazy.
Why bother, when you can get
someone else
to do it for you?
Nothing to do with love,
fucking?
Uh-uh. Nothing.
Who was your first?
What?
You don't need to tell me.
I know it was Dylan.
We were kids.
Tents piled
in a beach hut.
Nice and comfy, then.
We were children,
still innocent.
We are still innocent,
me and Dylan.
I only want it as a memory.
I don't want it back.
Does William know?
Don't ever tell him.
I can forgive the past.
He won't.
The past I can forgive.
You warning me?
You love William,
don't you?
Well, you have to love someone.
These days you do.
You sure
you want to marry him?
I've never had
a best friend before.
Here.
See if I look like
a mermaid.
[laughs]
We've a couple
of cleaners
who'd be pleased
to act as witnesses.
They'll be here,
they will.
I'm sorry,
we've got
couples queuing up.
[loud coughing]
(Dylan)
Sorry!
About bloody time.
See?
Look.
Bend down, can't you?
Three guineas
that cost me.
How many words is that
for a couple of feathers
and a piece of cloth?
Where did you get
three guineas?
He wrote a check.
It'll bounce,
of course.
Oh, you look beautiful.
Tell her
she looks beautiful.
She is beautiful.
Come on,
let's get married.
Actually it was Dylan's idea.
He chose it.
You always did have hats.
Would you mind awfully?
I'm terribly sorry.
Purely for old times' sake.
Sorry, old chap.
Call of duty.
Carry on, Sergeant.
Oh, treat me right,
can't you?
Oh, no, no!
I want to give a toast.
I'm going to squeeze
the life out of you.
- Yes, after the toast.
- Go on!
You're killing me.
Oh, go on,
you great Welsh bastard,
or I'll break you in two!
To all the things
that really matter.
And bugger the ones that don't.
Hear, hear.
Can you please get down?
Sing, and I might.
- Oh, God.
- Sing, Dullun, sing.
♪ Myfanwy boed
yr holl o'th fywyd ♪
[together]
♪ Dan heulwen disglair ♪
♪ canol dydd ♪
♪ Boed i rosyn
gwridog iechyd ♪
♪ I ddawnsio ganmlwydd
ar dy rudd ♪
It's that old heiryth,
that old Welsh thing
they're always banging on about.
He hates the bloody place,
doesn't he?
Who doesn't?
But all he wants, see,
he wants back there.
She's no different.
Nope, you'll never
come between them,
not with them
being Welsh together.
Why should I
come between them?
'Course, you've always got me.
Perfect.
(William)
"For old times' sake,"
that's what he said.
No harm will ever come to you.
He'll always be my friend.
(William)
No word of mine
will ever hurt you.
I can still have friends.
You're crying.
Dreaming, that's all.
You're shaking.
It'll pass.
You'll come back to me.
I know you will.
Tell me the truth.
You're hurting me.
I want everything
to be open between us...
and fresh and clean.
Stop it.
You and your friend.
Tell me.
We were kids, William.
We were on a beach,
and it happened once.
That's all.
William.
Tell me you love me.
Come back alive
and I'll say it.
Come back to me,
I'll say anything you want.
And mean it?
Come back and see.
♪ Drifting and dreaming ♪
♪ While shadows fall ♪
♪ Softly at twilight ♪
♪ I hear you call ♪
♪ Love's old sweet story ♪
♪ Told with your eyes ♪
♪ Drifting and dreaming ♪
♪ Sweet paradise ♪
[speaking Greek]
Sergeant, get these men
off the aircraft now!
Everybody off the plane!
(William)
"Of course you told me
"because I asked.
"I should have bitten out
my tongue.
"You're all I love.
"You're all my need.
"You're what I see
in front of me.
"And if I look over
my shoulder, there...
"there, I can see your smile.
"All honor I would give up
for you.
"I could accept defeat
if you were by my side."
Vera.
[retching]
Do you want me to come
and hold your head?
Christ, no!
(Caitlin)
Now you'll get fat
and Dylan won't love you
anymore.
[chuckles]
You're a bitch.
It's the past
Dylan loves.
And you.
Doesn't love me at all.
When's William get back?
I keep writing.
No word.
Think he's dead?
We're still getting his pay.
Army wouldn't pay
a dead man.
You'll have
to stop singing.
I'll sing if I want.
They won't let you.
Not pregnant,
they won't.
Oh, I can't do this.
I can't.
A mother, me?
Look at me.
Well, get rid of it, then.
It's William's.
Ah.
You love him.
I hate him.
Oh, God,
I hate him so much.
Look what he's done to me.
Don't laugh.
Don't damn well laugh!
I can't do this alone.
I can't.
I'm here, aren't I?
Let's go home, Caitlin.
I don't have a home.
Wales, Caitlin.
Are you insane, woman?
I've got money.
What, William's pay?
I've savings.
Of course I have.
[screaming]
Hold him!
Bloody hold him!
[screaming]
You'll have
the whole town hearing you!
Shut your damn mouth!
You see this here?
Yes.
Give it here.
[screams]
Don't let go!
It's only a baby.
You scream if you want to, Vera.
You hear me?
[screaming]
(Vera)
"Please write to me.
[baby crying]
"They tell us what to write
to our boys,
"so we keep your morale up.
"It's our duty.
"Damn duty, I say.
"I'm no heroine, you see.
"I'm fed up to the back teeth
of being on my own.
"It's not
what I married you for.
"Come home.
"I've got something
I might want to say to you.
"Remember?
"You do remember, don't you?
"Come home.
"I want to touch you where
the rain fell on your skin.
"Damn you for making me
feel this way.
"Damn you to hell and back.
"And back, William.
And back."
[gunfire]
Down.
Down!
Man down!
Open fire!
No, sir.
[gunfire]
(Dylan)
"Forgive us your death
"that myselves the believers
"may hold it in a great flood
"till the blood shall spurt
"and the dust shall sing
like a bird.
"As the grains blow,
as your death grows,
"through our heart,
"crying, your dying.
"Cry.
"Child beyond cockcrow
by the fire-dwarfed street
"we chant the flying sea
in the body bereft."
Come on.
Sleep tight.
- I'm hungry.
- Shh.
Baby is sleeping.
It's bloody freezing.
Bloody Wales.
When I was little, my da always
used to warm me like this.
You loved him?
Adored him.
I hated mine.
You didn't hate him,
not hate.
He was loathsome.
Pity you're not a man.
If you were a man,
I'd fancy you.
[snickering]
Don't think I didn't
know you were there.
I didn't.
I could smell him.
Come here, Dylan.
Let Vera smell you,
smell the woman on you.
Stop it.
She thinks I should twiddle
my thumbs while she-
What?
Don't wake the kids, Dylan.
So where are they,
Caitlin, hmm?
Where are
your little friends?
Come on, boys,
out you come.
Feeding time.
Ow!
She's killing me, Vera!
I will kill you!
I will!
If I catch you at it again,
Why don't you see to the kids,
Caitlin?
Go on.
[children crying]
Why do you do it?
I don't do anything.
I do it,
sleep with other women...
- Hello.
- Morning.
Because I'm a poet,
and a poet feeds off life.
[chuckles]
What?
Pompous sod, aren't you?
I do it because she does it.
She always has.
She can't help herself.
It doesn't mean anything to her.
You don't need William.
You've got me.
Nothing but you and me
with time on our hands
and each other
to spend it with.
[door creaks open]
Hello, Daisy.
Come back with me.
Come on.
I'll take you back
to a time when we were safe,
where no bombs fell
from the sky,
and no one died,
ever.
You can't go back.
We can.
You and me.
It's not real.
It is if we want it to be.
Pity about
the poor bloody husband.
Off bleeding
for his country
and paying for the fun
back home.
Don't mind if I join you,
do you?
(woman)
Room for a small one?
Ooh, wartime luxury.
[shouting]
(woman)
You can drop me here.
[horn honking]
[screams]
- Cat?
- That looks nasty.
Catty, Catty.
Cat, Cat, Cat.
Cat, Catty.
God, you're drunk
in charge of a bike.
And what are you
drunk in charge of?
(man)
Am I hurting you?
(Dylan)
You can't hurt her.
She's got skin like
a rhinoceros hide.
We're only friends,
Dylan and me,
you know that,
don't you?
Don't ever lie to me.
I won't. Not ever.
Friends don't lie
to each other.
Still as you can now.
Tell him to come back, Rowatt.
Tell your daddy
to come back to me.
Think he sees it, lovely?
Your daddy?
You think he sees the rain?
Hmm?
(boy)
Mama, Dada.
(Dylan)
Caitlin, shut it up!
You're its father!
Play with him!
That's what he wants.
I'm writing!
Damn it, Dylan.
Daddy! Mummy!
That's my only-
Dada.
That's my only draft!
You'll find it
in the cesspit, then,
along with my only life!
Cat! Cat!
Cat!
(Dylan)
When I was a windy boy and a bit
and the black spit
of the chapel fold,
sighed the old ram rod
dying of women,
I tiptoed shy
in the gooseberry wood.
The rude owl cried
like a telltale tit.
I skipped in a blush
as the big girls rolled
ninepin down
on the donkeys' common.
And on seesaw Sunday nights
I wooed
whoever I would
with my wicked eyes.
The whole of the moon
I could love and leave...
For God's sake,
don't wake Rowatt.
[whispering]
All the green-leaved
little weddings' wives
in the coal black bush
and let them grieve.
Wash my back for me?
There is nothing
like a proper sponge.
Give us a kiss,
Vera Phillips.
Give us a penny,
then.
I haven't got a penny.
Like we used to be.
Little dog says,
"Play with me."
That's all you'll get.
And don't you wet
my jumper.
We've had baths together before.
We were children then.
I made love to you
on a beach.
Once, and it was cold.
So lonely.
Not for you.
Aching with it,
you are.
No, Dylan.
No what?
Don't make mischief.
There's no harm in it.
You're getting me wet.
Walk away, then.
Go on, Vera Phillips.
Hmm? Walk away.
You want us all to love you.
So I can love you back.
All right, then.
Love me.
[screaming]
Look at me.
I'm soaking!
Shh!
Vera!
Hello.
(Caitlin)
Where have you been?
Nowhere.
I'm going to make laver bread.
Look.
No, don't.
Have you been crying?
They're sending William home.
I've never seen a man
love anyone
the way I saw
that man love you.
I'm not that me anymore.
I've got Rowatt.
Just tell him you love him,
Vera.
What if it's too late?
It's never too late.
It's cold! It's cold!
Of course it's bloody cold!
Catty!
I'm pregnant, you know.
Oh, God, Cat.
Whose is it?
Don't know.
Can't have it,
of course.
I won't have it.
I need money, Vera.
Do you know someone?
He costs.
Is he safe?
Just say if you can't help.
I'll do it myself.
Maybe Wilfred knows how,
he's a vet.
What did you bother
with him for?
He's no bother.
Come on,
we'll go to the bank.
I'd tell you you'd get it back,
but you wouldn't believe me.
Treats. Come on.
(Vera)
It's like I only
half remember him.
(Caitlin)
Dark.
Good-looking.
Dangerous.
Can't live on memories,
though, can you?
There's only
so many of them.
Use yourself up
living on memories.
It'd be a better place,
a world without men.
Possibly.
Dylan, see,
sex for him's a giggle.
He makes a joke of it,
whoever it's with.
Bet William's romantic.
I can't remember.
I think Daddy is very lucky.
Hmm.
Oh, God, look, Rowatt.
Who's that funny woman?
Who is she?
[baby crying]
(Vera)
William.
It's me.
I know.
Well, then.
[clears throat]
Can't you put him down?
He'll only cry.
What's that?
(Vera)
It's a collage...
for you.
Hold me, William.
I should deal with the post.
Let them wait.
(Dylan)
In my craft or sullen art
exercised in the still night
when only the moon rages
and the lovers lie abed...
(Vera)
William?
(Dylan)
With all their griefs
in their arms,
I labor by singing light,
not for ambition nor bread
or the strut and trade of charms
on the ivory stages,
but for the common wages
of their most secret heart.
You all right?
Are you?
I will be.
Will you?
I don't know where he is.
Give him time.
He's changed.
So have you.
He doesn't love me anymore.
Everybody loves you.
And Dylan,
everybody loves him.
Oh, God!
Oh, Catty.
Does it hurt?
I didn't think
it would mean anything.
'Course, it's a relief.
I'll stop.
In a minute, I will.
There, see?
Happy Caitlin.
[man on record]
♪ Whistling a tune ♪
♪ all the live long day ♪
♪ If you want
to know just why ♪
♪ I can truthfully say ♪
♪ I've got a feeling
about her ♪
♪ It was something
she said ♪
♪ She's got me walking
on the tips of my toes ♪
♪ My hat's on the side
of my head ♪
Let's throw that.
♪ All my troubles
are mended ♪
♪ She's my needle
and thread ♪
♪ 'Cause she's got me walking
on the tips of my toes and ♪
[record scratches]
Sorry, I-
I'm sorry.
I can't remember when I last-
♪ I've got a feeling
I've found her ♪
♪ It was something
she said ♪
Shall we have some tea?
♪ And my hat's on the side
of my head ♪
♪ All my troubles
are mended ♪
♪ She's my needle
and thread ♪
♪ 'Cause she's got me walking
on the tips of my toes ♪
♪ And my hat's on the side
of my head ♪
[baby crying]
♪ Funny thing
what love can do ♪
♪ Take a little look at me ♪
(Dylan)
All you heroes,
you think the women
just fall at your feet.
(Vera)
He'll always be my friend,
Dylan.
It's a fox.
It's a fox, that's all.
What's wrong, William?
Talk to me.
Please.
[baby crying]
♪ Bye baby bunting ♪
♪ Daddy's gone a-hunting ♪
♪ Gone to get a rabbit skin ♪
♪ To wrap his baby bunting in ♪
[Vera humming]
♪ ♪
What did you want me for?
Was it the money?
Was that it?
Was that all?
Don't-don't wake Rowatt.
My money to keep your tame poet.
Oh, I had better offers,
richer offers.
You?
Have you looked at yourself?
They're my friends.
I bought them food.
- You have to feed people.
- I've nothing left.
You've got Rowatt!
At least look at him, William!
Why can't you hold him?
Is he Dylan's?
That's what they're saying
out there, Vera.
"He's Dylan's child."
I love you.
When did that happen?
I said come back
and I'd say it.
I said!
You've been with him.
Haven't you?
[baby crying]
Hey.
What do they want, blood?
A finished script.
For God's sake, man,
you've been paid for it!
(Dylan)
Yes, but not enough.
Be that as it may-
It's like doing
my homework.
It's not even broken down
into scenes yet, Dylan.
That's because I'm not
a secretary, Anita!
Well, I'm not
a bloody writer!
I'm looking for Dylan Thomas.
On the house,
Captain Killick.
Ah, yes, the returning hero.
There'll be another
when you've finished.
The least we can do.
Where is he?
There it is.
Waiting for you, see?
(Anita)
It's the specter of communism.
That's what frightens them,
the Allies.
Two pints of bitter
and a gin and tonic.
Make mine brains.
(Anita)
Greece. Now, Greece.
It's the communist partisans
that risk their lives
to fight the Germans,
not the British Tommy.
What they're aiming for,
secretly, the Allies,
is for the Germans
to wipe out the partisans,
wipe out the communists,
so they won't have
to deal with them
after the war.
You listen to me.
I held a boy while my sergeant
hacked his arm off.
Later I held him
while he died.
British boy, he was.
That was in Greece.
I beg your pardon?
We fight...
out there...
so you and your friends can-
can sit around in Hampstead
and theorize.
You do that
while we bleed
our lives away.
What do you know about war?
You people,
what do you know about war, hmm?
Drink up, boys and girls,
drink up.
Introduce me to your
knowledgeable friends, Dylan.
Please, introduce me.
I'd be charmed
to meet them.
I'll introduce you
just as soon as you calm down.
Oh, you can take my money.
Hmm?
You can take my bloody money,
but you can't even introduce me
to your friends?
Ha! I'm just a bloody Tommy.
[bell rings]
Time, gentlemen!
Gentlemen, please.
It's time.
- Whisky, double.
- Time's called.
Are you refusing to serve me?
- I said time's called.
- What do you mean, time?
Go home, Captain Killick.
No, don't you laugh at me.
Oh, play the big man.
Come on.
Easy in front of a woman,
isn't it?
We only have
your word for it
that you weren't
skulking at the back
with urine
running down your leg.
William, come on.
Don't bother with them,
Captain Killick.
Best off home.
[laughter]
William?
What in heaven's name?
Take your hands off me.
- Put it down!
- Please, take your hands off.
Put the damn thing down!
Vera!
Vera?
Give me words,
and I'm a giant.
Above all women.
Hmm? Words.
Beyond the bottle.
More than love.
Better than sex.
Words...
for me.
Hmm?
(Dylan)
Shall I tell you about
our first night together
at the Wheatsheaf?
She offered her honor,
so I honored her offer.
All that long,
I've got her on offer.
[laughter]
Very easily entertained,
this one.
Thinks a pint of Guinness
with a potato in it
is a cocktail.
Don't you, my darling?
[gun cocks]
[gunshot]
(Vera)
William, no!
No! No!
[gunshots]
No!
No! No! No!
[gunshot]
William, no, stop, please.
Please stop!
[child crying]
No one here means you any harm.
Please.
Don't you care?
Your husband and my wife.
My son.
You've got a bruise.
Take me home.
Did I do that?
[child crying]
Take her home, William.
Not without my gun.
Give me the gun...
or I'll pull the pin on this
and kill the lot of us.
My son.
What'd you give it to her for,
you daft sod?
(man)
There isn't a pin in it,
William.
Either it's faulty or...
it's just gone off,
and we're standing here dead,
looking at it.
[child crying]
(boy)
Mommy!
[crying continues]
Look, the boy's screaming.
Come home, William.
William.
(Dylan)
All they care about is
keeping the lid on it, but...
that's Wales for you.
Doesn't want the world
knowing its business.
I mean,
we could have been killed.
Cat.
I haven't got any more money.
I've nothing left, Dylan.
Got your toe.
Can I...
Hold him, then.
See?
You won't hurt him.
Thank you.
Shall we take him out?
Now.
You're an expert.
Eyelashes like feathers,
like yours.
[knocks on door]
Captain Killick,
it's the police.
Open up.
Oh, God.
One way
to get rid of me, eh?
William.
I love you.
Come here.
(Caitlin)
Don't think I don't understand.
His kind of violence, I mean.
I do.
It's just I've never had
a Sten gun handy.
Tea's got scum on it.
He's a beauty.
Does William think he's Dylan's?
Is he Dylan's?
No.
I've used up all the sugar.
Were you sleeping with him?
I love my husband.
I should kill you.
You're my friend.
For lying...
I mean.
For lying to me, Vera.
You look smart.
Quite your old self.
(man)
I recovered
five empty bullet cases from the gravel.
The walls being made
of wood and asbestos,
the bullets had penetrated
through to the living room,
where I also found
five more
empty bullet cases.
All with him,
aren't they?
The whole bloody village.
I'm the bard, aren't I?
They've only just met him.
Shh.
(man)
A revolver, a grenade,
and 100 rounds
of 9-millimeter ammunition.
(man)
Used to lay minefields,
Captain Killick.
When he left an area, though,
he used to dig up
the mines he'd laid.
(Dylan)
Why don't you take
the witness box
and sing Killick's praises
to his judgeship?
Why don't you do that?
Everybody loves a hero.
(man)
Are you telling me
Captain Killick didn't know
he had to hand in
his weapons?
(man)
Captain William Killick
is an expert marksman.
If he'd been intent on murder,
he couldn't possibly
have failed.
'd be obliged
if you confine yourself
to answering
the questions I ask,
Lieutenant Colonel.
(Dylan)
Scratch my head, Cat.
Can't.
(man)
Is there any reason
why a man of your rank
should strike a woman
in the face?
No, sir.
Why did you go to the Thomas
bungalow so late at night?
I have no idea why.
They cut me dead.
I suppose
they didn't want to see
the goose that lay
the golden egg.
I thought I'd show them
that war is real.
I could see there was
no one in my line of fire,
so I fired at a partition.
I never imagined the bullets
would penetrate the wall.
The walls were asbestos,
Captain Killick.
I didn't know that.
I wanted to frighten them, that's all.
There was a child present.
Is-is that a question, sir?
I can't live without him.
Did you know
the entire unit were killed
when they
went back out there?
Wiped out.
That would have been him.
I'm begging you
to help him.
It saved his life,
this trial.
Did him a favor.
Dylan...
please.
You were the star in my sky.
You can't stay the same
all your life.
I can.
You'll help him, won't you?
It means that much to you?
William's my world,
him and Rowatt.
I've no room
for anyone else.
I don't want anyone else.
I see.
I do, I see.
(man)
Mr. Thomas?
Captain Killick and I
were no more than acquaintances.
We would occasionally stand
next to each other at the bar.
Captain Killick
was stone-cold sober
on the night of the shooting,
and it is my firm belief
that he tried to kill me,
that he tried to kill my wife,
and that he tried
to kill my son.
(Vera)
Why?
You.
Leave Caitlin.
Go on.
You've got rid
of the opposition.
Now you come on.
Leave your wife
and live with me.
Do you see?
You want a 15-year-old girl
back on the beach,
not me.
You don't even see me,
do you, Dylan?
All you've got
is stories in your head, words.
And I have to be real.
William makes me real.
If you have sent
my beloved husband to jail...
I will never forgive you.
It is my opinion
that it is not
an innocent hand
that wields a gun
against a civilian household.
It is, however,
your peers who judge you,
Captain Killick,
and not I.
They have found
that there is no evidence
to support the charge
of attempted murder.
I have, therefore,
no choice
but to pronounce you free to go.
[voices overlapping]
[laughter]
There's that smile.
I never meant to hurt you.
Might as well, I suppose.
Smile, I mean.
Write, Catty.
I'll leave that to Dylan.
Write to me.
Don't be lonely.
Don't you, Catty.
Don't you.
(Dylan)
Not for the proud man apart
from the raging moon I write
on these spindrift pages,
nor for the towering dead
with their nightingales
and psalms,
but for the lovers,
their arms round
the griefs of the ages.
[romantic jazz music]
♪ ♪
(woman)
♪ Was it a marriage ♪
♪ made in heaven? ♪
♪ Was it a gift
from God above? ♪
♪ Do you believe
the things you told me? ♪
♪ Or was it simply
careless love? ♪
♪ You told me once
when we were dreaming ♪
♪ Through life together
we would walk ♪
♪ Those words of love
seemed set in starlight ♪
♪ But now it seems
like careless talk ♪
♪ All your lies
are jolly melancholy ♪
♪ Your eyes were always
slightly sad ♪
♪ But now you're always
saying sorry ♪
♪ We've lost the good times
that we had ♪
♪ Over all this careless talk
of love ♪
♪ This careless talk ♪
♪ Over all
this careless talk ♪
♪ This careless ♪
♪ Talk ♪
[dramatic cabaret music]
♪ ♪
(woman)
♪ The four of us ♪
♪ oh, yes, alone again ♪
♪ Our curtains drawn
into the setting sun ♪
♪ Beautiful children
that pretend to play ♪
♪ Pretending it's such fun ♪
♪ Playing with fire
with you and with life ♪
♪ Only good men
dying young ♪
♪ Soldiers and sailors
and planes up above ♪
♪ All careless talk
and careless love ♪
♪ You called it love,
I called it lies ♪
♪ You stole my dreams
but no one ever cries ♪
♪ Oh, ho-ho! ♪
♪ Playing with fire
with you and with life ♪
♪ Only good men
dying young ♪
♪ Soldiers and sailors
and planes up above ♪
♪ All careless talk
and careless love ♪
♪ You called it love,
I called it lies ♪
♪ You stole my dreams
but no one ever cries ♪
♪ Just dies,
just dies ♪
♪ Just dies ♪