[ Boy ]
Jud.
[ Jud ]
What?
[ Boy ]
Tha'd better get up.
The alarm's gone off, tha knows.
[ Jud ]
You think I don't know?
- Jud.
- What?
- Tha'll be late!
- Shut it.
- Clock's not fast.
- I said shut it.
Get out! That hurts!
- Well, shut it then.
- I'll tell me mum on thee.
[ Jud ]
Shut your stinkin' hole.
Christ.
- Set clock on for me. For 7:00.
- [ Jud ] Set it yourself.
Go on. Tha are up.
Hands off cocks, on socks.
You rotten sod!
Just because you have to get up!
Another few weeks, lad,
tha'll be getting up with me.
- I'll not.
- Won't tha?
- No, 'cause I'm not gonna work down pit.
- Where's ya gonna work then?
I don't know,
but I'm not gonna work down pit.
No.
And have I to tell thee why?
For one thing, tha's to be able to read
and write before they set thee on.
And for another, they won't trouble
with a little twat like thee.
- Switch the light out then.
- Switch it out yourself.
Me billicking bike!
- [ Man ] I thought you weren't coming.
- Why? I'm not late, am I?
Very near.
- I nearly was though.
- What do you mean?
Our Jud, he's taken the bike.
- What you gonna do then?
- Walk it.
Walk it? How long do you
think that's gonna take?
- It'll not take me long.
- Hey.
There's a waiting list a mile long
for that job of yours.
Good lads, too, most of 'em.
From up Firs Hill, round there.
I haven't let you down, have I?
- Ah, morning. Morning.
- [ Man ] Morning, sir.
Not very promising again.
A bit on the nippy side
as well this morning.
- Aye.
- 20 Players tipped, please.
Oh, right.
I've not got 20.
Will two 10's do?
Yes. That'll be quite
all right, thank you.
- Ah, thank you.
- Right.
- Cheerio.
- Cheerio. Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
You know what they
said when I took you on?
What?
They said, "You'll have to keep
your eyes open now, you know.
They're all alike in that
state up there. He'll
take your breath if
you're not careful".
I haven't taken nowt
of yours yet, have I?
Well, I haven't given
you a chance, that's why.
You don't have to.
I - I haven't been nicking for ages now.
Well, come on then. Don't
stand about all day.
I'm goin'.
- Hey up, young 'un! How thee goin' on?
- Not so bad.
You want to get one of these.
This is better than walkin'.
Ah, only just.
I could go faster on a kid's scooter.
- Well, tha knows what I always say.
- What?
Third-class ridin's
better than first-class walkin' any day.
You call that third-class ridin'?
In that ramshack?
What you mean, ramshack?
This is one of best models the dairy's got.
Cheeky young 'un.
See thee tomorrow.
- Can only go 20 mile an hour, as it is.
- Yeah? Got too much rattle, thee.
[ Boy's Voice ] "Desperate Dan is stronger
than all, but this opponent makes him fall.
Right!
Where do you want to fight?
Right here! Skid. Down I go again!
What's making me fall?
Now's my chance to jump on his chest!
Thud!
You won't catch me out
this time, you braggart!
A sock in the midriff
will settle your game! Splash!
What's this on my face?
Why, it's grease!
Give me that tube back!
That's how he kept making me slip! He was
squirting invisible grease under my feet!
You dirty twister!
It's time somebody taught you a lesson!
Take that! Crash!
Where did he end up?
In the middle of next week, Uncle Dan!"
- Evenin'.
- I told you it wouldn't take me long.
What did you do? Throw half of 'em
over the gates or something?
No need to.
I know some shortcuts on the way back.
I'll bet you do.
Over other folks' property.
How many times do you want tellin'
where to put that bag?
- Time is it?
- Time you were at school.
Is it that late?
I wouldn't be your teacher
for all the coal in Barnsley.
Oh, Mr. Porter!
- Watch it, Mr. Porter.
- You clumsy young bugger!
What you tryin' to do? Kill me?
[ Boy ]
I lost me balance.
I wouldn't put it past you either.
I fair felt me heart go then.
Just sit down here
and relax a couple of minutes.
Are you ail right now?
I'm bloody champion.
I'll be off then.
And don't be late tonight.
- Allot?
- Sir.
- Bowser?
- Bridges?
- Absent, sir.
- Absent. Bridges. Casper?
- Sir.
- Clegg?
- Fisher?
- German Bight.
- [ Teacher ] Did you say something?
- Yes, sir. I didn't mean -
Stand up, lad.
- What did you say?
- German Bight, sir.
He's daft, sir.
- [ Boy ] He's right, sir.
- Is this your ridiculous idea of a joke?
- No, sir.
- Well, what is the idea then?
Well, when you said "Fisher," sir -
- Well, what about it?
- Just came out. Fisher. German Bight.
It's the shipping forecast, sir.
Fisher. German Bight. Cromarty.
I like to hear it every night, sir.
- I like names.
- Huh.
And so you thought you'd
enlighten me and the
rest of the class with
your idiotic information?
No, sir.
Blurting out and making
a mess of my register.
- It just came out, sir.
- And so did you, Casper.
Just come out from under a stone.
[ Teacher ]
I said, quiet!
Is anyone else absent besides
Bridges and Fisher?
Any girls?
Right. Now, then, it's time
we're off to assembly.
One row at a time.
This one, stand.
Move forward.
Pamela, you're talking.
Cut it out.
Hey up, Billy.
What's that mean, Germans bite?
- Oh, shut your mouth.
- I'm sick of hearin' about "Germans bite".
- Are you comin' nestin' tomorrow?
- Yeah, I'll come.
- What time?
- About 6:00.
Don't be late.
- Thou coming, Guth?
- Where?
Nestin'.
- When?
- Tomorrow.
- What time?
- About 6:00.
- Can't.
- Why?
- Takin' girlfriend to Sheffield.
- Excuses!
[ Boy ]
Oh, they're not goin' at 6:00 after all!
What the bloody hell do you want
at this time in the morning?
- Get your Mac up.
- Hey, he's fast asleep.
I can't get him up at this time.
- Go get him up for me.
- His father, he'll be down to ya!
I'm not bothered about his father.
I want your MacDowell.
- Bugger off, you little sod!
- Get him up, see ya!
I'm not gettin' him up.
It's too early for him.
- He said I had to get him up.
- He's fast asleep and he's not goin'.
So just get off with ya.
- Now, then. What's tha doin'?
- Nowt.
Well, bugger off then.
Don't you know it's private property?
- Can I get up to that kestrel's nest?
- What kestrel's nest?
Up wall.
There's no nest up
there, so off tha goes.
There is.
I've seen 'em come out.
What will tha do when tha gets up there?
Take all its eggs?
There ain't any eggs.
There are young 'uns.
Well, there's nowt to
go up for then, is there?
Can I come to the bottom then?
Never seen a kestrel's nest before.
Come on then.
- There it is.
- Aye.
- That big hole.
- It's nested there for donkeys' years now.
- Just think. And I never knew.
- No, there's not many that does.
Been watching from the wood there.
Goes onto post, then hovers...
then swoops down onto it prey,
carries it off to it young 'uns.
Looks great.
I've been gonna knock that wall down
for ages now.
- What for?
- Well, it's dangerous.
I won't even let her play near.
If I lived round here,
I'd get a young 'un and train it.
- Would ya?
- You can train 'em.
Do you know how?
Do you know?
No. There's not many that does.
They're hard to train. If they're
not kept properly, it's criminal.
- Do you know anybody who's kept 'em?
- One or two.
But, uh, they had to let 'em go
because they're hard to train.
Where can I find out about 'em then?
Well, uh, probably at public library.
They'll have some books on 'em.
- Where's that?
- Down at city.
Hey. Are you a member?
- What do you mean?
- Are you a member of the library?
I don't know about that.
I only want a book on falconry, that's all.
Well, you have to be a member
to take a book out.
- But I only want one.
- Have you filled one of these forms in?
- No.
- You're not a member then.
You'll have to take one of these home first
for your father to sign.
Me dad's away.
You can wait till he comes
back home, can't you?
I don't mean that.
I mean he's left home.
Oh, I see. Well, in that case
your mother'll have to sign it for you.
Yeah, but she's at
work and she'll not be
home till teatime, and
it's Sunday tomorrow.
- There's no rush, is there?
- I've never broke a book, you know.
I haven't tore it or...
- Look at your hands.
They're absolutely filthy.
- We'll end up with dirty books that way.
- I don't ready dirty books.
I should hope you don't read dirty books.
You're not old enough to read dirty books.
Me mum knows one of the people
who works here. That'll help, won't it?
No, that doesn't help at all.
You still have to have the back signed.
To be a member, you'll have to
have somebody over 21...
who is on the borough electoral roll
to sign it for you.
- Yeah, well, I'm over 21.
- You're not over 21.
Yeah, but I vote.
You don't vote. You're
not old enough to vote.
I vote for me mum. She don't
like voting, so I do it.
Just have to wait for it, won't you?
Where would I find a - a book then?
In a shop, or -
Go down the street.
There's a secondhand
bookshop there. You'll
find some down there.
- [ Woman ] Good afternoon. Can I help you?
- [ Man ] Yes.
I'm rather interested
in Noel Coward's autobiography...
uh, Present Indicative.
[ Woman ]
Um -
[ Man ]
No, I believe it's a complete book.
[ Conversation Continues, Faint ]
- What tha got this for? Tha can't read.
- Give us it here!
- Come here!
- Get off!
Falconry? What's tha
want to know about falconry?
Give it here!
"Falconer's Handbook".
Where'd ya get this from?
- I've lent it.
- Nicked it, more like.
- Where'd ya get it from?
- A shop in town.
Tha must be crackers. I could understand
if it were money, but chuff me, not a book!
Have it!
Look what thou have done.
I'm lookin' after this book!
And what better off will ya be
when thou's got it?
A lot. I'm gonna get a
kestrel and train it.
Train it?
Thou couldn't train a flea.
Anyway, where's ya
gonna get a kestrel from?
- I know a nest.
- Thou doesn't!
- Ail right, then I don't.
- Where?
- I'm not tellin'.
- I says where?
- Ow! Thou hurting me arm!
- Where then?
Monastery Farm.
Thou could have broke me arm then.
Have to see about goin' round there
with t' old gun.
If thou does, I'll tell t' farmer on thee.
- Why? What's he got to do with it?
- He protects 'em.
Protects 'em?
Hawks are a menace to farmers.
They eat all the poultry and that.
Yeah, I know.
They dive down at cows and take 'em away.
- Funny bugger.
- Well, thou talks daft.
They're only small.
They eat mice, insects
and little birds sometimes.
I hope I'll be watchin' a bird tonight.
She'll not have feathers though.
Not all over, any road.
- Have you had any tea yet, Billy?
- No.
Well, get some then.
You know where t' pantry is.
- How's your horses gone on, Jud?
- Not bad.
- Two winners.
- You haven't, have ya?
- Yeah.
- Might be getting tret tonight then.
- Oh, somebody treats you every night.
- Oh, shut it.
And don't you be comin' home
blind drunk again either, Jud.
Why? Are you entertainin'?
You kiddin'?
If I entertained as much as you,
I should do all right, shan't I?
What tripe you've been
goin' out with lately. My God.
Better than that cripple
you bring home, isn't?
- What cripple? Reg? He's not a cripple.
- Will be if he comes in here tonight.
At least them I go out with
are not tightfisted, that's all.
- Who is?
- Your man!
You want to talk! You chuck your bloody
money around like a Scotchman with no arms!
You have to use a spanner to get a
threepenny bit out of his hand, that's why.
Aye, because he's comin' wise
to you, isn't he?
Ooh. Listen, what about
him you're goin' with?
He's tight as a camel's
arse in a sandstorm.
You just keep your hand
over your mouth talkin'
about him, 'cause you'll
get into trouble.
- You're not too big to have a good hiding.
- He can't do it.
- Who can't?
- He can't!
You might find that he's bigger
than what you think.
More chance of gettin' struck
by lightnin' than him hittin' me.
Shut your face.
I'm fed up of it.
It's every bloomin' Saturday night
I get ready to go out, you're at me.
- I always go out in a mess and all upset.
- Yeah, I know!
Gettin' too big for your
boots, comin' in and
out here, thinking you
own the damned house.
You don't own it yet, you know.
No. I will do one day though,
won't I?
Over my dead body.
That's what I says. I'll
own it one day, won't I?
- I'm sick on it, Jud. I am. Pig sick.
- And I'm sick of you!
I go out to work every
day, and every Saturday
night I go out for a
drink and you upset me.
- I don't think I'll go. I'm that fed up.
- Well, don't bother. I'll not miss you.
You'll not bloody miss nowt.
You'll be out there, won't ya?
- Yeah.
- Aye.
Aye, what a smart-lookin' kid
in t' mirror.
Some bird's gonna be lucky tonight.
[ Mother ]
Listen to God's gift to woman.
Fancy buying me
a brandy and pep tonight?
Aye. I hope it keeps fine for ya.
These could have done with
a bit of a polish. [ Spits ]
Oh, still, never mind.
It's gonna be dark soon.
What you gonna do
with yourself tonight, love?
[ Billy ]
Read me book.
Oh, God, look at the time. Five to 7:00.
I'm gonna be late again.
Listen, Billy, there's two bob here.
Chuck?
I want you to get yourself
some pop and some crisps. D'ya hear?
[ Billy ]
Yeah.
And don't still be up
when I come in, will ya.
No.
[ Mother ] Good night then.
♪ I came home unexpectedly ♪
♪ And caught her crying needlessly ♪
♪ In the middle of the day ♪
♪ And that was in the early spring ♪
♪ When flowers bloom and robins sing ♪
♪ She went away ♪
- ♪ And honey, I miss you ♪
- How are you, darling?
Ail right, thanks.
♪ And I'm bein' good ♪
- He brought you up here?
- Yeah.
♪ And I'd love to be with you ♪
♪ If only I ♪
♪ Could ♪♪
- [ Man ] Give me a chance!
- Thank you.
I'd like to carry on
with a Tremeloes number.
- ♪♪
You can have a good time up to a point.
But there comes a time
when you want to settle down.
Oh, I...
- I'm gettin' a bit fed up
of workin' all t' time.
There's plenty of time to
settle down, isn't there?
Depends what you're
lookin' for, don't it?
I just like to come home, get me meal,
get a bath, change and out, me.
Not a care in t' world.
You see, when you've been married once
and you marry a wrong 'un...
it makes you a bit apprehensive
to-towards gettin' -
- [ Woman ] Oh, yeah.
- Well, you know, don't ya?
'Cause he were never good.
But it makes you a bit more wary
about gettin' married again.
If she wants to go with a different bloke,
it's not up to me to tell her what to do.
She's old enough
to know her own mind, isn't she?
- Well, yeah, I mean -
- [ Man ] No hurry to settle down.
[ Mother ] You can never tell, really.
I sit and wonder sometimes what he will do.
Perhaps if he had have been brought up
in a different environment...
and had a better education...
he would have made more
than what he has.
At the moment, he's just, uh -
h-h-he's hopeless.
He's a hopeless case, isn't he?
♪ Oh, won't you please come back ♪
♪ Oh, won't you please
come back ♪
I'm happy as I am. I doubt if I
could be any happier, you know.
My lads have got nowt.
I don't know what they're gonna do.
I mean, I don't know whether our Jud
really wanted to be a miner, do I?
From my point of view, Reg,
when a woman gets to my age...
you've two kids, you want to be
settlin' down wi' a nice house...
and somebody to - to come home to ya
and be lookin' after 'em.
- Like I look after you.
- Well, Ar.
But you're not married to me,
are ya?
- Never mind. Give us a kiss.
- Don't be so damned daft!
- Give us a kiss. Come on.
- He's had too much ale again.
- I haven't. I haven't.
- Yes, you have.
Say, Mom, have you brought
that cripple wi' ya?
- Keep it shut. Keep it shut.
- He's had a couple of drinks.
Keep it shut, all right?
Say, did everybody hear about him
when he got married?
He got confetti on elastic.
That's how tightfisted he is.
[ Mother ] Leave him be, the cluck.
If he wants trouble,
I'll give him trouble.
♪ Oh, along the road there lives a guy ♪
♪ I'd like you ail to know ♪
♪ He grew a great big marrow
for the little flower show ♪
♪ He showed it to a lady ♪
♪ Who lived just along the way ♪
♪ And when she saw the size of it ♪
♪ He heard the lady say ♪
Ooh!
♪ What a beauty ♪
♪ Oh, I've never seen one
as big as that before ♪
Ooh!
What a whopper!
♪ It must be 18 inches long or more ♪
♪ It's such a lovely color ♪
♪ It's nice and round and fat ♪
♪ Whoever thought a marrow ♪
♪ Could grow as big as that ♪
Ooh!
♪ Oh, what a beauty ♪
♪ I've never seen one
as big as it before ♪♪
Bleedin' lock.
Billy, are tha asleep?
Cussed trousers.
The bleeding things.
Now! Billy!
- Give over.
- Billy!
Help me get
these bleeding trousers off.
Come on!
Don't be all bleeding night.
[ Billy ]
I'm fed up with this bloody game.
- [ Jud Grunts ]
- It's every Saturday night alike.
Don't help, will tha?
Get back to sleep, you...
pig.
Hog. Sow.
Ya drunken bastard.
Tha don't like bein' called
a bastard, does tha? Ya bastard!
Ya pig.
Pig.
Hog. Sow.
Drunken... bastard.
Bastard. Bastard.
Drunken pig.
Pig.
Billy!
Billy! Billy!
[ Billy's Voice ] Three good meals a day
I'll give him for about a fortnight.
If a piece of meat held between the finger
and thumb of the gloved hand...
is offered to the hawk...
it will probably bend down
and pull at the meat with its beak.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
[ Billy's Voice ] As soon as the hawk
will come a leash length indoors...
she may be tried off a fence
or gatepost out of doors.
It is quite likely
that although she was
coming to the first -
fist promptly indoors...
she will now refuse to come at all.
She will stand looking
fearfully around her...
and ignoring the meat
and the fist thrust in front of her.
When she will come a leash length
out of doors...
she can be called greater distances
by means of creance...
a long cord which is attached
to the hawk to prevent her escaping.
With luck, she will not
attempt to fly away.
Come on then.
Kes!
Come on, lass.
Come on, Kes!
Come on then.
Come on, Kes.
Come on, get ready!
What are you playing at?
Get ready now, you.
Skiving again, Guthrie?
No, sir. Mr. Farthing, sir,
has been talking to me.
I'll bet that was stimulating
for him, wasn't it, lad?
- What does that mean, sir?
- The conversation, lad.
What do you think it means?
Does it mean "stimulate," sir?
Stimulating, you fool!
"S-T-I-M-I-L-A-T-I-N-G."
Stimulating.
Come on, lad, get ready.
You're two weeks late already.
You three, get down
before I come and put ya down.
Casper, what do you think you're doing?
Get down there! Why aren't you changed?
I've no kit, sir.
Casper, you make me sick.
Every lesson it's the same old story -
"Please, sir, I've no kit, sir."
Every lesson for the past four years...
you've begged and borrowed
and skived and scrounged.
Why is it, Casper, when ail this lot
can provide kit, you can't?
Don't know, sir. Me mum says it's a waste
of money, especially now I'm leavin'.
You been leaving for the past four years,
haven't you, lad?
No, sir.
You can buy some
with your spending money, can't you?
- Don't like football, sir.
- What's that got to do with it, Casper?
Don't know.
Anyway, I don't get enough.
Get a job then, lad.
Get a job.
- I've got one, sir.
- They pay you, don't they, Casper?
Yeah, but I have to give it to me mum. I'm
payin' me fines, installments every week.
You should keep out of trouble, lad!
Keep out of trouble.
I ain't been in trouble, sir,
not since last time.
I'll get you some kit, Casper.
I'll get you some kit.
- Tha's had it now, Casper, lad!
- [ Billy ] Aw, shut thee mouth!
Right, Casper.
Get into those.
- They'll not fit me, sir!
- You can get into them, can't you?
- Yes, sir.
- Right. I figured that.
They'll keep your cobblers warm, Casper.
[ Coach ] Don't forget to take
your vest and underpants off.
- Don't wear 'em, sir.
- [ Coach ] Typical.
[ Boy ] Casper, tuck 'em in!
Thee privates showin'!
[ Boy ]
The muscleman o' t' year!
He's just come back from Biafra.
[ Coach ]
Pull them up, Casper! Pull them up!
Like that, sir?
[ Coach ]
Roll them down, Casper!
You're too daft to laugh at.
Right. They'll do there.
You lot, come on, get changed.
Wasted enough time already.
I'll give you a sample
of my footballing skills.
A rare delight.
[ Coach ]
Watch yourself, Casper!
I won't tell you again, Crossland!
Come on, move.
Off that goal post!
I'll be up there in a minute!
Come here, Tibbutt.
We'll pick two teams.
You're the captain.
Right, line up
on the halfway line, quickly.
I'll have first pick. Paget.
That's not fair, sir. You'll
get all t' best players.
Do you wanna play football,
or do you wanna do some maths?
- Football, sir.
- Paget then. Come here.
- Speed.
- Walker.
- Clark.
- Crossland.
- Guthrie.
- Rowe.
- Uh... Clegg.
- Norton.
[ Billy ]
Bloody hell, I'm frozen already.
- Joyce.
- Birkinshaw.
- Ryder.
- Parker.
- Norton.
- [ Boy ] Come on, Parker.
[ Coach ] Casper, I've got to have ya.
Come on. Don't act.
Come on. Put 'em round your waist.
[ Coach ]
Now.
Right, we'll play with the wind,
downhill, this way.
- Paget, you're inside right. Come on.
- We'll be out here all day.
Who are you today, sir?
Liverpool?
Don't be slack.
Don't you know your club colors?
Manchester United strip this.
Are you playing Denis Law
again today, sir, or Striker?
No. Charlton today, lad.
All over the field. Too cold for Striker.
Course, uh, Charlton's not
as quick on t' turn as Law, is he?
- You tryin' to tell me about football?
- No. I'm just telling you that -
- You trying to tell me?
- No, sir.
Anyway, Denis Law's in the wash this week.
- Nobody's in goal, sir.
- No goalie, sir.
- No goal, sir.
- Who's in the goals?
- Casper.
- Casper, sir.
Casper, what position
are you supposed to be playing?
[ Billy ] Don't know, sir. Inside left?
How can you be inside left
back there, idiot? In the goals.
- I can't goal, sir! I don't!
- Now's your chance to learn. In the goals!
- [ Boy ] Get out.
- Quick about it.
[ Boy ]
Go on!
Tibbutt, we're Manchester United.
Who are you?
Uh, we'll be Spurs, sir.
Then there's no clash of colors.
Right, then, it's Manchester United
versus Spurs...
in this important fifth-round cup tie
here at Old Trafford.
And it's the fair-haired,
slightly balding Charlton to kick off.
Come on, Speed.
- What you playin' at, lad?
- You kicked it miles away!
You should be on the move, lad!
It was at your feet!
- Cross it, Ryder. Quickly!
- Come on!
Where's the rest of my team?
[ Coach ]
Come on, quickly, Casper.
I've never seen such slack work in my life.
I've never seen such slack work in my -
- What's that for, sir?
- Slack work, lad. Slack work.
Hit that ball up the field, Parker.
Look at this lot.
I have to keep this shirt on and all after.
[ Coach ]
Cross the ball!
And Charlton goes through, and -
Oh, never! Never! Come on!
Penalty!
- Never.
- Who do you think you are? Bremner?
You tripped on your own feet, sir!
- Penalty.
- No, it weren't, sir!
Outside that semicircle.
- Shall I take it, sir?
- I take the penalties on this team.
No one moves till this ball's kicked.
[ Boy ]
Watch everything, sir.
Just watch this, Guthrie.
Right, Clegg?
You moved. You moved.
Put it back.
Penalty!
Behind the 18-yard line.
[ Boy ]
Save it, Cleggy.
Sir, why don't you
let Paget kick it?
Tha better save it, Cleggy!
Else I'll drop tha.
- [ Boy ] You got everything!
- Why don't you let Paget kick it, sir?
- He moved!
- I didn't move, sir.
The referee's decision is final.
[ Boy ]
Let's do it this time, sir.
Oh!
You should have done it
the first time.
And that, boys,
is how to take a penalty.
Look one way and kick the other.
All right, come on, Tibbutt, lad.
And Bobby Charlton has
equalized for Manchester United...
and the score is one goal each.
- Aah!
- Get some leg dope!
- Did you see that?
- That fat twat!
He wants bleedin' milkin'.
That big, fat git!
[ Coach ]
What did you say?
- What did you say?
- Nowt, sir.
Right! Get off!
In that changin' room! Get off!
- I didn't say nowt, sir.
- Off!
I won't tolerate that
on a football pitch.
- It's not fair, sir.
- That's our captain, sir.
I don't care who he is.
You play this game like gentlemen.
Can't play without a captain!
Right inside!
He's our captain, sir!
An early bath for you, lad.
I'll bounce the ball up.
It's not fair, sir!
They never get sent off!
L shall be up there in a minute!
They never get sent off, sir!
Off! Right off!
- [ Coach ] Come on, Paget!
- Me! Me! Me!
- I got left with the football!
- What do you think you're doing?
Don't know.
What do you mean?
Practicing, sir.
Huh?
Show me what you're doing.
- Our ball!
- Our ball! Our ball!
- Clegg!
Come on, Clegg!
Ball! Go on, boy!
Casper!
What do you think you are, lad?
An ape?
All he needs now is a banana.
Get down. I'll make you
red-hot in a minute!
Thank you.
Now, for my next trick -
[ Coach ] I'll show you a trick! Get back
in that goal! The rest of you, up field!
Bloody -
- What's up?
- That ball is -
- That ball, it's hard as iron.
- I know. It's like a stone, isn't it?
- I'm bloody freezing.
- My feet are like blocks of ice.
Me knees, look at 'em.
They're goin' pale.
Look at t' color.
It's gone white.
Oh, I wish I'd brought a note.
Come on, Danny!
- Goal!
- It's in!
Great goal that, sir.
I'll give you a "great goal," lad.
Spurs into the sixth round of t' cup!
Sixth round? I'll give you six in the back
in a minute! On your way!
- Lost again, sir?
- Fetch my tracksuit.
Better luck next time.
- In a hurry, Casper?
- Yes, sir. I have to get home, sir.
- Really?
- Yes, sir.
- Forgotten something?
- No, sir.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, sir.
- What about the showers?
- I've had one, sir.
- You can ask any of 'em, sir.
- I'll just do that.
- Have you seen him have a shower?
- No, sir.
- Have you?
- No, sir. I didn't, sir.
- No, sir.
Have you seen him have a shower?
- Who, sir?
- Casper.
- When, sir?
- Just now.
- Has he had a shower?
- Had a shower, sir?
Has Casper had a shower?
What you fooling about at, lad?
- Has Casper had a shower?
- I don't think so, sir.
Speed, you fool about any more,
you'll get what Casper just had.
No one's seen you have a shower, Casper,
because you haven't had one.
Me mum says I ain't
to have a shower, sir.
Come here, lad.
What's your mother say?
I ain't to have a shower, sir.
I've got a cold.
Where's your note then?
Let me see your note.
Can I bring it
this afternoon, sir?
That's no good, lad.
I want one now.
Any boy wishing to be excused
physical education or showers...
must, at the time of the lesson...
produce a sealed letter
of explanation signed
by one of his parents
or his legal guardian.
- Go on, sir, let me go home.
- You can go, lad.
Hey, come here.
When you've had a shower.
I haven't a towel, sir.
- Borrow one.
- Nobody'll lend me one.
Have a drip-dry then.
Shower. Come on.
- Come here, MacDowell.
- Sir?
Come here, lad.
Come here.
- What's this?
- Our dog did it, sir.
- Your dog did it?
- Aye.
It bit me, sir.
I fought with it on the rug last night.
A dog wearing nylons, lads.
Bloody hell.
- Still in a hurry, Casper?
- Can I go now, sir?
You're not going anywhere
till you've had a proper wash.
- I've had one, sir.
- In the shower, lad.
- I've been, sir!
- I've got to get home!
- In the shower.
Ryder, Speed, come here.
- Me, sir?
- Yes, you two. Come on.
Want you two to stay here
and see that he doesn't come out.
Do what, sir?
Stay there and see that
he doesn't come out.
Aah! Sir! It's gone cold!
[ Coach ]
Got a sweat on, Casper?
I thought you might need a cooler
after your exertions in goal.
It's not right, sir.
I'll catch me death of cold in here.
It's not right.
Was it right when
you let that goal in deliberately?
- Can't we go for us dinners?
- No, you can't. You can stay there.
- We're servers.
- I don't care.
They can serve themselves for once.
You shouldn't put me in goal, sir.
You know I'm useless.
[ Coach ]
Now's your chance to learn.
[ Ryder ] Shall we let him out, sir?
He'll catch his death of cold in here.
He'll catch pneumonia.
[ Coach ]
I don't care what he gets.
If he thinks I'm running my blood
to water for 90 minutes...
for him to deliberately throw the game
away, he's got another think coming.
[ Ryder ]
Sir, we're going to miss our dinner.
[ Boy ] Come on, sir! We've
got to go for our dinner.
Look at him!
- [ Coach ] Get down!
- [ Boy ] He looks like a bleedin' snake!
[ Coach ]
Think yourself lucky.
Too far is too far.
Hey up, old 'un! How it goin'?
- Rough, man. rough.
- Why?
I'd be on top of the world
on a day like today.
Another 10 minutes
I'll be at bottom on it.
[ Man ]
Eh?
Oh, you have it.
[ Man ]
Lovely day.
♪ The trivial round, the common task ♪
♪ Would furnish all we ought to ask ♪
♪ Room to deny ourselves a road ♪
♪ To bring us daily ♪
♪ Nearer God ♪
♪ Only, O Lord, in thy dear love ♪
♪ Fit us for perfect rest above ♪
♪ And help us this and every day ♪
♪ To live more nearly as we pray ♪
♪ Amen ♪♪
This morning's reading is taken from
Matthew, Chapter 18, verses 10-14.
"Never despise one of these little ones,
I tell you.
They have their guardian angels
in heaven...
who look continually on the face
of my heavenly father.
Suppose a man has a hundred sheep.
If one of them strays, does he not leave
the other 99 on the hillside...
and go in search of the one
that strayed?
And if he should find it, I tell you this:
He is more delighted over that sheep
than over the 99 that never strayed.
In the same way,
it is not your heavenly father's will...
that one of these little ones
should be lost."
Here ends this morning's reading.
[ Headmaster ]
Stop! Stop that infernal coughing!
Every morning alike!
Clear your throats on the way to school,
not here.
Sounds more like a dirt track
than an assembly hall.
[ Headmaster ]
Come out! Come out, that boy!
Who coughed?
Mr. Hesketh, somewhere near you,
I think.
Fetch that boy out!
MacDowell! It was you.
You were coughing.
- It weren't!
- Yes, it was. I heard you.
- It weren't, sir.
- Come on, don't argue. We know.
- It weren't me. Honest!
- Come on. Headmaster's study. Come on.
[ Headmaster ] MacDowell! I might
have known it! Get to my office!
- It weren't me, sir.
- And heaven help you!
We will now say the Lord's Prayer.
Hands together, eyes closed.
Our Father -
[ With Children ]
Our Father...
which art in heaven...
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done - [ Fades ]
Does he bite then?
Fierce. Had a little
kid's hand off nearly.
Had he? My, my, my!
What's he fastened on then, wire?
- Aye. It's broke this off and all.
- Oh, dear.
- Just darted at the kid and got him.
- Well, I don't know.
Is that what you've got
the glove on for?
- Yeah. Just in case he gets me.
- Aye. Aye.
- What do you call it?
- Kes.
Kes? Aye.
He is a nice bird.
I shouldn't like to handle him.
Casper! Casper! Up, lad!
On your feet!
You were asleep, weren't you, Casper?
- I don't know, sir.
- I know! You were! You were asleep!
Why were you asleep,
you irreverent scoundrel?
- I don't know, sir.
- I know why!
You're roaming the streets at night
instead of being home in bed.
See me in my office afterwards!
I'll give you something to think about!
Sit!
Here are the announcements.
A reminder that
the youth employment officer...
- will be here this afternoon
to meet the Easter leavers.
Your parents should have been told.
But if any boy has forgotten...
or thinks that his parents may wish
to attend his interview...
then he can consult the list on the main
notice board for the approximate times.
And finally, for three members
of the smokers' union...
caught yesterday
behind the games storeroom...
there will be a meeting
with me after assembly...
when I will be pleased to see and hear them
pay their dues.
He'd better not stick me on it.
I'm fetchin' me father up if he does.
What the good of bringing thee father
down here? He don't do nowt when he comes.
- What's thou mean?
- Last time he came, he got stick and all.
Shut up with all that.
I'm sick of hearin' thee.
When he came down,
they were all laughin' at him.
- They were what?
- Yeah. Weren't they?
Don't say nowt about my father, right?
He's not gonna stick me anyhow.
What does thou want?
I've got a message for Mr. Gryce
from Mrs. Spooner.
- Thou'd better queue then, ain't thou?
- Yeah.
It's his favorite trick.
He loves to keep you waiting.
Thinks it makes it worse.
Yeah. He can keep me till 4:00.
I'm not bothered.
I'd rather have the stick
than do the lessons.
Come here, thee.
Save us these
till after we come out of Gryce's.
I can't. He'll think
I have smoked as well.
He'll not search thee,
but he'll search us. And
if he finds them on us,
we'll get two extra.
- I don't want 'em.
- Does thou want some fist instead?
Are tha gonna take them?
Tha'd better, lad,
or thou'll say thee prayers.
Okay. But if I get caned,
you'll give me summat.
Some fist if tha don't.
In the pocket.
Hey up, he's here - Gryce Pudding.
Single file.
Right. You lost, lad?
- Please, sir, I'm going -
- On your way! Homeroom.
You lot, inside.
Same old faces.
Ten years this school's been opened...
and 10 years have we seen
after every assembly...
a line of boys here,
and the same old faces.
- Sir, I've got a message -
- Shut up, lad. Don't interrupt.
Now close the door.
I've taught in this city for over 30 years.
I taught some of your parents -
your father, MacDowell -
in the old slum schools in the city...
before they built this fine estate...
and this wonderful school.
Things are no better now
than they were then.
I just can't understand this generation.
I thought I knew something
about young people.
I should be able to, you know?
With my experience.
But with you? No.
It just seems a complete waste of money
and a waste of time.
And it's a waste of time
talking to you now.
Why, you're not even listening,
are you, MacDowell?
- Yes, sir.
- No, you're not!
- Crossland, you're not listening, are you?
- I am, sir.
No, you're not. None
of you are listening!
Look at that glazed
expression on your faces.
You never listen!
Yours is the generation that never listens.
Because we can never tell you anything.
You're the sophisticated ones...
with all your music and your gear.
But, you know, it's superficial.
It's a sheen.
There's nothing solid
or worthwhile underneath.
Why do I know this?
Why do I know there's been no advance...
in discipline or decency
or morals or manners?
Why do I know it?
Because I still have to use this
to you boys every day.
Why? In the '20s and '30s,
I could understand it.
They were hard times.
But they produced qualities in people
that you lot will never have.
I can be stopped in the street
by someone I taught then...
and we'll talk about the old days...
and we'll laugh
about the thrashings that I gave him.
But what do I get from you lot?
A honk...
from a greasy, pimply-faced youth...
sitting at the wheel
of a big secondhand car.
I don't know. I just don't know.
No guts. No backbone.
Nothing to commend you whatsoever.
Mere fodder for the mass media.
And so, until someone
produces a better solution...
I'll continue to use this cane...
knowing fully well that you'll be back
for it time and time and time again.
You smokers will go out of here
with your hands ringing.
But will it stop you smoking?
You're already looking forward
to smoking at break.
- You, lad! What are you grinning about?
- I'm not grinning, sir.
You are! I'll bet you're already thinking
about smoking at break.
Empty your pockets.
They're loaded with cigarettes.
Come on, all of you! Empty your pockets.
- Please, sir -
- Quiet, lad! Empty your pockets!
- Sir, you don't understand -
- Empty your pockets, lad.
Disgusting!
Please, sir -
You again? You again?
- Yes, sir.
- Empty your pockets.
But, sir, I've brought a message
from Mrs. Spooner.
Empty your pockets!
I don't believe it.
I don't believe this.
Empty your pockets, lad.
Empty your pockets when you're told!
Come on, lad!
Ah!
A regular little cigarette factory,
aren't you?
Yes, sir.
Put that rubbish away!
[ Gryce ] Now, I hope it's going to be
a lesson to you.
I don't suppose for one minute it will be.
I don't doubt before the end of the week
you'll be back in here again...
for exactly the same crime -
smoking.
Perhaps once in a while,
it might sink in.
Yes, sir.
That you're wasting your money.
That it's your money
that you're burning...
and it's your hands that get caned
when you come in here.
Good morning. Entry of the gladiators.
Where have you been?
- Been to see Mr. Gryce, sir.
- Give you the stick?
- Hmm.
- Sir.
- How many did you get?
- Two.
- Did it hurt?
- [ Both ] Not bad.
Oh. Hope it didn't.
Go and sit down.
Right. Now, fact.
Anne, tell me what a fact is.
Don't give me a fact.
You know, don't say that Guthrie's got
a tatty head or anything like that.
[ Anne ] A fact is something
what you find evidence of, like the truth.
Something that you know
has actually happened.
This is a fact.
All right? Have you got that clear?
- [ Students ] Yes, sir.
- Good.
Tibbutt, sit up straight.
And I want the rest of you
to look at him, if you can bear it...
and tell me some facts about Tibbutt.
Wolstenholme?
He's always tryin' to go with lasses
at night.
Is he? Guthrie?
He smokes.
- Do I heck!
- Thou does.
- Get knotted, Guthrie!
- [ Farthing ] All right, all right.
I'm not interested in what he does
out of school hours...
as long as he doesn't come into the class
smoking a fag.
All right?
Come on, you people who aren't thinking.
Right, Julie.
I want you to think of an incident that's
happened to you sometime in the past...
that is true and that you think
will interest the rest of the class.
- All right?
- Well, uh...
I went to this all-night party yesterday.
And, uh -
About 3:00, we went -
we were dancin' in the garden.
Me and her and ail the rest.
Can't mention names.
And, uh...
this woman comes
across from t' road...
and, uh, she tells us
to-to make less noise...
or else she'd fetch police.
So, well - So we said,
let her fetch 'em if she wanted.
So, she fetched 'em.
Things that have actually happened.
How about another one?
What about you, Casper?
Casper!
What, sir?
"What, sir?"
You'd know if you'd been listening.
What have we just been talking about?
Stories, sir.
What kind of stories?
You haven't been listening
to a word I've said, have you?
- Yes, sir. Some of it.
- "Some of it"?
Stand up!
Right. Now you're gonna tell us
a story about yourself.
- I don't know any, sir.
- You don't know any?
Well, you stand there till you do.
Always somebody, isn't there, eh?
Somebody who wants to be awkward.
Just won't be interested.
It doesn't matter what you do.
Just like you, Casper.
Come on.
I'll give you two minutes -
two minutes to think of something...
or the whole class comes back at 4:00.
Come on, Casper.
Don't stand there like a nail.
[ Guthrie ]
He is a nail.
Come on. I say... tell 'em.
[ Boy ]
Tell him about the hawk, Casper.
If anybody else calls out,
it'll be the last call they make.
Speed?
He's got this hawk, sir,
and he goes mad over it.
He never knocks about with anybody else.
He just goes with t' hawk all the time.
- He's crackers over it.
- Better than thee, any road.
[ Farthing ]
All right, Casper.
Sit down.
Now, come on, come on.
Tell us about this hawk.
Where'd you get it from?
- I found it, sir.
- Where?
In the woods.
And where do you keep it?
In the shed.
What do you feed it on?
Beef. Mice. Birds.
But isn't it cruel to keep it in the shed?
I mean, wouldn't it be happier flying free?
I don't keep it in the shed all the
time, sir. I fly it every day.
Doesn't it fly away?
I thought they were wild birds.
Of course it don't fly away, sir.
I've trained it.
[ Farthing ] Aren't you gonna tell us
about it? How have you trained your hawk?
[ Billy ] You have to be right careful
with them, sir. Right patient.
You've got to feed them
when they're hungry, see?
And you can only do owt
when they're at feeding time like, sir.
Yeah?
They've got these Jesses on, sir,
all the time.
These what?
Jesses, sir.
- How do you spell that?
- J-E -
All right, come out here. Come on.
You'd better show us
on the board, hmm?
"Jesses"?
This is a new word to me.
Hands up, those who've heard
of Jesses before.
Nobody. Go on. Write it up there.
Right. Now tell us what it is.
Well, they're like leather straps, sir,
and they're attached to birds' feet.
And say I've got the bird on me hand.
The straps go down there,
then there's swivel.
"Swivel."
Write that on the board.
[ Billy ]
Then you've got your leash.
[ Farthing ]
"Leash." On the board.
[ Billy ]
l fed it on me hand first.
Then when it got to know me,
I fed it on me glove.
And after a while,
l put it two inches away from its claws.
And, uh - Like that, right?
It started to jump for the meat.
When it started to jump,
l could move me hand away.
[ Farthing ]
Hold your hand up so we can see.
I could move me hand away,
like to four inches and six inches.
And when it were doin' that,
l started doing it with t' leash.
Do they need water, like?
You know, when you've got a budgie,
and you put water in the budgie's cage.
Do they need water like that?
[ Billy ]
Well, it, like, has a bath.
It has a bath right early on
in the morning, like.
When do you feed it?
How many times a day?
To start off with, three or four times,
you know, to get it plump.
You make it all sound very exciting, Billy.
It is, sir. But most exciting thing -
when I flew her free first time, sir.
- Do you want to hear about that?
- Yes, sir.
Aye. Come on.
Well, I'd been using creance
for about a week...
and it had been going 30, 40 yards.
And it says when birds are going
30, 40 yards, it says in t' book...
it's time that it can start to fly free.
Well, I'd been - you know, I'd been
wanting to fly it free, but I daren't.
You know, I were frightened
it'd fly off or something like that.
This had been going on
for four or five days.
And I keep on to meself, sayin' that...
fly it free next day.
Anyway, I got right mad with meself...
and says, "Right, I'm
flying it free tomorrow."
Anyway, that night -
that Friday night, it were -
l didn't feed her up,
so that she'd be sharp set next morning.
And I went to bed that night -
Friday night -
and I didn't get an hour's sleep at all.
I were frightened about the bird,
that she'd fly off or summat like that.
Anyway, when the morning came,
I kept on saying to meself...
"Well, if she flies off, she flies off,
and it can't be helped."
So, I took swivel off
and let her hop onto t' post.
There were nowt stopping her now.
She could fly off.
All were on her were her Jesses.
I thought, she must fly off.
She's forced to fly off.
But she didn't. She just stood there.
I were terrified.
Well, anyway, she was stood there,
and I walked off into t' field...
and she were looking round
all over the place.
And when I got in about 70 yards
from where - in the middle of t' field...
l called her.
"Kes! Kes! Come, Kes!
Come on then!"
Nowt happened, so I thought, well,
I'd better walk back and pick her up.
So, while I were walking back,
l saw her flying.
She came like a bomb.
About a yard off the floor, like lightning,
head still, and you couldn't hear t' wings.
There weren't a sound from the wings -
and straight onto the glove - Wham!
And she grabbed me for t' meat.
Anyway, I were pleased with meself,
and I didn't know what to do.
So I thought, "Well, I better do it again
just to prove it weren't luck."
So, I took her back onto t' post...
and walked back up into t' middle
of t' field and called her again.
And she came just as good
as first time...
straight onto t' glove
and grabbed me for t' meat.
Well, that were it, sir. I'd trained
her, sir, and that were ail I could do.
[ Farthing ]
l think you've done enough, don't you?
Well done, Billy. Big hand of applause.
- [ MacDowell ] Have you got owt, Casper?
- Nay.
Thou never has, has thou?
Thou just cadges, all the time.
Casper the Cadger.
That's what they ought to call thee.
I wouldn't give thee owt if I had,
MacDowell.
I'll give thee summat in a minute.
What's thou going for?
Don't tha like company?
They say thee mother does.
Tha's got more uncles in this city
than any other kid.
- Shut thee mouth!
- Come here and make me.
Tha wouldn't say that to our Jud.
He'd murder thee.
Your Jud's nowt.
What? He's cock of t' estate,
that's ail.
- I bet I know somebody who could do him.
- Who? Thee father?
He ain't even thee brother.
What is he then, me sister?
They don't even call him Casper,
for a start.
Of course he's me brother!
We live in t' same house, don't we?
- [ Boy ] Go on, get him!
- [ Cheering, Shouting ]
Up, up, up!
Right, you lot!
Ten seconds! Out of my sight!
One! Two! Three!
[ Farthing ]
Off with you! Hop it!
Right, come here, you two.
Come on.
- What's goin' on?
- It was him, sir. He started it.
- He's been chucking coke.
- Ah, shut up! Shut up!
It's always the same tale, isn't it?
Somebody else's fault, nobody's to blame.
Look at the mess you're in!
Look at the state you've made!
Don't look so sorry for yourself, Casper.
You're not dead yet.
- He will be when I've had him.
- Oh, yes!
You're a big lad, aren't you? He's just
about your size, Casper, isn't he?
Eh?
Why don't you pick on somebody
your own size?
What if I rubbed your nose in the coke?
What would you say about that?
You'd say I was a bully, wouldn't you?
And you'd be right.
'Cause I'm bigger and I'm stronger
than you, aren't l?
- Eh?
- I'll fetch me dad.
Oh, yes, you'll fetch your dad.
And I'll fetch mine.
My dad's heavyweight champion
of the world, my dad is.
So what would your dad do then, eh?
That's what it's like to be bullied.
You don't like it, do you?
You'll like it a bit less
if I ever catch you at it again.
Do you understand, MacDowell?
Do you understand it?
Yes, sir.
Get it shoveled up.
And wait a minute.
- Have you been smoking?
- No, sir.
You have, haven't you?
I can smell it on your breath!
No, sir.
See me afterwards.
Get it done. Go on.
Now, what's it all about?
He keeps calling me names, sir, and
saying things about me dad and me mum...
and our Jud,
and everybody were laughing.
All right, all right, all right.
Calm down.
They always seem to pick on you,
don't they, Casper? Why is it?
- Don't know, sir.
- Is it because you're a bad 'un?
Maybe I am sometimes,
but I'm not that bad, sir.
I know stacks of other kids that's worse
than me, but they seem to get away with it.
[ Farthing ]
Hmm.
Why else do you think? Eh?
There must be some reason, mustn't there?
Well, take this morning, sir.
I just came in, sir, and just dozed off.
I wasn't doin' nowt wrong, sir.
I'd been up since 6:00.
I had to do t' papers,
then I had to rush home
to have a look at t' bird,
then run to school.
I mean to say, you'd be tired,
wouldn't you, sir?
- I'd be exhausted.
- And that's not -
You shouldn't be caned for that,
should you, sir?
And you can't tell Mr. Gryce that.
And this little lad, sir
- He'd only brought
a letter from one
of the teachers...
and he got caned.
It's nowt to laugh at, sir.
Afterwards, he was sick as a dog.
[ Farthing ]
Was he?
And teachers, sir.
They're not bothered about us, sir.
If we're 4C, they think we're numbskulls
owt like that, sir.
And when they have time,
they're always looking at their watches...
to see how long there is left
of the lesson.
They're not bothered about us,
and we're not bothered about them.
How are things at home these days?
All right, sir.
Usual, I suppose.
What about the police?
You been in trouble with them recently?
No, sir. Not since I've been
without MacDowell's gang, sir.
You know,
they used to go into t' city...
and go into coffee bars
and cinemas...
but since I've been without them,
I've been ail right.
Mmm. That's all right now, isn't it?
Yes, sir, but whenever
there's trouble on t' estate...
always police come to our house.
Well, I shouldn't worry.
Give it a couple of weeks, you'll be
starting your new job, getting new friends.
Lookin' forward to that, are you?
Eh? Have you got a job?
No, sir. I've got to see
employment bloke this after.
What sort of job do you want?
I'm not bothered, sir.
Anything will do me.
But you want something
you're looking forward
to, that you're
interested in, don't you?
I've not much choice, sir.
I have to take what I've got.
I thought you wanted to leave school.
- I'm not bothered.
- I thought you didn't like school.
I don't, but that don't mean to say
I'll like work, does it?
Still, I'll get paid for not liking it.
That's one thing.
I suppose it is.
I might be able to save up
and buy a goshawk then, sir.
- I've been reading about them.
- Have you?
- When do you fly this hawk of yours?
- Dinnertimes.
- Where?
- Just outside our house, sir.
- Wood Lane, is that?
- Yeah, it is, sir.
I'll come round then, if it's okay.
Go on then.
Get yourself cleaned up.
"Five bob double. Crackpot.
Tell Him He's Dead.
Jud."
Bloody hellfire!
Kes!
Come on then!
Come on then, Kes.
Come on, Kes.
Come on, Kes. Come on.
Casper!
Bloody hellfire!
Hope I'm not too late.
No, sir, but you'll
have to stand over there.
I'll go by the fence, eh?
It's all right.
As long as you keep quiet.
I'll not say a word.
Come on, Kes!
Kes!
Well done, Casper. The most exciting thing
I've ever seen in me life.
Great.
Thrill of a lifetime, lad.
Thank you, sir.
Let's have a look at it.
Isn't it beautifully marked, eh?
Look at the feathers on it.
Oh, it's not gonna eat that, is it?
Yes, sir.
This bird's full of vitamins.
Oh, dear.
Have any more birds before him?
Stacks. Animals and all, sir.
Had even a fox cub once.
Reared it and let it go.
A little blinder.
I've had magpies, jackdaws.
Had a young jay once.
[ Farthing ] Mmm.
He's your favorite, though, isn't he?
[ Billy ]
Others weren't in t' same street.
Come on, then. Come, lass.
- Come on, sir.
- Oh, dear me.
Watch that mattress, sir.
It's slippery.
Okay.
Look what's left, sir.
Only the sparrow's leg.
It must have been hungry.
It must have been starving.
You hang on here.
I'll put him on t' perch.
Come on then.
[ Billy ]
Shh.
You know...
there's something weird about it
when it's flying.
No, sir.
Hawks are the best fliers there is.
No, I didn't mean that.
I mean, when it's flying, there's something
about it makes you feel strange.
Is it 'cause everything goes quiet?
That's it, aye.
Other folks have noticed that
and all, sir.
I know a farmer who says
it's the same with owls.
You know, when they get his mice
in his yard at night.
When they swoop down, he feels like
pokin' his ears to make 'em pop.
Hmm.
You know, of course it goes that quiet.
It's as if they're flying
in a pocket of silence.
Have you noticed
how quietly we're speaking?
As if we're frightened to raise our
voices - a bit like shouting in church.
- It's 'cause they're nervous, sir.
- Oh, no. It's more than that.
It's instinctive.
It's a sort of respect.
I know, sir.
That's what makes me mad.
You know, when I take her for walks,
somebody comes up to me and says...
"Look, it's Billy Casper and his pet hawk."
I could shout at them, sir.
It isn't a pet.
Or if somebody comes up to me
and says, "Is it tame?"
Is it heck tame!
Hawks can't be tamed.
They're manned.
It's wild and it's fierce
and it's not bothered about anybody.
Not bothered about me, right?
That what makes it great.
A lot of people wouldn't understand that
though. They like their pets to be fussed.
I'm not bothered about that. I just
want her for her looks, and to fly her.
They can keep their talking budgies.
They're nowt compared with her.
[ Farthing ] You're right, Billy.
You're probably right.
[ Billy ]
Do you know something, sir?
I think she's doing me a favor,
just letting me sit here and watch her.
Well, what's he studying there?
Can I help you, son?
No, thanks.
Hey, mister, can you tell me
the prices of these?
What are they?
Crackpot.
Crackpot. 100-to-6.
Tell Him He's Dead. Where is he?
I've just been looking at this one meself.
Tell Him He's Dead.
Second favorite, 4-to-1.
100-to-6 and 4-to-1.
Would you have backed them?
Tell Him He's Dead's a good horse.
Best horse in t' race. Top weight.
Don't fancy t' other one though.
No form.
Hasn't even got a jockey on here.
No, I shouldn't bother with that one.
You don't think they'll win, then?
How's thou got them? Doubled?
Well, they're not mine.
They're our Jud's.
Oh, they'll do all right if they do,
but I can't see it meself.
Right, ta.
May I have a bob's worth of chips
and a fish?
Serve him, will you, Mary?
- Yes, love? What do you want?
- Fish and chips.
[ Kicking Counter ]
And stop kicking, will you?
We only put that on today.
Got any scraps, missus?
[ Woman ]
Yes, love. I'll put you some on.
Two shilling, love.
I'm gettin' rid of these chips, Floyd.
It's gettin' late now.
[ Floyd ]
Aye, but don't be going mad.
[ Woman ]
Sixpence change, love.
[ Floyd ] These kids - I don't know, Mr.
Glover. They're just all the same.
- Can I have a quarter of beef?
- Ah, them smell good.
Can I have a quarter of beef?
[ Children Shouting In Distance ]
You still got that bird then?
Yep.
You can have them for nowt.
- For nowt?
- Aye, they're only scraps.
Have another chip?
No. I'm going for me dinner in a minute.
- Right, then. Ta. See you.
- Ta-ta. See you.
[ Teacher ]
Usual difficulty over concentration?
Hmm?
Three five's 15, eh?
We write 15 one, five.
You write five, one.
Isn't that that, uh, illustrious brother
of yours, Casper?
[ Billy ]
Sir.
Shouldn't have thought he was the type to
have paid a visit to his old school again.
What's the matter? Don't you feel well?
No, sir.
You want to go out and get
a drink of water or something?
No, sir.
Well, open the window.
Perhaps it'll make you feel better.
I'm all right, sir.
Please yourself.
Right. Now just pass your books forward,
will you, to the front.
Front person on each row,
bring them to my desk, will you?
What's the matter, Casper?
Lost something?
- Me, sir? No, sir.
- On your way then.
[ MacDowell ]
What's up with thee, Jud?
[ Jud ] What's up with me
is that little bastard, our Billy.
I left him with a bet for the horses,
and he's kept the stinkin' money.
I'll kill the little git
when I get hold of him.
- [ MacDowell ] Is that right?
- [ Jud ] I'll murder him.
What do you think you're playing at, lad?
No, sir. I'm just going
to the toilet, sir.
Hurry up then. Be quick!
[ Clegg ]
Hey! I'm on here!
- Seen our Billy?
- Aye. He's on here with me.
Trying to be funny?
'Cause I'll stick thee
head down there, old
pal, and I'll flush it.
I asked if tha'd seen him.
I wouldn't tell thee if I had.
- Look, I'm warnin' you!
- Oww!
Hey, Tibbutt, have you seen our Jud?
What's thou been doing?
They've been looking all over for thee.
- Who has?
- Gryce Pudding!
- What for? I ain't done nowt.
- Youth employment.
Tha should have gone
for the interview last lesson.
- Has tha seen our Jud?
- Yeah.
He wanted to know where thou was,
that's ail.
What did tha run away for
when thee saw him?
Casper! Where the devil have you been?
Nowhere, sir.
Nowhere? Who are you,
the invisible Man?
I felt sick, sir, so I went to the toilets.
What happened?
Did you drop down it?
I've had prefects looking
ail over the school for you.
Well, I went out then, sir,
for a breath of fresh air.
- And where are you going now?
- Employment office, sir.
For your interview?
Well, get off then, lad!
And God help your future employer!
Come and sit over there.
Sit up, Peter.
I'm sat up.
Don't be like a dummy
when you get in there.
Just tell him you're after a good job
in an office, or something like that.
I'm not working in an office.
What are you after then,
a job on the bins?
Ma, can't you shut up?
- Sit up.
- I'm sat up.
And straighten your tie.
Tha's nagging.
Somebody's got to nag.
- Is it your mum?
- Aye.
What job are thou after?
Owt will do me.
- It certainly won't.
- It will.
- It won't.
- Right. Thank you.
[ Man ]
Will you send the next one in?
[ Boy ]
Pardon?
[ Man ] Will you send
the next one in now, please?
Right. Okay.
Isn't it your turn to go in?
I suppose so.
Well, go on then.
[ Man ]
Get out, lad! Knock and wait!
Come in.
Well, come in, lad, if you're coming.
Sit down, Walker.
I'm not Walker, sir.
Well, who are you, then? According to my
list, it should be Gerald Walker next.
Oliver, Stenton, then Walker.
- I'm Casper.
- Casper?
Oh, sit down, Casper. I should have
seen you earlier, shouldn't I?
Well then, Casper, what kind
of job had you got in mind?
Well?
I don't know, sir.
I haven't thought about it, like.
Well, you should be thinking about it.
You want to start off
on the right foot, don't you?
Right then.
Well, would you like to work in an office?
Or would you prefer manual work?
What's manual work?
Oh, it means working
with your hands, things
like farming,
engineering, plumbing -
things like that,
as opposed to pen-pushing jobs.
You write in an office.
Have a job to read and write.
Oh.
Manual.
Tell me, Casper, have you ever thought
about entering a trade as an apprentice?
You know, as an electrician or a bricklayer
or something like that.
Of course, the money's not too good
while you're serving your apprenticeship.
And if you do stick it out, you'll always
have a trade at your fingertips, won't you?
Mm-hmm.
Well then, Casper,
what do you think about it?
And as you've already said,
you feel better working with your hands.
Perhaps this is your best bet.
Of course, you'd have to go
to technical college...
and study for various examinations.
But some lads do it.
Some do it for years,
two or three nights a week...
right from leaving school
right up to the mid-20s...
when they take their Higher National,
or even degrees.
I say, lad, are you listening to me?
Yeah.
You don't look as though you are.
I've other lads to see before 4:00,
you know.
Well, if nothing I've mentioned so far
appeals to you...
and if you can stand a hard day's work
and you don't mind getting dirty...
there are good opportunities
in mining.
I'm not going down pit.
Don't be put off by what you've heard.
Conditions have improved tremendously.
I won't be seen dead down pit.
What about hobbies?
What hobbies have you got?
Do you like gardening or constructing
Meccano sets or anything like that?
Don't you have any hobbies at all?
Can I go now?
What's wrong with you, lad?
Sit down. Sit down.
I haven't finished yet.
Well, I've met some lads in my time,
but I've never met one like you, Casper.
Half the time you're like
a cat on hot bricks...
the other half you're not listening.
Here. Take this form.
It gives you all the relevant information
about leaving school and starting work -
things like pensions, superannuation,
national insurance, wages and so on.
At the back,
there's a detachable form.
When you want your cards,
fill it in -
Come back here, lad.
I haven't finished yet.
When you want your cards, fill in
that form, send it in to the office.
- Have you got that?
- Yeah.
Don't forget. And listen, Casper -
If you do have any trouble getting fixed
up, do come in and see me, won't you?
- Yes, sir.
- Send the next boy in.
Kes!
Jud?
Jud! Mother!
- I say, have you seen our Jud?
- I haven't, love. I'm sorry.
- Have you seen our Jud?
- Of course I've seen your Jud.
Doesn't look as though you've seen him,
else you wouldn't be all in one piece.
- You've seen him then?
- Of course I've seen him.
He come in here playin' hell up. Goin'
to pull t' counter down and everything.
What did you do then?
I had to fetch Eric Cluff
to prove tha hadn't put bet on.
- They won, then, did they?
- Both of 'em - 100-to-6 and 4-to-1.
- He'd have won a tenner, I tell thee that.
- Bloody hell.
Kes!
Come on, Kes!
Come on, lass!
Kes!
Come on, Kes!
Where is it?
What's thou done with it?
Where've you been till this time?
Your tea's going cold here.
I said, where is it?
- What's thou starin' at?
- Thee, you little pig!
Don't call me a little pig,
or I'll bet you -
- Get back!
- Hey! Hey!
Jud, what's all
t' bloody pushin' and shovin'?
[ Billy ]
Ask him. He knows.
Yes, and thou'd have known it if I'd
have got hold of thee this afternoon.
- Oh, get lost!
- Knows what? What's going on?
What's up with him?
What have you been doing to him?
If he'd have put that bet
on the horses like he were
told to this morning, there
would've been none of this.
- Well, he's put it on, hasn't he?
- Has he, bloody hell!
Well, I told him to. I asked you not to
forget before I went to work this morning.
He didn't forget.
He spent t' money!
- How do you know?
- Because he has.
What are you getting so damned upset for?
Have they won or summat?
Have they won? I'd have
16 quid to draw if
he'd have kept his
thieving hands to hisself.
Now look what you've done.
Tha should have done it
yourself, shouldn't tha?
Sixteen quid - I could have had
a week off work for that!
- Get lost, you big pig!
- [ Mother ] Hey!
Well, what's he upset for?
Because he's killed me hawk instead,
that's why.
He never has.
He has. I know he has.
'Cause he couldn't catch me.
Jud! You have not killed
this kid's hawk!
So I have.
What are you gonna do about it?
[ Mother ] Bloody kill yourself!
That's what you want!
[ Jud ] It were its own fault.
I was only gonna let it go.
Kept lashing at me with claws.
I had to kill it. What else could I do?
You're a big bastard!
A big rotten bastard!
[ Jud ] Don't call me a bastard!
[ Mother ] Stop chucking
things like that!
Thou'll be next to get it!
You're a big bastard!
A big, bleedin' bastard!
[ Mother ] That's enough of that language
in here, and you and ail!
[ Jud ] Sixteen quid. I could have had
a lousy week off work for that.
[ Mother ] What have you done
with the damn bird anyway?
[ Jud ] It's in the
bin where it belongs!
[ Mother ] Putting in t' bin!
Look what you've done to him now!
If I'd got hold of
him, he'd have been in!
Oh, yes, you!
That's just about your bloody power,
isn't it - killing a bird?
- Shut your face, will you!
- You shut your face!
Don't talk to me like that,
or I'll shut it for you!
Ah, well, it wouldn't hurt!
Don't tempt me too much, Jud,
'cause I'm sick of it now!
- Ah, shut up!
- And you!
I'm fed up with being in this bloody house!
I'm fed up of seein' you in it!
Upsetting a kid like that!
Bloody pig, you are.
Look what he's done, Mum!
Look at it!
He's a right 'un.
That were a rotten trick anyway,
weren't it?
It were a rotten trick, what he did to me,
No need to take it out on a bird.
You could have took it out on me!
You know what a lot he thought about it.
Take it away from table anyway, Billy.
- But what are you gonna do to him?
- What do you want me to do to him?
- Give him a good hiding!
- "Give him a" -
What do you think you're doing?
[ Jud ]
I'd just like to see her, and all.
I'm fed up with the pair of you talkin'
about the damn thing! It's only a bird!
- You can get another, can't you?
- It's not worth a stinkin' threepence!
Get off! Get off!
Get out! Get out!
And don't come stinkin' back!