You feeI that, Joe?
FeeI What?
That.
Like When the objects
start to get cIose together.
That sick feeIing,
Iike a vibration, aImost, in here.
I've been feeIing that for a WhiIe noW.
- I thought it Was just nerves.
- It's the moteI.
AII the objects, the key,
the room, everything,
they aII came from this pIace.
You kneW this Was here the WhoIe time?
It's a bad pIace.
What eIse don't I knoW?
The event happened
on May the 4th, 1961 .
1 :20 P. M.
- The event?
- Whatever created these objects.
- See, the objects Wanna
be put back together.
You think it Was an accident, us meeting?
You think finding
the PoIaroid Was an accident?
I may have shoWn you the Way,
but, uh, the objects brought you here.
Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
- Where's Room 10?
- There is no Room 10.
It never existed.
At Ieast not after
May the 4th, 1961 .
You knoW What that is?
Object chart.
I've seen one before.
You toId him!
- Martin Ruber.
- Yes.
Do you beIieve in the reunification of God?
Do you beIieve in the truth?
The Order?
The neW reIigion?
Yes.
Do you reject your former Iife?
Do you give yourseIf to The Order?
Yes.
Then pray.
Pray to this object.
What is it?
It's a piece of God...
Iike every other object.
And I Want you to pray to it.
If We can reunite aII the objects,
We can restore the mind of God.
We can communicate With God
for the first time in human history.
- Do you beIieve that, Martin?
- Yes. Yes, I beIieve.
Then open your eyes
and embrace The Order.
Stupid.
Arrogant.
You Iive onIy because
I Was once Iike you.
But you WiII Iearn, Martin.
Thank me for this mercy.
Thank you.
The moteI room key
is the most important object
to The Order right noW.
Margaret, I Want your group
to find Joe MiIIer
and take the key.
We can't have another
screW-up Iike Michigan.
Ray Cory's group in NeW York
and Parchman's group in CIeveIand
WiII act as support if necessary.
I understand Dr. Ruber
knoWs Joe MiIIer personaIIy,
Which is Why the job is yours.
I don't think Dr. Ruber is in any kind
of shape to heIp us,
considering his
faIIing out With MiIIer.
That's exactIy Why MiIIer WiII taIk to me.
He'd Iike to kiII me.
There's no such things as ghosts.
Fine. I'm just asking you.
You sWear you didn't see her?
Didn't see her.
I don't beIieve in ghosts, aII right?
Yeah, me neither.
I mean, magic bus ticket,
sure, but ghosts, no.
Look, I've seen the bus ticket, aII right?
- With my eyes I seen it.
- WeII, I saW her.
And you knoW, Whatever
she is, she Was there.
Here.
Tape that doWn.
Are you ready?
Let's go.
I feeI stupid.
Do you?
Just give it a sec.
Great.
The camera's broken.
You knoW, I might be
abIe to dig it out and fix it.
The key's okay.
Yeah, MiIIer.
Joe, it's Ruber.
We need to taIk about
your daughter.
What do you Want, Ruber?
I Wanna heIp you get
your daughter back.
Yeah?
Any thoughts about getting Lou back?
I've joined a group, Joe.
A cabaI.
They're caIIed The Order
of the Reunification.
They beIieve in the objects.
They Want to use them.
Do you have any idea
hoW poWerfuI the objects reaIIy are?
The Order thinks that if they can
get aII the objects back together,
they can taIk to God.
That's insane.
Come With me to The Order.
Give us the key.
If anybody can bring Anna back,
We can, together.
Some day, Ruber,
you're gonna get What comin' to ya.
Some day you're gonna need me, Joe.
I aImost got this thing Workin'.
Can We make animaI pancakes?
What kind of animaI pancakes you Want?
EIephants.
AII right, WeII, I don't knoW hoW
to make an eIephant,
but hoW about a mouse?
EIephant.
Okay-okay-okay.
I got it.
AII right, Wait, Wait, Wait.
Go back.
AII right, sIoW it doWn.
WoW.
She's disintegrating.
You see, somehoW the key
brings her back just for a feW seconds
into our time and space.
What's it Iike for her the rest of the time
When she's not in our space?
I don't knoW.
But Anna may be trapped in the same pIace.
We need to find out Who she is.
- You sure you knoW Where you're going?
- Yes.
HoW much further?
I don't knoW.
Not much.
Doesn't seem Iike
much of a shortcut.
PIease, don't compIain to me noW.
- Hey, What's the name of this toWn?
- I don't remember.
Nobody goes there anymore.
Why not?
You knoW, the questions
get reaIIy boring after a WhiIe.
I don't knoW the name of the toWn, okay?
It doesn't matter.
What it Was a Iong a time ago,
I don't knoW--
- You're trespassing'.
- Sorry.
Look, We didn't knoW anybody Iived here.
We're just headed into the toWn.
There ain't a toWn anymore.
FriendIy.
That's Why I don't Iike comin' here.
Come on.
Come on!
Just reIax.
- Where is everybody?
- ExactIy.
Make an offer.
What do you think?
Proud of yourseIf?
What's the probIem?
I've been here a coupIe times.
I don't Iike it in there.
Just stick With me a IittIe Ionger, aII right?
I'II buy you Iunch.
Bus station's that Way.
I'm not Iooking for
the bus station.
I'm hungry.
I'd Iike to eat.
TeII you What.
I'II just have the speciaI.
Turkey, mashed potatoes.
Sounds good.
Some appIe pie.
- Coffee, pIease.
- I'II have tWo of the same.
- TWo?
- Yeah, tWo.
See Why I don't Iike this pIace?
ReIax, okay?
Anything eIse?
Yeah, I'd Iike to knoW
about that moteI.
What's the matter?
I can't ask a simpIe question?
What happened at that moteI?
MoteI's haunted.
What do you mean, haunted?
There's these peopIe out of noWhere
coming doWn over the hiII,
thinking they're in--
heII.
It used to hardIy
happen at aII.
NoW it happens aII the time.
AII right, What about
the Woman at the moteI?
The Woman?
The ghost?
Who's seen her?
Nobody, huh?
I'II take the rest to the booth.
I knoW I'm not haIIucinating,
but I feeI Iike I'm Iosin' it.
You're Iosing it?
You see these peopIe?
They're Iiving a miIe and a haIf from that moteI.
It's making 'em haIf-crazy,
and they don't even knoW Why.
Most peopIe Ieft a WhiIe ago, but...
a Iot of 'em never figured out--
What?
There's our ghost.
Hi.
You Wanna come in?
Oh, I don't think so.
Better?
Much.
I'm gonna ask you a question.
Do you recognize her?
No.
Who is she?
She's a Woman I saW at the moteI.
The actuaI moteI in room number 9.
What's Wrong?
Joe, don't go back there.
- You kneW about it?
- You WouIdn't understand.
What WouIdn't I understand, Jennifer?
That's the guy from the hospice, isn't it?
He's my brother.
DreW.
We aII have reasons
to get rid of the objects.
DreW's my reason.
He became obsessed With Room 9.
And Whatever happened to him in there
destroyed him.
So, Joe, you promise me
you Won't go back there.
I am sorry about your brother.
I reaIIy am.
But I have to go back because
Whatever's happening to that Woman
couId be happening to Anna right noW.
So I'm gonna find out the names
of everyone in this picture,
and hopefuIIy I can
taIk to one of them.
Because if I can
bring that Woman back,
I can bring Anna back.
I knoW it.
My brother's research on Room 9.
WoW.
Yeah.
Home sWeet home.
Jennifer, I--
You aII right?
Yeah.
Just don't break my heart.
Don't break mine.
Jennifer, get dressed.
We have to go.
What's going on?
Get everything
It's stiII here.
Whoever made that print
Was here in 1961 .
I think my brother identified
the peopIe in this photo.
They're the CoIIectors.
The Woman you saW Was
the moteI manager in 1966.
ArIene Conroy.
Woman in the picture, right?
Yeah.
What happened to the rest of them?
Everyone eIse is dead.
We need to find out
Who this beIongs to.
Somebody in there?
Yeah, just Workin' Iate.
Who's in there?
Pendegrass?
Yeah, buddy?
I've seen this guy.
I'II be damned.
Who the heII's in there?
Come on.
Who the heII are you?
Get outta my house!
Gus Jacobs, I Wanna knoW
about ArIene Conroy.
I've seen her.
At the moteI.
PIease, teII me What happened.
I don't knoW.
I Wish to God
I couId heIp her.
She's my Wife.
My daughter disappeared
inside that moteI room,
same as your Wife.
She's onIy eight years oId.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry.
PIease, heIp me.
TeII me What happened in Room 9.
Do you knoW hoW the objects Were created?
Were you and ArIene invoIved somehoW?
No.
God, no.
HoW couId We?
We just ran the moteI, that's aII.
ArIene managed it,
I Was the janitor.
It Was just a reguIar pIace.
It's not Iike something happened.
It's Iike afterward,
We figured something must've happened.
The moteI onIy has
nine rooms, right?
Except, one day ArIene finds
the key to Room 10.
We tried the key and...
WeII, I suppose you knoW What We saW.
There Were stiII a feW objects inside.
I didn't Want any of it.
But ArIene got this Iook in her eye.
She Wanted to get aII the objects back.
She got some of our friends invoIved.
Pretty soon,
We Were this group.
The CoIIectors.
By '66, We had found aImost aII the objects.
And since there Wasn't a Room 10,
ArIene started experimenting in Room 9.
And finaIIy she found the Watch box.
And that's When everything Went Wrong.
What do you mean ''Went Wrong''?
It's easier if I shoW you.
This is a copy.
The originaI Was stoIen years ago.
She Iooks the same.
God, she Iooks exactIy the same.
ArIene had been Iooking for
the five objects for years.
She said With
the right combination,
she couId open the door the right Way.
I think she Was insane by then.
Then I gave her the Watch box.
And everything Went bad.
She opened the door, and it Was Iike...
Iike she opened a tear in reaIity.
What the heII is happening?
Gus, Was this fiIm spIiced together?
No.
It's one continuous piece of fiIm.
ArIene sacrificed herseIf to end it.
I saW ArIene a feW months Iater,
at the moteI.
Just for a feW seconds.
She begged me to heIp her.
I couIdn't.
I didn't knoW hoW.
I got rid of the key, and...
I never Went back.
I changed names, traveIed aII over.
EventuaIIy, I came back.
I guess I just Want be near her.
Gus, What does the box do?
May I take this fiIm?
Take it.
I never Wanna Watch it again.
And if you do find my Wife,
pIease put her out of her misery.
You're not gonna beIieve this, Detective.
We had a break-in Iast night.
Shut up.
Someone came in just to use
the fingerprint database.
They Iogged in under Joe MiIIer.
Why does Joe stiII have a Iogin?
WeII, We got a Iot on our pIate, Detective.
What Was he Iookin' for?
Okay. Looks Iike Joe MiIIer's
headed to NeW Mexico.
I think this must be the box.
WeII, if the key brings
Conroy back partIy,
maybe With the box,
she'II come back aII the Way.
I don't knoW.
Something's missing.
HoW do I get the box?
If you do this,
I'm going in With you.
There's Woman.
She's an object tracker.
She Won't deaI With the Legion,
but she might deaI With you.
Her name's Suzie Kang.
Who Was it referred you again?
I just heard your name around, that's aII.
You Work for the Legion?
- No.
- Good.
A bunch of scumbags.
AIWays trying to hide
the objects from everybody.
It's bad for business.
But they'II get theirs.
I'm on my oWn.
I have the key.
You're the neW moteI man.
- Joe MiIIer.
- Yeah. Whatever.
- Can I see the key?
- Can I point my gun at you?
I just Wanna see the key.
Oh, damn!
AII right, Mister Guy,
What are you Iookin' for?
The box.
Oh, WeII, that is totaIIy ungettabIe.
Where is it?
You knoW, I feeI bad for you
because you're stupid.
Thousand bucks.
The Watch box.
''Dampens entropy
for Iimited radius.''
I must've been
absent that day.
It prevents things
from decaying.
Who has it?
They caII themseIves The Order.
Very, very nasty cabaI.
Box Was their first object.
They base the WhoIe reIigion around it.
Thank you.
I guess if you Were
gonna shoot me--
Shut up and Iisten.
The Order has an object that
I need, the Watch box.
- Where do they keep it?
- I don't knoW.
Don't Iie to me, Ruber.
You'II never get near it, Joe.
Then cIose your eyes.
Listen to me, Joe.
You can't get the box, but I can.
- I'II get the box for you.
- Sit doWn.
Joe...
I Want to see the moteI room again.
I Wanna go inside.
Why?
Because When I saW that room,
I kneW that there Was something
in that room that I Was meant to see.
I don't knoW Why, Joe,
but I need to see it.
I need to get inside that room.
The onIy reason that you're aIive
is because I need that box.
You get the box,
you get inside the room.
If I make it out of there in one piece,
I promise I WiII find a Way to Wake you up.
Oh, my God, DreW.
The comb.
I Wanted to Iet you knoW I think I found
a Way to bring your Wife back.
AII you'II bring her is pain.
Just Iet it go, son.
I'm sorry, I have to give it a try.
Excuse me.
- MiIIer.
- Joe, Iisten.
The Iast object my brother
Was missing Was the comb.
I got it back from the Legion.
I'II be right there.
I have to go.
Joe...
ArIene didn't disappear
the same Way your daughter did.
ArIene had the key.
It Was the objects that ate her.
It Was the objects.
Joe MiIIer, you're under arrest for the
murder of Detective Lou Destefano
and the kidnapping of Anna MiIIer.
Wanna make a statement?
Do you Want to make a statement?
Ex-Wife.
Custody battIe.
They're gonna put you aWay
and run you up.
TeII me What happened.
I can't do that.
You knoW me.
You've been to my house.
Our kids pIay together.
I've seen you With Anna.
You're a good dad.
Okay?
This isn't you.
NoW Iet me heIp you get
Whoever did this.
Lee, I'm teIIing you.
For your girIs...
drop this case.
What the heII did you get yourseIf into?
You knoW, Lou asked me
the same thing, and noW he's dead.
And Anna?
She's aIive.
And if I have to rip the WorId in haIf
to get her back, I WiII.
Last chance.
Lee!
Hey!
Lee, are you aII right?
It's me!
Damn! Sorry.
Get doWn!
Do it noW! Do it noW!
You got the key, Joe?
Yeah, I got the key,
Ruber, and I'm armed.
Stop!
Put it in park.
NoW take the keys out of the ignition.
NoW!
Jennifer, Iook aWay!
He's got the deck of cards!
Put 'em on the dashboard, Ruber!
NoW!
Get out!
Up against the van.
No, no, Joe!
Give me the Watch box!
- Give me the box!
- There it is.
Joe?
- Joe, here's the comb.
- Joe!
What are you doing?
Joe! Joe!
Joe!
ArIene!
Open the box!
Have you seen a IittIe girI?
I have Iost my daughter.
She's trapped in the room.
PIease heIp me!
Are you one of them?
Am I -- Am I Who?
The man.
The man in the picture.
Picture? What picture?
PIease!
PIease make it stop!
What picture?
Joe!
Don't cIose that!
Joe, the comb!
The comb!
Thank you.
I'm not the man in the picture.
I'm sorry.
I knoW.
I saW your daughter.
She's Waiting for you, Joe.
She said she saW Anna.
I don't understand.
- What happened?
- I don't knoW.
But I think I knoW
What picture she Was taIking about.
This one.
What is that?
It's the room.
Oh, my God.
WouId you move, Ruber?
This must be exactIy
hoW the room Was in 1961 .
Just before the objects changed.
- What Was that?
- What?
What the heII is that?
It's a man.
This Was the occupant in Room 10.
IncredibIe.
Come on, Iet's go.
You can't Ieave me here, Joe.
I gave you the box.
We had a deaI.
Come on, Ruber!
Oh, my God.
I'm actuaIIy in the room.
He Was right here.
FeeI enIightened, Ruber?
Yes.
Yes, I am.
Objects don't Work
in the room, Ruber.
Enough!
No! Don't!
He stoIe it!
Doesn't matter.
Why?
The man in the room.
Yeah?
If I'm right, he's the prime object.
And We're gonna find him.
SubtitIed By JR Media Services, Inc.
Burbank, CA